<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 050 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-050/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 16:09:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 050 Author Interview: Tisha Marie Reichle-Aguilera and &#8220;Seven Strands&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-050-author-interview-tisha-marie-reichle-aguilera-and-seven-strands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 050]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28269</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[And so we&#8217;ve reached our final Issue 050 author interview. We hope you&#8217;ve enjoyed getting&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>And so we&#8217;ve reached our final <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-050/">Issue 050</a> author interview. We hope you&#8217;ve enjoyed getting to know the authors in this milestone issue as much as we have. The honor of wrapping things up goes to Tisha Marie Reichle-Aguilera and her thoughts on her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/seven-strands/">Seven Strands</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: I love how this story starts off with us thinking one way about Norma before it turns onto a different path. When writing this, how did you envision the twist?</strong></em></div>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28496 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/drew-jemmett-qEcWgrTG578-unsplash-300x201.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="201" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/drew-jemmett-qEcWgrTG578-unsplash-300x201.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/drew-jemmett-qEcWgrTG578-unsplash-1024x685.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/drew-jemmett-qEcWgrTG578-unsplash-768x514.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/drew-jemmett-qEcWgrTG578-unsplash-1536x1028.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/drew-jemmett-qEcWgrTG578-unsplash-2048x1371.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Tisha: Often, the women in my community were expected to be supportive of their men and their elders, without question. Something I&#8217;ve resisted most of my adult life (okay even when I was younger, a little bit). And one of the ways I&#8217;ve resisted is through not conforming to the religious expectations I was raised with, so I thought I&#8217;d see how that could play out in a character. I wanted Norma to be the kind of person who took control of a situation. It becomes clear that her rhetoric has influenced Cristian and his mother already. This is the first opportunity she&#8217;s had with Magdalena who proves to be a challenge. There&#8217;s always that one person, right, who has their own way of resisting already and might not be so easily influenced. That person demands a twist!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: We all know a Tia Magdelena who<span style="color: #000000;"> has, as Cristian’s mom describes it, “duh-ra-muh”. Was her character inspired by a real life person?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Tisha: Most of my characters are composites of several people, so it is natural for some people, not just mis Tias, to see themselves reflected in the duh-ra-ma. My mom was worried that my Nina, her younger sister, would think Magdalena was her because that&#8217;s who would be at my mom&#8217;s bedside if she was sick, but Mom always worries that people think she&#8217;s the mom in all my stories and I have to remind her that I write fiction. (There is one time I published nonfiction that she insisted was fiction because she didn&#8217;t like what I revealed about her giving her grandkids candy in church.) My Nina knew Magdalena was NOT her.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: You have interesting themes of taking care of others (in more than one way) and taking care of ourselves. How did this become a part of your story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Tisha: I&#8217;m the oldest of four kids and one of the oldest girls in a whole bunch of cousins, so I&#8217;ve taken on that care role in my own family. I was also a high school teacher for 20 years so providing emotional and sometimes physical care (I always had cleansing wipes, bandages, and antibacterial ointment in my desk drawer) was part of my daily routine. It is only recently that I learned to take care of myself, to prioritize my physical and mental health so that I can be present for others. Through my fiction, I hope I reveal alternative ways to be in relationship with those who need care. And in this case, those whose caring methods might need a little adjusting.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: You have two characters essentially trying to influence events with their own kind of magic. Do you enjoy writing about physical magic? Other magic?</strong></em></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28497 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ursula-castillo-aLfHUE8o5Xc-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ursula-castillo-aLfHUE8o5Xc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ursula-castillo-aLfHUE8o5Xc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ursula-castillo-aLfHUE8o5Xc-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ursula-castillo-aLfHUE8o5Xc-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ursula-castillo-aLfHUE8o5Xc-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Tisha: I&#8217;m sure there are people who would balk at the idea of their religious practice being &#8220;magic,&#8221; but I don&#8217;t see it as that different from what are often referred to as the &#8220;dark arts&#8221; or the spells of brujas. Both require faith and ritual. Both can have outcomes that are not what we want. I don&#8217;t know what the statistics are for number of prayers granted, but I imagine they are about the same as the number of spells that work. This is only the second story I&#8217;ve written with magical elements. (The other one is unpublished right now.) I find it quite challenging to make magic believable without being cliche. I wanted Norma to be a person who contradicts the religious traditions I grew up with by using her own spiritual truths, to offer a different way of seeing how we can influence others&#8217; behaviors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 050 Author Interview: Jamie M. Boyd and &#8220;The End of Sleep&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-050-author-interview-jamie-m-boyd-and-the-end-of-sleep/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 050]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28467</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In our penultimate Issue 050 author interview, Jamie M. Boyd is bringing the science to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In our penultimate <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-050/">Issue 050</a> author interview, Jamie M. Boyd is bringing the science to science fiction! Find out what kind of research she did for her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-end-of-sleep/">The End of Sleep</a>,&#8221; as well as her thoughts in happy endings.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This has such a precise and scientific concept. Is there such a thing as unilateral sleep? How much research went into writing this story?</strong></em></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28468 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ruc9hve-l-e-300x200.jpg" alt="woman sleeping on bed under blankets" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ruc9hve-l-e-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ruc9hve-l-e-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ruc9hve-l-e-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ruc9hve-l-e-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ruc9hve-l-e.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Jamie: Yes, unilateral sleep is real. It allows birds to sleep with half their brain while still flying and dolphins to sleep while surfacing for air. When I heard about it, my first thought was, “Imagine if humans could do that.” At the time, my children were very young, and I was exhausted. I still fantasize about having an extra eight, productive hours a day.</p>
<p>In real life, the closest thing humans have to unilateral sleep is what’s known as the “first night effect,” named after the poor sleep many people experience when sleeping in a hotel for the first time. One side of the brain is more awake then the other, as if on guard duty. (You can read more about it in this <em>Scientific American</em> article “<a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/sleeping-with-half-a-brain/">Sleeping with Half a Brain</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>I did quite a bit of research for this story, mostly to make it believable, but also because I’m just<br />
fascinated by sleep and sleep disorders. Sleep is something we all spend so much time doing, yet science knows so little about it. Consider sleepwalking and night terrors, where people are up and moving around and interacting with the world, yet overlaying dreams and nightmares on top of reality. It’s spooky and begs the question, ‘How do our brains decide what’s real and what’s imagined? How do our dreams and nightmares affect our daily lives?’ That’s where the rest of the story started to fill itself in, with Ocan and his dreams of his dead wife.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What a story arc! You cover years in Ocan’s life and so many changes. What was your process for planning “The End of Sleep”?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jamie: I didn’t plan out this story in terms of plot &#8212; if I had, I probably would’ve told myself to focus on a smaller slice! Especially in a short story, whenever you jump forward months or years, you risk disorienting the reader or losing the flow, so it’s not really something I’d recommend or do on purpose. During the editing process I tried to reign it back in – a lot of speculative publications won’t even accept a short story that’s over 5,000 words – but each time I carved a section out, it fell flat. I finally accepted that Ocan’s journey from hopelessness to hope was what I was most attached to, and I needed the longer story length and time span to do that in a believable way.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Despite the years and trauma, you gave Ocan a happy ending in line with his dream<br />
fantasies: a daughter. What were your thoughts for Ocan’s happy ending? Happy endings<br />
for stories in general?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jamie: A lot of people suffer from grief and addiction, so with Ocan, I wanted to show it was possible for him to rebuild his life.</p>
<p>Happy endings are common in novels but rarer in short stories. Part of this is just the logistical<br />
challenge. You only have only so many words to introduce your character and conflict. There’s not always time to get them out of trouble in a way that feels true. The second issue is that the entire purpose of many short stories is cautionary. For example, if a science fiction story is imagining all the things that could go wrong with a new technology, a tragic or ironic ending can be more fitting.</p>
<p>The last reason I think there are fewer short stories with positive endings is that they require the author to take a bigger risk. If an editor or reader doesn’t like piece of dark fantasy or sci-fi, they might call it cynical or bleak, but that really doesn’t sound so bad, does it? But if a story with a happy ending doesn’t work, it might be labeled trite or naïve. Especially in speculative fiction, where writers are working so hard to be taken “seriously,” that somehow feels more personal. And in the literary world, where male authors have traditionally held the power and money, anything labeled soft (i.e. feminine) also risks being more easily dismissed.</p>
<p>Despite this, I believe stories that offer hope are vital. You saw this during Covid, with the flurry articles recommending fiction to lift everyone’s spirits. Within science fiction, the solarpunk sub- genre is an important next step in the conversation about climate change. I can only read so many depressing end-of-the-world stories. We need to start exploring worlds with workable solutions.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: “The End of Sleep” was a complex sci-fi drama. What other genres do you like to write in?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jamie: I generally gravitate toward anything in the speculative realm. I also like to write about animals and nature, anything that evokes a sense of wildness and wonder.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 050 Author Interview: Hannah Hulbert and &#8220;Daemonum Ex&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-050-author-interview-hannah-hulbert-and-daemonum-ex/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 050]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s spotlighted author, Hannah Hulbert, tells us all about how she tried something new with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s spotlighted author, Hannah Hulbert, tells us all about how she tried something new with her writing. &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/daemonum-ex/">Daemonum Ex</a>&#8221; is the result, and we couldn&#8217;t be happier to have it in our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-050/">milestone issue</a>!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This is a twisty one! The whole time I thought one thing and the other thing happened! Did you have it in mind from the beginning for Marthim to have summoned Everelda?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28458 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/melina-kiefer-Co079FVq3v0-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/melina-kiefer-Co079FVq3v0-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/melina-kiefer-Co079FVq3v0-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/melina-kiefer-Co079FVq3v0-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/melina-kiefer-Co079FVq3v0-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/melina-kiefer-Co079FVq3v0-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/melina-kiefer-Co079FVq3v0-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Hannah: Absolutely! This is the first romantic story I&#8217;ve ever written and I wanted to make it as interesting as possible. Every time the romance trope took the plot into a &#8216;zig&#8217; I made a deliberate effort to &#8216;zag&#8217; back again in the opposite direction. I&#8217;m delighted that you didn&#8217;t see the twist coming!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: At the core, this has a theme of relationships and about how people/demons/witches change over time. Did you end up drawing on personal experience to create the evolution of the two characters?</strong></em></p>
<p>Hannah: Yes, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever written a main character who wasn&#8217;t actually a facet of my own personality. I&#8217;m not many birthdays away from forty and imagining what the future might look like for me and my family. I love using fiction to work through matters which are important to me, and then sending the work that I produce in the process out into the world. It seems a more fruitful kind of angst &#8211; never waste a midlife crisis!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: At the end, their bond is sealed by the idea to visit Lord Fortesque (which is funny and wicked at the same time). I can imagine lots of future mischief together. What do you imagine they are doing after the story ends?</strong></em></p>
<p>Hannah: You know, I very rarely have an idea of what characters will do next when I finish a story. Occasionally they will pop up in another somewhere down the line. But I do like your idea of them having adventures together and causing low-level trouble. I think that&#8217;s exactly what they would do!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Within the grim world you painted, you added such a lovely breath of romance. Is this a genre you often write in? What are your favorite kinds of stories to create?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28459 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/martin-brechtl-S02FHccCSdA-unsplash-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/martin-brechtl-S02FHccCSdA-unsplash-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/martin-brechtl-S02FHccCSdA-unsplash-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/martin-brechtl-S02FHccCSdA-unsplash-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/martin-brechtl-S02FHccCSdA-unsplash-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/martin-brechtl-S02FHccCSdA-unsplash-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/martin-brechtl-S02FHccCSdA-unsplash-2048x2048.jpg 2048w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/martin-brechtl-S02FHccCSdA-unsplash-550x550.jpg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Hannah: No, I actually challenged myself to write a romance in this story because my default fictional relationships are between The Girl Who Doesn&#8217;t Realize How Strong She Is<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> and The Awful Boyfriend<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />. Although lighter, more hopeful stories are becoming more appealing to me these days. I&#8217;ve been thinking a lot about how fictional narratives provide a framework for us as both individuals and communities to envision our future. I think taking a more optimistic view of humanity (and other sentient life!) is a change I needed to make, and I&#8217;m glad to share that step with you all!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 050 Author Interview: Jennifer Lee Rossman and &#8220;Maiasaura Deifaeria&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-050-author-interview-jennifer-lee-rossman-and-maiasaura-deifaeria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 050]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28273</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Longtime readers may recognize today&#8217;s author&#8217;s name! Jennifer Lee Rossman joins our pages once again,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Longtime readers may recognize today&#8217;s author&#8217;s name! Jennifer Lee Rossman joins our pages once again, bringing magic to <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-050/">Issue 050</a> with their story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/maiasaura-deifaeria/">Maiasaura Deifaeria</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What a perfectly lovely and quirky story!  I never would have imagined a dinosaur fairy godmother! How did she first come to mind?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: There was an anthology call for stories about fairy godmothers I wanted to write for, but I didn&#8217;t feel like I had a creative enough idea. Everything I could think of had already been done before. But since I have a bit of a reputation on Twitter for adding dinosaurs do everything (only slightly deserved, lol, I actually don&#8217;t do it as much as people think I do), I figured why not dinosaurs?</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: But this story is also about relationships. Your MC was more than Asha’s fairy godmother, even if she couldn’t see it until the end. Would you say that Asha’s wish was granted? What about your MC’s?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: Asha&#8217;s wish was granted eventually, although definitely not the way she originally intended. I think if she could read the story, she would understand why her godmother acted the way she did, and she would be satisfied with the way things turned out.</p>
<div dir="auto">My main character&#8217;s wish has always been to take care of her godchildren. I&#8217;m not sure if she would consider this a success, I think part of her will always think she failed Asha, and it might take her a long time to come to terms with her feelings on that.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: It took a long time (65 million years) to find resolution. Even so, the ending was left a little open. Do you think your MC was able to assimilate enough to help the human girl?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Jennifer: I think she&#8217;s going to try. That&#8217;s all a mother can do, isn&#8217;t it? Try your best to take care of the children who need you.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: You have some complex themes spaced throughout your story: bones, grief, love, and a dash of humor. What are the themes you tend to go for in your other writing?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Jennifer: Blame a lifetime of watching <em>Jurassic Park</em>, but Life Finds A Way tends to pop up in my stories a lot. Even in this one, which seems to be all about death, is still about life going on with or without you, finding a way to make things work out in the end.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 050 Author Interview: Claire McAneny and &#8220;Reaping Rewards&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-050-author-interview-claire-mcaneny-and-reaping-rewards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 050]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Issue 050 authors are so talented, aren&#8217;t they? We love getting to look behind&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div dir="auto">Our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-050/">Issue 050</a> authors are so talented, aren&#8217;t they? We love getting to look behind the curtain at their creative genius. Today, sharing her genius with us is Claire McAneny, author of &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/reaping-rewards/">Reaping Rewards</a>.&#8221;</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><strong><em>LSQ: Nicola is such an interesting character. Tell us the origin of how you created her.</em></strong></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28395 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/vero-photoart-AsoGv4adoao-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/vero-photoart-AsoGv4adoao-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/vero-photoart-AsoGv4adoao-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/vero-photoart-AsoGv4adoao-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/vero-photoart-AsoGv4adoao-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/vero-photoart-AsoGv4adoao-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Claire: Nicola is a combination of different people that I have known. My children were young when I wrote this story and I was coming to terms with the influence that other adults have in their life. So, Nicola&#8217;s experience is my version of a worst case scenario as a parent.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: This is a world where magic works, but doesn&#8217;t seem to be commonplace. How did you choose to use magic in this story? How does it compare to the use of magic in other stories?</strong></em></p>
<p><span id="m_2492881849062258185gmail-docs-internal-guid-0c9dd758-7fff-4fc2-9149-5e2c18158de2">Claire: All of my stories so far have ended up with magic in them. I love exploring the idea that there is more to our world than what we see on the surface. If we keep looking in the hidden places we will find more.</span></p>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">I also like exploring how magic would work in our every day lives.</div>
<div dir="auto"><span class="im"><br />
</span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: I enjoyed the detail of keeping the emotions and associations in hair. Also how Nicola had to help to be part of the spell. Why was it important to involve her?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Claire: I find it really interesting how a &#8216;good hair day&#8217; can make us feel better and how often women change their hair style when they make a change in their life.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Nicola needed to learn how to take back control of her life. It can be hard to move from feeling like a victim of your circumstances to taking action. I also wanted the magic to be more tangible and accessible by anyone instead of a magic wand that can only be accessed and used by the &#8216;chosen few&#8217;.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: What kinds of subjects do you like writing about? Are there any other stories that you are currently working on?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28397 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pure-julia-ky-ni5-FAKk-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pure-julia-ky-ni5-FAKk-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pure-julia-ky-ni5-FAKk-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pure-julia-ky-ni5-FAKk-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pure-julia-ky-ni5-FAKk-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pure-julia-ky-ni5-FAKk-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pure-julia-ky-ni5-FAKk-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">Claire: I like writing in the fantasy genre because I love mirroring situations that we might experience in our own lives but with a magical twist.</p>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">I am currently working on a novel length mystery set in contemporary Ireland.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 050 Author Interview: Hannah Whiteoak and &#8220;Earth Report&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-050-author-interview-hannah-whiteoak-and-earth-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 050]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In today&#8217;s Issue 050 author interview we&#8217;re taking a close look at human nature with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-050/">Issue 050</a> author interview we&#8217;re taking a close look at human nature with Hannah Whiteoak and their story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/earth-report/">Earth Report</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28356 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/eduardo-soares-QsYXYSwV3NU-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/eduardo-soares-QsYXYSwV3NU-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/eduardo-soares-QsYXYSwV3NU-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/eduardo-soares-QsYXYSwV3NU-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/eduardo-soares-QsYXYSwV3NU-unsplash-1229x1536.jpg 1229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/eduardo-soares-QsYXYSwV3NU-unsplash-1638x2048.jpg 1638w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/eduardo-soares-QsYXYSwV3NU-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />LSQ: This is a wonderfully transformative piece where the transformation lies with the main character. Share with</strong></em> <em><strong>us</strong><strong> about your use of perspective to tell this story.</strong></em></p>
<p>Hannah: I enjoy using the perspectives of people who are outsiders in some way. People who don&#8217;t quite understand a society, and/or aren&#8217;t understood by it, can give interesting insights.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I think we’ve all been to the supermarket on Sunday and felt the human chaos you describe so well. Is there one annoying human thing in particular that really gets under your skin? Anything in particular that motivated your story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Hannah: The part of this story I relate to most strongly is actually the main characters&#8217; love of biscuits. Humans are annoying in so many ways that sometimes I wonder why we bother to keep going, but then I have a cup of tea and a biscuit and feel better. Perhaps there&#8217;s a life lesson there.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Your story was funny as well as incredibly touching. How often do you combine different techniques for a certain effect? Is humor something you enjoy writing?</em></strong></p>
<p>Hannah: I don&#8217;t usually write humor, but occasionally a story will pop out with a humorous voice. It&#8217;s always a nice surprise when that happens and I try not to kill it with edits.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: In your stories, do you usually look for emotional closure for your characters? The ending to this story was just perfect! Is there anything else</em></strong><strong><em> about the ending you wanted to add?</em></strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28357 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ulvi-safari-AfH5kgvdk0E-unsplash-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ulvi-safari-AfH5kgvdk0E-unsplash-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ulvi-safari-AfH5kgvdk0E-unsplash-673x1024.jpg 673w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ulvi-safari-AfH5kgvdk0E-unsplash-768x1169.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ulvi-safari-AfH5kgvdk0E-unsplash-1009x1536.jpg 1009w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ulvi-safari-AfH5kgvdk0E-unsplash-1346x2048.jpg 1346w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/ulvi-safari-AfH5kgvdk0E-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1682w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" /></p>
<p>Hannah: I really struggle to write endings. Real life so rarely has emotional closure. I have a hard drive full of stories that are fine apart from the fact that they just stop, as I can&#8217;t find a satisfying and believable way to end them. An ending idea that works is a rare gift from the writing gods.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 050 Author Interview: Altaire Gural and &#8220;State Vs. Hades&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-050-author-interview-altaire-gural-and-state-vs-hades/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 10:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 050]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, dear readers! We&#8217;re bringing a little courtroom drama to today&#8217;s Issue 050 author interview.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello, dear readers! We&#8217;re bringing a little courtroom drama to today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-050/">Issue 050</a> author interview. Have you read &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/state-vs-hades/">State Vs. Hades</a>&#8221; yet? You won&#8217;t want to miss what Altaire Gural has to say about the inspiration behind this one!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The format of this story was really interesting, I loved following the trial as it proceeded. I also felt profoundly sad for Persephone no matter who had taken the stand. What made you decide to adapt the classic myth of Hades and Persephone like this?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28282 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/emma-francis-TlWRHiKDCvA-unsplash-300x202.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="202" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/emma-francis-TlWRHiKDCvA-unsplash-300x202.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/emma-francis-TlWRHiKDCvA-unsplash.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Altaire: I saw a court document floating in the air (don’t ask).</p>
<p dir="ltr">Nevermind. You did ask, didn’t you?</p>
<p dir="ltr">My writing process is rather intrusive: characters start speaking to me quite loudly, or images will suddenly float directly in front of me. It&#8217;s never till I’m part way into the writing of it that I can say “Ah. Now I see what this is.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">I think Persephone and Hades is one of the most beloved, romanticized mythologies; all my students love it, there’s fanfiction for it. From the time I was tiny, I was fascinated with the Nathaniel Hawthorne/Tanglewood Tales version of it (pomegranates became one of my “things”).</p>
<p dir="ltr">And then I saw the court document floating in the air, and to say that I was triggered is an understatement. It made so much sense. I wasn’t even sure I wanted to write it at all, because there are universal truths in the story that are part of the core for women everywhere: grooming, molestation, family dynamics, older men/younger women, mother/daughter dynamics. It’s all so difficult; the anger.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I saw Persephone as her own person with big dreams, and how circumstances beyond her control shaped who she became.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I think she’ll eventually grow to the eat the stars. At least, I hope she does.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: When you got to the part about the family dynamic being “complicated” and the Egyptian Pantheon being similar, I laughed. Some parts of this were so funny, while others were sad, but it all came together really well. How did you figure out the kind of tone you wanted for this?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Altaire: I’m not clever enough to plan for tone, so I guess my style is to walk between humor and tragedy naturally. Maybe it’s because I’m a Gemini …?</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Have you thought about adapting any other myths? I hear there’s a really interesting, super complicated Egyptian Pantheon out there that could be fun…</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28284 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/sara-cervera-rrRPFsYB-x0-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/sara-cervera-rrRPFsYB-x0-unsplash-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/sara-cervera-rrRPFsYB-x0-unsplash-681x1024.jpg 681w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/sara-cervera-rrRPFsYB-x0-unsplash-768x1155.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/sara-cervera-rrRPFsYB-x0-unsplash-1021x1536.jpg 1021w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/sara-cervera-rrRPFsYB-x0-unsplash-1362x2048.jpg 1362w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/sara-cervera-rrRPFsYB-x0-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1702w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">Altaire: Called. Out.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I really seem to love the parallels between modern social issues, and the truths embedded within fairytales and mythologies. Flipping narratives to long held assumptions has definitely become a theme in my work.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Maybe Sekhmet has something to say …</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 050 Author Interview: Elizabeth Guilt and &#8220;Other Lives&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-050-author-interview-elizabeth-guilt-and-other-lives/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 050]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to another Issue 050 author interview! If you had the chance to see what&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-050/">Issue 050</a> author interview! If you had the chance to see what your life would look like had you made different choices&#8230; would you? We ask Elizabeth Guilt this and more about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/other-lives/">Other Lives</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><span class="im"><em><strong>LSQ: What a brilliant idea! Who hasn’t ever wondered what would have happened if they’d made anther choice or followed another path? What made you hone in on the idea for this story?</strong></em></span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28246 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/david-deleon-yf0wWlwS2Ok-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/david-deleon-yf0wWlwS2Ok-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/david-deleon-yf0wWlwS2Ok-unsplash-1024x767.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/david-deleon-yf0wWlwS2Ok-unsplash-768x575.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/david-deleon-yf0wWlwS2Ok-unsplash-1536x1150.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/david-deleon-yf0wWlwS2Ok-unsplash-2048x1534.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Elizabeth: Thank you! The story grew originally from the idea of an amazing, magical fair, and the sorts of things you might find there.</p>
<p>Hearing about an &#8220;other life&#8221; felt like something which would be popular, and would be in keeping with the tradition of traveling circus shows. Despite the narrator&#8217;s question &#8211; why would you want to hear about that? &#8211; I think many people would been keen to hear one of their other lives. Pinning down quite *why* people would find these other lives interesting is much harder, which is why I found it a compelling idea for a sideshow.<br />
<span class="im"><br />
<em><strong>LSQ: I loved getting the intriguing little glimpses into other lives for Emily and Robert, and then I got seriously concerned for the main character! What an ending. Did you always see this story concluding like this, or did you plan out a more specific fate for the main character at one point?</strong></em></span></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I am not one of life&#8217;s careful planners, so for a long time I had no idea how the story was going to end! I always knew that the main character wouldn&#8217;t get to see an other life, but originally I expected that to be their own choice.</p>
<p>The &#8220;Other Life woman&#8221; does this every day, reviewing people&#8217;s other lives and selecting one she believes they will enjoy hearing. It&#8217;s magic, but it is mundane to her. I started wondering about what might frighten her. A great-aunt of mine used to read tea-leaves to tell fortunes, got scared by how accurate she felt her readings were, and stopped. Presumably the seer of other lives is comfortable with her own abilities, and presumably she sometimes sees unpleasant or dangerous lives &#8211; but what could she see that she&#8217;d never encountered before?</p>
<p>From there, I could see the ending. I don&#8217;t usually feel like I&#8217;m choosing how to close a story, more that I&#8217;m writing in assorted directions until I manage to find out what the ending has been all the time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28247 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/burst-aoN3HWLbhdI-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/burst-aoN3HWLbhdI-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/burst-aoN3HWLbhdI-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/burst-aoN3HWLbhdI-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/burst-aoN3HWLbhdI-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/burst-aoN3HWLbhdI-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: If you could see one of your own “other lives,” what do you hope it would show you?</em></strong></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I&#8217;ve always been very aware of paths not taken in life, or choices made. I think what I&#8217;d most like to see is a self who&#8217;s taken a route that I hadn&#8217;t even thought of, and has a life I didn&#8217;t know I&#8217;d missed. I hope she&#8217;s enjoying it!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 050 Author Interview: M. J. Garland and &#8220;Chokeleaf&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-050-author-interview-m-j-garland-and-chokeleaf/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 050]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We have another Issue 050 author interview for you today, dear readers! M. J. Garland&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We have another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-050/">Issue 050</a> author interview for you today, dear readers! M. J. Garland is in our hot seat talking with us about her poignant story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/chokeleaf/">Chokeleaf</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This is such a complex, moving story. It led me down a tangle of emotions and potential scenarios and finished by giving me what I desperately hope is a metaphor for the main character. She, and the chokeleaf itself, are fascinating. Where did you get the idea for this story?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28220 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/byron-johnson-pj1jt4vBGZY-unsplash-300x190.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="190" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/byron-johnson-pj1jt4vBGZY-unsplash-300x190.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/byron-johnson-pj1jt4vBGZY-unsplash-1024x649.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/byron-johnson-pj1jt4vBGZY-unsplash-768x487.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/byron-johnson-pj1jt4vBGZY-unsplash-1536x974.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/byron-johnson-pj1jt4vBGZY-unsplash-2048x1298.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />M. J.: <span dir="auto">My roommates and I have a garden, and I&#8217;m always impressed by the tenacity of unwanted plants. Some weeds are almost magical in their ability to spring up and overshadow other plants overnight. I</span>&#8216;m easily distracted or overwhelmed by excessive background noise at home or at work, so the idea of a plant engineered to absorb sound appealed to me. Chokeleaf is an improbable organism, but I like imagining improbable or even impossible things. Once I had come up with this plant that absorbs sound, I began to imagine how the invention could go awry. I pictured the plant taking over and blanketing the world in silence. The response to this crisis would likely rely on underpaid and untrained workers, so I came up with an AmeriCorps-style group of young people tasked with removing this invasive species from national parks. The sound-absorbing qualities of Chokeleaf inspired me to think of a character who has a complicated relationship with silence, someone who has cultivated silence to protect herself but at the same time yearns for expression and connection.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I didn’t even think of the environmental implications of a semi-magical, sound-absorbing plant until one of the Trailblazers mentioned it, and then it really sank in with the imagery of the bird. If a thing like this existed, where do you see it being useful, outside of dorm rooms? Where would it be a menace, like it was in the wild?</strong></em></p>
<p>M. J.: I&#8217;m interested in adaptations that can be advantageous and destructive. A plant that absorbs sound could be helpful for people living in noisy environments. At the same time, if it spread uncontrolled, it could have deleterious environmental effects, including preventing animals from hearing the calls they depend on for mating and communicating danger. My main character has also cultivated silence as an adaptation, by not expressing her pain or attraction. This has helped her avoid attracting negative attention, but it&#8217;s also prevented her from connecting with others.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Not to spoil things for readers, but I just have to ask—where do you see the arc of this story going for the main character? Have you thought about a potential future for her, and what it could look like?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28221 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/timothy-meinberg-xqV9QdGOSas-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/timothy-meinberg-xqV9QdGOSas-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/timothy-meinberg-xqV9QdGOSas-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/timothy-meinberg-xqV9QdGOSas-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/timothy-meinberg-xqV9QdGOSas-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/timothy-meinberg-xqV9QdGOSas-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/timothy-meinberg-xqV9QdGOSas-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<p>M. J.: I don&#8217;t have a clear vision for my main character&#8217;s future. I do think she will find the other Trailblazers and make it out of the woods. Before the events of the story, she opened up to her roommate and a therapist, and as a result was placed on a medical leave which she viewed as more of a punishment than a support. It can be incredibly hard to be vulnerable again after an attempt at reaching out results in a worse situation, but I think her experience with the Chokeleaf will inspire her to make new attempts at communicating with others, including reconnecting with her former roommate. I think her journey will have ups and downs, but I do see her life improving.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 050 Author Interview: Savannah Wade and &#8220;Magpie Girls&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-050-author-interview-savannah-wade-and-magpie-girls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 050]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The best kinds of dreams are the ones so wild and vivid that that they&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The best kinds of dreams are the ones so wild and vivid that that they immediately inspire a story. Such was the case for Savannah Wade and her <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-050/">Issue 050</a> story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/magpie-girls/">Magpie Girls</a>.&#8221; Read on as she tells us all about it!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What a journey this story is! It’s so vivid, and the emotion I felt while reading it was so strong—Lily’s apprehension surrounding her father and Josephine’s determination to see that she’s treated right. What inspired you to write this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Savannah: This story first began as a dream. I dreamt of two young school girls both becoming obsessed with a visiting magician and their descent into madness. My dream was so vivid that I could tell it wanted to be a story. When I sat down to write it, the story began morphing under my fingertips into something quite different than my dream. Josephine and Lily’s relationship came naturally so I knew I needed to follow that string and it led to a sapphic yearning tale inspired by <em>Picnic at Hanging Rock</em> by Joan Lindsay and <em>A Great and Terrible Beauty</em> by Libba Bray.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I love the inclusion of Le Bateleur! Did you always know you wanted a divination angle with this story? How did you decide on this card? Do you practice Tarot?</strong></em></p>
<p>Savannah: In my dream, the magician was just that, a magician. I didn’t connect him to the tarot until I was writing it and it came about naturally. Also, I have always wanted to put the magician card in a story because it is my favorite card in the tarot. To me, the magician card is one about becoming a master of knowledge, keeper of secrets and wielder of manipulation and manifestation. I always squee with glee when I get it in my own personal tarot readings. I use tarot for personal and writer reasons. Its incredibly beneficial to create writing structures, characters, and arcs.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The story has a satisfying but open end. Would you write more of the story of Josephine and Lily?</strong></em></p>
<p>Savannah: I don’t think I will write any more of Josephine and Lily, but I do have in my mind what happens to them. Josephine goes onto to take a secretary course in London. Both Lily and Jo live in a small flat above a bakery. Lily lives with Jo while she goes on dates with unavailable but attractive men. Josephine finally gets a job as a secretary and makes a vow to Lily to take care of her so she doesn’t have to marry. Lily hesitantly agrees and slowly, but surely the two form a romantic inseparable bond. Josephine does eventually tell Lily about the magician and she doesn’t believe a word, haha.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
