<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Real Life Rant &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/real-life-rant/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 22:32:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Screw Up and Let it Go: AKA, Be Your Own Holiday Miracle</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/how-to-screw-up-and-let-it-go-aka-be-your-own-holiday-miracle/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 12:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Life Rant]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Everybody’s heard of those terrible, awful times that can happen to the unsuspecting creative, right?&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everybody’s heard of those terrible, awful times that can happen to the unsuspecting creative, right? Those times when the creator loses something they’ve been working on. Something big. Something beautiful. Something <em>important</em>. They lose it because they didn’t save it, didn’t have a backup in place, didn’t…do something right. And then something goes wrong, and they lose their hard work. Exit calm stage left, enter tearful rage.</p>
<p>You resolve to never let it happen to you. Nuh-uh, not you. You have backups for your backups. You’re saving your document every five minutes…or whatever, you’ve got autosave, it’s just as good. You’re gonna be fine, just fine. That tear-stained, devastated muse will never be you. You’re good to go.</p>
<p>And then…</p>
<p>And THEN.</p>
<p>Your computer forces an update, shuts everything down, and when it all comes back you have a version that’s telling you to save it and you DO, before checking to make sure all your latest work was in there.</p>
<p>Which it wasn’t.</p>
<p>Because HA, BEST LAID PLANS! TAKE THAT!</p>
<p>This is me right now.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-26580" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/giphy-300x169.gif" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></p>
<p>I had thousands of words written for the next update on my Patreon story. Words that flowed, words that were beautiful and precious and just what I needed them to be. Words that <em>worked</em>, darn it. And what did I go and do after my computer auto-updated and handed me the version it told me was the most recent?</p>
<p>I saved the wrong version of the story and deleted all my lovely new words.</p>
<p>Welp, I’ve still got a story to get out there to my followers, guess I’m going to have to hove to and go at it until all those words are back. They might be lesser, they may be unenthusiastic, it could feel like stabbing myself in the gumline with a toothpick over and over again, but I should do it. Right?</p>
<p>No. No way. I can’t do it. And the nice thing is, I don’t have to.</p>
<p>Anyone who’s into my writing enough to be a member of my Patreon community will undoubtedly understand when I relate my tale of woe. They will get that I can’t force my mind back to that story right now—I just can’t, it makes me too sad. They’ll know that this isn’t a season for enduring avoidable sadness, and that I’ll make it up to them—which I will, with some different stories and some fun polls and some custom artwork and all the other things I have going on my Patreon.</p>
<p>I don’t make these screw-ups often, but I’m experienced enough now to know that the best thing to do when you make a mistake like this is just…forgive yourself. Nobody’s going to be harder on you than you under these circumstances, so please, don’t. Be kind to yourself. Be your own <img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26581 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/anthony-tran-8i2fHtStfxk-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/anthony-tran-8i2fHtStfxk-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/anthony-tran-8i2fHtStfxk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/anthony-tran-8i2fHtStfxk-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/anthony-tran-8i2fHtStfxk-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/anthony-tran-8i2fHtStfxk-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />holiday miracle and let it go, at least for a while. Do something you love, eat something delicious, be around people you enjoy. Don’t stress over what’s already happened, because yeah, you’ll have to confront that again, but not while you’re still sore</p>
<p>Leave it be, and give yourself a break. Heck, give yourself a pat on the back, a little squeeze, a foot rub. You’ll be okay.</p>
<p>And when you feel better, plan your revenge against the devilish auto-update.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hey, Hey, I Got An MFA! Good For Me, But&#8230;Why Bother?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hey-hey-i-got-an-mfa-good-for-me-but-why-bother/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 10:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Life Rant]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25978</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It seems like “Do I need an MFA to be a writer?” is a question&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It seems like “Do I need an MFA to be a writer?” is a question that gets debated in the Twittersphere on a regular basis. Plenty of people point out the benefits—learning more about the craft of writing, reading outside your normal scope, and creating a community with your fellow students among others. There are lots of points on the other side too, though—expense, how it doesn’t necessarily prepare you to publish, more expense, narrow genre restrictions, and oh yeah, expense!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-25980 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/simone-secci-49uySSA678U-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/simone-secci-49uySSA678U-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/simone-secci-49uySSA678U-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/simone-secci-49uySSA678U-unsplash-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/simone-secci-49uySSA678U-unsplash-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/simone-secci-49uySSA678U-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />I went into my MFA program having already been publishing professionally for over a decade. So why bother with the MFA?</p>
<p>Partly it was because I liked the look of the program—low-residency, a good focus on exploring genres I actually enjoyed reading, in-person meetings twice a year to help build community—and partly, I wanted an educational experience I’d actually enjoy for once. I had a new baby, I was working from home, and for the first time in a long time I had the bandwidth to explore a subject I was truly interested in, rather than pursuing classes relevant to my previous career. So I thought, “Why not?” and applied, and subsequently began my MFA that summer.</p>
<p>Was it as good as I’d hoped it would be? I got lucky in a lot of respects, because when the pandemic really settled in, my schooling wasn’t dramatically impacted. I was already learning at a distance, and it was simple to extend that through what would have been our in-person residencies. I read a lot of interesting stories by fantastic authors I might never have learned about otherwise, got some valuable feedback on my own work, and wrote a book in a genre I’d never tried before and probably wouldn’t have even considered without the right push from my mentors. All yay!</p>
<p>Do I feel more confident heading back out into the publishing world now? Not thanks to the MFA, to be honest. I get way more from my professional connections in that regard than I did from school. But I do have new work to query, and new friends to cheer me on and for me to cheerlead for. Also, having an MFA does make a different to some of my freelance editing contacts, which is helpful on a professional level.</p>
<p>Overall, I’m glad I did it. Of course, YMMV, but for me the community-building was key to making <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-25979 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/patty-brito-l5sAmrAOw9g-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/patty-brito-l5sAmrAOw9g-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/patty-brito-l5sAmrAOw9g-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/patty-brito-l5sAmrAOw9g-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/patty-brito-l5sAmrAOw9g-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/patty-brito-l5sAmrAOw9g-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/patty-brito-l5sAmrAOw9g-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />it worth my while, and was something emphasized by my program. If you’re new to writing, as a confidence builder, the MFA could be a truly great experience. Do your research on different programs, though, and most of all make sure you’re willing to take on the debt. Two years of writing fun will fly by, but tens of thousands of dollars in loans can last forever!</p>
<p>(That’s a joke. It’s almost a joke. It’s <em>mostly</em> a joke.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
