<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Kiana-Danielle &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/kiana-danielle/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:54:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Experimental Film about the Dark Side of Sharing on Social Media</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/experimental-film-about-the-dark-side-of-sharing-on-social-media/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiana-Danielle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outside the Default]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cracked Screen: A Snapchat Story is a fascinating short film, directed by Trim Lamba and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_8319" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8319" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/617925113.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-8319" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/617925113-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-8319" class="wp-caption-text">Cracked Screen (dir. Trim Lamba, 2016)</figcaption></figure>
<p><em>Cracked Screen: A Snapchat Story</em> is a fascinating short film, directed by <a href="https://twitter.com/trimlamba?lang=en">Trim Lamba</a> and starring <a href="https://twitter.com/chantslevene?lang=en">Chantelle Levene</a>, that documents the before and after moments of a young woman’s attack in London completely through Snaps. If I didn’t read the synopsis of the film it would definitely feel like watching anyone’s Snapchat story filled with rants, workout shots, partying with friends, and silly anecdotes. Knowing that something was about to happen that would change this woman’s life made each shoot infused with impending doom. When the attack finally happened the film took a nosedive into the dark, disturbing world that social media can become. This woman had been sharing most of her life online and felt the need to prove to the world that her attack was real by posting footage of her injury for the whole internet to screenshot and share. Her shift in confidence was the most heartbreaking part for me to witness. She went from dancing and laughing to defending herself and her story in the darkness of her room.</p>
<p>I feel this film definitely starts a conversation around how we use and participate in social media. Should we be so quick to share so much of ourselves and our lives with others? Do others deserve to know if we are lying or not while posting on our own social media accounts? Does our audience have the right to demand evidence authenticating our story? The film also brings into question the idea of attractiveness being the sole reason this woman felt worthy to have her own space on the Snapchat platform. Post-attack, the woman continually berates her own appearance as if to beat everyone else to the punchline. I find it interesting that her Snaps, no matter how much they are edited, are true reflections of how she feels about herself. I’m completely aware of how much people curate their lives to appear more impressive than they are in reality, but under all the curation are little bits of truth.</p>
<p><em>Cracked Screen: A Snapchat Story</em> is currently available to watch on <a href="https://www.shortoftheweek.com/2017/02/11/cracked-screen-snapchat-story/">ShortoftheWeek</a>. It is seven minutes that will make you think about your own relationship with social media. I encourage you to share your thoughts below. How do you feel about the medium used to tell the story? Did it make you feel more connected to the main character? Did social media help or hurt the woman’s recovery after her attack? Let’s start a dialogue because I’m sure there’s so much more to say and dissect about this topic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ink: Immigration, Interracial Relations &#038; Bit of Magic</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ink-immigration-interracial-relations-bit-of-magic/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ink-immigration-interracial-relations-bit-of-magic/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiana-Danielle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 17:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outside the Default]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sabrina Vourvoulias&#8217; Ink was mentioned in a previous post by Phoebe Wagner, which gathered a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/index.jpe"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8203 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/index.jpe" width="183" height="275" /></a>Sabrina Vourvoulias&#8217; <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ink-Sabrina-Vourvoulias/dp/0615657818/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1486836416&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=ink+by+sabrina+vourvoulias"><em>Ink</em></a> was mentioned in<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/reading-protest/"> a previous post by Phoebe Wagner</a>, which gathered a few other works that reflect our time to an eerie tee. I picked up the novel because it was a part of my course material in a university class. Vourvouslias&#8217; novel evokes all the feelings of horror that dystopian works tend to successfully do for readers. But, what makes this horror a little different is the world of <em>Ink</em> isn&#8217;t like the world of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nineteen_Eighty-Four"><em>1984</em></a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hunger_Games"><em>The Hunger Games</em></a>. The world of <em>Ink</em> is here and has been here for quite some time.</p>
<p>The novel is split between four characters: Finn, Mari, Del, and Abbie. All the characters are working towards equality for the &#8220;inks,&#8221; who are immigrants with different levels of privilege in society. The inks&#8217; privilege is dictated by the color of their tattoo, which lets others know if they are temporary workers, permanent residents, or citizens. The characters&#8217; narratives orbit around and entangle with one another. The main storyline focuses on the effort to free the inks from their forced branding. Finn and Mari are coupled at the beginning of the novel. Finn&#8217;s a &#8220;legal&#8221; citizen and enjoys all the privileges that come with it. Mari is an inked citizen, confined to certain buses and curfews. Their interracial relationship explores the reality of what it is like to fall in love in a world that believes certain people aren&#8217;t worthy of being treated as human. Finn begins the novel with no knowledge about how oppressive his nonchalant attitude is when it comes to referring to Mari as an ink. It&#8217;s an interesting thing to explore considering that in our own world, more and more relationships are interracial and most often involve one person having more privilege than the other. Finn&#8217;s character was always considered an ally to me as I read the novel, but he understandably had limitations because of his non-inked skin.</p>
<p>Del and Mari bring some magical realism to the story. Del is half Native-American, lives on a farm with his wife, who desperately wants to move to the city. Del&#8217;s love for his land is deeper than just the fact that it&#8217;s his home. He&#8217;s connected to it in a spiritual way that allows him to know when someone has stepped foot on the land without being welcomed on it. Mari is &#8220;twinned&#8221; with a jaguar. It is described as a companion that she was born with in order to protect her. It makes multiple appearances throughout her narrative, exploring an unseen world and shielding her from the evils that lurk there. The addition of these magical elements gave me an extended look at who Del and Mari were as characters. Their powers acted as a window into their histories, reminding me that they represented more than themselves in this novel. They stood for their culture and their people.</p>
<p>For me, Abbie&#8217;s character grew the most through the course of the novel. The fact that she was the youngest might have something to do with my feeling. She starts the story off as seventeen, working with her mother at a facility that takes inks to chip and imprison them. Once she gets involved with helping a few of them escape and helps create patches to cover their tattoos she&#8217;s forever changed. She becomes an activist and that leads her down a path with some serious consequences.</p>
<p>Multiple narratives can be a tricky thing to pull off but without it, this novel things wouldn&#8217;t feel as honest. The subject of immigration touches the lives of many, so seeing one side of the story wouldn&#8217;t have been satisfactory. <em>Ink</em> reminds readers of the past with callbacks to internment camps, offers commentary on the present with the hierarchical system inks are forced into, and warns about a potential future where inked skin (which could just as easily be a wall) could permanently exclude a whole group of people. <em>Ink</em> is definitely a must-read, created for a time where history is once again repeating itself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ink-immigration-interracial-relations-bit-of-magic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>To Whom It May Concern, Let’s Write a Rom-Com</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/to-whom-it-may-concern-lets-write-a-rom-com/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiana-Danielle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 17:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outside the Default]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7979</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To Whom It May Concern, I’m not delusional, I know most romantic comedies are crap.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To Whom It May Concern,</p>
<figure id="attachment_7980" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7980" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a class="left-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/cinderella-story-cover.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-7980 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/cinderella-story-cover-300x200.jpg" width="300" height="200" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7980" class="wp-caption-text">Hilary Duff and Chad Michael Murray in &#8216;A Cinderella Story&#8217;</figcaption></figure>
<p>I’m not delusional, I know most romantic comedies are crap. The teen ones are filled with angsty kids that speak about life as if they’ve lived it six times over. And the adult ones are filled with people who haven’t learned how to communicate properly, despite existing on this planet for decades. The declarations of love are ridiculously long and way too well-worded for them to sound remotely realistic. But, I won’t for the life of me give them up. They’re my guilty pleasure and sometimes even my muse. My devotion to the genre started when I was very young after watching <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0356470/"><em>A Cinderella Story</em></a>. After that, my spare time consisted of marathon after marathon of the 90s and early-2000s rom-coms. I watched anything I could record or get my hands on at the local library. No surprise here, it was mostly straight, white, cisgendered couples I was swooning over. The older I got the more I unconsciously assumed that only white people starred in swoon-worthy romances.</p>
<p>Everyone outside of that white bubble (or outside the default, wink, wink) struggled with love in a stereotypical manner. Films featuring black couples were riddled with violence and abuse. Both of which are very real, but insanely normalized in association with black culture. Same goes for films about Latinx couples. Asian romances were probably the most difficult for me to find back then. When I did manage to find some I noticed the women were supposed to be these delicate flowers, hiding from the sun. The men always got their pick of the bunch. It frustrated me so much that for a long time I gave up on seeing people of color fall in love. I mean, I wanted to witness well-rounded heroines and their equally impressive love interests. And white-led films were delivering that and occasionally more (see: <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0338013/">Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind’s</a></em> take on memory or<em> <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1022603/">(500) Days of Summer</a></em> take on the “good” guy)</p>
<p>Solution? Let’s write one. Reasons?</p>
<ol>
<li>Do you really want Nicholas Sparks’s stories to bombard television and theater screens for every Valentine’s Day from now to eternity? We’re better than that, people.</li>
<li>Other dating cultures are fascinating. The action of telling someone you like them differs from place to place. For example, in Japan, it’s the girls that buy the boys chocolate on Valentine’s Day. And one month later, on <a href="http://us.jnto.go.jp/blog/valentines-day-white-day-in-japan/">White Day</a>, the boy returns the favor – if he’s interested in the girl.</li>
<li>Since rom-coms aren’t exactly the hottest genre to be working in right now, I think it’s safe to say, there’s not going to be a lot of movement towards diversifying content. Time to take matters into our own hands.</li>
<li>If I have to sit through another film where the guy obviously has more chemistry with his male friend than his actual love interest my heart’s going to give up.</li>
</ol>
<p>I believe in us. I declare this upcoming Valentine’s Day a “Write a Rom-Com” day. Give it a try. It doesn’t have to be an actual screenplay. Just play around with some ideas. Think outside of the box. Remember, people who aren’t white, straight and cisgendered can and do fall in love. Let’s give them some happily ever afters. Share them with me below or on Twitter because that’s where I’ll be this Valentine’s Day. Wishing you a Happy Write a Rom-Com Day. Or, of course, if you&#8217;re celebrating, A Happy Valentine&#8217;s Day.</p>
<p>Yours Truly,</p>
<p>Kiana Danielle</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Onward: New rules, smart women, and endless potential</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/onward-new-rules-smart-women-and-endless-potential/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiana-Danielle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 17:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outside the Default]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2016 in was a doozy. I don’t usually make resolutions, but this year I promised&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2016 in was a doozy. I don’t usually make resolutions, but this year I promised to look forward and not lament on the could-have-been. Despite how exhausting last year was I feel like there were a lot of things that helped set the groundwork for a better future… Well, as better as the future can get in the world’s current state. It’s time to focus on some positives, so here’s a few of my favorite things I hope keep happening in the push for diversity:</p>
<p><a href="http://deadline.com/2016/12/bafta-diversity-standards-film-awards-membership-1201870394/"><strong>BAFTA’s new diversity rule</strong></a> – Starting in 2019 for a film to be considered for an award, filmmakers must demonstrate they “worked to increase the representation of under-represented groups.” They must demonstrate this through on-screen representation, behind the screen, creative leadership roles, or accessibility. To be blatant about inclusion is exactly what we need in a time where Hollywood churns out movie after movie with the same actors and same narratives. After<a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/life/movies/2016/02/02/oscars-academy-award-nominations-diversity/79645542/"> #OscarsSoWhite</a> maybe the Academy will take note and follow suit towards this brave, new world.</p>
<p><em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4846340/"><strong>Hidden Figures</strong></a></em> – I feel I started my year off right after watching this movie. It’s a story I’ve never been told despite living just one city over from the NASA’s space center. Women at NASA: it’s something you’d think my teachers would have at least tried to mention once or twice during a history lesson. Growing up as a black girl in the south I <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/hidden-figures-poster.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7784 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/hidden-figures-poster-203x300.jpg" width="203" height="300" /></a>was aware of how resilient my mother and grandmothers had to be during those times. But I didn’t know that not only were black women surviving, but thriving. Thriving at NASA! I hope this trend of biopics of people of color continues &#8211; especially with women of color. I want more. More women of color in space, more as scientists, inventors, and leaders. And from the looks of <a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/weekend-box-office-hidden-figures-earns-12-million-thursday-961421">the film’s performance </a>my dream just might come true. If Hollywood loves one thing it’s making a movie that&#8217;s capable of capturing a high spot at the box office. And now that they know these stories have an audience it’s likely we’ll get more.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1825683/?ref_=nv_sr_2"><strong>Marvel’s <em>Black Panther</em></strong></a> – I’m one of those consumers who has been experiencing superhero fatigue. But, not even that is going to stop me from anticipating the 2018 release of this film because for the first time in the Marvel universe dark-skinned women (<a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm1775091/">Danai Gurira</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/find?ref_=nv_sr_fn&amp;q=Lupita+Nyoung%E2%80%99o&amp;s=all">Lupita Nyoung’o</a>, and newcomer <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Florence_Kasumba">Florence Kasumba</a>) have actual roles. I mean, Alfre Woodard’s scene in <em>Captian America: Civil War</em> was great and all, but not really vital. I’m ready to see these three women kick ass, take names and fall in love because why not have it all?</p>
<p>Though these are just a few gems in the rubble that 2016 left behind I think it’s enough to incite hope. There’s no denying that all media, be it literature, film or television is moving at a snail’s pace when it comes to widening the net of narratives. But there’s also no denying that we’re moving. I hope the future surprises me with stories I’ve never heard of like that of Katherine Johnson and the women at NASA. I hope industry leaders work harder towards cultivating a community that welcomes more than one type of storyteller. I hope we leave the disappointment that was 2016 behind and exchange it for a more inclusion, knowledge, and color.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Tis The Season to Marathon</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/tis-the-season-to-marathon/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/tis-the-season-to-marathon/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiana-Danielle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 17:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outside the Default]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Holidays are the best excuse a person can have to partake in a television and/or&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Holidays are the best exc<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/3-netflix-10out2016-1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7679" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/3-netflix-10out2016-1-300x151.jpg" alt="3-netflix-10out2016-1" width="351" height="177" /></a>use a person can have to partake in a television and/or movie marathon. Personally, I’ve been depriving myself of anything that might be addicting up until yesterday. Now that the holiday season feels more real&#8211;because my calendar reads <em>December</em>&#8211;my schedule is clear and my pillows, fluffed. I’m a huge fan of the classic series that practically beg for a binge-watch: <em>Gilmore Girls</em>, <em>LOST</em>, and <em>Star Trek</em>. But, of course, I’m always on the lookout for new material that strives elevate diverse characters and stories. I was in luck when I came across the Netflix original, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/3%25"><em>3%</em></a>. It’s Netflix’s first Brazilian series, offering the option of subtitles or dubbed English. In this dystopian thriller, three percent of society is chosen to live a life separate from the rest, on an island called The Offshore. In order to become a part of this elite three percent, the candidates, at the age of twenty, go through a rigorous series of tests called The Process. In all honesty, it sounded like a mismatched version of <em>The Hunger Games, The Maze Runner, </em>and<em> Divergent</em> to me. Which is not very appealing because how many times can a group of young people being tested going to excite an audience? That was my question going in and here are some of my thoughts coming out:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>3%</em>’s testing, The Process serves as a commentary on our society&#8217;s relationship with higher education. I’ve been waiting for a depiction of this type of struggle for what feels like forever. The pressure the candidates put on themselves reminds me of my senior year of high school. Their interviews in the first half of the pilot episode is a definite parallel to the college interview process. Much like the characters, I remember trying to say the right words and sell myself even though I had no clue who I was at that point. What I remember even more vividly is how much the pressure made me feel like it was acceptance or nothing. What type of future is worth living if you can’t get into a good school or in this case, The Offshore?</li>
<li>I adore television and film that makes me reconsider how I approach problem-solving. The Process is filled with so many different types of tests that challenge not just the characters, but the audience to think outside of the box. I wasn’t passively watching – which kind of relieves me from some of the guilt that comes with binge-watching TV. I know a show has done something right when I’ve put my phone face down on my couch. <em>3%</em>’s invitation to play along is hard to decline.</li>
<li>I don’t usually enjoy watching live-action dubbed. It’s distracting to notice when audio doesn’t match an actor’s lips so I opted for the subtitles this time. The decision to avoid subtitles is something I think a lot of Americans – like myself – are most comfortable with and this is why all ton of television and films in foreign languages don’t reach the audience numbers they deserve. After watching this with the Portuguese as the audio I was reminded at just how beautiful this language sounds. Like race, gender, and sexual orientation, I feel like it’s vital we diversify languages in media. I’ve been kicking myself trying to learn a second language and listening to these actors speak encourages me to keep at it.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>3%</em> is most definitely a binge-worthy series. If the commentary on class systems isn’t enough of a hook, the brain-teasing puzzles will make things feel fresher, and less like beating-a-dead-horse. I’m two episodes deep and ready to dedicate the rest of my weekend. Why don’t you join me? Tell me what you think afterward. Did you watch it with subtitles or is dubbing more your style? Were you able to figure out any of the puzzles before the characters? If this show’s just not your cup of tea then please share, what is? I’m dying to know because honestly, I’ll probably be finished with this series by tomorrow night.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/tis-the-season-to-marathon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let&#8217;s Talk About Race-Bending</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lets-talk-about-race-bending/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiana-Danielle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outside the Default]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s a collage of fanart right above my desk and it features one of my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_7524" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7524" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/jk-rowling-slams-racist-trolls-who-criticize-black-hermione-in-harry-potter-play.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-7524 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/jk-rowling-slams-racist-trolls-who-criticize-black-hermione-in-harry-potter-play-300x217.jpg" alt="Noma Dumezweni as Hermione Granger" width="300" height="217" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7524" class="wp-caption-text">Noma Dumezweni as Hermione Granger</figcaption></figure>
<p>There&#8217;s a collage of fanart right above my desk and it features one of my favorite art prints of Hermione Granger. She is, of course, surrounded by books in a studious pose. Her hair’s in a kinky bun and her skin is a shade of brown. The Harry Potter franchise was the first to introduce me to the term, “race-bending.” It is exactly what it sounds like. Fans take a white character and change them into a character of color. When I came across the interpretation of Hermione as a black girl I couldn’t be convinced she was ever anything but. In the novels she’s described as having wild, untamable hair, which is the most common way to describe the natural hair of black women.  The interpretation of a black Hermione has since taken off from the small corners of fandom online and reached the stage earlier this year when Noma Dumezweni portrayed Hermione in<em> Harry Potter and the Cursed Child</em>. It’s fascinating to see how this theory has grown so much that even J.K Rowling<a href="https://twitter.com/buzzfeed/status/679216574515941376"> considers the race-bend to hold validity</a>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7525" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7525" style="width: 198px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/083fc55056a4bae103e0250cd87fe8d5.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7525" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/083fc55056a4bae103e0250cd87fe8d5-211x300.jpg" alt="Cinderella" width="198" height="281" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7525" class="wp-caption-text">Roger and Hammerstein&#8217;s Cinderella (1997)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Another one of my favorite race-bends is the 1997 version of Roger and Hammerstein’s <em>Cinderella</em>. I was that girl who grew up begging her mom to read Cinderella to her night after night. It baffles me now, but little Kiana never tired of that blue dress, pumpkin carriage and glass slipper. So when I saw Brandy in a blue dress of her own with all her braided hair glory I went crazy. I could be Cinderella! If you read <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/adventures-in-curating-diverse-reading-materials-online-edition/">last month’s post</a> you know that I love having options &#8211; in case this college thing doesn’t work out. Moving on, the freak out didn’t end there because there is also the matter of Prince Charming. Now, this is a portrayal that took me a few years to fully appreciate because I wasn&#8217;t old enough to notice how much stigma surrounds Asian men. They are rarely shown as masculine, strong, and attractive in mainstream media. But, there was Paolo Montalbán as a prince and he was even more swoon worthy and interesting to watch than Disney’s Charming.</p>
<p>Race-bending will never take away the need for new diverse characters in literature and film, but that doesn’t mean we should refrain from doing it. There’s something powerful about diversifying content after it’s already been in the public’s eye for consumption. Without those who resisted the unconscious urge to make all characters white in their minds we might not have a black Hermione. The wonderful pairing that is Brandy and Paolo wouldn’t exist in a world where we don’t challenge the cannon, a.ka. material officially a part of a story’s universe. The cannon is normally people’s main argument when it comes to race-bending. I feel we have to remember that cannon isn’t the padlock of a story, but the foundation. Fiction is alive and has the potential to represent multiple people. So let’s continue to avoid boxing ourselves in.</p>
<p>Next time you read a novel I want you to try something. Despite what the writer says I want you to imagine the characters as people of color. I can guarantee it’ll break the monotony that is known as defaulting to white. Perhaps it’ll even get you drawing some fanart? Maybe you’ll cast a completely race-bended version of Sleeping Beauty (I beg you!)? Maybe you’ll produce a play with race bent characters? Or simply get rid of the bad habit that is assuming. Whatever it may be, it’s worth it.</p>
<p>I want to leave you all with this clip from <em>Cinderella</em> featuring Whitney Huston and Brandy singing <em>Impossible/It&#8217;s Possible</em> because one: it&#8217;s Whitney! And two: it works as a perfect response to those who still don&#8217;t believe in race-bending.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Whitney Houston &amp; Brandy - IMPOSSIBLE / IT&#039;S POSSIBLE (from &quot;R&amp;H&#039;s Cinderella,&quot; 1997)" width="730" height="548" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dd0fuaD-OwE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adventures in Curating Diverse Reading Materials: Online Edition</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/adventures-in-curating-diverse-reading-materials-online-edition/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiana-Danielle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 15:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outside the Default]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m the type of person who enjoys having options. Netflix is my kryptonite. The insane&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m the type of person who enjoys having options. Netflix is my kryptonite. The insane amount of chip flavors out there oddly feels me with joy. And I was glad to discover a few years back that purchasing a book from a publishing house isn’t the only option I have when I want to read a new story. There’s so many wonderful online writing communities that have attracted talented writers. The writers on these sites tend to be more diverse than ones on bookstore shelves because there’s more opportunity for them to share their voices.  For a first timer it might be a bit daunting to search through pages and pages of stories, but don’t start scratching your head yet. I’ve put together a beginner’s list of works by, and featuring, people of color to give you an idea of what’s out there. So if you too enjoy exploring your options or you’re just looking for a new way to support diverse, upcoming writers, check out some of the following stories:</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://swoonproduction.s3.amazonaws.com:443/media/cover_images/lets_talk_about_love_cover_not_final.jpg?Signature=1IuVc4UV5HKI8eHEAHKksOxtEMQ%3D&amp;Expires=1539003663&amp;AWSAccessKeyId=AKIAJ6SEGNO7AOYOUE7Q" width="135" height="209" /> <a href="https://www.swoonreads.com/m/lets-talk-about-love-2/">Let’s Talk About Love</a></em> by Claire Kann</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">This gem is available to read on <a href="https://www.swoonreads.com/">SwoonReads</a> for a limited time before it hits the shelves in January 2018! The novel follows Alice who is a college student, asexual, and dreaming of a &#8220;rom-com grade romance.&#8221; It’s so refreshing to find a story featuring a young, black woman aware of her sexuality.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em><a href="https://www.swoonreads.com/m/summer-of-firsts/">Summer of Firsts</a></em> by Chen Yan Chang</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">This is also on SwoonReads, but has yet to be selected for publication, so that means once you’ve read it you can vote to support the author! I’m guilty of having a soft spot for anything that takes inspiration from Austen’s <em>Pride and Prejudice</em>. Grace is a character who – like many of us – is fixed on having an Austen-like romance.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright" src="https://a.wattpad.com/cover/60026339-144-k430603.jpg" alt="Augustine by TraceyJo-" width="138" height="215" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.wattpad.com/story/60026339-augustine"><em>Augustine</em></a> by Tracey Joseph (a.k.a. TracyJo-)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.wattpad.com/home">Wattpad </a>has a plethora of works to sort through. I go on there whenever I have time to kill and hunt for whatever matches my mood. I was ready for a romance with an edge when I found <em>Augustine</em>. The protagonist, Kathryn, is caught in a crazy dilemma when the guy she gets involved goes too far when declaring his love.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.wattpad.com/story/38929890-where-seagulls-fly-featured"><em>Where Seagulls Fly</em></a> by mittasw</p>
<p>This story is described by the author to be a Korean drama meets modern-day Elinor Dashwood. If that doesn’t hook you, I give up. Su Bin has to put her dreams of becoming a doctor on hold to fulfill her father’s wish for her to become his heiress. And that cherry on top is when she falls for her father’s right-hand man who so happens to be engaged.</p>
<hr />
<p>I know these stories are all romances, but what can I say? I’m addicted. I’m aware that not everyone is so inclined and that’s why I encourage to just think of these recommendations like the first stop on the tour. There’s so much out there for readers looking for online material by diverse writers. It’ll take some hunting, for sure, but it’s well worth it in the end. I also encourage you to comment and share whenever you find a work you enjoy. These writers are sharing their work freely with the hope that readers connect and enjoy what they’re creating. Go out there and explore those archives, ladies and gents. Let all those diverse options fill you with joy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coming of Age (with Color)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/coming-of-age-with-color/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiana-Danielle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 16:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outside the Default]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s the driving force of young adult literature. It’s something not just writers but filmmakers,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s the driving force of young adult literature. It’s something not just writers but filmmakers, artists, and even people outside of creative fields never tire delving into. Young kids always can’t wait for it, adults always reminisce on it, and teenagers get so tangled up in it they forget it’s not going to last forever. Coming of age is that romantic in-between. When someone’s finally growing into their body and mind. It’s scary, exhausting, and fun. My own coming of age story isn’t as interesting as the books I devoured during those years. Holden Caulfield was the cynic I thought I wanted to become. Mia Thermopolis was just living my ultimate dream. Charlie from <em>Perks of Being a Wallflower</em> made the group of friends I – to this very day – can only dream of having. And any Judy Blume heroine made growing up feel like an event and not a necessary evil. My coming of age could never be like any of theirs for obvious reasons. The biggest being it’s fiction, of course. But once you peel back that layer there’s this whole color thing.</p>
<p>I can pick out key elements in my developmental stages that overlap with themes like: Holden’s cynicism, Charlie’s loneliness, and Mia’s insecurities. But, there’s always a thread these stories couldn’t touch. A thread plenty of POC (people of color) know well, like being the only person that looks like them in the room. Navigating the dating world when you’re unsure if the person you like goes for someone of your complexion. Avoiding sounding or looking like a stereotype. It’s awkward enough with body hair and hormones. Censoring yourself because of how much pigmentation’s in your skin brings on an extra load of problems.</p>
<figure style="width: 414px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image" src="http://static1.squarespace.com/static/553879aae4b01ab27b454bdb/t/553894ece4b09f4577db0156/1429771510267/screen-shot-2012-07-17-at-5-49-39-am.png?format=1000w" width="414" height="232" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The Perils of Growing Up Flat-Chested (dir. Yulin Kuang, 2013)</figcaption></figure>
<p>I didn’t think about coming of age as a POC until I graduated high school. Not long after graduation I stumbled upon <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/yulinisworking">Yulin Kuang’s </a><em>The Perils of Growing Up Flat-Chested</em> and a light bulb turned on. I was like, “Hey, wait, I haven’t seen this before.” Here was a woman of color trying to figure out her body and the changes &#8211; or lack thereof &#8211; it was going through. It&#8217;s rare to find this on-screen or on the page. There seems to be a straight line from childhood to adulthood for POC. All the fumbling in between exists for us too. And the absence of fumbling in literature and film communicates that we don’t, can’t, or shouldn’t, struggle with growing pains. So when we do – and trust me, it’s inevitable – we feel like maybe we’re doing something wrong. It&#8217;s that old stereotype that we don&#8217;t struggle the same way a white person does.</p>
<p>POC coming of age stories are a vital part of proper representation. I came of age not only worrying about my skin breaking out but how dark it got in the summer. I came of age straightening my hair until it started falling out. I came of age training myself to speak quietly and laugh lower because heaven forbid I fit the stereotype. Seeing a girl like me struggle through teen years might have not stopped me from editing myself. But at least I would have had proof that I wasn’t the only one struggling. And with that proof I would have had permission to just be in the romantic in-between instead of trying to hurry through it.</p>
<p>You only come of age once. Sure, most of the time it sucks, but it&#8217;s something special. And my hope for the next generation is that they get more tales from people who resemble them. Because POC can be cynics, lonely freshmen or insecure about not growing into a certain cup size. It&#8217;s about time we&#8217;re shown as unsure and afraid because there&#8217;s no straight line to adulthood. Every one of us stumbling to it awkwardly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adventures in Curating Diverse Reading Materials</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/adventures-in-curating-diverse-reading-materials/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiana-Danielle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outside the Default]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Step one of curating your reading materials to focus more on diversity: Make the decision&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Step one of curating your reading materials to focus more on diversity: Make the decision to do so. Easy part, done.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-pact/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">My last post </a>was easy. Choosing to only read books with characters and authors of color was simple. But now, I have to actually start putting my back into it. So, where to begin?</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/22295304.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6961 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/22295304-207x300.jpg" alt="22295304" width="207" height="300" /></a>At first I was going to focus on one genre. I was very keen on only dipping my feet into the pond that is urban romance. But I stumbled upon urban fantasy which was something I didn’t realize existed until I spent a late night scrolling through the depths of the Kindle library. And then there’s the world of Asian Literature I once ventured into during high school because of its beautiful settings and culturally-infused stories. Plus, the world of Hispanic Literature &#8211; where I have <em>even less</em> experience. Can you tell I was a little overwhelm?</p>
<p>It seems a bit silly to be torn in so many different directions. Since my goal is diversifying my reading why limit it to just one sub-genre? That would defeat the purpose of this whole resolution. So I’m doing a little bit of everything. I threw in some genre classics and then added some newer things with the cheesy romance covers I’ve previously tried to avoid. For Asian Literature I’m revisiting two authors that captured my attention quite a few years ago, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/28719.Gail_Tsukiyama">Gail Tsukiyama</a> and <a href="http://www.harukimurakami.com/">Haruki Murakami</a>. For Hispanic Literature I found <a href="http://ghoststar.net/">Daniel Jose Older</a>, who is in the beginning stages of his career as an author and already lending a hand in nudging the industry in a more inclusive direction.</p>
<p>Before I reveal my list here’s a few tips on trying to find your own diverse books to add to your reading lists:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Remember what you like.</strong> Just because you’re adventuring outside of your normal reading habits doesn’t mean you have to compromise. I love young adult romance. Transitioning to romance with more diverse characters was a little shock to the system because the marketing&#8217;s much different than what I&#8217;m use to. Judging a book by its cover is a habit I have yet to kick. Searching for romance between two African-American people had my inner critic flashing red stop signs. But I’m not giving up the genre just because publishers think sexy covers is how you sell a book – another topic for another post.</li>
<li><strong>Mix it up.</strong> Read the staple writers of a certain genre like, Haruki Murukami or Octavia E. Butler. And more new, upcoming authors which you can track down on sites that create intensive lists like this one on <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/list/show/11395.Non_Caucasian_Protagonists_in_Science_Fiction_Fantasy_Horror_and_Paranormal_Romance">Goodreads</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Keep in mind some books are going to be a miss.</strong> Just like with not so diverse novels there’s going to be a book that you’re just not going to like. It’s not because of the genre – you didn’t quit tragedies after your teacher forced you to read the melodramatic tale of <em>Romeo &amp; Juliet</em>, did you? Eh, well, you might have. But, just because you might hate Murukami but that doesn’t mean every Asian author is going to disappoint you.</li>
</ol>
<p>Here’s the list of diverse reads I’m going to tackle for the rest of this year. Feel free to steal some for your own diverse list. Though they are tailored to my own specific needs/wants I’m sure you’ll find at least one book interesting enough to pick up for yourself.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60931.Kindred#"> <em>Kindred</em></a> by Octavia E. Butler</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/list/show/11395.Non_Caucasian_Protagonists_in_Science_Fiction_Fantasy_Horror_and_Paranormal_Romance"><em>The Night of Many Dreams</em></a> by Gail Tsukiyama.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4929.Kafka_on_the_Shore?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><em>Kafka on the Shore</em></a> by Haruki Murakami</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25760151-forbidden?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><em>Forbidden</em></a> by Beverly Jenkins (this one definitely satisfies the cheesy cover and I’m embracing it)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25667918-binti?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><em>Binti</em> </a>by Nnedi Okorafor</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20642659-long-hidden?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><em>Long Hidden: Speculative Fiction from the Margins of History</em></a> by Various Authors</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22295304-shadowshaper?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><em>Shadowshaper</em></a> by Daniel Jose Older</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Pact</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-pact/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kiana-Danielle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 16:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Outside the Default]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the beginning of the year my sister and I made a pact. We both&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of the year my sister and I made a pact. We both grew up in between the shelves of our local library and in front of our television. I can guarantee most of our conversations are centered around fictional worlds. During any given time of the day you can find us ranting about the Marvel universe or arguing about the morality in <em>The Walking Dead</em>. So it’s no wonder we’ve both grown up to become writers. We noticed a pattern in our works that was quite unsettling … we’d never written a story from a person of color&#8217;s point of view.</p>
<p>My writing journey began when I was nine years old. When I was that age I devoured Christian fiction set in the Canadian frontier. Odd choice for a child but to me that world was exciting and romantic (and very mom-approved) in the eyes of a kid living in the suburbs. As you can guess there weren&#8217;t really people like me gracing the pages of a frontier novel. That was fine. Then, I aged into the teen section just in time to experience the rise of dystopian heroines. Once more there weren&#8217;t many people who looked like me. But, like the blank canvas I was, I absorbed everything I read and ended up I reflecting it back by writing and sharing stories on creative writing sites.  I looked up to the girls in these novels. They had a story to tell and things to get done. It didn’t matter that they didn’t look like me. I never opened those books with the hope that they’d speak like me or express the same concerns I had growing up. My mouthful of slang and head full of kinky curls would have been awkward on the page. Not exciting enough. Not romantic enough. And definitely not able-to-get-stuff-done enough.</p>
<p>But why?</p>
<p>I’ve always been uncomfortable with AAVE (African-American Vernacular English) on the page because I’d been told educated people didn’t talk in that way. And I’ve always hated that without AAVE one couldn’t officially dub a character black unless the author specifically said so. The “urban fiction” section was something to be avoided because it wasn’t “edifying” in the eyes of my teachers and my parents.  I hated those feelings. To subdue them I simply never specified a character’s race. When I shared my stories online the readers would assume the color of their skin. And I went along with it because I learned rather quickly I was more likely to get reads if the cover featured a girl with fair skin and dialogue clean of any slang. And I kept doing it and doing it until I didn’t realize I was doing it anymore.</p>
<p>At the beginning of this year I made pact with my sister. From that day forward whatever fiction we wrote it would be from a person of color’s point of view. It didn’t end there for me. I decided this year I’m going to read as many books as I can that feature a person of color as the narrator. So that means I’m diving into the section I’ve so carefully avoided until now, urban fiction. I want to finally see that it&#8217;s possible for someone who speaks and looks like me to get stuff done. That they can be exciting or romantic. For once I want to read something through a pair of eyes similar to my own.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
