<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>A Random Walk Through Speculative Fiction &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/a-random-walk-through-speculative-fiction/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 16:41:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Book review: vN (Madeline Ashby)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-vn-by-madeline-ashby/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[JY Saville]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 16:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Random Walk Through Speculative Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This fast-paced science-fiction thriller from 2012 was Madeline Ashby&#8216;s debut novel, the first of The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13033939-vn"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="http://d.gr-assets.com/books/1327673811l/13033939.jpg" width="233" height="352" /></a>This fast-paced science-fiction thriller from 2012 was <a href="http://madelineashby.com/">Madeline Ashby</a>&#8216;s debut novel, the first of <em>The Machine Dynasty</em> series.<em> <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13033939-vn">vN</a> </em>stands for von Neumann machine, a self-replicating android with advanced repair mechanisms, and what&#8217;s known as &#8216;the failsafe&#8217; which means they can&#8217;t harm humans or even see them being harmed by others, otherwise they&#8217;ll have some kind of breakdown.</p>
<p>Amy Peterson has been grown at roughly human-child pace in a mixed organic-synthetic family for five years, so although she&#8217;s still in kindergarten she&#8217;s smarter (and stronger) than most of her class. Special arrangements mean she never gets exposed to situations where she might see the other kids get hurt, so it&#8217;s only when Amy&#8217;s ruthless and violent vN granny turns up that anyone realises Amy has a broken failsafe.</p>
<p>The bulk of the novel follows Amy as she&#8217;s on the run, suddenly alone and fending for herself. Amy&#8217;s mixture of childish innocence and android intelligence, strength and resilience make for a fascinating character and some odd situations. Her interactions with both humans and vN are interesting as she&#8217;s in some ways neither one nor the other and it&#8217;s not as simple as humans trying to capture her and vN trying to help her, there&#8217;s a mixture of attitudes on both sides. At any one time there are people (human and vN) trying to destroy her, study her, cultivate more of her, or protect her, all because of that broken failsafe.</p>
<p>As well as being a gripping thriller, the book tackles some big subjects. For one thing there&#8217;s the mixed synthetic-organic relationships of families as a reflection on attitudes to race and otherness. There&#8217;s also a fairly deep exploration of what makes friendship, love, and family ties. The use, abuse, wielding and withholding of power are strong threads through the story, and the nature of freedom – when is a choice not really a choice? This links in with the idea that all parents &#8216;programme&#8217; their children to some extent &#8211; is that natural or can it be circumvented?</p>
<p>There&#8217;s the old conundrum of nature vs nurture, with Amy having been brought up as much like a human child as possible and thus having a different perspective on morality and relationships for instance from most synthetics she meets. Ethics in general gets a good and thought-provoking going over. Is it okay to do bad stuff if the &#8216;person&#8217; you&#8217;re abusing isn&#8217;t human? If not, why not? And what if it takes the abuse away from a human?</p>
<p>The book does get quite violent in places but it never feels gratuitous. The world (mainly the western USA at some unspecified time not too far in the future) seems fully thought through, and every time I had a question about why something happened a certain way or about consequences, I found it was answered within a page or so. The main characters were worth spending time with, I wanted to know what happened to them and how things turned out, and the way they interacted with each other was great. This is one of the best science-fiction novels I&#8217;ve read in ages.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: “The Sin Eater’s Daughter” by Melinda Salisbury</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-the-sin-eaters-daughter-by-melinda-salisbury/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[JY Saville]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 15:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Random Walk Through Speculative Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Sin Eater&#8217;s Daughter is the delicious first book in a new YA high fantasy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1422735103l/21936988.jpg" width="263" height="404" /></p>
<p><em><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21936988-the-sin-eater-s-daughter">The Sin Eater&#8217;s Daughter</a> </em>is the delicious first book in a new YA high fantasy series, first released last year. Set in the pseudo-medieval surroundings of Lormere castle, we have politics, intrigue, danger, and an obedient and naive seventeen year old who&#8217;s about to make the rocky transition to adulthood.</p>
<p>Twylla is a young woman with a gift. Chosen by the gods at thirteen, she has spent four years fulfilling her role as Daunen Embodied, the daughter of the gods made flesh again. She has a place in the Royal household, a destiny within the kingdom as the prince’s future wife. She is special, set apart, and she knows her place. She is the court executioner.</p>
<p>This chilling fairytale is about the way adults – parents, guardians, mentors – feed their wards lies and half-truths to keep them in line. Those logical fallacies that fall apart under close examination, but which as children – unless we’re unusually questioning or rebellious – we just accept. The book deals well with both the gradual realisation of truth, and the guilt at having been coerced into regrettable behaviour. There is a strong element of romance as well as the dark strands, and we watch Twylla grow up and begin to make adult choices and have a hand in her own destiny.</p>
<p>I saw <a href="http://www.melindasalisbury.com/">Melinda Salisbury</a> speak at a literature festival a couple of months ago and she mentioned that in Twylla she had wanted to create a ‘real’ central character, with signs of cowardice and weakness instead of the stereotypical strong, heroic type who’s equal to any challenge. It’s the vulnerability that makes Twylla so appealing and, sadly, recognisable to so many readers. It also makes her desperation for friendship and affection so believable.</p>
<p>The <em>Sin Eater’s Daughter</em> is a lot more complex than its fairytale setting makes it seem at first – you think you’re going on a familiar journey (well written, with characters you care deeply about, but still you think you know where it’s heading) and then it twists into something darker and really ramps up the tension. I read the whole novel incredibly quickly, desperate to find out what happened. The descriptions are vivid, and the history and mythology of Lormere form a well-created world in which to immerse yourself.</p>
<p>I must confess that I’m not a Young Adult aficionado, I’ve borrowed a couple of urban fantasy novels from the library this year and been completely baffled by contemporary references (the onset of middle age, unfortunately!). I was put off by simplistic language then realised the books were marketed as YA fiction, which made me somewhat wary of the label. However, hearing the author talking about her series piqued my interest and once I’d read the first few pages of the ebook as a preview online I was impressed enough to buy it. I suspect the high fantasy setting helps avoid the ‘this is written for hip teenagers’ trap.</p>
<p>Book 2 in the series (<a href="http://www.melindasalisbury.com/#!the-sleeping-prince/c1l1j"><em>The Sleeping Prince</em></a>) has recently come out in paperback and seems to be going down well, judging by the ratings on Goodreads and Amazon. Melinda Salisbury is definitely one to watch.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: “The Gracekeepers” by Kirsty Logan</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-the-gracekeepers-by-kirsty-logan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[JY Saville]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 15:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Random Walk Through Speculative Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m not sure how to categorise The Gracekeepers (whether novels should be pigeon-holed at all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p lang="zxx"><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23012481-the-gracekeepers"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="http://d.gr-assets.com/books/1409948410l/23012481.jpg" width="318" height="446" /></a>I’m not sure how to categorise <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23012481-the-gracekeepers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The Gracekeepers</em></a> (whether novels should be pigeon-holed at all is best left for another time and place) but I will settle for describing it as a grown-up fairy tale. I fell under its spell within the first couple of pages and remained utterly enchanted all the way to the end. I cared about the main characters Callanish and North so much that I emitted a pathetic whimper when it all got rather tense towards the end, and my other half gave me a concerned look from his armchair. It was one of those books that was so wonderful I had to tell people about it even when I knew it wasn&#8217;t their cup of tea and they’d never consider reading it.</p>
<p lang="zxx">A few generations ago there were oceans and there was land, now there is only a scattering of archipelagos in a world of water. Land is scarce and consequently something of a status symbol among those who value that sort of thing. The population is divided into landlockers and damplings, mutually distrustful, each on the whole sticking to their own preferred habitat of land or sea, living in a house or on a boat. Callanish Sand is a gracekeeper, living in a house surrounded by water, consigning the bodies of those who&#8217;ve died at sea to their proper resting place in the graceyard she tends as punishment for a past mistake. North and her performing bear live on a boat attached to the circus they grew up in. Both Callanish and North are living with secrets that could finish them, and when their paths cross the possibility of a different future opens up for them both.</p>
<p lang="zxx">Each chapter of the book is from a particular character’s perspective so we see the world and the current situation from the point of view of several of the circus performers as well as North and Callanish and a couple of others. The crew of the circus boat are like an extended family centred round the ringmaster, his second wife and his adult son, and all the usual secrets, lies and jealousies abound. Family ties and what makes a family are themes that run throughout the book.</p>
<p lang="zxx">The writing was so vivid that each of the characters came to life and the world made perfect sense within itself. I loved the contrast of the magic and illusion of the circus at night, with the slightly faded past, its best version in the daylight as the crew go about their day to day tasks. The constant movement of the boat echoes the precariousness of the circus as they perform for their supper on island after island, hoping for an appreciative crowd of landlockers but wary of the revivalist boats decrying them and looking for converts.</p>
<p lang="zxx"><em>The Gracekeepers</em> was one of those completely immersive reads, where you enter the world fully but so far it’s Kirsty Logan’s only novel. She does have two short story collections available, which I haven’t read yet but sound like they might have a similar fairy tale feeling. Her website is at <a href="http://www.kirstylogan.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://www.kirstylogan.com/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: &#8220;The Lathe of Heaven&#8221; by Ursula K Le Guin</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-the-lathe-of-heaven-by-ursula-k-le-guin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[JY Saville]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 16:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Random Walk Through Speculative Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5812</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I finally got round to reading Ursula Le Guin&#8217;s classic 1971 science fiction novel&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59924.The_Lathe_of_Heaven"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="http://d.gr-assets.com/books/1433084322l/59924.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="296" /></a>When I finally got round to reading Ursula Le Guin&#8217;s classic 1971 science fiction novel <em><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59924.The_Lathe_of_Heaven">The Lathe of Heaven</a> </em>a little while ago, I was amazed (and a little sad) that I&#8217;d never read it before, though I had seen the <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0290230/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2002 tv film</a> without realizing it was based on a novel. I had read Le Guin&#8217;s<em> Earthsea Trilogy</em> (now expanded to more books) and a few of her short stories. I tended to think of Ursula Le Guin in terms of thoughtful and thought-provoking fantasy. The kind of futuristic, climate change and weirdness, philosophical science fiction evidenced in <em>The Lathe of Heaven</em> was more what I was used to from Philip K Dick. Except Ursula Le Guin gives it to us with more well-rounded characters and less misogyny.</p>
<p>George Orr is a quiet, unassuming but ultimately courageous man living in Portland, Oregon who starts to realize his dreams are altering reality. Consequently, he is afraid to sleep. Although everyone else is seemingly unaware that the world has ever had a different history, George can remember multiple histories – multiple realities – which, understandably enough, upsets him. He is referred for psychiatric help and attends a series of controlled dreaming sessions to overcome his fear, but his apparently friendly therapist, Dr. Haber, is almost immediately revealed as unethical. He lies about noticing a change in the world after one of George’s effective (reality-altering) dreams, in order that George still feels completely alone and like he’s losing his mind. Haber then tries to control George and manipulate his dreams, changing the world to suit Haber and his ambitions and beliefs, until George finally learns to resist.</p>
<p>The opening chapter is suitably disorientating, full of poetic language and mesmerizing images, mirroring George&#8217;s disorientation nicely. The chapters are written from one of three different viewpoints: George Orr, Dr. Haber, and Heather Lelache, the lawyer George hires at one point to help him against Haber. It’s these different views of similar events that confirm the change in reality is genuine, not just in George&#8217;s head. As changes occur, we notice similarities or even constants, which leads us to ponder the nature of reality. What persists in all George&#8217;s different realities? What constitutes the essence of a person’s existence?</p>
<p><em>The Lathe of Heaven</em> also gives us an interesting (and fairly pessimistic) 1970s view of the turn of the 21st century. The Greenhouse Effect means there is no permanent snow on any mountains, there are ultra-high-rise buildings, food shortages, extinctions, overcrowding, and constant warm rain in Portland, and there’s a war in the Middle East. Meddling – even for the best intentions – is shown to have unforeseen consequences, but while George cares about what&#8217;s happening to other people and worries about causing problems, Dr. Haber thinks he knows best. However, as anyone who’s ever read alternate history will know, stopping the bad stuff might just cause an even worse alternatives to spring into being, and in any case one man’s paradise is another man’s hell.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: &#8220;Clementine&#8221; by Cherie Priest</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-clementine-cherie-priest/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[JY Saville]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 15:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Random Walk Through Speculative Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Clementine is the second novel in Cherie Priest&#8216;s steampunk Clockwork Century series, set in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7670800-clementine"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="http://d.gr-assets.com/books/1277163268l/7670800.jpg" alt="Cover of Clementine by Cherie Priest" width="235" height="354" /></a><em><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7670800-clementine" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Clementine</a></em> is the second novel in <a href="http://www.cheriepriest.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cherie Priest</a>&#8216;s steampunk Clockwork Century series, set in the late nineteenth century during a protracted version of the American Civil War.</p>
<p>When I was a teenager in the 1990s I had never heard of steampunk but I enjoyed a good alternate history, and the ones I read often included technology that had taken off before it did in real life&#8211;based on Tesla&#8217;s electrical experiments or Babbage&#8217;s difference engine for instance. Later when I started hearing people talk about steampunk it seemed to encompass a large part of the kind of alternate history I&#8217;d enjoyed, and I began to seek out steampunk novels. Too often lately it seems that steampunk as a fiction sub-genre has become a bit like steampunk as a style &#8211; stick a few cogs on something mundane and call it done. The worst kind of bandwagon-jumping. With Cherie Priest, what we seem to have is actual alternate history.</p>
<p>Middle-aged widow Maria Boyd&#8217;s long career as a Confederate spy is over, much to her disappointment, but when Mr Pinkerton offers her a place at his detective agency in Chicago, she reports for duty and takes her first assignment. Working on behalf of the Union Army.</p>
<p>Meanwhile air pirate (and runaway slave) Croggon Hainey is pursuing a thief across the Rockies in a dirigible. This thief stole from Hainey, and once Hainey catches up with him he&#8217;ll wish he hadn&#8217;t been born. Unfortunately the man Hainey is pursuing is currently working for the Union Army on an important mission, and they need him to arrive at his destination in one piece, along with his cargo. Which is where Maria comes in.</p>
<p>During a complicated situation in Kansas City, Hainey and Boyd form an uneasy alliance. Dangerous and experienced as each of them is alone, they make an even more formidable team.</p>
<p><em>Clementine</em> was a fast-paced novel with a relatively simple and effective story line. My lack of familiarity with American history (and indeed geography) did make me a little slow on the uptake about implications occasionally (a runaway slave heading for the southern states for instance) but even with that it was an easy read with a good pacing of tension and release.</p>
<p>The two main characters are presented with enough depth and backstory that I felt like I&#8217;d read about them before (this is the second in the series, picked up because the library had books 2-4 but not <em>Boneshaker</em>, the first Clockwork Century novel. I don&#8217;t know if either Hainey or Boyd features in the previous book). Hainey in particular came across as a complex character with conflicting drives, an intelligent man scarred by slavery, capable of both compassion and calculated violence.</p>
<p>The anachronistic technology was subtly done, with much of the setting familiar from many a Clint Eastwood film &#8211; dirt and mules, Gatling guns and Colts, segregation and dubious hotels. It was the military (or those that worked for them or stole from them) that had the most impressively advanced hardware.</p>
<p>I mean to work my way through the rest of the Clockwork Century novels just as soon as I can lay my hands on them. In the meantime, there is a <a href="http://theclockworkcentury.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">great website</a> where excerpts and shorter works set in the Clockwork Century world are available to read for free.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lives of the Monster Dogs by Kirsten Bakis</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lives-of-the-monster-dogs-by-kirsten-bakis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[JY Saville]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 16:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Random Walk Through Speculative Fiction]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4034</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First published in 1997, Lives of the Monster Dogs is the first (and so far&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First published in 1997, <em><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/301727.Lives_of_the_Monster_Dogs" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lives of the Monster Dogs</a></em> is the first (and so far as I can discover, only) novel by Kirsten Bakis, picked at random from the sci-fi and fantasy shelves of my local library because I liked the font on the spine. Well, hurrah for pleasing fonts – I would have been sorry to pass this odd book by.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/monster-dogs.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-4991 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/monster-dogs-194x300.jpg" alt="monster-dogs" width="194" height="300" /></a>In 2017, New York journalist Cleo Pira finally understands she will never feel ready to make sense of the events of 2008-11 and write the story of the hundred and fifty &#8216;monster dogs&#8217; who arrived in the city, so she gives it her best shot anyway and the result is the book we have here. Working with her own recollections and the notes and journals of her former friend Ludwig von Sacher, a dog who&#8217;d taken it upon himself to write the history of his race, Cleo tries to piece together the whole story.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a pleasingly old-fashioned feel to the structure of the novel, with its excerpts from journals, newspaper and magazine articles, scholarly notes, and even the libretto of an opera written by one of the dogs to commemorate an important event in their history. When you mention all of that, alongside a quick synopsis of the fantastical plot, it sounds like it must be (if you&#8217;ll pardon the pun) a bit of a dog&#8217;s dinner, but it works wonderfully; the dogs&#8217; world is eminently believable and I was drawn in immediately. In fact, twenty-something New Yorker Cleo Pira was the least believable character, a hasty sketch alongside the more rounded characters of the dogs themselves.</p>
<p>The monster dogs of the book&#8217;s title are, for the most part, polite and well-mannered. &#8216;Monster&#8217; refers to their surgically-enhanced state. In the best traditions of these things, it all began with a mad scientist in 19<sup>th</sup> century Prussia and culminated in intelligent dogs with mechanical voiceboxes, prosthetic hands, and seriously out of date dress sense. Arriving mysteriously in New York to start a new life, they&#8217;re received enthusiastically as the latest celebrities, sparking new fashions and appearing on TV and across acres of newsprint, with every gawking bystander and reporter wanting a piece of them. Being a celebrity is not quite the same as fitting in, however.</p>
<p>In the edition I read, there are a couple of pages of quotes from favourable reviews of <em>Lives of the Monster Dogs</em>, and one of them caught my eye with a mention of <em>Frankenstein</em>. It&#8217;s not a bad comparison, as Ludwig wrestles with ethics and what makes a monster, as he tries to understand the dogs&#8217; progenitor Augustus Rank and what drove him to begin his cruel experiments in the first place. Ludwig&#8217;s dignity and shame are quite moving: a so-called &#8216;monster&#8217; just trying to live his life, feeling neither part of the dogs&#8217; world any more since he&#8217;s started to question their role, nor a part of the human world where he lives on the fringes. It soon becomes clear that the dogs are being struck down by an illness, and their star is set to burn fiercely but not for long.</p>
<p>This is, ultimately, a novel about loss, loneliness and being an outsider. From Augustus Rank, the friendless young boy in Prussia, to his isolated successors perfecting the dog experiments in secret over the following decades, to Ludwig von Sacher trying to keep Cleo at arm&#8217;s length when he becomes one of her dearest friends. The loss of dreams and hope, of a way of life, a species, and a group of close friends – they&#8217;re all there on the pages of <em>Lives of the Monster Dogs</em>. There is a deep sadness to the story as Ludwig understands he&#8217;s one of the last of his race, and Cleo watches the passing of the unusual and short-lived beauty the dogs brought to the city. It&#8217;s almost impossible not to be moved by this book, though thankfully the ending wasn&#8217;t as bleak as I&#8217;d feared. There are a few niggles, not least Cleo owning a laser pistol for self-defense, but it&#8217;s such a fascinating world to be immersed in for a while that it&#8217;s easy to overlook them and just enjoy the experience.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: &#8220;The Left-Handed Hummingbird&#8221; by Kate Orman</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-left-handed-hummingbird-by-kate-orman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[JY Saville]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 15:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Random Walk Through Speculative Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4036</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This – as proudly announced on the back cover blurb – was the first Doctor&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1177062176l/678305.jpg" alt="" width="188" height="311" />This – as proudly announced on the back cover blurb – was the first Doctor Who New Adventure novel to be written by a woman; in fact, I think Kate Orman was the only female author for the New Adventure series. Doctor Who is now a popular BBC TV series again, but it was discontinued in 1989 after 26 years and Virgin Publishing issued a run of novels from 1991-1997 continuing the well-loved time-traveller&#8217;s story. It&#8217;s always a challenge to take on someone else&#8217;s characters, and some of the novels work much better than others, but I found <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/678305.The_Left_Handed_Hummingbird" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Left-Handed Hummingbird</a> particularly tense and gripping.</p>
<p>The Doctor, in his seventh incarnation (as played on TV by Sylvester McCoy), has been travelling through time and space for a while with two very different women: Ace, a 20th century streetwise Londoner, and Professor Bernice Summerfield, an archaeologist from an Earth colony of the 26th century. A mysterious note, which reaches them in the middle of the 21st century, brings the three travelling companions to Mexico City in 1994, to the hospital bedside of psychically sensitive Christián Alvarez whose timeline they&#8217;re already entangled with. Christián has been counting on their arrival, thinking everything will be OK when the Doctor arrives, but the Doctor has no idea who Christián is. The time-travellers aren&#8217;t hitting Christián&#8217;s timeline in chronological order, which doesn&#8217;t help his fragile mental health.</p>
<p>The New Adventures novels, not bound by the rules of teatime family entertainment, took the opportunity to delve deeper and darker into the Doctor&#8217;s world, which is what makes this novel work so well as a thriller. Shuttling backwards and forwards in time with the Doctor and his friends we encounter drug-taking hippies flirting with dark forces in 1960s London, human sacrifice in the Aztec empire of the 15th century, the panic and chaos on the Titanic as it begins to sink, and the senseless murder of John Lennon. Not to mention a few other deaths along the way, possession by a vengeful god, and some horrifying near-misses for some of the central characters. Someone has been messing about with time, including events that happened in the Doctor&#8217;s own past, and it&#8217;s going to take a lot of sorting out.</p>
<p>The Left-Handed Hummingbird is one way of translating into English the name of Huitzilopochtli, the Aztec god of war and the sun. His influence extends throughout the timeline of the novel, and various related aspects of Aztec mythology are woven into the story, with some surprising explanations for them. It was interesting to see such a strong thread of manipulation and control, when it wasn&#8217;t the Doctor doing the controlling. There&#8217;s also a recurring theme around Ace&#8217;s readiness for violence and affinity with weapons, and whether the Doctor&#8217;s disapproval is reasonable or not.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve watched maybe a tenth of the TV episodes, read quite a few of the books and listened to most of the Eighth Doctor audio adventures, but I wouldn&#8217;t call myself a Doctor Who aficionado. I don&#8217;t think you need to know much more than that this guy is pretty old and travels through time in a blue box to enjoy <em>The Left-Handed Hummingbird</em>, though obviously if you do know more about the set-up you&#8217;ll pick up on various references or perhaps be quicker to spot where a plotline&#8217;s going. All in all, the novel&#8217;s an easy read (apart from some of the unfamiliar Aztec names), while being more satisfying and thought-provoking than many Doctor Who novels.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
