<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Breakfast Anytime &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/breakfast-anytime/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:09:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dear Ms. Ann Thrope</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dear-ms-ann-thrope/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth McCabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast Anytime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15468</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Ms. Ann Thrope, I’ve always dreamed of living in a hut in the woods,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-15485 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/pen.jpg" alt="" width="287" height="191" /></em>Dear Ms. Ann Thrope,</p>
<p>I’ve always dreamed of living in a hut in the woods, but I’m not sure I can survive without brunch. What should I do? &#8212; Hungry</p>
<p><em>Dear Hungry: </em></p>
<p><em>Learn to cook. And remember to buy a <strong>stovetop</strong> espresso maker. Unless you also buy a generator.</em></p>
<p>Dear Ms. Ann Thrope:</p>
<p>Why is Trump so determined to send a manned mission to Mars? &#8212; Puzzled</p>
<p><em>Dear Puzzled:</em></p>
<p><em>Everyone in New York knew Trump was an asshole. Then he got involved in politics, and everyone in the U.S. knew he was an asshole. Then he stole the presidency, and now everyone on Planet Earth knows he’s an asshole. What else is left? (The moon is too small for his ego.)</em></p>
<p>Dear Ms. Ann Thrope:</p>
<p>I want to write hard science fiction but I hated science in school. What should I do? &#8212; Ambitious</p>
<p><em>Dear Ambitious:</em></p>
<p><em>For those of us who forgot to get science degrees, there is a wealth of information out there—books, reputable web sites, podcasts. With some effort you can learn enough science to frame a story; as fiction writers we get to focus on the human aspects of the story and let the technical and scientific details form the backdrop. </em></p>
<p><em>Self-educating, although undervalued in our society, is a beautiful thing.</em></p>
<p><em>That said, I think it’s important to be <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/breakfast-anywhere/">accurate in those details</a>. Read widely, science fiction as well as fact. Concentrate on the field that most enthralls you, be it gene modification, climate science, quantum physics, or that all-time sci-fi favorite, space exploration. (If it’s the last, I recommend a daily dip into <a href="https://www.space.com/">space.com</a>.) Good luck, Ambitious!</em></p>
<p>Dear Ms. Ann Thrope:</p>
<p>I’m a Bahai, about to enter into a polyamorous marriage with a Druid, a Congregationalist, a Buddhist, a lapsed Catholic, and a Reformed Jew. How should we raise the children? &#8212; Wedding Bells, Bells, and More Bells</p>
<p><em>Dear Bells: </em></p>
<p><em>Do. Not. Procreate.</em></p>
<p>Dear Ms. Ann Thrope:</p>
<p>Why should I vote in 2020 if the Democratic candidate, once again, isn’t truly progressive? I don’t want to simply go back to the way things were. &#8212; I’ll Stay Home Again</p>
<p><em>Dear Home:</em></p>
<p><em>Go ahead. I’m old, and I don’t have to care. But you should. Old men (and women&#8211;who are often the enforcers of the societal &#8220;norms&#8221; that men invent) are trying to turn back the clock, and they’re succeeding because so many people refuse to compromise. Vote for president, whether your preferred candidate is nominated or not, and for the goddess’ sake, vote <strong>down-ticket</strong> for <strong>House of Representatives</strong> and <strong>Senator. </strong></em></p>
<p>Dear Ms. Ann Thrope:</p>
<p>You say you don’t care, but you sound like you do. &#8212; Gotcha</p>
<p><em>Dear Gotcha:</em></p>
<p><em>You got me. I care.</em></p>
<p><em>True story: The year was 1969. I had just started college. My best friend from high school—call her Sally—showed up at my dorm in tears. Her boyfriend waited downstairs.</em></p>
<p><em>Sally was pregnant. Roe v. Wade was still several years out. My college had a reputation for being in the forefront of the growing new wave of feminism. She thought I might know someone who knew someone, and though I had only been there for a week, I did.</em></p>
<p><em>I got Sally the phone number and password she needed to arrange a clandestine abortion in Canada. She hemorrhaged afterwards, which was not unusual. Luckily she recovered. </em></p>
<p><em>In 1973 Roe v. Wade finally began to make the coat hanger as medical device obsolete. Now our rights are being systematically demolished with an eye toward reversing the decision in the Supreme Court. And it’s not just women’s right to control our bodies, of course. LGBTQ rights. Voting rights. The rights of refugees to seek asylum. </em><em>We all have stories.</em></p>
<p><em>IMHO, we have to survive the undertow before we can swim.</em></p>
<p>Dear Ms. Ann Thrope:</p>
<p>This column started out funny, but then it got too serious. I object. &#8212; Light-Hearted</p>
<p><em>Dear Light:</em></p>
<p><em>Pain and laughter can exist in the same place.</em></p>
<p>Dear Ms. Ann Thrope:</p>
<p>I hear you have a friend with a similar name who also writes an advice column. What does she think we should do about Trump and the Republicans? &#8212; Curious</p>
<p><em>Dear Curious:</em></p>
<p><em>Yes, I do. Her name is Ms. Ann Dei, and she has just one word for us:</em></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-15469 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Dracarys-300x169.png" alt="" width="533" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Dracarys-300x169.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Dracarys.png 720w" sizes="(max-width: 533px) 100vw, 533px" /></p>
<p><em>Dear LSQ Community: With that cheap shot, I bid adieu to my column, Breakfast Anytime, for a while. Thank you so much to the readers, editors, and fellow bloggers who have inspired and enlightened me.<br />
</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spring Cleaning</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/spring-cleaning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth McCabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast Anytime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve got a few cobwebs in my brain that need clearing out. Bear with me.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-15171 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/spring-300x140.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="140" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/spring-300x140.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/spring.jpg 329w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I’ve got a few cobwebs in my brain that need clearing out. Bear with me.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s something that&#8217;s been knocking around for a while. I’ve been going on at length <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/columns/breakfast-anytime/">in this column</a> about the obstacles and challenges women spec writers faced in the 1960s, 70s, and into the 80s.</p>
<p>A while ago an alert writing friend sent me <a href="https://www.wired.com/2019/02/geeks-guide-history-women-sci-fi/?fbclid=IwAR00HOATPoUPgnboqUd1Mf2lu0Hm27OWVRQwLkI-b3ng23ZeetEQQiwtO0c">“The History of Women in Sci-Fi isn’t What You Think”</a>, based on a <em>Wired Magazine</em> podcast from the series <a href="https://www.wired.com/author/geeks-guide-to-the-galaxy/"><em>Geek’s Guide to the Galaxy. </em></a>The article summarized an interview with Lisa Yaszek, who teaches Science Fiction Studies at Georgia Tech.</p>
<p>She knows a lot more about this subject than I do.</p>
<figure id="attachment_14962" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-14962" style="width: 215px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image wp-image-14962" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Anne-McCaffrey.jpg" alt="" width="215" height="278" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-14962" class="wp-caption-text">Anne McCaffrey</figcaption></figure>
<p>Yaszek tells us there were, in fact, numerous successful women spec writers during this period. The piece goes on to say that 1) only a few editors discriminated against women writers, and 2) only a small number of women writers—famously, James Tiptree, Jr.—found it necessary or desirable to use male pseudonyms or initials.</p>
<p>Yet these situations come up on a regular basis when I look at the histories of individual authors, which I have been doing, somewhat obsessively, over the past few months.</p>
<p>Quite honestly, I don’t know what to think now. Which is it? Did women face discrimination in bringing their stories forward in the spec world or not?</p>
<p>Obviously it’s not a black and white issue. How many rejections from how many editors qualifies as discrimination? How do we know, even now, <em>why</em> a story gets rejected?</p>
<p>Unfortunately, it doesn’t figure in my world view right now to go back to the original sources and do enough research to feel confident to draw a conclusion rather than simply sport an opinion. (I thank, or blame, the English department at Barnard College for instilling such over-the-top requirements for drawing conclusions deep in my psyche.)</p>
<p>I do know it’s important to consider both sides and to avoid claiming victim without cause. If I have misled you, dear readers, by assuming discrimination, I apologize. But honestly, I’m not ready to concede this point either. So I’m leaving the issue open. Comments welcome.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p><strong>One Crone&#8217;s Tips for Eliminating Clutter<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Speaking of spring cleaning, here are my three best tips. This may not seem to have much to do with speculative literature, but it has a lot to do, for me, with making a space within which I can breathe, write, and create a world.</p>
<p><strong> <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-class alignleft wp-image-15178" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/box-1-251x300.jpg" alt="" width="135" height="161" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/box-1-251x300.jpg 251w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/box-1-768x920.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/box-1.jpg 820w" sizes="(max-width: 135px) 100vw, 135px" />1. Locate your nearest Goodwill</strong> or other not-for-profit that accepts donations of items and clothing. (The success of the following tips may depend on your willingness to implement this one.)</p>
<p>Keep a box in your garage, hallway, closet, etc., for items you wish to donate. Bring the box to the organization on a regular basis, before you can second-guess yourself.</p>
<p><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-15173" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cloth.jpg" alt="" width="124" height="124" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cloth.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/cloth-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 124px) 100vw, 124px" />2. Do women still have tablecloths?</strong> Getting rid of mine was a highly symbolic action. Something about no longer needing to nurture those around me with a decorative home. (It’s kind of a fish-without-a-bicycle, why-we-don’t-write-symphonies kind of thing.) Maybe for you it’s not a tablecloth, but some other bit of domestic flotsam. You get the drift.</p>
<p>And maybe this is way too last-century for many of you. Now, women <em>do</em> write symphonies. But someone’s buying them. There they are in the store, those tablecloths, mocking us, a drag on our progress, a siren song to lure us back to toxic traditional values. So if you have any, put them in that Goodwill box. Right now, before you think about it.</p>
<p><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-15174 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/gift.jpg" alt="" width="144" height="125" />3. Give yourself permission to get rid of stuff people have given you.</strong></p>
<p>This can be the hardest piece of anti-clutter advice to follow because it can feel, in some visceral sense, like getting rid of the item is getting rid of the person or her memory. It’s especially difficult when it’s someone who is or was close to you; almost impossible if it’s your mom, no matter what kind of relationship you have or had with her.</p>
<p>But it&#8217;s not that person. It&#8217;s just a thing.</p>
<p>That was the other most liberating anti-clutter thing I did for myself, and once I made the decision, I was amazed how many unlovable toiletry storage items and scarves and pieces of costume jewelry I had been clinging to.</p>
<p>Most of it came from my husband&#8217;s maiden aunts, who maintained huge inventories of this stuff to circulate at Christmas. No emotional significance at all, yet it was all still there in my closet.</p>
<p><em>Hmmm&#8230;I wish I could take all my random anxious and non-productive thoughts with no emotional significance, put them in a box, and give them away too!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Old Favorites: YA Edition</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/old-favorites-ya-edition/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth McCabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast Anytime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When my daughter Mikah was a preteen, I was curious to see why she loved&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-14959 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/opener-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/opener-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/opener.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />When my daughter Mikah was a preteen, I was curious to see why she loved certain authors so much. I began reading some of her YA fantasies more as a dutiful mom thing.</p>
<p>I wasn’t in the least prepared for the magic land of strong characters, fast-moving plots, and intense emotional engagement into which I stepped.</p>
<p>These books refused to be limited by labels. They were, quite simply, fabulous reads. As life cut in and narrowed my overall reading time, I let my interest in YA slide for a while. Then <em>The Hunger Games</em> struck and I was hooked all over again.</p>
<p>I’ve spoken before in this column about some YA books I consider stand-outs. But, for a retrospective post, I went back to my source.</p>
<p>So here are some of Mikah’s Girl Power faves from the 90’s and aughts. If they were also part of your coming-of-age—or your daughter’s, or your sister&#8217;s—I hope they bring back fond memories. If not, maybe have a look. Like many of the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/columns/breakfast-anytime/">adult spec classics</a> I’ve been recollecting, these books have some serious staying power.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Alanna-First-Adventure-Song-Lioness-ebook/dp/B002ZJCQYW/ref=sr_1_2?keywords=alanna&amp;qid=1554425495&amp;s=gateway&amp;sr=8-2"><em>Alanna</em></a> (2009) by Tamora Pierce <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-14961 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Alanna-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Alanna-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Alanna.jpg 331w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></p>
<p>Book One of the <em>Song of the Lioness Quartet</em>. Alanna wants to be a knight, and her twin brother, Thom, wants to learn magic. So they switch genders and places: Alanna heads off to the castle to become a page, and Thom goes to the convent.</p>
<p>Much magic, mayhem, good and evil ensue.</p>
<p>“It’s the quintessential Tamora Pierce main character,” says Mikah. “She took a girl dressing as a boy and gave it depth.”</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acorna"><em>The Acorna Universe</em></a> by Anne McCaffrey et. al.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-14962 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Anne-McCaffrey.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="255" />Together with two co-writers, Anne McCaffrey wrote ten Acorna books in all. The first one, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Acorna-Unicorn-Girl-Book-ebook/dp/B000FCKBFW/ref=sr_1_1?crid=37SDAL4JV9UZX&amp;keywords=acorna+series&amp;qid=1554426475&amp;s=gateway&amp;sprefix=acorna%2Caps%2C219&amp;sr=8-1"><em>Acorna: Unicorn Girl</em></a><em>,</em> was published in 1997.</p>
<p>Acorna is an alien baby with a tiny horn nestled in her forehead. She’s discovered by three grizzled yet kindly asteroid miners after her escape pod is jettisoned by her doomed parents. But hey, Acorna has more going for her than that little horn.</p>
<p>Not only does she grow (alarmingly quickly) into a lovely young woman, but she also has the ability to purify air and water, make plants grow, and heal scars and broken bones. (Apparently, this is what her race is all about.)</p>
<p>“This one wins for its unique premise,” Mikah says. I also appreciated the fact that this series, in spite of its fantasy-based main character, involves interstellar travel and all that good sci-fi stuff.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-14963 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Acorna-186x300.jpg" alt="" width="186" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Acorna-186x300.jpg 186w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Acorna.jpg 215w" sizes="(max-width: 186px) 100vw, 186px" /></p>
<p>I loved McCaffrey’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dragonriders_of_Pern"><em>Dragon Riders of Pern</em></a> back in the 1970s and 80s when women were trying to establish a base within the speculative fiction arena. It’s good to know that she, like so many of our other spec foremothers, felt it was important to create young women characters with agency, power, and self-awareness.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sabriel-Old-Kingdom-Book-1-ebook/dp/B000FC13MM/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=sabriel&amp;qid=1554422860&amp;s=gateway&amp;sr=8-1"><em>Sabriel</em></a> by Garth Nix</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-14965 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Sabriel-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="193" height="291" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Sabriel-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Sabriel.jpg 332w" sizes="(max-width: 193px) 100vw, 193px" />This is Book One in Nix’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Kingdom_(book_series)"><em>Old Kingdom</em></a> trilogy.</p>
<p>When she hears that her father is missing, young Sabriel must leave boarding school and enter the Old Kingdom, where magic rules and the line between dead and living is not always apparent. This book, plus its follow-on volumes <em>Lirael</em> and <em>Abhorson</em>, catapulted the Australian Nix into worldwide YA popularity.</p>
<p><strong>The Here and Now</strong></p>
<p>For more recent YA, Mikah recommends a “wacky” standalone 2012 space opera called <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Confusion-Princes-Garth-Nix-ebook/dp/B007ED6VWW/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2OH8UT66IUD7B&amp;keywords=a+confusion+of+princes&amp;qid=1554510000&amp;s=gateway&amp;sprefix=a+confusion+o%2Caps%2C213&amp;sr=8-1">A Confusion of Princes</a></em>, also from Garth Nix<em>. </em>The description sounds enticing, at least to a sci-fi fan: kind of a mash-up of <em>Ender’s Game</em> and <em>The Highlander. </em>I&#8217;ve put it on my reading list.<em><br />
</em></p>
<p>She also recommends <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Scythe-Arc-Book-1-ebook/dp/B01BKR487W/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1SESFOLY7LFI5&amp;keywords=scythe+book&amp;qid=1554423352&amp;s=gateway&amp;sprefix=scythe%2Caps%2C207&amp;sr=8-1"><em>Scythe</em></a> by Neal Shusterman. In this series, war, hunger, and other scourges have been eliminated. Only entities known as scythes can and must end lives in order to control population.</p>
<p>Book One (2016) follows two teens who are apprenticed to a scythe and must learn to take lives or risk losing their own. Book Two, Thunderhead, came out in January 2018 and Book Three is expected in September of this year. <em>(Wuss that I am, I found the premise too disturbing to get into it.)</em></p>
<p>And there are so many more. Perhaps the books that most stuck with me from that period, even more than they did with Mikah, were <em>Wise Child</em> and <em>Juniper</em> by Monica Furlong. I&#8217;m sure you have your favorites as well.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WD40: Love Lube of the Future?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/wd40-love-lube-of-the-future/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth McCabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast Anytime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last month I talked about The Silver Metal Lover by Tanith Lee, about a poignant&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-14657 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/silver-183x300.jpg" alt="" width="183" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/silver-183x300.jpg 183w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/silver.jpg 305w" sizes="(max-width: 183px) 100vw, 183px" /></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/women-on-the-edge-part-2/">Last month</a> I talked about <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KDXTGPH/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">The Silver Metal Lover</a></em> by Tanith Lee, about a poignant romance between a human girl and an empathetic, sensitive, android bard. The month before that I mentioned <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/women-on-the-edge-of-time-2/">Marge Piercy’s inclusion of the topic</a> of human-machine love in one of her spec novels.</p>
<p>I decided to take a closer look at this topic. After all, an exploration of human-artificial intelligence love pushes us to define our humanity, and, in fact, attempt to define love itself. How human does a technological construct have to be to inspire passion? Even more basic, what do we want from a partner? What if that partner is programmed to provide these things? Does that make those attributes less real?</p>
<p>We can also look at it from the AI’s point of view. How can the robot/android/AI have true agency—i.e., can they choose to love? What are the ethical implications?</p>
<p>There are a few examples of this trope in science fiction. And it’s got its own, somewhat disturbing, relatively new field of academic inquiry. There’s even a seminal (no pun intended) text entitled <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000XUACXM/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">Love and Sex with Robots: The Evolution of Human-robot Relationships</a></em> by David Levy.</p>
<p>I don’t really think we are all that close to being able to create a dream date in the lab. But that doesn’t mean it won’t happen. Still, for now I think I’ll just stick with sci-fi. <em>Note: I’m going to avoid the purely sex robot thing. No judgement, it’s just a separate topic. </em></p>
<p><strong>“In Theory”</strong></p>
<p>Looking for other examples of human-machine love, I immediately thought of the 1991 episode of <em>Star Trek: The Next Generation</em>, <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0708735/mediaindex?ref_=tt_pv_mi_sm">“In Theory”</a>, in which a woman crew member falls in love with the android Data.</p>
<p>Although he tries his best, Data ultimately cannot respond to his partner’s nagging to feel more, love more, <em>be more human</em>. The credited writers on this episode are Joe Menosky and Ronald D. Moore, so I took this to be an example of how male writers might approach the topic. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-14658 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Data-in-love-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Data-in-love-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Data-in-love.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Pondering this dichotomy, I reached an over-hasty conclusion: that human-machine love as portrayed by women vs. men might reflect women’s traditional desire for a sensitive partner who responds to their needs—and men’s equally traditional desire for a woman who doesn’t ask them to.</p>
<p><strong>What is it about that origami unicorn?</strong></p>
<p>Next I thought about Deckard falling for Rachael in the <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0083658/?ref_=nv_sr_2">1982 film <em>Blade Runner</em></a><em>. </em>(The original cut of which is the only <em>Blade Runner</em> worth watching, IMHO. Don’t get me started on <em>Blade Runner 2049</em>.) This classic is based on the story “Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?” by Philip K. Dick.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-14659 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Blade-Runner-300x150.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="150" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Blade-Runner-300x150.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Blade-Runner-768x384.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Blade-Runner-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Blade-Runner-1110x555.jpg 1110w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Blade-Runner.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Deckard thought Rachael was human at first, but finding out she is a replicant (android) doesn’t change the way he feels about her. Sure, Deckard is a piece of work; what Philip K. character isn’t? But there is nothing in this relationship to set off my sexist alarm bells in spite of the author and the times in which he wrote.</p>
<p>Hmmm, thinks I. Maybe my hypothesis is faulty.</p>
<p><strong>The AI who loved me</strong></p>
<p>Recalling the 2013 movie <em><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1798709/mediaviewer/rm2063192064">Her</a> </em>pretty much finished off said hypothesis. Maybe this film is an encouraging indication that rigid gender expectations are slowly evolving. Or maybe it’s just a reminder that in art, all things are possible.</p>
<p>In the event you haven’t seen it, <em>Her</em> is the near-future story of Theodore Twombly, a lonely work-at-home letter writer who becomes intimately involved with an artificial intelligence in the form of a personal assistant on his computer—basically, a very advanced piece of software with the ability to adapt and evolve.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-14660 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Her-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Her-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Her-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Her-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Her.jpg 1777w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />In a way, Samantha, as the AI is called, reminds me of Tanith Lee&#8217;s Silver. Emotionally, she is the perfect lover: sensitive, funny, caring, intelligent. The fact that she has no body doesn’t chill Theodore’s passion, and the fact that we believe it is a testament to the talent of filmmaker Spike Jonze.</p>
<p>In fact, when Samantha arranges for a surrogate to come to Theodore’s apartment to simulate the act of physical love between the two of them, Theodore can’t hack it. His love for Samantha is way too spiritual and romantic.</p>
<p>How’s that for a turnabout?</p>
<p>I’ll avoid an actual spoiler about the ending. Suffice it to say that Samantha turns out to be the non-exclusive member of this relationship.</p>
<p><strong>The next frontier?</strong></p>
<p>In many ways this seems like a frivolous topic. We have too many real-world challenges to worry about it. But consider this: it&#8217;s been difficult enough to achieve legal parity for same-sex couples. Just imagine what will happen when you go to your Human Resources department to sign your android wife or husband up for benefits.</p>
<p>Maybe love is just love.</p>
<p>If you are interested in additional human-machine love examples from the sci-fi canon, check out this <a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/blog/sci-fi-fantasy/of-love-and-robots-11-stories-of-truly-science-fictional-romance/">excellent blog post</a> on the Barnes &amp; Noble web site by Ceridwen Christensen.</p>
<p><em>Movie and television images courtesy of IMDb.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women on the Edge, Part 2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/women-on-the-edge-part-2/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/women-on-the-edge-part-2/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth McCabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast Anytime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12766</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With a little help from my friends, this column has been revisiting favorite authors from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With a little help from my friends, this column has been revisiting favorite authors from the ground-breaking days of women in spec lit. Here are two more.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://vondanmcintyre.com/">Vonda N. McIntire</a></strong></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mcintyre.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12768 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/mcintyre.jpg" alt="" width="219" height="266" /></a>McIntire has garnered an impressive share of kudos and recognition for her work starting in the 1970s.</p>
<p>Her best known novel is probably the 1978 <em>Dreamsnake</em>, which won Hugo, Nebula, and Locus awards.</p>
<p>The book is set on a post-apocalyptic earth. It is the story of a healer named Snake and her quest to replace Grass, her rare, beloved dreamsnake, an essential element in her healing ability.</p>
<p><strong>My most loved</strong></p>
<p>I tend to go for harder sci-fi, and McIntire does not disappoint. On my <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/women-on-the-edge-of-time/">special bookshelf</a> she was represented by:</p>
<ul>
<li><em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Superluminal-Vonda-N-McIntyre/dp/0395349427/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1548967144&amp;sr=8-2&amp;keywords=superluminal">Superluminal</a></em> (1983), in which a young woman has her heart replaced with an artificial pump so that she can become an interstellar pilot.</li>
<li><em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/The-Exile-Waiting/dp/B00G03Y6DS/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1548874410&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+exile+waiting">The Exile Waiting</a></em><em>,</em> McIntire’s 1975 debut novel about a young mutant thief in a post-apocalyptic world.</li>
<li><em>Barbary</em> (1986) is generally considered a YA novel, but that just makes me love it more. It’s a tale about a 12-year-old girl and her cat who move to a space station.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Barbary.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image wp-image-12772 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Barbary-195x300.jpg" alt="" width="186" height="287" /></a>In an era when the most popular girls’ series featured well-scrubbed suburban baby sitters, McIntire shone at presenting courageous young women in challenging situations.</p>
<p><strong>Other accomplishments</strong></p>
<p>Pride of place on my bookshelf was held by the 1976 feminist sci-fi anthology <em>Beyond Equality</em>, co-edited by McIntyre, which includes the Nebula-winning “Houston, Houston, Do You Read?” by James Tiptree, Jr., aka Alice Sheldon.</p>
<p>McIntire also wrote the novelizations for many of the <em>Star Wars</em> and <em>Star Trek</em> movies. And in reading <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vonda_N._McIntyre">her bio</a> I discovered two fun things: she is a fellow Greater Seattleite, and she did graduate work in genetics.</p>
<p>McIntire’s work can be hard to find in print. Several of her books are available in audio format on Amazon, and like many of my recommendations from this period, they are good requests to make at your nearest used bookstore.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tanith_Lee">Tanith Lee</a></strong></p>
<p>T<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/tanith-lee.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12776 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/tanith-lee-300x227.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="227" /></a>he great Tanith Lee, most likely known to LSQ readers, was a prolific British author of fantasy, sci-fi, and horror.</p>
<p>She penned over 90 novels, 300 short stories, and a variety of other works. Her first publication was <em>The Dragon Hoard</em>, a children’s book in 1971.</p>
<p>As widely known as her works are, I was surprised to find out that during the course of her career Lee often met with resistance from publishers.</p>
<p>Perhaps this was partly a result of the fact that Lee, like many of the authors I’ve been recollecting, often explored overtly feminist and sexual themes. That doesn&#8217;t sound so earth-shaking today, I know.</p>
<p>Sadly, Lee succumbed to breast cancer in 2015.</p>
<p><strong>My fave</strong></p>
<p>It’s difficult to find a consensus on Lee’s most successful and/or most popular work. But choosing my favorite is easy: <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07KDXTGPH/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">The Silver Metal Lover</a></em> (1981).</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/silver.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12777 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/silver-183x300.jpg" alt="" width="183" height="300" /></a>This is the story of Jane, a wealthy 16-year-old girl in an imaginary world who falls deeply in love with a silver-skinned android minstrel. Silver is more complex than the other robots, and Jane moves to the slums with him, giving up all her privileges for love.</p>
<p>As she does so she finds herself in a way that would never have happened in her prior life.</p>
<p>It’s a little sappier than most of my favorites, but then, I was a lot more sappy in my youth than I am in my cronedom. And&#8211;not that there&#8217;s anything wrong with romance novels&#8211;other issues are explored as well: the role of art in society. The haves vs. the have-nots.</p>
<p><strong>Love and metal</strong></p>
<p>Revisiting <em>Silver </em>got me thinking about the depiction of <strong>human-machine love</strong> in books, movies, and TV, and how it might differ in the eyes of male and female writers.</p>
<p>I asked my husband if he remembered any examples of this topic. He said, “Yeah. I remember how you wouldn’t shut up about the robot with the guitar.”</p>
<p><em>More about this next month, so stock up on Kleenex and WD40 .</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/women-on-the-edge-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women on the Edge of Time</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/women-on-the-edge-of-time-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth McCabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast Anytime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout the latter part of the last century my bookshelf held a rather good, if&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/shelf.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12461" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/shelf-300x164.jpg" alt="" width="346" height="189" /></a>Throughout the latter part of the last century my bookshelf held a rather good, if dog-eared, collection by spec women pioneers. I gave away these physical manifestations when we moved coasts in a single U-Haul UBox a few years ago. But they live on in my heart.</p>
<p>Some of the writers from my shelf have slipped entirely into obscurity outside of the most woke used bookstores. Some of the works were those of better-known authors that weren’t their most commercially successful, but were the ones I loved best.</p>
<p>Last month my friend <a href="https://crhodges.wordpress.com/">C.R. Hodges</a> offered insight into the fiction of two of his favorite trailblazers, <a href="http://azsf.net/cwblog/">Connie Willis</a> and <a href="http://www.elizabethmoon.com/">Elizabeth Moon</a>. Thanks again, C.R., for painting my fence. What are friends for, right? <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/welcome-guest-blogger-c-r-hodges/">Here’s his guest column.</a></p>
<p>And here are three of mine.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://margaretweis.com/">Margaret Weis</a></strong></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Weis.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12462 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Weis.jpg" alt="" width="186" height="279" /></a>Weis&#8217; books resided on our co-ed shelves, not on my Special Shelf, since my husband and I both loved them. Her early work definitely qualified as “gee whiz, look what women can do.” I was pleased to find out that Weis (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Margaret_Weis">read her bio here</a>) and her co-writers are still churning out books. I’m looking forward to catching up.</p>
<p>In the early 1980s Weis co-wrote the <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_ss_i_2_11?url=search-alias%3Ddigital-text&amp;field-keywords=dragonlance+chronicles+trilogy&amp;sprefix=dragonlance%2Cdigital-text%2C227&amp;crid=NPTXOYNDHL2M">Dragonlance Chronicles</a></em> trilogy, the first of many collaborations with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tracy_Hickman">Tracy Hickman</a>. The trilogy and its universe became immensely popular. However, my favorite fantasy collaboration of theirs was an off-beat series called <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B003E8AJ1U/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">The Darksword Trilogy,</a></em> written in the late eighties.</p>
<p>Moving from fantasy to sci-fi, my very favorite Weis series was a kick-ass space opera that she wrote solo, <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lost-King-Star-Guardians-Book-ebook/dp/B004H4XRAK">The Star of the Guardians</a></em>. The first book appeared in 1990, with three more to follow and a slew of spin-offs which I thought were far superior to most series add-ons.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Lost-king.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12463 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Lost-king-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="147" height="196" /></a>The world in this series is a vast, complete, and utterly believable universe ruled by imaginative future tech. The story revolves around a young prince, Dion, but the true main characters are Guardians Sagan and Maigrey; apparently, Weis wrote the fourth book just to complete their journey.</p>
<p>The Lady Maigrey is an amazing character, especially for the times, when women had yet to commonly hold positions of authority—not to mention swords that are linked to the user by a flow of nanobots from the hilt—in the science fiction world. Just as brave but more complex than Leia, she is a warrior who puts planet, prince, and right above love and personal satisfaction. Read Book One, <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B004H4XRAK/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">The Lost King</a></em>, just to meet her.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joanna_Russ">Joanna Russ</a></strong></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/russ.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12464 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/russ-208x300.jpg" alt="" width="174" height="251" /></a>According to <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/908311.The_Female_Man">Goodreads</a>, Russ’ <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Female-Man-Joanna-Russ-ebook/dp/B07B4752KQ/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1546800959&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+female+man">The Female Man</a></em> (1975) shows up on lists of essential science fiction. Yet Russ certainly does not share the prestige of some of her male counterparts from that era. It’s easy to see why; as you may gather from the title, her fiction is seriously political.</p>
<p>Goodreads says: “…THE FEMALE MAN is a suspenseful, surprising and darkly witty chronicle of what happens when Jeannine, Janet, Joanna, and Jael—four alternative selves from drastically different realities—meet.”</p>
<p>I don’t know how relevant Russ’ work will feel today. Although issues of equality are still urgent, the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Female-man.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12465 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Female-man.jpg" alt="" width="131" height="200" /></a>cultural context has changed dramatically. Definitely worth a look, though, even if you aren’t writing a dissertation on the portrayal of women in spec lit in the second half of the 20<sup>th</sup> century.</p>
<p>Another Russ work I particularly enjoyed was the <em>The Adventures of Alyx </em>(1976). All I could find was a paperback copy on Amazon for $15, so it’s a good title to ask your local used bookstore about (and probably cheaper that way too).</p>
<p>Russ was also a playwright, essayist, and author of nonfiction works, generally literary criticism and feminist theory. She died in 2011.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marge_Piercy">Marge Piercy</a></strong></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/marge-piercy.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12466 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/marge-piercy-300x196.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="196" /></a>Piercy is probably best known as a poet, literary novelist, and social activist. <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Woman-Edge-Time-Marge-Piercy-ebook/dp/B003Z9KFBC/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1546806840&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=woman+on+the+edge+of+time">Woman on the Edge of Time</a></em> (1976), however, can’t be omitted from a list of speculative trailblazers.</p>
<p><em>Woman </em>has a lot to say. It’s a time travel book and a utopia. It’s gender bending, feminist theory, and awareness of the rights of those incarcerated in mental institutions. And those are just a few of the dragons at which Piercy aims her lance.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/he-she-it.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12467 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/he-she-it-182x300.jpg" alt="" width="118" height="195" /></a></p>
<p>Her other major speculative work is <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/He-She-Novel-Marge-Piercy-ebook/dp/B004BXA3A4/ref=pd_sim_351_2?_encoding=UTF8&amp;pd_rd_i=B004BXA3A4&amp;pd_rd_r=688e612b-11f2-11e9-a35a-b10cdd98bd7b&amp;pd_rd_w=UKmJn&amp;pd_rd_wg=YBEyg&amp;pf_rd_p=18bb0b78-4200-49b9-ac91-f141d61a1780&amp;pf_rd_r=N30YRHS5VMJXEJN32ZQX&amp;psc=1&amp;refRID=N30YRHS5VMJXEJN32ZQX">He, She, and It</a> </em>(1991), also published as <em>Body of Glass. </em>It’s classified as cyberpunk; how trail-blazing is that? This book takes on post-apocalypse, more gender-bending, and human-machine love. Buckle up if you check out the fearless Marge Piercy.</p>
<p><em>A tip o’ the hat to the LSQ blog and bloggers for keeping our spec pioneers from being forgotten. More next month!</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcome: Guest Blogger C.R. Hodges</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/welcome-guest-blogger-c-r-hodges-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth McCabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 11:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast Anytime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12086</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This month my friend and fellow author C.R. Hodges was kind enough to contribute notes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Willis-book.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12093 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Willis-book-181x300.jpg" alt="" width="181" height="300" /></a>This month my friend and fellow author <a href="https://crhodges.wordpress.com/">C.R. Hodges</a> was kind enough to contribute notes on two of his favorite sci-fi writers: Connie Willis and Elizabeth Moon.</em></p>
<p><em>C.R. is ambidextrous in that he can write the sci-fi </em>and <em>the fantasy (kind of like being able to cook the dinner </em>and <em>the dessert). His stories and longer works have won a number of prestigious awards. Last year his sci-fi story “Run” was included in </em>Escape Pod’s <em>Hugo nomination collection.<br />
</em></p>
<p><em>C.R. has devoted considerable time and effort to writing women characters whose strength comes from within as well as without. </em></p>
<p><em>He’s created a lethal 6-year-old Valkyrie, a granny </em>kitsune<em>, a twenty-something AI expert, a seasoned space captain with a penchant for 19<sup>th</sup> century literature, and many others I’ve been privileged to meet.<br />
</em></p>
<p><em>Check out his <a href="https://crhodges.wordpress.com/">web site</a> and read his prize-winning story <a href="https://www.writersdigest.com/online-exclusives/jun-16/eleventh-annual-popular-fiction-awards-science-fiction-winner-the-twentieth-of-july">“The Twentieth of July”</a>, one of my favorites. Here are C.R.&#8217;s comments:<br />
</em></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Connie.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12092 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Connie-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>Thanks for the opportunity to make my pitch for a couple of science fiction authors who I believe should be on every geek’s bookshelf.</p>
<p><strong>Connie Willis, </strong>in my opinion, is the best sci-fi writer many people may never have heard of. While she’s won more major sci-fi awards than any author, ever—11 Hugos and 7 Nebulas (!)—she shuns both social media and the spotlight, and just writes great books from her hometown of Greeley, Colorado.  Many a local writer here in Colorado has tales of seeing her in a coffee shop, plugging away.</p>
<p>Her Time Travel series—e.g. <em>Doomsday Book</em> and <em>Blackout</em>—are easily the definitive works on time travel. Many an aspiring writer, myself included, have turned to her books for clues on how to handle the conundrums created by time travel.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Moon.jpeg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12094 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Moon-300x300.jpeg" alt="" width="275" height="275" /></a>Elizabeth Moon</strong> was the first female sci-fi author I can remember reading, and honestly when I picked up <em>Hunting Party </em>back in the 90s, it was mostly because she was a fellow Rice alum.</p>
<p>But as the father of two young daughters at the time, and slowly awakening to the dearth of female protagonists even in children’s books, I was hooked by her strong female characters. And great yarns.</p>
<p>Also a Nebula winner, she actually started in epic fantasy, went through a space opera phase (where I found her) and went on to become an prolific writer of military sci-fi and hard science fiction, all subgenres still heavily dominated by male authors.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Moon-book.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12095" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Moon-book-184x300.jpg" alt="" width="170" height="277" /></a>And while I’m not sure if this is 100% true, every book of hers I’ve read has a strong female protagonist.</p>
<p>Since Beth mentioned 19<sup>th</sup> century authors, I&#8217;ve got to give a shout out to Mary Shelley, who almost single-handedly created the horror genre with <em>Frankenstein&#8211;</em>published 80 years before Bram Stoker’s <em>Dracula.</em></p>
<p>&#8211;C.R. Hodges</p>
<p><em>Next month I&#8217;ll add some more of my own favorites!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who Was Cele Goldsmith?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/who-was-cele-goldsmith/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/who-was-cele-goldsmith/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth McCabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 11:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast Anytime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11837</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I sat down at my laptop to write about women authors. Then I found a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Cele.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11839 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Cele.jpg" alt="" width="183" height="275" /></a>I sat down at my laptop to write about women authors. Then I found a foremother lurking in the background.</p>
<p>Like most of my contemporaries, I cut my speculative teeth on male authors. I still feel grateful to Kurt Vonnegut and Philip K. Dick (“Mountains, Bruce, mountains…”) for making me feel perhaps the world was crazy, not me. I also devoured Isaac Asimov, James P. Hogan, Robert Heinlein, John Varley, Harlan Ellison, et. al.</p>
<p>Slowly, along with my elevating political consciousness, my collection of women spec writers started growing.  Many of them came in the back door and into my avid hands by using pen names. I still remember what a kick it was to find out that these prominent, in-your-face sci-fi writers were women.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/tiptree2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10552 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/tiptree2-188x300.jpg" alt="" width="188" height="300" /></a><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Tiptree_Jr.">James Tiptree, Jr</a>., as I have <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/in-praise-of-used-bookstores-part-i/">previously noted</a> in this column, was really Alice Sheldon. And according to Wikipedia, &#8220;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/C._J._Cherryh">C.J. Cherryh</a> (pronounced ‘Cherry’) appended a silent &#8216;h&#8217; to her real name because her first editor…felt that &#8216;Cherry&#8217; sounded too much like a romance writer. Her initials, C.J., were used to disguise the fact that she was female.” Well, yeah.</p>
<p>The late great <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ursula_K._Le_Guin">Ursula K. Le Guin</a> was one of the few women who found an early market for sci-fi written under her own name, publishing her first story in <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantastic_(magazine)">Fantastic Science Fiction</a></em> in 1962 after multiple rejections of mainstream stories from literary publishers.</p>
<p>It’s easy, given Le Guin’s talent and ultimate stature, to assume she was just such a good writer that the editors of the time simply had to publish her even though she was a woman. Dig a little deeper, though, and you’ll find out that the editor of <em>Fantastic</em> at the time was one <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cele_Goldsmith_Lalli">Cele Goldsmith</a> (1933-2002).</p>
<p>Goldsmith started her sci-fi publishing career as a previous editor’s secretary. In 1958, when he left, she took over. It’s safe to say that she brought a new openness to the lively spec magazine publishing scene; her male predecessors and counterparts might not even have read submissions from someone named Ursula. Even with a woman at the helm of two major magazines, during that period and for many years to come, sci-fi covers of the time feature all male author lists and lots of sleazy half-dressed girl art.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/800px-Fantastic_October_1961_front.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11840 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/800px-Fantastic_October_1961_front-218x300.jpg" alt="" width="218" height="300" /></a>At <em>Fantastic</em> and <em>Amazing Stories</em>, Goldsmith nurtured authors like Le Guin, Roger Zelazny, Keith Laumer, Larry Eisenberg, and many others, including lesser-known women writers such as Sonya Dorman. In the early 60s she received a special Hugo from the World Science Fiction Convention for her work, and during her tenure, the magazines received multiple award nominations.</p>
<p>In 1965 Ziff Davis sold <em>Fantastic</em> and <em>Amazing Stories</em> and the new owner hired a male editor. Goldsmith stayed on at Ziff Davis, becoming Editor-in-Chief of <em>Modern Bride</em> magazine. She stayed there for 30 years.</p>
<p>If going from space ships to brides sounds like a betrayal of our cause, remember that even accomplished, educated women had few options in the higher echelons of publishing, or any industry for that matter.  Women were grateful to have serious careers and loyal to employers who valued them.</p>
<p>It’s not just a quaint Mad Men-esque meme that women were once given the choice of becoming a secretary, teacher, or nurse; that was the condition my father put on helping me pay for college. I was grateful that I was a middle-class Jewish girl whose parents assumed I would <em>go</em> to college, even if they had husband-shopping in mind. Women without financial resources had far fewer options.</p>
<p>Still, I can’t help but wonder how Goldsmith felt about overseeing stories about centerpieces and bouquets after rising so high in the heady world of spec and nurturing the careers of some of its greatest luminaries. Maybe it was a welcome change. I don’t like to make assumptions. I just wish she could have lived a bit longer to see how far the world of women&#8217;s spec has come.</p>
<p>One of the most uplifting things about this story, for me, is that women <em>do</em> help and promote other women. Not all women, all the time, sure. But lets not accept the toxic cliché that we are all out for ourselves. We aren&#8217;t, and we never were.</p>
<p><em>Next month I’ll talk about some radical women writers who quickly followed through the doors opened by Tiptree, Le Guin, and Cherryh.<br />
</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/who-was-cele-goldsmith/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Location, Location, Location</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/location-location-location/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/location-location-location/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth McCabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast Anytime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;For small creatures such as we the vastness is bearable only through love.&#8221; &#8212; Carl&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>&#8220;For small creatures such as we the vastness is bearable only through love.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Carl Sagan</p>
<figure id="attachment_11551" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-11551" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Stanford_torus.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-11551 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Stanford_torus-300x234.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="234" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-11551" class="wp-caption-text">1970&#8217;s Torii exterior rendering courtesy of NASA Ames Research Center</figcaption></figure>
<p>Last month I started writing about<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/breakfast-anywhere/"> planning a realistic space colony</a> as a setting for a story. I still find myself obsessed with this inquiry instead of getting down to making the story. Procrastinate much? <em>Moi</em>?</p>
<p>In that post I mentioned that Mars and Earth’s moon are generally considered to be the front-runners for planetary colonies, although the moons of other planets in our system and the main asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter orbits have their share of both cheerleaders and fictional depictions.</p>
<p><strong>Tossed in space</strong></p>
<p>Some space aficionados don’t want to put a colony on a planetary body at all. They prefer the idea of a free-standing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Space_habitat">space habitat</a> – in crude terms, a giant version of the International Space Station. For example, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lagrange_point_colonization">LaGrange Points</a>, five equilibrium points in the Earth-Moon and Sun-Earth orbits, have been researched as possible space habitat locations.</p>
<figure id="attachment_11557" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-11557" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Torus_Interior_AC75-2621_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image wp-image-11557 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Torus_Interior_AC75-2621_1920-300x237.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="237" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-11557" class="wp-caption-text">1970&#8217;s Torii interior rendering courtesy of NASA Ames Research Center</figcaption></figure>
<p>A surprising number of people and institutions have already designed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stanford_torus">torii</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/O%27Neill_cylinder">cylinders</a>, and other forms for such a habitat.</p>
<p>The advantages of this approach include Earth proximity and lack of a gravity well to enhance trade and travel; potential for resource utilization from other bodies such as Mars and the asteroids; and access to abundant solar energy.</p>
<p>The solution shares many of the challenges of creating a colony on a planetary body, such as protection from radiation, the need for an artificial atmosphere, and the creation of a sustainable food system. However, like all options, the habitat has its own downsides.</p>
<p>For example, a body like Mars would supply some gravity, while a free-standing colony would need to create all its own. Is there a benefit to having zero-g conditions available, such as for sports? It&#8217;s hard to see why that would beat the low-g conditions of small planetary bodies. But it&#8217;s another fun thought for writing a story.</p>
<p>I’ve also been musing about whether or not having a solid body beneath one’s feet would be comforting, no matter how alien that body might be.</p>
<p><strong>Water, water anywhere?</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/water-iss.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11556 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/water-iss-300x140.jpg" alt="" width="285" height="133" /></a>One of the prime practical considerations for colony building is water. It would be helpful to have some naturally occurring H2O accessible, even if our colonists have a sophisticated recycling system. Astronauts on the<span class="ILfuVd NA6bn"> ISS extract every possible drop from human breath, sweat and urine, and re-use shower water.  </span></p>
<p>So of course, scientists get excited about indications of potential water ice on other bodies (as opposed to other kinds of ice, e.g. the frozen methane dunes of Pluto). Water ice could theoretically be extracted and melted, not only as drinking water for explorers and colonists, but also as a component in the manufacture of rocket fuel.</p>
<p>Recent re-analyses of hydrogen signatures on Mars has indicated the possible existence of <a href="https://newatlas.com/mars-water-equator-nasa/51565/">equatorial water ice</a> deposits. While this is not the first time water has been detected on Mars, these new analyses give scientists hope that water might be present at much lower latitudes than was previously thought.</p>
<figure id="attachment_11554" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-11554" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Diviner-north-pole-map.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image wp-image-11554 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Diviner-north-pole-map-300x214.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="214" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-11554" class="wp-caption-text">Image of moon&#8217;s polar region courtesy of Sky &amp; Telescope</figcaption></figure>
<p>And just this past summer, a report in the <em>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</em> claimed a clear <a href="https://www.express.co.uk/news/science/1006997/nasa-news-moon-water-discovery-space-travel-moon-mars">confirmation of the presence of water ice</a> in the moon’s polar regions.</p>
<p>There appears to be widespread acceptance of this proof; however, I recently read about a top expert in the field who disagrees. At some point in the future, perhaps a lunar mission will acquire first-hand data. Until then, we get to enjoy a little poetic license about water in space.</p>
<p>Sometimes it seems insensitive to be wondering about water on distant celestial bodies when an adequate amount of drinking water is still out of reach for many on our own planet.</p>
<p><strong>Why travel?</strong></p>
<p>Of course, being obsessed with the <em>where</em> of this story doesn’t mean I can avoid those other pesky W’s &#8212; who, what, when, and why.</p>
<p>In a novel, the author can slowly develop a rich scenario for the <em>why</em>. In a short story, it has to be quick and immediately relevant.</p>
<p>The obvious answer is that we are well on our way to using up the planet we have. I’ve also read some great stories that feature a push out there catalyzed by political conflict. Also not hard to imagine. It might even be that indomitable human spirit, seeking knowledge.</p>
<p>For this story, I’m feeling a pull toward less Buck Rogers, more every-day life; after all, that’s why I’m looking for near-Earth locations rather than some fantastic orb in Alpha Centauri. (My inspiration is probably an old fascination with the dark, rather grubby ship <em>Nostromo</em> in the 1979 classic <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alien_(film)">Alien.</a></em> So much more engaging, for me, than gleaming silver.)<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Nostromo.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11563 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Nostromo-300x128.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="128" /></a></p>
<p>So I think my colonists will come from an Earth where someone has simply figured out how to make a lot of money in space. Cynical? <em>Moi</em>?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/location-location-location/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breakfast Anywhere</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/breakfast-anywhere/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Beth McCabe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast Anytime]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11272</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s difficult enough to choose a setting for a realistic story. The place you grew&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/solar-system.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11276" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/solar-system-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="407" height="305" /></a></p>
<p>It’s difficult enough to choose a setting for a realistic story. The place you grew up? Went to college? Vacationed? The first home you chose as an adult?</p>
<p>When you’re writing fantasy you can make your world whatever and wherever you want it to be, but then you need to color in the outlines and make it feel real.</p>
<p>Right now I’m grappling with a third type of setting challenge: I’ve got a space colony tugging at my mind and I have to figure out where in the universe to put it.</p>
<p><strong>There’s a reason they call it science…</strong></p>
<p>Although it’s a time-honored solution to invent an earth-like planet and assume we can get there, I’m thinking about locales to which we can conceivably travel without worm holes and warp drives. And that&#8217;s going to take a little work.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/spaceship.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11277 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/spaceship-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>Unlike creating a fantasy world, I can’t simply make up a climate for Mars or the density of bodies in the asteroid belt. And when it comes to describing the colony and how my characters got there, I need to try to project, on a very basic level, how current technology might develop in a century or more.</p>
<p>In hindsight I wish I’d chosen STEM courses as college electives rather than <em>Introduction to Eastern Philosophy</em>. (Young writers, take note. Or not. I didn’t listen either.) Luckily I’m a good researcher, and I love that part of writing. And there are a lot of highly accessible books written for non-technical people by extremely patient scientists. And an internet.</p>
<p><strong>…but also a reason they call it fiction</strong></p>
<p>Science alone does not good sci-fi make.</p>
<p>In my quasi-humble opinion, for example, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Andy-Weir/e/B00G0WYW92/ref=dp_byline_cont_ebooks_1">Andy Weir</a>, author of the very popular <em>The Martian</em> and <em>Artemis,</em> gets so caught up in the technical details of his books that he totally misses the importance of things like plot and character.</p>
<p>I figure I need to have my background facts straight, but I don’t need to pretend I’m an astrophysicist (not that that would work). People want a story, first and foremost.</p>
<p>That said, here are some of the things I’m thinking about to present my space colony in a realistic light.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/mars-colony.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11273 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/mars-colony.jpg" alt="" width="284" height="177" /></a>Should I stay close to home?<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Thanks to space exploration, we already know quite a bit about how a colony in the closer reaches of our solar system would need to function.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colonization_of_Mars">Mars</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colonization_of_the_Moon">Earth&#8217;s moon</a> are considered by many experts to be the best candidates for a colony, given their proximity to Earth. Also, although they are barren, without our friendly protective atmosphere, they are not as inhospitable as some of our other neighbors, such as Venus and Saturn. (The jury is out on Mercury.)</p>
<p>More on humanity’s favorite extraterrestrial addresses in a future installment.</p>
<p><strong>Let’s talk asteroids</strong></p>
<p>Scientists—and authors&#8211;have also been intrigued by the potential of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asteroid_belt">main asteroid belt</a>, which occupies an area lying roughly between the orbits of Mars and Jupiter.</p>
<p>Asteroids are irregularly shaped bits of rock thought to be the crumbs left by the dawn of the solar system. The largest known asteroid in the main belt, Ceres, is big enough to be classified as a dwarf planet and regularly shows up in literature and legend. Eros also gets its share of attention as one of the largest near-Earth asteroids.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/asteroids.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11274" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/asteroids-300x129.png" alt="" width="335" height="144" /></a>The first thing people ask about settling on an asteroid is whether or not the rock you choose will be pelted by other asteroids and debris.</p>
<p>Forget those scenes where space pilots dodge in and out of hurtling rocks; asteroids in this belt are not nearly as dense as movies like <em>The Empire Strikes Back</em> would have us believe. While impact is possible, it&#8217;s not, according to my sources, a show-stopper. It&#8217;s just one more thing my colonists will have to worry about if I put them on an asteroid.</p>
<p><strong>Miners in the sky</strong></p>
<p>Asteroids possess water and minerals, including precious metals such as nickel, iron, and titanium. This suggests that they would be of great value to future colonists, whether we settle on them or just mine them.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/mudd.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11275" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/mudd.jpg" alt="" width="204" height="166" /></a>Original <em>Star Trek</em> and various novels have given us a meme of the rugged <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/startrek/comments/4cpk46/mining_by_manual_labor_in_star_trek/">space miner</a>. He (I haven’t yet seen it be a she) often looks suspiciously like a denizen of earth&#8217;s gold rush in a space suit. <em>Image courtesy of startrek.com.</em></p>
<p>Just as with the Moon or Mars, settling the asteroids would present plenty of challenges. Staging a story in space brings up questions of transportation of people and supplies, energy supply, food source, protection from radiation, and a ton more issues, before we even face the human side of the equation. While there&#8217;s no need to go on ad nauseum about these details, they form an important backdrop to the story.</p>
<p>Luckily, as writers we get a lot of creative license. After all, sci-fi authors managed to reach for the stars long before the launch of the <a href="http://hubblesite.org/">Hubble Telescope</a> or the first <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exploration_of_Mars">Mars probe</a>. But I hope <a href="https://www.thenewatlantis.com/publications/jules-verne-father-of-science-fiction">Jules Verne</a> would agree that it never hurts to root our visions in the facts we have available.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
