<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 032 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-032/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:39:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 032 author interview: T. D. Walker and &#8220;All the Songs the Little Birds Sing&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-032-author-interview-t-d-walker-and-all-the-songs-the-little-birds-sing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 12:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 032]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Society. A woman&#8217;s place. A woman&#8217;s fight. We had the opportunity to interview T.D. Walker&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Society. A woman&#8217;s place. A woman&#8217;s fight. We had the opportunity to interview <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/t-d-walker/">T.D. Walker</a> about her short story in <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-032/">Issue 032</a> titled &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/all-the-songs-the-little-birds-sing/"><em>All the Songs the Little Birds Sing</em></a>.&#8221; Please: go enjoy, then come back here and read what she has to say about women, society, and writing.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Where did the idea for this story come from? Was there something in particular that inspired it or parts of it? </strong> </em></p>
<div><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sven-scheuermeier-143704.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9375 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sven-scheuermeier-143704-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>T.D.: The original ideas for this story and a companion novella came from a couple sources. First I was thinking about the restrictions our state legislature has put on reproductive rights in recent years here in Texas. And second was a long ride in a tow truck. My car had broken down in bad weather, traffic had stalled, and the driver told me a few stories about jobs that had unnerved him. The latter made me think about how we&#8217;re affected by our work, how that shapes who we are, even if none of his stories have anything to do with Alice and her narratives.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><em>LSQ: </em> There seems to be an unspoken commentary on female gender roles &#8212; the work done by Alice, her coveralls, the dresses from Dani and Alice&#8217;s consideration of them, her fear of losing Desmond &#8212; can you speak to this?</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>T.D.: Alice keeps thinking about the idea of the middle ground. She&#8217;s not as feminine as Dani and the women who take more traditional women&#8217;s roles in this society are, or at least present themselves to be. She can&#8217;t be and keep her career. She&#8217;s not entirely comfortable in the masculine presentation of herself, either. Some of the backlash against progressive ideas about gender seems to take the form of reducing gender down to one set of possibilities. I&#8217;ve thought about how this restrictiveness would manifest itself, and how it would affect the lives of women who do want to live in the middle ground.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The fact that Alice so strongly identifies herself as a runner, and yet she mentions a history of being a starver . . . What does this say about how she views her own body? What does being a runner really mean to her? </strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>T.D.: In the society of the story, the government has restricted access to family planning technologies and information. (Which goes back to my fears about state and national <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ari-he-317209.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9376 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ari-he-317209-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>politics.) Since extreme exercise and extreme dieting are ways in which women can stop their menstrual cycles, and motherhood&#8211;especially single motherhood&#8211;would force Alice out of her education and then her career, she&#8217;s tried both. Running, for Alice, is a way of maintaining her life. But she&#8217;s also trying to run away, to escape from social restrictions.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What is the most important thing you&#8217;d like readers to get from this story?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>T.D.: Alice decides to fight. She decides to help Petra fight. While the story is dark&#8211;it has to be, given the subject matter&#8211;I hope readers are reminded to fight whatever injustices they encounter.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging part of this story to write?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>T.D.: The sections in which Genesis plays a role were emotionally hardest to write. What happens if that much basic science is stripped from the educational curriculum? As a parent, I fear what may happen to our public school system here and what has already happened. I do worry about how to best equip my children with knowledge, critical thinking skills, and the fortitude to challenge what assumptions and conclusions must be challenged.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: I love how each section starts with a brief description of a bird, with the time stamp as the day progresses, as well as the commentary at the start about how the birds&#8217; habits are attenuated due to the unnatural lighting. Can you comment on significance of the birds in this story?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/samuel-zeller-34761.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9377 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/samuel-zeller-34761-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a>T.D.: The lights allow the government and corporations to watch the citizens quite closely. In a sense, Alice feels like the small birds flying into windows: she&#8217;s trying to escape into a space that isn&#8217;t there. And to me, birds are details that most people don&#8217;t pay attention to&#8211;perhaps because I grew up in a more rural suburb, I&#8217;m used to seeing them and distinguishing them. We have great flocks of grackles here, and I&#8217;ve heard so many times people exclaiming: &#8220;Look at all those ravens!&#8221; The same is true for politics. If we don&#8217;t pay attention to the details in what legislation our elected officials propose, we&#8217;re likely to make those kinds of mistakes.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What are you reading currently? Does what you read influence whatever you are writing at the time? Who are some authors that inspire you?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div>T.D.: Recently, I read<i> Cosmovore</i>, by Kristi Carter, which I quite enjoyed. I&#8217;m also reading <i>Sisters of Tomorrow</i>, which is a wonderful reminder of the history of our field.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Perhaps one of the benefits of reaching midlife is that I find I&#8217;m less influenced by others&#8217; voices as I once was. My voice and my subjects are solidified just enough to be mine, but not too much so that I&#8217;ve stopped trying to improve my writing. Years ago, I studied early 20th century British and American poetry, so every once in a while, I&#8217;ll step back and wonder if a line is a little too H.D., not enough mine. Reading Atwood and LeGuin a few years ago brought me to science fiction, and as I read more widely, I find many more voices if not influential then inspiring in how they challenge me.</div>
<div class="yj6qo ajU">
<div id=":y6" class="ajR" tabindex="0" role="button" data-tooltip="Show trimmed content" aria-label="Show trimmed content"><img decoding="async" class="ajT" src="https://ssl.gstatic.com/ui/v1/icons/mail/images/cleardot.gif" /></div>
</div>
</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have any other projects you&#8217;re working on at the moment and can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>T.D.: I just submitted my first full-length poetry manuscript to a number of presses. Ordering the poems to make a coherent whole challenged my ideas about what narratives come from the poems themselves as well as the stories that come from their juxtaposition. And in January, after I finish up another project, I&#8217;m revising a novella that expands on Alice&#8217;s decision to stay and work against these social restrictions.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 032 interview: Katherine Inskip and &#8220;In this Life and the Next&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-032-interview-katherine-inskip-and-in-this-life-and-the-next/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 12:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 032]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You&#8217;re still enjoying Issue 032, right? Steady yourselves, dear readers, because we have another fabulous&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Dec032.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9285 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Dec032-193x300.jpg" alt="" width="193" height="300" /></a>You&#8217;re still enjoying <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-032/">Issue 032</a>, right? Steady yourselves, dear readers, because we have another fabulous author interview for your reading pleasure. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/katherine-inskip/">Katherine Inskip</a>, author of &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/in-this-life-and-the-next/">In this Life and the Next</a>,&#8221; answered our burning questions about her story, her writing, and her reading. Do go <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/in-this-life-and-the-next/">read it first</a>, then come back and see what Katherine has to say.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Where did the idea for this story come from? Medical implants, efforts to prevent having to say goodbye to loved ones (for a price) . . . were there current headlines that inspired this?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Katherine: Uploading someone’s consciousness isn’t a new idea, but what does it mean to quantify someone’s personality, or self? There’s a lot that’s still unsaid about how little we understand each other, even when we’re close family, lovers, or childhood friends. Would a technically-assisted replication or import of someone’s personality change any of that? And as soon as I’d tied that thought in with the purpose of uploaded consciousness &#8212; immortality, or at least a lengthening of life &#8212; it was impossible to ignore the way we seek genetic immortality through our offspring. (And, of course, how to abuse such technology for a different type of immortality.)</p>
<p dir="ltr">The relationships between parents and children are fraught with contradiction. You each have some level of responsibility to shape that young life well, whether as a parent or as the individual in question yourself, but also to let go of your own expectations, and those that others set for you, that you no longer want to meet. Becka’s parents will move heaven and earth for their child, but despite the intimacy of hosting her mind and thoughts, do they really have a clue who their daughter actually is?</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: </em> There&#8217;s an undercurrent hinted at in the story regarding the &#8220;soul&#8221; versus the more clinical &#8220;bundle of neurons&#8221; that make a person a person. Can you comment on this?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Katherine: There’s another story I never quite wrote about interstellar travel, uploaded <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/jesse-orrico-60373.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9286 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/jesse-orrico-60373-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a>consciousness, and the human soul &#8212; if there is such a thing &#8212; and what a soul might need in order to maintain a connection with a mind. Is there something quintessentially <em>us</em>, that fades away if we turn it off for too long? That’s kind of at the root of this for me. But in this story, there’s plenty of scope for a very different view. If mind is all there is to being human, and you can store a mind within a technical MacGuffin, there are still plenty of plausible social reasons for sticking it inside another human being while the original body gets fixed. What’s the legal status of a displaced mind? What kind of rules and ethical constraints might be put in place to prevent digital duplication? Or maybe the tech just isn’t good enough to sustain a mind without the biochemistry of a compatible organic vehicle to support it. I’ve dealt with chronic depression most of my life, so I’m pretty attuned to the vagaries of my own brain chemistry and its impact on how I think and feel. Is it a soul what makes me <em>me</em>, or the messy symbiosis of memory, chemistry, and neural architecture? You can only find out by breaking it.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The complexity of interpersonal and strained family relationships weaved into this story give it a painful human connection that the reader can relate to. Did this seem like a natural place to take this story, or was it difficult to figure out the human interest side of things?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Katherine: Very natural. I love big concepts, I love flashy, complex world building, but the story doesn’t happen for me without human emotions and desires. I had several miscarriages before my sons were born and lost my father to MND [motor neuron disease] a year and a half ago. That gave me a certain amount of experience of letting go when you really don’t want to, but also of finding comfort in seeing how each generation reflects the next in some way.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: What are you reading currently? Does what you read influence whatever you are writing at the time? Who are some authors that inspire you?  </strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Katherine: I’m currently deep in the <a href="http://www.castofwonders.org/">Cast of Wonders</a> slush pile! I’ve been part of the team for nearly three years, and it’s been a massive influence on how and what I write. Seeing what works and what doesn’t, different ways of telling a story, and the importance <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/robert-wiedemann-195099.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9287 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/robert-wiedemann-195099-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>of believing in it &#8212; and yourself &#8212; enough to finish it off and send it out has made such a difference to me. It’s given my resilience a real boost, knowing first-hand how many excellent stories don’t quite make it through.</p>
<p dir="ltr">My recent novel-length reads have been Delilah Dawson’s <em>Phasma</em> (great fun, and a good way of feeding my excitement for <em>The Last Jedi</em>), Anna Smith Spark’s <em>Court of Broken Knives</em> (beautiful prose and compelling, infuriating characters), Alex Acks’ <em>Hunger Makes the Wolf</em> (biker witches in spaaaaace!), and I’m mid-way through re-reads of Yoon Ha Lee’s <em>Ninefox Gambit</em> and my favorite childhood nostalgia read, <em>Watership Down</em>. I’m reading the latter with my nine year old son, and it’s really interesting to take the tale at his pace and see what he does or doesn’t pick up on.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Authors that inspire me? Too many to count! Emma Newman and Yoon Ha Lee are top of my ‘pre-order last year’ list, but I love the short fiction of writers like Rachael K. Jones, Amanda Helms, Natalia Theodoridou, and Aimee Ogden.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: </em> What do you think are the biggest challenges for female-identifying authors in the speculative fiction genre right now? Where would you like to see this genre go in the future?</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Katherine: I think the pressures and complexities of the world today aren’t helping anyone, and there’s plenty of challenge there just in getting from one day to the next. Within the genre? Confidence, probably. But crack that, and there’s nothing we can’t do!  I think we could still do better in terms of visibility for female-identifying authors, and also for people from other less traditionally dominant demographics, but it’s the breadth of character voices and experiences that matters most to me.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have any other projects you&#8217;re working on at the moment and can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Katherine: Sure! I’m in the middle of revisions/second drafts of a number of short stories with the usual dozen or so incomplete works in progress fighting them for my attention. There’s the YA inner-city witch story, the one with the evil unicorn, the dysfunctional mother/daughter quantum mechanics story, and a rather nasty take on sorcerers fighting for their academic tenure . . . I’m also part-way through a novel (who isn’t?) featuring a sentient spaceship of questionable status who thinks she’s on her first tour of the galaxy, but instead ends up at the nexus of four separate but inter-related conspiracies, some dark family history, and a race against time to save a doomed planet. I’m having a whale of a time with it!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 032 author interview: Hannah Sternberg and &#8220;Goners&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-032-author-interview-hannah-sternberg-and-goners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 12:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 032]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Got a hankering for a time-bending tale set on the beach? Author Hannah Sternberg&#8216;s tale&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Got a hankering for a time-bending tale set on the beach? Author <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/hannah-sternberg/">Hannah Sternberg</a>&#8216;s tale &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/goners/">Goners</a>&#8221; in <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em>&#8216;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-032/">Issue 032</a> is right up your alley. Go read her story, then come back here for our interview with Hannah.</div>
<div></div>
<div><span class="im"><b><em>LSQ: Where did the idea for this story come from? Do you live near the ocean in North Carolina, or have visited? </em></b></span></div>
<div><span class="im"><br />
</span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/alex-talmon-347.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9193 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/alex-talmon-347-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Hannah: I have an aunt who lives in the <a href="https://www.outerbanks.org/">Outer Banks</a> and I&#8217;ve visited her a few times. My family also goes to the Delaware beaches a couple times a year, and there are a lot of similarities&#8211;blustery, old-fashioned Atlantic shore towns with busted-up signs and locals fishing for dogfish right off the beach. We usually go to the beach in early spring or fall, so my mental image of the beach is a sweatshirt day where the sky is gray and the ocean is gray-green, except where it washes up over the sand and looks like faded teal over tan. I do a lot of daydreaming there, so I guess a lot of my stories make their way to the beach, too.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><b><em>LSQ: In a way, I was relieved that James seems to accept his fate at the end. What are your thoughts on this?</em></b></p>
</div>
<div>Hannah: I went back and forth on the ending. I wrote the story a few different ways, and it changed a lot in each draft. Earlier versions end with a heroic escape attempt, though I never quite defined whether they made it out or not. But I think James is the kind of guy who drifts on the wind. He has a rebellious streak, but ultimately he goes where the current pushes him&#8211;that&#8217;s how he wound up there in the first place. I don&#8217;t really want to interpret his choice for the reader too much, though. I think different readers can have different pictures of his emotional state in that moment&#8211;and I want them to; I want them to experience his moment in the way that they empathize with most. For example, I didn&#8217;t necessarily feel relief at the idea of his accepting what has happened&#8211;but that doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s wrong that you (one reader) did. I want you to experience that moment your own way, and think about why it makes <i>you </i>feel like that.</div>
<div><b><br />
<span class="im"><em>LSQ: </em></span> <em>What is the most important thing you&#8217;d like readers to get from this story?</em></b></div>
<div>Hannah: Ten minutes of escape from the news and a good shiver. If it makes you think about friendship and kinship and the loss of childhood and the inexorability of time, that&#8217;s cool. But mostly I&#8217;d like it to give you a mild case of the willies.</div>
<div></div>
<div><b><span class="im"><em>LSQ: </em></span><em> Sometimes, stories that incorporate time changes can be hard to write and for the reader to keep straight, although your piece does it well. What was the most challenging part of writing this story? Was it hard to keep the details straight and unravel the time mystery in such a way that you don&#8217;t lose the readers?</em></b></div>
<div></div>
<div>Hannah: Hopefully I can describe it in a way that doesn&#8217;t give away too much of the story! It was pretty challenging to write the shifts in time in this story because I wanted to show them through events, instead of just explaining it through the narration&#8211;especially because I wanted the reader to feel in the present moment with James and he, of course, has no <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/erwan-hesry-369799.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9194 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/erwan-hesry-369799-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>idea what the hell is going on. In addition to unique timeline problems created by the supernatural setting, there are the flashbacks to James&#8217; and Jimmy&#8217;s childhoods. Those were a lot easier to handle because if you write long enough you&#8217;re going to write flashbacks and know how to fold them in and make things clear with transitions and verb tenses. To describe the supernatural time that passes and re-passes in the story, I had to do a lot of rewriting. I didn&#8217;t really have to timeline it because the story isn&#8217;t that long and the looping events aren&#8217;t complex, so it was more a matter of figuring out how to <i>demonstrate, </i>through an action that could occur in a relatively short period of time, the supernatural effect on time this place has.</div>
<div></div>
<div><b><span class="im"><em>LSQ: </em></span> <em>Do you have any advice for new writers?</em></b></div>
<div></div>
<div>Hannah: Keep writing. I teach a class in D.C. called <a href="https://www.dclibrary.org/node/48523">Writing Games</a> and one of the biggest points we go over is how, with so many other arts, it seems obvious that practice makes perfect; you wouldn&#8217;t pick up a guitar for the first time in your life and expect to be stellar at it. But sometimes people think that if they&#8217;re meant to be a great writer, they&#8217;ll be great from the start and if they&#8217;re not great immediately, it means they weren&#8217;t meant for writing, and they give up. Practice writing like you&#8217;d practice guitar. When I play music, I pick songs I really, really like&#8211;even if they&#8217;re hard&#8211;and I practice on those because I know they&#8217;ll challenge me to learn a new technique and build my skills. But for whatever reason, a lot of writers feel like they have to hold on to their &#8220;good ideas&#8221; until they&#8217;re really good&#8211;they don&#8217;t want to waste them&#8211;so they spend their time practicing on stories and ideas that fall ever so slightly short of what they want to be writing. That&#8217;s like only practicing songs you don&#8217;t like. You&#8217;ll get discouraged and bored and all your hard work still won&#8217;t culminate in playing the song that made you want to pick up guitar in the first place. So start with the song you want to know, even if it&#8217;s really hard. Start with the story you&#8217;re afraid of ruining. Write the story you actually really want to write, and just keep practicing at it. You will get better. Will you become great? I don&#8217;t know. Ditch the idea of greatness. Just have fun and see where it goes, and make something <i>you </i>can feel proud of.</div>
<div></div>
<div><b><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/uros-jovicic-322314.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9195 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/uros-jovicic-322314-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a><span class="im"><em>LSQ: </em></span><em> What are you reading currently? Does what you read influence whatever you are writing at the time? Who are some authors that inspire you?</em></b></div>
<div></div>
<div>Hannah: I&#8217;m usually reading five or six books at a time, settling on one once it grabs my attention fully enough to pull me to the end, and otherwise just chipping away at them in rotation. A sample of the ones highest on my bedside table stack are <i>Lost Girls: An Unsolved American Mystery </i>by Robert Kolker, <i>The Lottery and Other Stories </i>by Shirley Jackson, and <i>World War Z </i>by Max Brooks (yeah, I know I&#8217;m late to the party). <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-shirley-jackson-2/">Shirley Jackson</a> is a big inspiration due to her way of writing around the ephemeral moments that define her women&#8217;s lives. There&#8217;s always something seething just under the surface&#8211;something futile and sad and maybe a generation later, maybe with some air, powerful. I also love Ursula Le Guin, especially <a href="https://www.tor.com/2009/06/08/the-poetry-of-anthropology-ursula-le-guins-the-left-hand-of-darkness/"><i>The Left Hand of Darkness</i></a>. Lately I&#8217;ve been into a mid-century suspense/horror author John Wyndham, who wrote surprisingly (and possibly, sometimes, unintentionally) feminist and extremely realistic disaster stories. I love ghost stories and eerie, weird fiction.</div>
<div><span class="im"><span class="im"><br />
<b><em>LSQ: Do you have any other projects you&#8217;re working on at the moment and can you tell us a bit about them?</em></b></span></span>Hannah: I&#8217;ve taken a short break from working on books to focus on music for a little while. I&#8217;m the bassist and co-songwriter for Daamsel, a gritty, emotional rock group, and we&#8217;re hoping to record our first demo early in 2018; we&#8217;ve been writing very rapidly and playing as many shows as we can in the D.C. area. In the meantime, I&#8217;ve been working my way through a stack of short stories I&#8217;ve written over the years and dramatically revising them&#8211;that&#8217;s how &#8220;Goners&#8221; landed at <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em>. I&#8217;m hoping to have a few more out on submission soon.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 032 author interview: Agrippina Domanski and &#8220;Everybody and His Mother&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-032-author-interview-agrippina-domanski-and-everybody-and-his-mother/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 032]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The current issue of Luna Station Quarterly is Issue 032, available online and in print.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/alessandro-di-credico-202750.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9104 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/alessandro-di-credico-202750-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>The current issue of <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> is <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-032/">Issue 032</a>, available online and in print. Within are nine stories ranging from speculative fiction to fantasy. Among them, you&#8217;ll find an eerily beautiful piece by Agrippina Domanski, titled &#8220;Everybody and His Mother.&#8221; We were lucky enough to chat with Agrippina about her work. Check out her interview below, but read her <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/everybody-and-his-mother/">story</a>, first.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Where did the idea for this story come from? Do you have an interest in the occult?  </strong></em></p>
<p>Agrippina: It&#8217;s usually difficult for me to answer those types of questions honestly, as my ideas tend to come from all over the place &#8212; my dreams, newspaper articles, lecture notes, and so on. For this one, however, there was definitely a source. I was reading <a href="https://www.psychforums.com/forum.html">psychforums</a> online (until recently it used to be an open blog where people could discuss serious psychological issues and what might be termed &#8220;deviant behavior&#8221;). Around 2015 the website got blocked by the government, so now you can only read archived posts. There was one topic thread about the experiences of people who think they have come into contact with the supernatural after a relative&#8217;s death. The story about an old lady coming back looking for her hair was one of the cases cited by one of the contributors online. However, it was a very brief comment, literally one sentence, and as it had captivated my attention I eventually put my own spin on it. The second plot line of the story, about one niece being obviously more favored than another, is a situation I have observed with my best friend, and her relatives on her mother&#8217;s side.</p>
<p>I do indeed have a huge interest in occult, which has only been growing over the years. In fact, I had originally chosen a theology degree in hope that this interest would thrive in such an academic environment. I can&#8217;t say this has been the case necessarily, but my degree has provided me with resources and places to go to access the information I need, especially on the occult and apocryphal (non-canonical) literature around the Bible &#8212; for which I&#8217;m immensely grateful.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The relationships between all the characters (both alive and dead) are tragic, in a way, but very realistic and identifiable. What was it like to write these types of characters?</strong> </em></p>
<p>Agrippina: I started writing at a very young age and I have always been certain this would be my main occupation in life, so one of my main concerns and worries was that since I was so young I did not have enough life experience and would not be able to create realistic characters or situations. The irony is that at some point (probably three years ago, when I was seventeen) I stopped trying to &#8220;copy&#8221; reality and just started working wholly from my imagination, while at the same time making use of the dialects and contextual peculiarities surrounding me. In a way I think this is the way to go when you create people and situations from scratch. I very rarely have prototypes for my characters, but then I think every writer brings in bits and pieces of his reality without noticing.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/ana-pavlyuk-420826.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9105 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/ana-pavlyuk-420826-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>This story is in fact my second attempt at the subject of old age and what may be called its dark side. I have always been interested in the unspoken social rules which prevent negative things being said about old people, and have witnessed cases among the people I know where that inability to articulate exasperation or other negative feelings ultimately results in more resentment. Also I believe every family has &#8220;favorites&#8221; and that it&#8217;s inevitable, no matter how people try to hide it. I recently read some scientific article which explained why being a favorite younger child has evolutionary advantages &#8212; it seemed to be arguing along the same lines if I understood it correctly.</p>
<p>The central conflict in this story for me is that the mother chooses to be guided by her obligations, while the boys, especially Jack, would see that as a betrayal of the self and an act of weakness. What particularly fascinated me in the source material was the irony of the two generations in the same family ending up on different sides of the barricade in the &#8220;favorites&#8221; dispute. I feel Jemima would never be able to understand Jack and his motives because she had only been on the side of the &#8220;unloved child.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The ending almost feels cathartic. Is this meant to be a positive or negative realization for Jemima? </strong></em></p>
<p>Agrippina: I would agree with the definition &#8220;cathartic&#8221;; in my reading of witchcraft in this particular story it&#8217;s [being a witch] almost a genetic condition passed on exclusively to women, rather like hemophilia (of course this has been addressed in Stephen King&#8217;s <em>Carrie</em> and elsewhere). Therefore the realization that she&#8217;s a witch is a very negative experience for Jemima, because that means she would grow to be a lot like Diane. But at the same time it is an inevitable thing, something to accept like any genetic condition to some extent. I think there is a possibility that she will learn to use witchcraft for her enjoyment and benefit, and that would soften the blow when her sons eventually leave her. Also by recognizing her &#8220;gift&#8221; she would allow herself to finally concentrate more on herself (which you can hardly ever do as a single mother) and to get over the betrayal of her children in a less painful way.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What is the most important thing you&#8217;d like readers to get from this story? </strong></em></p>
<p>Agrippina: At first I was certain I couldn&#8217;t answer that at all. This answer still feels arbitrary in a way. But I suppose it&#8217;s the sense that relationships and love never follow rational laws. You can&#8217;t make anyone love you, you can&#8217;t make yourself love anyone you don&#8217;t feel like loving &#8212; and it&#8217;s best to accept that as early on as you can. But then I think that only applies in the context of this particular story.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging part of writing this story?</strong></em></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/tamara-menzi-58748.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9106 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/tamara-menzi-58748-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Agrippina: I work a lot on improving my writing &#8212; taking courses and working roughly four hours per day as a must. But I still feel I&#8217;m very bad at doing action scenes &#8212; I&#8217;m even considering taking a master class in those or something. So the scene when Diane materializes and goes to get her hair was easily the most challenging thing I&#8217;ve ever written.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What are you reading currently? Does what you read influence whatever you are writing at the time? Who are some authors that inspire you? </strong></em></p>
<p>Agrippina: I just finished reading <em>Moby Dick</em> and now am trying to work my way through university teaching material. Whatever I&#8217;m reading always has an enormous impact on what I&#8217;m writing. The same goes for film &#8212; so much so that when I write drafts of some stories to finish later, I add a mini-bibliography of every book or film that has shaped that idea in my head. I re-watch and re-read them all later to get back into the mood. It&#8217;s a tough job to list the authors who inspire me off the top of my head, but T.S. Eliot would definitely be at the top of the list &#8212; especially &#8220;<a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/47311/the-waste-land">The Waste Land</a>&#8221; &#8212; also Laurence Durrell, John Fowles, D.H. Lawrence, and perhaps Dos Passos.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have any other projects you&#8217;re working on at the moment and can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Agrippina: I have about six stories I&#8217;m doing all at the same time right now, but sometimes they take three months or longer to complete. I have one story I&#8217;m working on actively, which is about musicians and a cult experience of sorts during a rock concert. But I add little bits and pieces to the other five almost every day &#8212; I open the plans and look at them, and slowly let them build up some core strength, as they say in my yoga classes. I have finished some longer things this summer, but I wouldn&#8217;t go as far as calling them novels &#8212; however, at some point when I&#8217;m facing a bit less pressure from university I&#8217;ll be sending them out for publication.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 032 author interview: Cathrin Hagey and &#8220;Baug&#8217;s Hollow&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-032-author-interview-cathrin-hagey-and-baugs-hollow/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 12:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 032]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 032 has so many wonderful stories&#8211;have you checked it out yet? One of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-032/">Issue 032</a> has so many wonderful stories&#8211;have you checked it out yet? One of the great things about <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> (if you will allow us a moment to toot our own horn) is that we get to showcase not only women authors but also a wide variety of stories, from strict science fiction to high fantasy to haunting speculative fiction and everything in between. Case in point: trolls. Cathrin Hagey&#8217;s story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/baugs-hollow/">Baug&#8217;s Hollow</a>&#8221; is a fantasy piece about characters who so frequently are the pariahs&#8211;but not necessarily in this case. Lucky for us (here we go tooting again) we had a chance to talk with Cathrin about her story. Here&#8217;s what she had to say.</p>
<p><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/delfi-de-la-rua-23324.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9049 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/delfi-de-la-rua-23324-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>LSQ: My favorite quote in this story is from Aghi, when she says: &#8220;The human notion that trolls are beasts is a case of the cod calling the eel fishy.&#8221; This story portrays trolls in a much more benevolent light that they are usually cast. Are you sympathetic to trolls? Do you think they get a bad rap in fantasy/folklore?</strong></em></p>
<p>Cathrin: Hmmm. Good question. I hadn’t really thought about it until you asked. From the reading that I’ve done, trolls are either dangerous and crafty or dangerously stupid. The first time I saw a depiction of benevolent trolls, I was watching Disney’s <em>Frozen</em> with my youngest daughter hours after she was diagnosed with Tourette Syndrome. It was a stressful time and the song “Let it Go,” as sappy as this might be, seemed written for us. Perhaps the friendly trolls made a bigger impact than I realized, given the circumstances, carrying over to the creation of “Baug’s Hollow.”</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do you mostly write fantasy or do you explore other genres as well? What draws you in to the fantasy genre?</strong></em></p>
<p>Cathrin: I’ve always loved fantasy but never considered writing it until I discovered the <a href="http://endicottstudio.typepad.com/jomahome/"><em>Journal of Mythic Arts</em></a>, co-edited by Terri Windling and Midori Snyder, about seven years ago. Discovering JOMA was like finding a long lost relative, igniting a spark inside me that eventually led to writing my own fantasy short stories. I also write creative nonfiction and I’m slowly developing what I hope will be a science fiction novel some day.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The &#8220;kindly&#8221; trolls in your story turn the &#8220;evil troll&#8221; fantasy trope on its head in a refreshing way. What do you think is seen too frequently in modern fantasy and are there aspects/concepts/characters you don&#8217;t think are seen enough in this genre? How can modern fantasy authors push the envelope and yet still remain true to the genre?</strong></em></p>
<p>Cathrin: I hope we see greater diversity in human types and become more honest with ourselves about our basest instincts. Fantasy and other subgenres of speculative fiction have a way of opening those sticky doors in our minds and hearts more easily than other types of fiction.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do your unique character names have special meanings (e.g. Baug, Grigg, Aghi)?</strong></em></p>
<p>Cathrin: I have to admit that the only character name in “Baug’s Hollow” with intentional meaning is Henrike, a <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/matt-antonioli-235957.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9050 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/matt-antonioli-235957-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Scandinavian form of Henry, meaning “home ruler.” I thought the nickname Hen would bring out her softness, while Henrike would be her strength. The others were names that seemed to pop into my mind and got confirmed by my heart before the inner editor (inhibitor) cast them off again.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Fish wine, Baug missing at sea &#8212; is there a special connection between trolls and the ocean? (I will forever think of trolls when I use fish oil in cooking now&#8230;)</strong></em></p>
<p>Cathrin: It’s funny that I included the sea in this story, since I live in the heart of the northern plains of Canada and couldn’t be farther from an ocean. What I do have where I live is harsh winters that can go on for six or seven months (July is the only month where I haven’t seen snow). As far as I know, there is no connection between trolls and the sea. Trolls are said to dwell in mountains, forests, and even at the bottom of lakes. Perhaps Baug’s kingdom of trolls followed their own path. They can be contrarian.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have advice for new writers trying to break into the fantasy genre?</strong></em></p>
<p>Cathrin: I started writing late in life and have a long way to go before I can say I’m no longer a new writer. It might never happen. My only advice is time-worn: read frequently, write as often as possible, find a like-minded critique group (online or otherwise) and be willing to accept criticism, submit often, take classes (online or otherwise). But please don’t quit if<br />
you love to write, because you have something unique to say (even if you don’t quite know what it is), and don’t wait for anybody else’s permission to believe in yourself.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What are you reading currently? Does what you read influence whatever you are writing at the time? Who are some authors that inspire you?</strong></em></p>
<p>Cathrin: I just finished <em>More About Boy</em>, Roald Dahl’s second memoir, with Carl Jung’s <em>Memories, Dreams, Reflections</em> in progress. I don’t really think about whether a current read is influencing my writing, but then again, I didn’t realize <em>Frozen</em> influenced my writing until you asked!</p>
<p>The authors who’ve inspired me over the years, in no significant order, are: Charlotte and Emily Brontë, Virginia Woolf, Doris Lessing, Neil Gaiman, Mary Shelley, Ursula K. Le Guin, Vladimir Nabokov, Fyodor Dostoyevsky, Terri Windling, Katherine Langrish, Lucy Maud Montgomery, André Norton, Charlotte Perkins Gilman, George Orwell, and Ray Bradbury.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have other projects you&#8217;re working on at the moment&#8211;or have finished since the original publication of this story in 2015&#8211;and can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Cathrin: I’m currently writing a memoir under the guidance of Canadian author <a href="http://alissayork.com/">Alissa York</a>, through the creative writing program at Humber College, Toronto. I have three first drafts I’m procrastinating over (two fantasy, one science fiction) and one science fiction novel with the gestation rate of a baby elephant, times ten. In addition, I’m very excited that my LSQ column “What’s in a Fairy Tale?” will be published on a monthly basis in 2018.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 032 author interview: E.K. Wagner and &#8220;Running Straight&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-032-author-interview-e-k-wagner-and-running-straight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 032]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9034</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re still in love with Luna Station Quarterly&#8217;s Issue 032, which came out December 1.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re still in love with <em>Luna Station Quarterly&#8217;</em>s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-032/">Issue 032</a>, which came out December 1. It&#8217;s available both digitally and in print, so do check it out when you get a chance. In the meantime, we had the pleasure of talking with E.K. Wagner, author of the sci-fi short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/running-straight/">Running Straight</a>&#8221; that appears in this issue. Here&#8217;s what she had to say about her story, the &#8220;itchin men&#8221;, and her writing.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Where did the idea for this story come from? Did it start as one idea or a gathering of thoughts in pieces, since there are multiple concepts that are dealt with throughout the story (dreams and their meanings; the mother/daughter bond; male/female relationships to name a few). </strong></em></p>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/guille-pozzi-439410.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9035 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/guille-pozzi-439410-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>E.K.: I wrote this story about two years ago, so I don&#8217;t remember the exact inspiration&#8211;but I do know that I was traveling for the holidays and staying with family. Perhaps this helped to inspire this text with its narrative of story-telling and community across generations of women? It seemed important to me to talk about community-specific forms of communication&#8211;ties that bind <em>and</em> exclude.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Given the open ending, is it your intent to leave the reader feeling hopeful for Cinti&#8217;s future? In your mind, what happens to her? Or do you prefer it left unsaid and full of possibility? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<p>E.K.: I would like to think that Cinti makes it to the sea and escapes to a better life, urged on by the advice her mother had embedded in years of stories. That said, the details of her escape and new life are open to the imagination. What is the wider world like? It must be filled with more like the itchin men&#8211;but hopefully also filled with wise women and new companions.</p>
</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The itchin men and the collars&#8230; oh those collars. Was it always this way on this planet? What are the men afraid of?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<p>E.K.: I think the collars and the itchin men are the gradual results of a society too-obsessed with a strict, gender-driven hierarchy. It hasn&#8217;t always been like this. But the dreams of these women have creative power (sometimes the metaphor seems oh-so-thin) and they are a threat to those in charge. The collars are meant to control and limit the dreams&#8211;to limit their generative power.</p>
</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging part of writing this story?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<p>E.K.: I think the most challenging part of the story was staying in the voice and mind of Cinti&#8211;especially between writing sessions. Consequently, I wrote the draft of this story very quickly over a day or two. I was afraid to lose the voice&#8211;naive, stubborn, brave, and inspired by my Appalachian roots.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/ian-dooley-325439.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9036 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/ian-dooley-325439-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a></p>
</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What are you reading currently? Does what you read influence whatever you are writing at the time? Who are some authors that inspire you?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<p>E.K.: I try to read a lot of fantasy and science fiction, including many new novels, so that I&#8217;m aware of the genres&#8217; <i>moods</i>, so to speak. This definitely informs my own fiction. I&#8217;ve recently read books 1 and 2 of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/8/17/16156416/n-k-jemisin-broken-earth-trilogy-the-stone-sky-fantasy-book-review">N. K. Jemisin&#8217;s </a><i>Broken Earth Trilogy, </i>and I loved it. Hoping to read the third soon! Great, strong narrative voice there&#8211;as well as an important engagement with our own current political realities. Right now, I&#8217;m reading <a href="https://www.tor.com/2016/06/15/stealing-the-future-ninefox-gambit-by-yoon-ha-lee/"><i>Ninefox Gambit </i>by Yoon Ha Lee</a>. Fascinating interplay of technology and ideology.</p>
</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Speaking to the writing process in general, can you tell us what your greatest strength and greatest weakness are as a writer? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<p>E.K.: Hm. It feels a bit awkward to speak of my strengths, but I do think I have an ability to capture voice and dialogue that feels real (if I&#8217;m writing well!). I have a tendency&#8211;and I&#8217;m trying to move beyond this&#8211;to overwhelm that dialogue with narration, though. I get caught up in my characters&#8217; thoughts sometimes and forget to move on with their lives.</p>
</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have any other projects you&#8217;re working on at the moment and can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
<p>E.K.: Always working on something! I&#8217;m in the process of expanding a short story into a novel called <i>Ye Are the Children of Prophets. </i>The novel narrates a not-too-distant dystopia, struggling with the rise of child militias in the U.S. and the implementation of AI soldiers. Light, cheery stuff. I almost always have a short story on the back burner as well&#8211;whether it be about golems in ancient Jerusalem or big-rig drivers facing a nuclear winter.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Irene Grazzini</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-irene-grazzini/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 032]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 032 is out now &#8212; go take a peek. We&#8217;re very excited to publish&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Issue 032 is out now &#8212; go take a peek. We&#8217;re very excited to publish the second story in our current issue which is our first translated work for the <em>Quarterly</em>. Written by Irene Grazzini and translated from Italian by Joyce Myerson, the short story &#8220;The Smile&#8221; takes a well-known artwork and twists it into an unforgettable tale. We chatted with Irene about &#8220;The Smile&#8221; and she gave us some extra insight that is our pleasure to share with you today.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/eric-terrade-8615.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="center-image aligncenter wp-image-8861" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/eric-terrade-8615-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="335" height="223" /></a></p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: How did the idea for your story &#8220;The Smile&#8221; come about? Your descriptions of the time period are very rich and detailed. Have you always been interested in the Mona Lisa, or did you research this artwork specifically for this story? Have you seen the Mona Lisa in person at the Louvre? What was it specifically about this piece that inspired this story? </strong></em></p>
<p>Irene: The idea for <i>The Smile</i> came to me while I was doing some house-cleaning. Rummaging through my university books, inside an illustrated anatomy text, I found some pages of old notes and a draft of a story that we had been asked to write for a course I can no longer recall. The theme was: imagine yourself inside a painting. I had told the story of a girl visiting the <a href="http://www.louvre.fr/en">Louvre Museum</a>. She finds herself catapulted inside the picture of the <em>Mona Lisa</em> and then has a witty conversation with her. It was only a sketch, about which I had completely forgotten, little more than a page long, but it was a delightful re-discovery, and so I decided to develop it into something more complete.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/sebastian-yepes-273295.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8862 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/sebastian-yepes-273295-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" /></a>I took advantage of a holiday weekend to go to Paris and the Louvre (I must admit that, in two days, I only managed to see less than half!). In this way I was able to enjoy the painting in person, imprinting on my mind the emotions it aroused. I had studied it in high school in a History of Art course, as well as a large part of the rest of Leonardo da Vinci’s works. This painting has always fascinated me. I live in Tuscany, whose landscape is the background of many of Leonardo’s works (Vinci is a small town about an hour and a half by car from my home). But the figure of <em>Mona Lisa</em>, with her enigmatic smile, has something special.</p>
<p>I did research on the subject, on the work, as well as on the historical period in question. I studied sources on the “real” life of <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/europe/italy/11888685/Who-was-Mona-Lisa-Burial-breakthrough-may-solve-the-identity-mystery-behind-Da-Vinci-masterpiece.html">Lisa Gherardini</a> who would have been an ordinary woman of the Renaissance had Leonardo not immortalized her in the painting. Thus I decided to alter the viewpoint of the original: I wanted the story to be told by the Mona Lisa herself!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Was there any part of this story that was challenging for you to write? </strong></em></p>
<p>Irene: When you set a story in another era, it is difficult to find the right balance between the description of the setting and the fluidity of the narrative. Writers cannot embark on endlessly long descriptive passages, but at the same time, we have to make the reader see and feel the time and place of the characters. It was also hard for me to identify with the point of view, the type of language, and the thoughts of Lisa, a Renaissance woman. I had to use somewhat “archaic” terms and turns of phrase, and the challenge was to make them accessible to a modern reader. And finally, the structure itself of the story is an exercise in style, because it is built upon a series of hints and clues until the final revelation.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ:</em> <em>There&#8217;s a sinister quality in Leonardo da Vinci&#8217;s character in your story. Could you speak to this? </em></strong></p>
<p>Irene: Leonardo da Vinci is a figure that has always fascinated subsequent generations throughout the world, not only his Italian countrymen and women. His irrefutable genius is enveloped in a halo of mystery. We know his works, everything he has produced, but who was Leonardo really? What did he think about when painting? What was his purpose? In <i>The Smile</i> I tried to reinterpret him in more sombre shades, imagining him a disciple of the art of alchemy, which in the Middle Ages and the Renaissance was well-known, so much so that often artists inserted alchemical symbols in their works (just think about the floors of the <a href="https://www.discovertuscany.com/siena/siena-churches/duomo.html">Siena Cathedral</a>!). The alchemists, according to the teachings of Hermes Trismegistus, an almost mythological figure, tried to gain control of nature and matter, dedicating themselves to a form of science, soaked in magic. Among their objectives were immortality and the famous Philosopher’s Stone (recaptured by J.K. Rowling in the Harry Potter saga). <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/tolga-kilinc-183453.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8863 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/tolga-kilinc-183453-300x197.jpg" alt="" width="364" height="239" /></a>My Leonardo, therefore, is a man obsessed with the search for perfection and immortality, a goal which he wants to reach through his art—a result which, from a certain viewpoint, he has succeeded in reaching in reality, inasmuch as he has rendered immortal the memory we all have of Lisa Gherardini.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ:</em> <em>If there is one thing that you&#8217;d like for your readers to get out of this story, what is it?</em></strong></p>
<p>Irene: That which Mona Lisa herself says: <i>O strangers from a world in constant flux, I only ask you this: Live for those who no longer have such fortune. Smile for real, in keeping with your deepest wishes.</i> Smile for real, not because you are obliged to as she was in the painting. And it is indeed that small imperfection that we call humanity that makes our smile perfect, marvelous, and unique.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What authors inspire you and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Irene: I am a voracious and omnivorous reader. In terms of stories, I believe that Isaac Asimov is unparalleled, but I also adore the stories of J.L. Borges (<i>The House of Asterion</i> is a masterpiece). In terms of novels, I have been mostly inspired by YA authors such as Suzanne Collins and Veronica Roth. In terms of world-building and plot structure, I have been inspired by Margaret Weiss and Tracy Hickmann (the Dragonlance and the Death Gate series) and David Gemmell (the Troy series).</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other writing projects? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?  </strong></em></p>
<p>Irene: I have many projects on the go. Most recently I have written and have had translated a new story, in a completely different genre—a fantasy/sci-fi story set in a remote but not improbable future for our planet. My New York agents, as well, are actively seeking a publisher for my alternate history YA novel, of which I cannot disclose the title, but which I hope to see published soon and available to all readers, young and old!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 032 author interview: Emma Grygotis on &#8220;While It&#8217;s Still Beating&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-032-is-live-author-interview-emma-grygotis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 032]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are continually psyched to announce the recent release of Issue 032! Last week you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are continually psyched to announce the recent release of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-032/">Issue 032</a>! Last week you all met our cover artist and this week we have another treat: an interview with our featured story author, Emma Grygotis. Emma talked with us about her masterful piece &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/while-its-still-beating/">While It&#8217;s Still Beating</a>&#8220;. Read on to see what she has to say.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: How did the idea for your story, &#8220;While It&#8217;s Still Beating,&#8221; come about? The insurance company &#8212; made an almost physical presence through the info packet &#8212; feels malevolent. Was there any influence from current politics and the battle over healthcare in U.S.? </strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: Absolutely. My day job is working as a research scientist, developing a technology that I hope will one day be used to design better materials to replace failing tissues and organs. While the possibility that these tools will one day be able to help real, living people is incredibly inspiring, the battles that we are fighting daily in the U.S. just to guarantee a basic level of healthcare access to all people make that dream seem downright impossible. Even when we look at healthcare technologies that have been around for years and are relatively inexpensive (for example, contraception), we as a society can’t seem to come to an agreement about who should have access to them, when, and for what cost. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/chuttersnap-233105.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8842 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/chuttersnap-233105-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>The core idea for the story came when I asked myself, “Under what conditions might engineered replacement organs actually be accessible to the average person?” and the only answer I could come up with was that it would have to be cheaper to replace a heart than allow a person to continue living with a failing one.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Was there any part of this story that was challenging for you to write? </strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: It took me a long time to strike the right balance between providing enough information and context for the reader to figure out what was going on without detracting from the core story – two women just struggling to carve out a life for themselves in a world that is rigged against them.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There&#8217;s a rich and haunting dichotomy in your story&#8211;the &#8220;miracle of medicine&#8221; whereby a blind woman can see again and a failing heart can be replaced&#8230; but not only do these things come at a cost, there&#8217;s also something unspoken in the trade-off &#8212; perhaps a loss of humanity, piece by piece? Could you speak to this? </strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: Don’t get me wrong &#8211; modern medicine gives us immense power over our own lives and destinies. That in itself seems to me like a good thing. Many of the technologies mentioned in the story already exist or are being developed (albeit in simpler, preliminary forms), and that’s incredibly exciting. But there is a trade-off, a line that could be crossed, and it’s just not something with a clear-cut boundary. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/piron-guillaume-361682.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8843 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/piron-guillaume-361682-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>It’s a question that every person will need to answer for themselves, over and over again, as each of us tries to not only survive, but to live a meaningful life in this rapidly changing world. So, the real danger, as I see it, is not the technology itself, but when we stop letting people making those decisions for themselves and instead hand it off to some third party, whether it’s a doctor, an insurance company, or society as a whole.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What authors inspire you and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: I love writing that tackles pressing, real-world issues while still providing the pure joy of reading an engaging, human story. The authors who achieve this time and time again for me are <a href="http://nkjemisin.com/">N. K. Jemisin</a> and <a href="http://margaretatwood.ca/">Margaret Atwood</a>. I also really admire writers who can weave together complex scientific or technical ideas with personal, emotional narratives. Two books I’ve recently loved that do this are Hope Jahren’s memoir, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25733983-lab-girl"><em>Lab Girl</em></a>, and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Chemistry-novel-Weike-Wang/dp/1524731749"><em>Chemistry</em></a>, a novel about a struggling graduate student by Weike Wang.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What is it about speculative fiction that draws you in as a writer? </strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: Fiction in general, and especially speculative fiction, is such a wonderful and important playground. It can entertain, but it can also enlighten by communicating complex ideas and helping us see things from different perspectives. The stories I enjoy most do both, and I strive to achieve the same with my writing.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What do you think are the biggest challenges for female-identifying authors in the genres of spec fic/sci-fi/fantasy right now?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: I actually feel incredibly fortunate to be writing as woman right now, and I’m lucky to be early enough in my writing career that I haven’t had to confront gender bias in publishing head-on yet. I have experienced it in my scientific career though, and I’m acutely aware of the fact that publishing, speculative fiction in particular, has historically been a male-dominated space. That history, and the pressure I think many women put on themselves to succeed in spite of it, is a powerful motivating force, but it can also become toxic.</p>
<p>The positive side to all this is that there is still so much wide-open territory when comes to exploring what it means to write with and about a female identity in the speculative fiction genres. It’s wonderful that magazines like <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> exist as a dedicated space to do exactly that!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: If there is one thing that you&#8217;d like for your readers to get out of this story, what is it? </strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: A lot of my own feelings of hopelessness about the state of the world went into writing “While It’s Still Beating,” but I hope that readers will also pick up on a glimmer of courage and resilience. I admire Alice and Lenore. They’re faced in this story with an impossible situation, but they’re still living, and therefore still fighting in spite of everything the world has thrown against them. That alone is heroic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 032 is LIVE! Meet our cover artist: Miranda Meeks</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-032-is-live-meet-our-cover-artist-miranda-meeks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 032]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8878</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Luna Station Quarterly is happy to announce that Issue 032 is now available! Grab a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_8881" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8881" style="width: 208px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Dec032.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-8881" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Dec032-193x300.jpg" alt="" width="208" height="323" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-8881" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;December&#8221; for Issue 032 by Miranda Meeks</figcaption></figure>
<p><em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> is happy to announce that Issue 032 is now available! Grab a copy and dive into nine amazing stories by female-identifying writers that push the boundaries of speculative fiction, sci-fi, and fantasy. We have trolls, we have specters, we have the future of medical science, we have our first translated work (!), AND we have gorgeous cover art. In fact, we quite recently chatted with our cover artist, <a href="http://mirandameeks.com/">Miranda Meeks</a>. Read more for what Miranda has to say about her art, creativity, and inspiration.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Where do you get your beautiful, haunting ideas? What inspires your art?</strong></em></p>
<p>Miranda: A lot of my ideas are inspired by various things, from photography, movies, music, classical paintings, etc. I&#8217;m especially inspired by images that tell a narrative <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Slide1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8887 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Slide1-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>or a story, without leaving too many clues as to what that story could be. I love hearing different interpretations of my paintings, which is part of the reason that ambiguity really resonates with me.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Can you tell us a bit about your methods? How long does it take to complete a piece? What media do you most commonly use?</strong></em></p>
<figure id="attachment_8883" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8883" style="width: 225px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/meg-the-poe-miranda-meeks-768x1024.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-8883 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/meg-the-poe-miranda-meeks-768x1024-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-8883" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Poe Sister&#8221; by Miranda Meeks</figcaption></figure>
<p>Miranda: Most of my pieces are digital, and they take anywhere from 15-50 hours, depending on the project, subject matter, etc. I&#8217;ve been fortunate to be able to experiment with oils these past few years as well, which has been really fun.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There is a lot of animal imagery mixed into many of your pieces&#8211;snakes, wolves, a lamb&#8230; Can you tell us about why you&#8217;ve picked these animals?</strong></em></p>
<p>Miranda: I really like certain animals and subject matter because they aren&#8217;t so exotic that I&#8217;ve never seen them before in person, or only at a zoo. I also enjoy drawing animals that have a lot of symbolism tied into their identities. When you draw a wolf, almost everyone has these pre-built ideas and biases associated with that wolf, so you&#8217;re able to convey mood and ideas without having to literally draw them out. Besides all those things, certain animals are simply a lot of fun to draw and paint.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Regarding your cover for Issue 032, &#8220;December,&#8221; &#8212; can you tell us the story behind it? Who is that girl? Where is she? What&#8217;s happening or going to happen? Or do you know?</strong></em></p>
<p>Miranda: For the &#8220;December&#8221; piece, I wanted to convey the idea that the girl is comfortable and strong, despite the snake wrapped around her neck and in her hair. I don&#8217;t know who she is or where she is, but I like to imply strength in the women I draw, despite their circumstances.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us a bit about your journey as an artist &#8212; did you anticipate being where you are today?</strong></em></p>
<p>Miranda: When I first went to college I thought I wanted to be a children&#8217;s book illustrator. That changed to wanting to go into editorial. Then a year or two after graduating, everything gradually shifted to doing book covers, which I am very happy with. I would not have guessed it 5-10 years ago, but I am so glad to be where I&#8217;m at now.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What feelings do you want to invoke in us as we look at your work? What messages are you sending?</strong></em></p>
<figure id="attachment_8885" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8885" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/what-lies-beneath-by-miranda-meeks-web-1024x1024.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-8885 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/what-lies-beneath-by-miranda-meeks-web-1024x1024-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-8885" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;What Lies Beneath&#8221; by Miranda Meeks</figcaption></figure>
<p>Miranda: I love the idea of bridging the gap between beauty and darkness. I hope to convey to my audience that there is beauty in those things that might be haunting or surreal.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Where do you hope to see your art over the next five to ten years, both figuratively and literally?</strong></em></p>
<p>Miranda: I hope to be able to improve my craft and continue to incorporate more traditional pieces into my portfolio. I hope I&#8217;m able to make series of pieces that really resonate and connect with people.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Is there anything you&#8217;d like to tell budding artists? Words of wisdom?</strong></em></p>
<p>Miranda: To artists who are just starting out, my advice would be to keep going, no matter what life throws at you. It&#8217;s been really difficult balancing family life with work life as I stay home with my two little kids, and although it feels impossible to get that balance right, it&#8217;s also fulfilling to be able to do both. It is somehow possible, if you just stick with it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
