<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Birthday &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/birthday/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 03:00:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday, Jan Brett!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-jan-brett/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jan Brett may not be the kind of author usually featured on the LSQ blog, but today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_22283" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22283" style="width: 229px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22283" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Jan_Brett_at_the_Arctic_Circle-229x300.jpg" alt="" width="229" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Jan_Brett_at_the_Arctic_Circle-229x300.jpg 229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Jan_Brett_at_the_Arctic_Circle.jpg 240w" sizes="(max-width: 229px) 100vw, 229px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22283" class="wp-caption-text">By Josephhearne at English Wikipedia, CC BY-SA 3.0, <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=16689865">https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=16689865</a></figcaption></figure>
<p><a style="font-size: 17px;" href="https://www.janbrett.com/index.html">Jan Brett</a><span style="font-size: 17px;"> may not be the kind of author usually featured on the </span><em style="font-size: 17px;">LSQ </em><span style="font-size: 17px;">blog, but today is her birthday and I think she deserves some recognition. An accomplished children&#8217;s author and illustrator, Jan Brett has written and illustrated </span><a style="font-size: 17px;" href="https://www.janbrett.com/booklist.htm">dozens of books</a><span style="font-size: 17px;"> with beautifully detailed illustrations. Some are fairy tale retellings, some are original stories, some take place in the real world, and some in imaginary lands. Does this mean Brett&#8217;s works can be considered speculative? Definitely! One of her more recent books, </span><a style="font-size: 17px;" href="https://www.janbrett.com/bookstores/the_mermaid_book.htm"><em>The Mermaid</em></a><span style="font-size: 17px;">, is an Okinawan retelling of &#8220;Goldilocks and the Three Bears&#8221; with an even more fantastical twist. My personal favorite of Brett&#8217;s is </span><em style="font-size: 17px;"><a href="https://www.janbrett.com/bookstores/comet_book.htm">Comet&#8217;s Nine Lives</a>, </em><span style="font-size: 17px;">a story about a mischievous cat named Comet who keeps losing one of his nine lives as he searches for a place to settle down on the anthropomorphic dog-inhabited island of Nantucket. The story is actually a little morbid when you think about it&#8211;the cat keeps having brushes with death&#8211;but of course it has a happy ending, and for a beach-lover like myself, the illustrations are such a treat.</span></p>
<p>Brett&#8217;s books are especially perfect to read this time of year. Lots of her stories take place in the winter, and she has plenty of Christmas stories, too. We&#8217;re probably all familiar with <a href="https://www.janbrett.com/bookstores/mitten_book.htm"><em>The Mitten</em></a>, the playful tale where a slew of animals in various sizes try to fit into a little boy&#8217;s lost mitten. One of my first encounters with Jan Brett&#8217;s works was <a href="https://www.janbrett.com/bookstores/christmas_trolls_book.htm"><em>Christmas Trolls</em></a>, where young Treva must teach two childish trolls about the spirit of Christmas. The fact that I can remember all of these stories perfectly even 20 years later proves how incredible Brett&#8217;s works are!</p>
<p>Although the stories themselves are memorable, what really sets Brett&#8217;s works apart are her illustrations. They&#8217;re so packed with detail, and often tell side-stories that aren&#8217;t in the text. She usually includes extra illustrations on the borders of the pages, like Lisa looking for her lost hat in <a href="https://www.janbrett.com/bookstores/hat_book.htm"><em>The Hat </em></a>while the animals are busy stealing more clothes in the main story, or what the lost cat Taffy is up to in <em><a href="https://www.janbrett.com/bookstores/annie_book.htm">Annie and the Wild Animals</a>. </em>Brett also does extensive research and traveling for her books, whether they&#8217;re set in Denmark or India, Sweden or Martinique. Her dedication to her craft really comes through, which I think sets her apart from a lot of other children&#8217;s authors.</p>
<p>Any time is a good time to check out Jan Brett&#8217;s impressive bibliography, but I think December, the month of her birth, is the best time. Christmas-lovers, fairy tale aficionados, art appreciators, and the young-at-heart&#8211;you&#8217;re all in for a treat! In honor of Jan Brett, do yourself a favor and pick up one of her books this month.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forget the bombshell, remember the brains</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/forget-the-bombshell-remember-the-brains-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 11:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The first thing I want you to note is that I will not be including&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12563 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/patent-hedylamar-248x300.gif" alt="" width="248" height="300" />The first thing I want you to note is that I will not be including any images of Hedy Lamarr in this post honoring her passing on this day in 2000. I think she would have found this refreshing. As I was writing this piece, the articles I found that spoke about her brilliant mind and focused on her plethora of inventions still featured at least a few pictures of her in her youth, when she was considered one of the most beautiful women on film.</p>
<p>A brief version of her biography goes something like this: born in Austria in 1914, at 18 she was in the infamous film, &#8220;Ecstasy&#8221; and also married a much older man. She left both husband and country when they became unbearable a few years later. After meeting Louis B. Mayer, she started a Hollywood film career, but that became a trap from which she would never find a way to flee.</p>
<p>There are many sad aspects to Lamarr&#8217;s life: a string of failed marriages, a flagging production company, and later on, deep seclusion from the outside world as her beauty and eyesight faded. Yet there was, in the background, her inventing which seemed to bring some satisfaction and joy into her life.</p>
<p>By all accounts, she considered her beauty to be a curse as much as anything. It&#8217;s easy to see why she would feel this way, despite the doors it opened for her. She was never respected in her lifetime for the various inventions she designed and the scientific mind that was, for lack of a better phrase, trapped in a beautiful body.</p>
<p>When the Navy purchased her patent for the frequencing hopping technology she invented to aid in the war effort, she was told she would be better off spending her time selling kisses and being a pinup for the men at the front. That technology she invented? It&#8217;s the basis for wifi, bluetooth, and other technologies we all use every day. Sell kisses indeed.</p>
<p>There are some who say she got the idea for this technology from a diagram she saw in her first husband&#8217;s office. As if this meant she should not receive the credit she gets for her patent. As a programmer and writer and I tell you that no idea ever comes from a vacuum. Everyone who has ever created anything built it on bits and pieces of what came before. It actually makes me a bit angry to hear someone try to devalue Ms. Lamarr&#8217;s contributions, as if she were too beautiful to have the brains for the work she did.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12564" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/US2292387-Fig-1-Hedy-Lamarr-patent-300x171.png" alt="" width="500" height="286" />The basis for wifi was not the only thing she invented, either. She worked on an improved version of a traffic light, an interesting carbonation tablet, and when she dated Howard Hughes, she offered up designs for streamlined versions of his airplanes.</p>
<p>It wasn&#8217;t until 1997 that she began receiving real recognition for her pioneering work. She (and her co-inventor) were awarded with the Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF) Pioneer Award and she was also honored with the prized BULBIEª Gnass Spirit of Achievement Bronze Award (the &#8220;Oscar&#8221; of inventing). In 2014 she was posthumously inducted into the Inventors Hall of Fame.</p>
<p>Her name began fading into obscurity when she began secluding herself from the public, and her passing in 2000 was quiet. Fortunately, she received some recognition for her beautiful mind as well as her beautiful visage before the end. I hope she was able to find some satisfaction in that.</p>
<p>I had known about her involvement in inventing frequency hopping, but am glad to know more of the details and about how much Ms. Lamarr valued intelligence and inventiveness. Now when I hear the name Hedy Lamarr, I&#8217;ll think of her brains before her beauty. I hope you will as well.</p>
<p>Want to learn a bit more?</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hedy_Lamarr">Hedy Lamarr &#8211; Wikipedia</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/shivaunefield/2018/02/28/hedy-lamarr-the-incredible-mind-behind-secure-wi-fi-gps-bluetooth/#4e485eca41b7">Hedy Lamarr: The Incredible Mind Behind Secure WiFi, GPS And Bluetooth</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2018/mar/08/hedy-lamarr-1940s-bombshell-helped-invent-wifi-missile">Hedy Lamarr – the 1940s ‘bombshell’ who helped invent wifi | Film | The Guardian</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.women-inventors.com/Hedy-Lammar.asp">Hedy Lamarr: Invention of Spread Spectrum Technology</a></p>
<p>And the documentary about her life and work, &#8220;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bombshell:_The_Hedy_Lamarr_Story">Bombshell</a>&#8221; is currently available on Netflix and Amazon streaming services.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Grandma COBOL&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/grandma-cobol/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 11:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12061</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rear Admiral, Teacher, Mathematician, Programmer. For my column this month I want to tell you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12063 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/grace-hopper-300x169-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" />Rear Admiral, Teacher, Mathematician, Programmer. For my column this month I want to tell you about an amazing woman who laid the foundation for the career I have today.</p>
<p>Born this day in 1906, Grace Hopper was an accomplished woman who invented some of the core features and tools of modern computer programming. The field would not be the same today without her work.</p>
<p>As a programmer myself, it amazes me what she was able to accomplish. Of course she was part of a team, not toiling away by herself in some dark room, however that fact makes it even more impressive that she is so clearly credited for her work in a time when women’s accomplishments were so often obscured.</p>
<p>She is credited with inventing the compiler, a program that translates written instructions into code that computers read directly. She also was key to inventing COBOL (and FORTRAN) a new kind of programming language that allows programmers to write their code using words instead of only numbers. The modern web would likely not exist without this development. These languages influenced the hundreds of languages that came after it.</p>
<p>If you have ever heard a programmer talk about “debugging” a bit of code, you can thank Grace Hopper for coining the term. A moth was trapped in a relay of the Mark II computer she was working on and she described its discovery and removal as “debugging” the machine.</p>
<p>She is sometimes called “Amazing Grace” for all her accomplishments, though she would say her biggest accomplishment was helping young people learn. She was an avid teacher and took joy in challenging those around her to think beyond the ways they had always done things. She even had a clock in her office that ran counter-clockwise as a reminder to look at problems in new ways.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12064" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/the-most-dangerous-phrase-in-the-language-is-we-have-always-done-it-this-way-lab-no-4.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="425" /></p>
<p>For all that, in this month of crone celebration here at LSQ, I find one of her most interesting traits is the age she started her programming career. Born in 1906, she did not join the Navy until she was 38 and it was only then that she began programming. She brought along her childhood curiosity for taking things apart and rebuilding them and her love of mathematics. Combined with her life experience, this meant Admiral Hopper was well-suited to bring new innovation to the burgeoning field of computer programming.</p>
<p>Throughout her life, she continued to buck traditions and expectations. She remained active in the Navy Reserve for 42 years, much of that by special permission of Congress that allowed her to serve well past the mandatory retirement date. After retirement she returned to teaching, her first love, and continued to inspire students until her passing in 1992.</p>
<p>Grace Hopper left behind a legacy of innovation and inspiration. Her work garnered her the Defense Distinguished Service Medal, the highest decoration given to those who did not participate in combat, along with a posthumous Presidential Medal of Freedom.</p>
<p>You can learn more about Grace Hopper here:<br />
&#8211; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grace_Hopper">Wikipedia page</a><br />
&#8211; <a href="https://cpsc.yale.edu/grace-murray-hopper">Yale’s Computer Science Dept. profile</a><br />
&#8211; <a href="https://www.public.navy.mil/surfor/ddg70/Pages/namesake.aspx">The U.S. Navy profile</a><br />
&#8211; <a href="https://www.womenshistory.org/education-resources/biographies/grace-hopper">National Women’s History Museum profile</a></p>
<p>I’ve also put together a video playlist, including a fabulous interview on David Letterman:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Who is Grace Hopper?" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fg82iV-L8ZY?list=PLeuUHSWc1tJzo2LVFdFjQ3TEW1LEzRtoR" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday, Margaret Atwood!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-margaret-atwood-2/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-margaret-atwood-2/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Get out your party hats, dear readers, (or maybe your handmaid&#8217;s bonnets?), because today we&#8217;re&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_11972" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-11972" style="width: 157px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Atwood123.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-11972 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Atwood123.jpg" alt="" width="157" height="245" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-11972" class="wp-caption-text">Credit: Moxy, Wikipedia</figcaption></figure>
<p>Get out your party hats, dear readers, (or maybe your handmaid&#8217;s bonnets?), because today we&#8217;re celebrating the birthday of the author, <a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/margaret-atwood">poet</a>, <a href="http://margaretatwood.ca/green-policies/">environmentalist</a>, literary critic, essayist, and <a href="https://www.livescience.com/7046-long-distance-pen-devised-author-margaret-atwood.html">inventor</a> Margaret Atwood.</p>
<p>A household name after <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5834204/">Hulu</a> picked up her novel <em>The Handmaid&#8217;s Tale</em>, turning it into a serial show (and expanding it beyond the book), there have been multitudes of articles, bios, summaries, and commentaries on her work and life. This will not be retold here. What will be told is a brief celebration of Atwood&#8217;s mark on my life.</p>
<p>I discovered <a href="http://margaretatwood.ca/">Atwood</a> my freshman year in college; I suppose many young women do. A new friend of mine suggested her to me&#8211;<em>The Handmaid&#8217;s Tale</em>, of course. I devoured it and never looked back. End of story.</p>
<p>Not really. Like with every relationship, there have been ups and downs.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not a fan of everything she&#8217;s ever written. Her first novel, <em>The Edible Woman</em>, is nowhere near the creative scope of some of her other works and I shudder to think if that work was the first one I had read instead of one of her best, I would likely not have given her a second look. But after <em>The Handmaid&#8217;s Tale</em>, I steadily picked up each of her other works where I could find them (I&#8217;m dating myself by admitting this was before the heydays of Amazon ordering ease): novels, short story collections, poetry. My favorites: <em>Oryx and Crake, The Blind Assassin, Alias Grace</em>. Those which I need to re-read to appreciate with older eyes: <em>Surfacing, Cat&#8217;s Eye</em>. Those which disappointed: <em>MaddAddam, The Heart Goes Last</em>.</p>
<p>Atwood has been with me during my entire adult writing career. I&#8217;ve looked to her use of language and character development as how-to examples; I&#8217;ve used her poems as portals to explore metaphor and subtleties of language and imagery; I&#8217;ve followed her prolific career as a trail of bread crumbs: be diligent, work hard, and behold the upper echelon of author-dom.</p>
<p>I met her once. On her book tour following the release of <em>The Year of the Flood</em>, 2009 I believe. She came to DC. A part of the book was performed. I stood in line, got the book signed. Then I reached out&#8211;I wanted to shake her hand.</p>
<p>I said: &#8220;I just wanted to say you are wonderful.&#8221; I&#8217;ll never forget the look she gave me: a small, amused smile. Her eyes danced. Her hand was thin, dry, and very light. It felt breakable. I don&#8217;t recall what she said in response but her expression will always remain because she looked directly at <em>me</em>.</p>
<p>I flushed with embarrassment (<em>what a stupid thing to say!</em>), clutched my signed book, and walked away. But I had done it. I met an idol. And so I continue, every few years, to re-read <em>The Handmaid&#8217;s Tale</em>, re-examining those twists of scene and narrative. The ending. The locked room of Offred. Each time I revisit, I gain something new. I&#8217;m overdue this time around, so I think I&#8217;ll pick up my worn copy this weekend. An old friend.</p>
<p>Happy birthday, Margaret Atwood.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-margaret-atwood-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Notorious CPG: A Tribute to Charlotte Perkins Gilman; Resisting Bad Faith</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-notorious-cpg-a-tribute-to-charlotte-perkins-gilman-resisting-bad-faith/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are few writers whose name creates as immediate and profound a sense of recognition&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are few writers whose name creates as immediate and profound a sense of recognition among my students as Charlotte Perkins Gilman’s. I would be surprised if it were any less the case. It’s not just that nearly every one of my teaching colleagues includes </span><a href="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/theliteratureofprescription/exhibitionAssets/digitalDocs/The-Yellow-Wall-Paper.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The Yellow Wallpaper,”</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Gilman’s disturbing tale of a young woman suffering from postpartum depression and her steady decline, in their sophomore English syllabi. It’s how the text opens up conversations about interpretation, and character stakes, and (most importantly) the struggle of women to be heard and believed, even about that most sacrosanct of things: their knowledge of themselves.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Charlotte-Perkins-Gilman-cover-1-e1529508103169.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10671 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Charlotte-Perkins-Gilman-cover-1-192x300.png" alt="" width="192" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Often, I tell my students to start by reading the article “Why I Wrote the Yellow Wallpaper?” from Gilman’s landmark feminist journal </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Forerunner</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (published from 1909-1916) </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">before </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">they read the short story itself. Here. </span><a href="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/exhibition/theliteratureofprescription/education/materials/WhyIWroteYellowWallPaper.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take minute to do that.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I’ll wait.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What stuns my students about Charlotte Perkins Gilman’s writing &#8212; not just this story, but her essays on economics, social policy, and yes, her utopic fantasy </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/531509.Herland"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Herland</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; is how much of it springs from personal experience and private conviction turned public. That she herself suffered from depression misdiagnosed as a symptom of “hysteria” and needed to endure the so-called rest cure, a frankly madness-inducing enforced isolation and mental lethargy, shakes them deeply because it reminds of them the very arguments we have today about victims, abusers, power, and the powerless.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s easy to lapse into thinking of authors as largely separate from what they write (it is, after all, a tent pole assertion in the debate about </span><a href="https://fashionmagazine.com/culture/who-made-my-art/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">how to deal with the wrongs artists commit when one is a consumer of their work</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). The idea that something so wrenching could be in some measure autobiographical alarms my students, and motivates them to see their world differently. Most especially and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">most importantly</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, it motivates the young men in my classroom.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consider Joanna Russ’ brilliant </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1047343.How_to_Suppress_Women_s_Writing?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to Suppress Women’s Writing</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Russ’ critical treatise covers </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Suppress_Women%27s_Writing"><span style="font-weight: 400;">eleven key rhetorical poses</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> adopted by those in a position to influence the landscape of publishing and criticism surrounding women writers. It’s the second of these poses that Gilman herself speaks to in “Why I Wrote the Yellow Wallpaper?”: “Such a story ought not be written&#8230;; it was enough to drive anyone mad to read it,” one of her critical contemporaries claims. Or, put in Russ’ language, “She wrote it, but she shouldn’t have.”</span></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Joanna-Russ-Cover.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10672 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Joanna-Russ-Cover-194x300.png" alt="" width="194" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Or, put in the language of 2018: Charlotte Perkins Gilman was one of America’s first #MeToo voices. The “problem” with Gilman’s writing, her career, her actual voice and existence itself, according to a critic of the type Russ warns us against, is that she’s alarmist, solipsistic, divisive, even (arguably) vengeful. She doesn’t understand the difference between the way things have to be and the way she </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">wishes they were</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. No one involved in her care meant her any harm, surely. She just failed to cooperate in her own best interests. Ultimately, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">she’s</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the problem. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I value Gilman’s work for how it affects the young men I teach because the young women are already painfully aware of what it’s like to be denied authority to explain their emotions, their wellness, their lives to the adults &#8212; especially the men &#8212; around them. But the young men? They’ve grown up in a world that tells them “gender politics” is basically over (or should be) and the playing field has been leveled. That the women around them experience no differences. That when oppression and dismissal did happen, it was not just in the past, but many hundreds of years ago, continents away from their present world. Doctors are experts. They are sensible people, driven by data and reason.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many of them want to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">be doctors</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The conversations that open up surrounding “The Yellow Wallpaper” touch on women’s health, including abortion and birth control; parental and government intervention; gender identity; and mental health. Each of these conversations circles back to the importance of empathy in believing people’s stories and, frankly, in the business of being human, period. They talk about giving each other the space to be heard. Everyone needs to be reminded of how important that praxis is; the population with the most power to enact change, once they hear it and believe it, though, are young men. They’re the ones whose voices will ultimately move the needle, because there are still more people in the world who will believe a man before a woman, no matter what topic is at hand.    </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In remembering Charlotte Perkins Gilman on her birthday, we should remember her work as an author and activist was an ongoing battle against the bad faith of willful ignorance: the toxic peddling of the lie that “these bad things aren’t happening,” becoming “you shouldn’t treat these things as if they are bad,” and then “they’re not happening all that often,” before finally arriving at  “you shouldn’t point out these bad things because they make us uncomfortable and that’s unfair.” Her goal was to rattle the scales off her readers’ eyes, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">particularly</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> those of the men in her world. Perhaps Russ, again, describes the system Gilman tries to break apart best:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“To slide into decisions without allowing oneself to realize that one is making any, to feel dimly that one is enjoying advantages without trying to become clearly aware of what these advantages are (and who hasn’t got them), to accept mystifications because they’re customary and comfortable, cooking one’s mental books to congratulate oneself on traditional behavior as it it were actively moral behavior, to know that one doesn’t know, to prefer not to know, to defend one’s status as already knowing with half-sincere, half-selfish passion as “objectivity” &#8212; this great, fuzzy area of human ingenuity is what Jean Paul Sartre calls </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">bad faith</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. When spelled out, the techniques used to maintain bad faith look morally atrocious and appalling silly.”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Celebrate the Notorious CPG today by finding that convenient self-deception around you. Ask questions. Demand answers. Agitate. Use your voice. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating Virginia Woolf&#8217;s Sapphic Fiction</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/celebrating-virginia-woolfs-sapphic-fiction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Virginia Woolf is a work of art. Her fiction, although sometimes dense and hard to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/George_Charles_Beresford_-_Virginia_Woolf_in_1902_-_Restoration.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9352 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/George_Charles_Beresford_-_Virginia_Woolf_in_1902_-_Restoration-220x300.jpg" alt="" width="220" height="300" /></a><a href="https://www.biography.com/people/virginia-woolf-9536773">Virginia Woolf</a> is a work of art. Her fiction, although sometimes dense and hard to understand, is each of them a masterwork of craft. I got into Woolf because my Aunt Linda, my namesake, knew I loved to read, and started giving me books authored by the <a href="http://www.tate.org.uk/art/art-terms/b/bloomsbury/lifestyle-lives-and-legacy-bloomsbury-group">Bloomsbury Group</a> when I was young. Probably too young to appreciate them, but in high school I finally managed to make it through </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Room of One’s Own</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This piece, for those that may not know, is a short non-fiction essay crafted around the premise that William Shakespeare had a sister, who was not given the same room to write and grow her work as William was. This sister, Judith, was equal to William in all ways. Her intellect, lyric genius, historical knowledge, and her desire to create were all a match for her brother. The difference between them was as simple and as complicated as she was a woman, and he a man. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This piece of speculative literature, originally delivered as a series of lectures at an all-women’s college, was remarkable for its simple and stunning assertions, its definition of creative womanhood, and its exploration of sapphic love in a time when obscenity laws <a class="right-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Virginia_and_Leonard_Woolf_1912.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-9355 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Virginia_and_Leonard_Woolf_1912-232x300.jpg" alt="" width="232" height="300" /></a>prevented almost any mention of homosexuality. The use of fictional characters in a series of academic essays and lectures, again, delivered to an all-female audience, truly underlined the reality of the world around these women. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Woolf is not often remembered for her speculative roots, but besides the formerly noted piece of non-fiction, one of her greatest works is the novel </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orlando</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Room </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">changed me as a high schooler, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orlando </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">changed me again in college. Whereas </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Room</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> flirted with the idea of sapphic love &#8212; “Chloe liked Olivia,” if anyone will remember that iconic line &#8212; <em>Orlando</em> did everything in its power to express that kind of love without censure. The titular Lady Orlando changes times, changes shapes, and reinvents themselves over the course of the book to become a man in order to pursue her first lady love. The book is an extended love letter to <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/07/28/virginia-woolf-vita-sackville-west/">Vita Sackville-West,</a> another member of the Bloomsbury Group, and Woolf writes her lover and friend into every situation and scenario, every sex and decade, over and over throughout the whole novel. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/220px-StracheyWoolf.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9354 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/220px-StracheyWoolf-205x300.jpg" alt="" width="205" height="300" /></a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although given the subhead ‘a biography,’ </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orlando </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is another masterwork of speculative fiction. It exhibits a sense of playfulness and daring that I consider ahead of its time. It is written in Woolf’s signature stream-of-consciousness style, which means that it can be difficult to parse through, and sometimes hard to follow, but the end result is a dedication to love and passion. <em>Orlando</em> is beautiful and flirty, at times frustrating and lonely. The novel treats its audience as it would a lover, and it is truly an incredible book. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many women writers owe a significant debt to Virginia Woolf’s work, and although her speculative fiction can sometimes be overshadowed by other published pieces, or the style in which it is written, her books are incredible statements to the genius of women, and the potential they have. The alternate realities of her characters and stories intertwine with the allegories and allusions in a stunning testament to her vivid imagination in a time when women novelists were not common, and not given the same kind of critical acclaim as men. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orlando </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">made Woolf’s career, and in some ways, the novel is as ubiquitous as Orlando themselves. It is remade in each new wave of feminism and activism as a banner of hope and purpose. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So happy birthday, Virginia Woolf. I’m excited to see what you become next. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday, Shirley Jackson!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-shirley-jackson-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danielle Perry]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 12:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I wrote about Shirley Jackson and The Haunting of Hill House three years ago,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/287px-ShirleyJack.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8969 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/287px-ShirleyJack.jpg" alt="" width="287" height="177" /></a>When I wrote about Shirley Jackson and <i>The Haunting of Hill House</i> <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/never-give-up-your-cup-of-stars/">three years ago</a>, I knew little about Shirley Jackson’s life, but I soon learned more because I spent 2015 obsessed with <i>Hill House</i>, not unlike Eleanor. On a whim, I decided to read the introduction of my copy, which told me that “Jackson, who had a lifelong interest in the occult, who dabbled in spells and liked to tell reporters that she was a witch, professed to believe in ghosts.” It made me love Shirley Jackson <a href="https://twitter.com/jekyllian/status/603642525518139392">even more than I already did</a> for her writing alone.</p>
<p>Then, in 2016, Ruth Franklin’s biography, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/entertainment/books/shirley-jackson-a-rather-haunted-life/2016/09/15/4293b85e-5f2b-11e6-af8e-54aa2e849447_story.html?utm_term=.c9963b94da18"><i>Shirley Jackson: A Rather Haunted Life</i></a>, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/hauntedlifecover.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8970 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/hauntedlifecover-203x300.jpg" alt="" width="203" height="300" /></a>came out. I’m not the sort of person, usually, who would necessarily want to read a biography of an author, even one I love as much as Jackson. But I loved this one. Partially this is because Franklin did a fantastic job, providing the reader with an incredible amount of detail about Jackson’s life and its contexts, and partially it is just because I really do love Jackson, even when she is at her most cantankerous, even when I disagree with her.</p>
<p>One of the primary reasons I love Jackson is her embrace of the occult. As Franklin writes, witchcraft was important to Jackson “for what it symbolized: female strength and potency” and “[t]o call oneself a witch, then, is to claim some of that power.” It didn’t matter what anyone else thought of witchcraft, or of Jackson’s claim of being a witch: it gave her some modicum of power otherwise not afforded to her.</p>
<p>That power is something she also bequeathed to her characters, particularly Merrikat of <i>We Have Always Lived in the Castle</i>. Merrikat makes use of witchery to protect herself, her sister Constance, and their home &#8211; and she doesn’t much care what anyone else thinks of it, or of her. (Going into the town and being confronted with what everyone else thinks of it, and her, is hurtful to Merrikat, of course, but not <i>important</i> to her.) Merrikat &#8211; more than Constance, more than Eleanor of <i>Hill House</i>, more than Jackson herself, oftentimes &#8211; takes action in her own life. She has the potency of a witch.</p>
<p>This is a thing worth celebrating, especially this year. It is Jackson’s 101st birthday, and women all over are taking action, reclaiming their potency, calling themselves <i>witch</i>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday, Tamora Pierce&#8211;May your Pen Stay Sharp.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-tamora-pierce-may-your-pen-stay-sharp/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 12:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8868</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are few authors that can stand on a history of writing like Tamora Pierce.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/tamora_pierce_163x236.jpeg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8724 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/tamora_pierce_163x236.jpeg" alt="" width="163" height="236" /></a>There are few authors that can stand on a history of writing like <a href="http://www.tamora-pierce.net/">Tamora Pierce</a>. For those of you who don’t know of Pierce’s work, her first series, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Song-Lioness-Quartet-Goddess-Rampant/dp/1481416499"><em>The Song of the Lioness</em></a>, is a quartet of YA books published in the early 80’s. These books chronicled the adventures of a cross-dressing young woman as she fights to become a knight in a realm infused with magic, a rich history, and mythical beasts. The world building is intense and comprehensive, and the realm of Tortall has been expanded to encompass 28 books. Her other mythical realm, Emelan, has its own set of mythology and magic, and comprises of twelve books. All this, and she’s still writing.</p>
<p>However, I’m not here to talk about her literary accomplishments. Today, on her birthday, I want to relate something much more personal.</p>
<p>Pierce’s novels, for the most part, focus on female protagonists. She’s a writer of young adult fiction for all genders, but her women stand out among her pantheon of characters. They are strong, fully-realized, desperate, passionate, and independent. Each one of her books stands as a tribute to well-written women; some mothers, some knights, some children, some spies, all with their own point of view and history. She writes women the way that women should be written, every single time, and she does it without pandering or talking down to her target young adult audience.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/153809.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8723 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/153809.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>Now, I wasn’t introduced to Pierce’s writing through her first series. Instead I received <em>First Test</em>, the first novel in the <em>Protector of the Small </em>series. These books chronicle the trials of Keladry of Mindelan, the first girl to openly try for her knight’s shield, even after the Lady Alana (from the previously-mentioned <em>Song of the Lioness Quartet</em>) has been named the King’s Champion.</p>
<p>Kel, unlike Alana, does not hide who she is. She does not have to bind her chest or avoid certain places of the palace. Instead she forces people to make changes for her, and she works harder than anyone else in order to prove her worth. She’s allowed to be a lady, to wear dresses and pants, to curtsy or bow as she chooses, and above it all, her friends respect her. Sexism is shown, of course, but it’s always dealt with. It’s never allowed to let lie. People who insult her are beaten into the ground, knights who demean her are challenged to duels and jousting tournaments, people who talk about her behind her back are revealed as duplicitous and mean.</p>
<p>I grew up on high fantasy books. My father read the <em>Lord of the Rings</em> to me as a child, and I loved to hear Arthurian legends, and watch those movies with knights and horses and armor. It was a magnificent distraction, but it wasn’t until I read <a href="http://www.tamora-pierce.net/series/the-protector-of-the-small/"><em>Protector of the Small </em></a>that I found what I had really wanted all along: a way to imagine myself in these stories. Finally, a woman in a fantasy realm that wasn’t a bar wench, a forbidden love locked in a tower, or a cold queen on a throne.</p>
<p>Kel was everything I wanted to be. She was broad-shouldered and worked out with the boys; I was a competitive athlete before I turned ten. She didn’t care about dating, and neither did I. She stared bullies in the eye and didn’t back down; I dealt with the meanness of classmates for years. She was not only everything I was, but she was who I wanted to be.</p>
<p>This character was an incredible realization of all the hopes I had for women in fantasy literature. I loved Kel dearly, and throughout high school, continued to reread <em>Protector of the Small</em>, and discovered the rest of Pierce’s writing. Her other books were just as fantastic and beautifully rendered, but I always returned back to Kel, who remained my steadfast favorite.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/lady-knight-tamora-pierce-58993_638_886.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8724 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/lady-knight-tamora-pierce-58993_638_886.jpg" /></a>This year, I returned to Kel again, and was reminded again of the strength and charm of Pierce’s writing. Kel didn’t disappoint, but I realized another character who tied me into the story. Kel’s mother, Ilane, reminded me of my own mom.</p>
<p>My mother is a captain in the Navy (retired), who spent 26 years in the service. She was not the typical mom. She kept her last name when she married, moved our family halfway across the country, and remained strong and steadfast during my entire childhood. Ilane does the same with Kel, and the Mindelan family. They move around as an ambassador, she fights (literally) to defend her country, and loves her daughter, no matter what. It was only this year that I realized how completely Kel’s story mirrored my own, and for that I’m so grateful.</p>
<p>So, today, on Tamora Pierce’s birthday, I will pick up my worn copy of <em>Lady Knight, </em>probably not for the last time<em>, </em>and marvel at Ms. Pierce’s ability to write my story so well, without ever knowing me. I can only hope that other girls find her work as wonderful as I did. Her writing is lovingly crafted, fully rendered, and affirming in a way that has not been matched by any author.</p>
<p>Happy birthday, Tamora Pierce&#8211;may your pen stay sharp.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy birthday, Madeleine L&#8217;Engle!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-madeleine-lengle-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 12:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8826</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On this day in 1918, science fiction author Madeleine L’Engle was born. She is best&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On this day in 1918, science fiction author Madeleine L’Engle was born. She is best known for her Time Quintet, especially the first novel, </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18131.A_Wrinkle_in_Time?from_search=true"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Wrinkle in Time</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Born and raised in New York City, L’Engle began writing at the age of five and never stopped, despite <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/117980.jpg"> </a><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/117980.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8837 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/117980-182x300.jpg" alt="" width="182" height="300" /></a>discouragement from her teachers. As an adult, the temptation to quit writing returned after </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Wrinkle in Time </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">received over thirty rejections. Thankfully for us, L’Engle never gave up on this novel, and it was finally published in 1962. It remains her most well-known work.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What I like most about L’Engle is that she was a children’s writer who made me feel that she trusted me as a child reader. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Wrinkle in Time </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is, in a word, bizarre. It was like nothing I’d ever read before. There was a group of women who talked so strangely, a bodiless telepathic brain (yes, a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">real brain</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">), and the dilemma of describing something to someone who’s never experienced that something before. It was my first time reading a book and thinking, “Hey, this book is weird. It’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">really </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">weird, but that’s okay!” L’Engle believed that children approached science fiction and fantasy more open-mindedly than adults, and as a child who read almost exclusively fantasy, I felt respected. She wasn’t just telling me a strange story, she was giving it to me, trusting me to imagine it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Something else that always stuck out to me was Meg, L’Engle’s protagonist. She is a young girl who doesn’t like herself. She’s good at math but not so much other subjects. She’s awkward, doesn’t get along with others, and feels like the misfit of her family. And yet the things she doesn’t like about herself, such as her stubbornness and rudeness, are what help her prevail over the evil brain (again, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">what?</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">) in the end. I’ve read plenty of books where the heroine was independent and plucky from the start, using her wits or magic powers to overcome her adversary. Instead, L’Engle presented me with a girl who was more like me. She feels uncomfortable with herself, with her place in her family, and among her peers. She has no magic powers. Yet she stands up to the brain (the literal brain) and beats it by being her old stubborn self. As much as I liked fantasizing about magic and pretending I went to Hogwarts, reading about an ordinary girl in a highly unorthodox situation was just as captivating.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/220px-Armofthestarfish.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8839 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/220px-Armofthestarfish-208x300.jpg" alt="" width="208" height="300" /></a>In honor of this cherished author’s birthday, why not head to your local library and pick out some of L’Engle’s other novels, such as </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/208909.The_Arm_of_the_Starfish?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Arm of the Starfish</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/251947.The_Small_Rain?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Small Rain</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, or </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/790132.The_Other_Side_of_the_Sun?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Other Side of the Sun</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">? She also published a few poetry titles, such as </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/790133.A_Cry_Like_a_Bell?from_search=true"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Cry Like a Bell</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Or, brush up on </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Wrinkle in Time</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in preparation for <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1620680/?ref_=nv_sr_1">the movie</a> coming out in 2018! It’s got an all-star cast, including Reese Witherspoon, Mindy Kaling, Gugu Mbatha-Raw, and Oprah. Yes, that’s right, Oprah. I&#8217;m looking forward to seeing how the cast works with this strange and wonderful tale, and I hope the result is something Madeleine L&#8217;Engle herself would be delighted by.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday Elizabeth Hand &#038; Mary Gentle!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-elizabeth-hand-mary-gentle/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today we celebrate two female genre writers: Elizabeth Hand (1957- ) and Mary Gentle (1956-&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today we celebrate two female genre writers: <a href="http://elizabethhand.com/">Elizabeth Hand </a>(1957- ) and <a href="https://www.fantasticfiction.com/g/mary-gentle/">Mary Gentle</a> (1956- ). Those these authors share the same birthday and nearly the same birth year, they are known for vastly different material.</p>
<p>Hand&#8217;s most well-known (and on-going!) series, beginning with <em><a href="http://elizabethhand.com/books/generation-loss/">Generation Lost</a>, </em>is noir detective novel, following Cass Neary. Hand described her anti-heroine as &#8220;this total screwup-alcoholic-speed freak&#8221; and that Cass continues to be trouble. Check out a video about the most recent book in the series <em>Hard Light </em> (2016).</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="HARD LIGHT by Elizabeth Hand/Book Trailer" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/160785147?dnt=1&amp;app_id=122963" width="730" height="411" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture"></iframe></p>
<p>Today we celebrate Hand for being unafraid to delve into darkness of action and psychological darkness. Especially for creating complicated, screwed up female characters for readers to love. As Hand explained in an interview with the <em><a href="http://www.pressherald.com/2016/04/17/author-qa-elizabeth-hand-on-the-freaking-mess-of-her-anti-heroine-the-steadiness-of-her-own-writing-life/">Portland Press Herald</a>, </em>after the publication of <em>Hard Light, </em>&#8220;if I make somebody cry at the end, then I know that my work here is done. Or if I know that I’ve succeeded in really disturbing somebody.&#8221;</p>
<p><a class="entry-author" title="Posts by Liz Bourke" href="http://www.tor.com/author/liz-bourke/" rel="author">Liz Bourke</a>, writing about Mary Gentle&#8217;s novel <em>The Black Opera, </em>similarly <a href="http://www.tor.com/2012/05/23/sleeps-with-monsters-go-thou-and-read-mary-gentle/">describes Gentle&#8217;s work </a>as &#8220;uncomfortable  or at least disconcerting  is the way she plays with expectation, genre, and continuity.&#8221; For instance, her alternate history novel <em>Ash: A Secret History </em>(the omnibus was released in 2013), is unflinching in its depiction of medieval violence, especially through the female captain Ash. Looking for flawed female characters and grimdark before grimdark was a coined term? Pick up Mary Gentle.</p>
<p>Thank you Hand and Gentle for giving us flawed women to admire, love and shy away from, with all their imperfections laid bare. Happy birthday to two women, unafraid to venture into darkness to bring light to women&#8217;s stories.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
