<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Lesbrarian&#8217;s Corner &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-lesbrarians-corner/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 20:59:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Review: I Kissed Alice, Anna Birch</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-i-kissed-alice-anna-birch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexa Kelly]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 10:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Lesbrarian's Corner]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve talked at length before about how much I love when YA queers and subverts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve talked at length before about how much I love when YA </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-you-should-see-me-in-a-crown-leah-johnson/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">queers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-late-to-the-party-kelly-quindlen/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">subverts</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> its own tropes and clichés. And I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">could</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> talk about it even further: the importance of diverse stories that reflect the diverse readership of YA cannot be overstated. I could write whole essays, in fact, about the significance of seeing familiar tropes—which historically have mostly been for and about white, cisgender heterosexuals—played out with characters that don’t fit all (or any) of those boxes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">could</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> write whole essays, but this, friends, is not an essay. In fact, I’m concerned it’s not even </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-19574 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/alice-194x300.jpg" alt="" width="194" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/alice-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/alice.jpg 307w" sizes="(max-width: 194px) 100vw, 194px" />articulate</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. I have been absolutely felled by enemies-to-lovers-with-a-sapphic-twist—courtesy of author Anna Birch’s debut </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43300915-i-kissed-alice?from_search=true&amp;from_srp=true&amp;qid=xV0mOhWadv&amp;rank=1"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I Kissed Alice</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">—and now am incapable of doing anything more than yelling “I WILL TAKE 100 MORE OF THESE, PLEASE” in what I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">think</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is her general direction. Because this book won me over, and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">hard</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Part of that, of course, is the fact that, confoundingly, I’ve </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">never</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> come across a sapphic enemies-to-lovers romance before. Ever. And it’s not like I don’t know about that trope (I know it enough to have audibly </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">gasped</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> when I saw the blurb for this book), so I guess </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">everything I read up to this point was heterosexual. All of it.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> And the premise for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I Kissed Alice</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> immediately grabbed me with how angsty and delicious it was: our two protagonists, Iliana and Rhodes, are seniors at a prestigious art school, competing for the same scholarship prize that will allow them to continue their arts education in college. Both are ridiculously competitive (of course), and each girl sees the other as the main thing standing in the way of her winning, but it’s more than just professional, creative animosity. Thanks to a misunderstanding, the two genuinely can’t stand each other on a personal level. Birch does a masterful job showing the slow, simmering dislike between them, as well as the ways in which their differences exacerbate the bad blood that’s already present: Rhodes is wealthy and privileged, but feels burned out as an artist and suffocated by her parents’ money and expectations. She sees Iliana’s effortless talent as smug, while Iliana, who comes from a family that is barely scraping by financially, is bitterly resentful of both Rhodes’s privilege and her demeanor, which she interprets as superior. It’s a classic case of pride and prejudice, and makes for an incredibly compelling starting point all by itself. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">then</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, there’s the twist.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The twist—because what would a romance like this be without one?—is that, while the two girls hate each other IRL, it’s quite a different story online. Unbeknownst to either of them, they’ve <img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19576 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/alice2-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/alice2-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/alice2.jpg 317w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />spent the better part of a year collaborating on an </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice in Wonderland</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> fancomic. And while they only know each other in this context by their usernames, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Curious-in-Cheshire </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I-Kissed-Alice</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, there’s no doubt whatsoever that they’re falling hard. And there’s no chance whatsoever, over the course of this turbulent senior year, that their identities are going to be able to remain separate for very long.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There was, no exaggeration, absolutely </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">nothing</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I didn’t love about this, but most impressive is just how </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">right</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Birch gets it. Enemies-to-lovers is a hard thing to do right—especially with a story like this, where there’s genuinely a lot that our protagonists need to work through before they can arrive at any kind of healthy relationship. One of my absolute favorite things about this book is that Birch doesn’t shy away from making her characters be fully realized in ways both bad and good. All of them, including the side characters, are complex, and have as many negative qualities as they do positive. They can be selfish, and petty, and take advantage of the people around them, but you still root for them, because these things don’t make them unlikable so much as just </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">real</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. So real, in fact, that I found myself reminded (sometimes uncomfortably) of some less than admirable things </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> did, or saw my friends do, when we were teens. And it’s honestly refreshing to see a YA romance that lets its characters be </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">bad</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">—not the “oh, I’m so tortured and tragic, it’s so sexy” kind of bad, but genuinely toxic to the point where they need to learn from their mistakes, own up to them, and grow to become better people. (This makes their growth much more satisfying, too!)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I loved that the love story never felt easy, and I loved that online personas (writing sapphic </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alice in Wonderland</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> fancomics! Of which there are several panels in this book!!!) became a safe place for the characters to be the people they were—unencumbered by the influences and stressors of the outside world. I loved that being queer was never made into a big deal, but wasn’t shied away from either. And I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">loved</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Iliana and Rhodes. Their progression from enemies to—well, that would be telling (but you can probably guess)—was so authentically, sensitively, and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">beautifully</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> written that it had me absolutely ripping through the back half of the book, and absolutely giddy by its conclusion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Queering your tropes is <em>magic</em>, y&#8217;all. Maybe that&#8217;s the title of my future essay. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(P.S.—Anna, if you’re reading this, I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">super</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> wasn’t joking about 100 more books like this.)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Late to the Party, Kelly Quindlen</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-late-to-the-party-kelly-quindlen/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-late-to-the-party-kelly-quindlen/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexa Kelly]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Lesbrarian's Corner]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this year, I decided to clear out my TBR list on Goodreads a little&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Earlier this year, I decided to clear out my TBR list on Goodreads a little bit—the logic being, I suppose, that what is quarantine for, if not all the sapphic books you never got around to reading? As with any such endeavor, the results were a mixed bag—the </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52915426-something-to-talk-about"><span style="font-weight: 400;">good</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43300915-i-kissed-alice"><span style="font-weight: 400;">excellent</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and the “</span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35053372-the-lost-coast"><span style="font-weight: 400;">bizarre, but it was about witches</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">”—though there was one novel in particular I had a hard time parsing my feelings about: </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20886492-her-name-in-the-sky"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Her Name in the Sky</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, author Kelly Quindlen’s debut novel, which follows a queer teen named Hannah and her friends through their senior year of high school. On the one hand, I was really impressed with Quindlen’s writing: her characters felt so three-dimensional, and their relationships to each other were written so authentically, it was like taking a nostalgic trip back to my own high school days. But on the other hand, this is a book about coming out—a painful, dramatic coming out that puts our main character through so much hell, it was really difficult, at times, to read about. And while I obviously don’t think queer novels centered on coming out are a bad thing—in a lot of ways, they’re necessary, especially to young queer kids—I’ve grown fatigued in recent years of reading stories about the pain that comes with discovering your queerness. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19275 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/latetotheparty1-196x300.jpg" alt="" width="196" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/latetotheparty1-196x300.jpg 196w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/latetotheparty1.jpg 310w" sizes="(max-width: 196px) 100vw, 196px" />But the things I’d loved about </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Her Name in the Sky</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> had left an impression on me. And so when I saw </span><a href="https://twitter.com/merylwilsner/status/1241940654990807040"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meryl Wilsner</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (author of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Something to Talk About</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, another excellent sapphic romance) raving about Quindlen’s new book </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44581495-late-to-the-party?from_search=true&amp;from_srp=true&amp;qid=YXWUUxSSv1&amp;rank=1"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Late to the Party</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, I was more than willing to give it a chance. Turns out, second chances are an apt theme for this entire review: they’re an important aspect of the novel, but also, giving Quindlen a second chance was </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">easily</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> one of the better decisions I’ve made all year.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Late to the Party</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> accentuates Quindlen’s strengths as a writer by centering the novel on friendship. There’s some really excellent queer romance in this novel, but it comes in second to the platonic relationships, particularly those among Codi, our introverted, artistic main character, and her two best friends since forever, Maritza and JaKory. Right off the bat, we learn that this kind of queer narrative is completely different from </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Her Name in the Sky:</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> where Hannah’s friend group was mostly straight, Codi is a lesbian, Maritza bisexual, and JaKory gay. In a very sweet and realistic way, we see the three of them come out to each other, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">at the same time</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, without any fuss or drama or fanfare. It’s really amazing and still refreshing that this isn’t a story </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">about</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> being queer: it’s about characters who are messy and complicated and yes, also just so happen to be queer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The central conflict of the novel comes from the fact that the three friends—who are all a bit introverted—feel they’re missing out on “typical” teenage experiences. None of them has ever been to a party or out on a date, and their lack of experience is beginning to chafe at them. Codi, too, is growing discontented with their friendship: she fears that because Maritza and JaKory have known her forever, they have an outdated idea of her in their heads and don’t see the real, dynamic Codi who’s capable of more. In part as an effort to let this real, dynamic Codi shine, Codi attends a party being thrown by the cool kids—and in so doing meets Ricky, a popular kid whom she accidentally discovers kissing another boy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The bond that forms between Codi and Ricky is one of the novel’s strongest: on the surface, they don’t have much in common, but this chance encounter with the secret of Ricky’s queerness creates an opening for something deep and true. Ricky’s not totally comfortable with his sexuality, but Codi makes it clear that not only is his secret safe, but she can empathize with what he’s going through, in a way the rest of his friends (although it’s made clear that they would<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19276 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/people-2589091_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/people-2589091_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/people-2589091_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/people-2589091_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/people-2589091_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/people-2589091_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> be supportive) really can’t. Ricky, in return, takes Codi under his wing: he introduces her to his friends and to all the things she’s felt she was missing out on. This includes parties, alcohol, nighttime romps on the town, and, most significantly for Codi, a beautiful girl named Lydia with whom she instantly connects. These experiences and these characters are so </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">alive</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> they seem to jump right off the page, and, best of all, Codi isn’t punished for drinking and going to parties. Part of me was braced for some kind of teen cliché peer-pressure situation with her newfound friend group, but it never came. Ricky’s friends are the “cool kids”, but they also are genuinely nice, supportive of Codi’s talent as an artist, and don’t make a big deal of it when she doesn’t want to drink or smoke. Which was wildly, <em>awesomely</em> refreshing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course, getting a second chance at being what Codi calls a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">real</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> teenager means potential complications with her old friend group—which Quindlen handles well, in a way that makes it clear everyone has things to apologize for but nobody’s a bad person. They’re just teenagers—messy, complicated, and incidentally, queer. I adored this book with every part of me (especially the part of me that’s still a queer, anxious, introverted teen) and can’t wait to see what Quindlen does next. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-late-to-the-party-kelly-quindlen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: You Should See Me in a Crown, Leah Johnson</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-you-should-see-me-in-a-crown-leah-johnson/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexa Kelly]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Lesbrarian's Corner]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18954</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In recent years, I’ve seen a completely amazing trend take root in YA literature: what&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In recent years, I’ve seen a completely amazing trend take root in YA literature: what I like to call “zany high school hijinks </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">but make them gay.”</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> For somebody who grew up at a time when a lot of LGBT books for teens were either a.) all about the pain of being gay, or b.) all about the pain and drama of coming out, I absolutely cannot get enough of this new wave of LGBT YA. In part because it really emphasizes that being LGBT is normal, good, and way more common than a lot of people think; and in part because, dammit, these books are </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">fun</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. When I think back to when I was a teenager reading YA, and how much I scoffed at those “cliché high school stories,” I can’t help but wonder if what I really disliked about them was that nothing about them felt relatable.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Representation matters, and it matters especially for queer people of color in a literary landscape that still, for the LGBT community and at large, looks overwhelmingly white. For this and about a <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19042 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/50160619._SX0_SY0_-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/50160619._SX0_SY0_-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/50160619._SX0_SY0_-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/50160619._SX0_SY0_-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/50160619._SX0_SY0_-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/50160619._SX0_SY0_-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/50160619._SX0_SY0_.jpg 1650w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />million other reasons, Leah Johnson’s debut novel </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">You Should See Me in a Crown</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">—featuring a queer Black protagonist campaigning to be her high school’s prom queen—is both a breath of fresh air and an absolute delight.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s Liz Lighty’s senior year of high school, and she’s got it all figured out. Sure, her high school years weren’t a walk in the park—in addition to being Black and poor in a majority white and rich community, Liz has suffered from anxiety since childhood, and only her family and closest friends know that she’s queer. But Liz is smart and ambitious (she’s class valedictorian AND first chair in her school orchestra), and she already has her ticket out of small-town Indiana: she’s been accepted to the prestigious Pennington College, her late mother’s alma mater. However, at the last minute, scholarship money she had counted on to pay her tuition falls through. Left with no other good options, Liz makes what is, for her, a radical decision: to throw her hat in the ring for a scholarship Campbell County High School awards each year—to the prom queen.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But prom is no joke at Campbell County High School—it’s an obsession, for both the students and the community at large. I loved the way Johnson wrote the prom to be this larger-than-life event, overinflated in its importance to not just the students at Campbell, but many of the teachers, as well. It felt like a riff on the (often true) stereotype of high schools that are obsessed with their student athletes, and was really creative in what it demanded from Liz. Campaigning for prom king and queen is like being in a bizarre cross between a Miss America pageant and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Amazing Race</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, with bake-offs, community service projects, powder puff football games, and, of course, good old-fashioned campaign posters and buttons. All of which is fanatically documented on social media by a group that calls themselves the Prom Projectioners. It’s a ridiculously high-stress environment for someone like Liz: quiet, reserved, and eager to go unnoticed. To say nothing of her competition, which includes mean girl Rachel Collins, her former best friend Jordan Jennings, and a new girl named Mack whom Liz </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">miiiiiiight</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> just have a bit of a crush on.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">T</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">he really magical thing about this novel is that it starts w</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">ith Liz and her friends desperately trying to</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> turn her into a prom queen—like the cliché </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19043 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/leah-johnson-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/leah-johnson-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/leah-johnson-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/leah-johnson.jpg 399w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">makeover seen in teen movies where the “ugly duckling” turns into a swan. But gradually, something amazing starts to happen: Liz succeeds not by changing herself, but by being exactly who s</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">he is and utilizing strengths she already has. What’s more, she discovers that people </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">like</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> her for being exactly who she is. In an </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/blog/show/1861-meet-the-authors-of-june-s-popular-queer-young-adult-fiction?ref=book-show"><span style="font-weight: 400;">interview</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with Goodreads, Leah Johnson stated that her aim in writing this story was “for Black girls to come to my books and walk away knowing that they are loved. That they deserve beautiful things—that they are their own most beautiful thing.” Liz discovers that she is her own most beautiful thing not in spite of the things that make her different in her community—being Black, poor, and queer—but because of them, and the response from the community around her reflects that in a really beautiful, positive way.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course, it isn’t all kindness and support from every corner. Liz does meet with pushback from bullies and the school administration, who don’t mind if she wins prom queen—as long as it’s on their terms. </span></p>
<blockquote><p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">You could make history if you just follow our rules.</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">You could be a real credit to your people if you just straighten up and fly right.</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">You could actually be worth something if you would shut up and take what we give you.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And I know then what I’ve always known: Campbell is never going to make a space for me to fit. I’m going to have to demand it. </span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a powerful, affirming book, but it’s also fun and full of joy and has some downright </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">swoony</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> romantic scenes. (I guess I’m someone who </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">swoons</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, now? The romance was definitely swoony.) If for some reason that doesn’t convince you, there’s a part midway through the book where a character goes on a rant about how </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avatar: The Last Airbender</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is the greatest show ever made. Leah Johnson, I knew you were speaking my language. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Upright Women Wanted, Sarah Gailey</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-upright-women-wanted-sarah-gailey/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexa Kelly]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 10:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Lesbrarian's Corner]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I came out in 2016. At that time I was living in a relatively conservative,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I came out in 2016. At that time I was living in a relatively conservative, isolated environment, and the idea that anyone—beyond a handful of close friends—might accept me seemed impossibly farfetched. It was a lonely, frightening thing to come to terms with, especially since television was one of my few outlets for positive LGBT representation: 2016 happened to be </span><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/feature/nbc-out/bury-your-gays-why-are-so-many-queer-women-dying-n677386"><span style="font-weight: 400;">very</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="https://www.vox.com/2016/7/13/12172166/bury-your-gays-death-the-100"><span style="font-weight: 400;">very</span></a> <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/record-highs-black-transgender-characters-tv-glaad-report-finds-943208"><span style="font-weight: 400;">bad</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for queer women on television. When the most prominent stories available to you seem to reaffirm what you already believe to be true—that people like you can’t have happy endings—what reason do you have to hope?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is th</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-18706 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/upright-188x300.jpg" alt="" width="188" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/upright-188x300.jpg 188w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/upright.jpg 297w" sizes="(max-width: 188px) 100vw, 188px" /></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">e question at the heart of Sarah Gailey’s novella </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upright Women W</span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">anted</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Part action-adventure, part political parable, this tale of queer librarians working in secret against a totalitarian government challenges the status quo in more ways than one. Set in a future America of endless war and crumbling infrastructure—an America that has</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> deteriorated so much as to resemble the Wild West of its past—the novella follows a group of Librarians, who in this future society are travelers tasked with distributing state-approved materials to the far-flung communities of the Southwest. It’s an important government job: in this society, possessing “unapproved materials” is sufficient cause for hanging. The Librarians are therefore regarded as a kind of moral police, maintaining the status quo by ensuring that the only media people are exposed to is that which the government has deemed appropriate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Esther, the protagonist of the novella, has some experience with the consequences of not maintaining the status quo. The story begins with her best friend and secret lover, Beatriz, being publicly hanged for “deviance” and “possession of unapproved materials.” The trauma of witnessing Beatriz’s death is compounded by her father quickly arranging a marriage for her—to the man who was intended for Beatriz. Unable to bear the idea of becoming a wife, and overcome with guilt over Beatriz’s death (which Esther views as a consequence of their “deviant” love), Esther stows away with a group of Librarians in the hopes that they will let her become one of them. She believes that because the Librarians are (supposedly) “chaste, and morally upright, and&#8230;loyal to the State no matter what,” they are her only hope of redemption.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I know my bill’s in the mail,” she said bitterly. “Just a matter of time before I get what’s </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">coming to me. But I thought that maybe if I did enough good, if I just stayed on the right </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">path&#8230;maybe I’d be alright. Maybe I wouldn’t bring hurt to anyone else’s life.”</span></i></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Librarians, however, turn out to not be at all what Esther envisioned. The Head Librarian, Bet, and her second-in-command, Leda, are a lesbian couple, while Bet’s Apprentice Librarian, Cye, is nonbinary and uses they/them pronouns. All of which mark them as deviant under the eye of the totalitarian State; working as Librarians is not only their protection, but their cover for the subversive, anti-government work they actually do. What follows is a delightful, action-packed, gunslinging romp complete with chases on horseback and lots of flirtatious bickering between Cye and Esther. And that’s so much fun, but what really took my breath away was the secondary plot of Esther, by becoming a Librarian, unlearning everything she once thought was true.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Esther is queer. The novella makes it clear that she’s a woman who only loves people who aren’t men. Just like when I came out, she experiences a sense of isolation, but also, she’s been deliberately only exposed to stories that describe her feelings as evil, wrong</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-18707 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kimberly-farmer-lUaaKCUANVI-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kimberly-farmer-lUaaKCUANVI-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kimberly-farmer-lUaaKCUANVI-unsplash-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kimberly-farmer-lUaaKCUANVI-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kimberly-farmer-lUaaKCUANVI-unsplash-1536x1021.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kimberly-farmer-lUaaKCUANVI-unsplash-2048x1362.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and bound to destroy her. Gailey makes passing mention of some of these titles, which are evocative of lesbian pulp novels of the 1950s—books which could only be published if they ended in a death or tragedy. With these books serving as Esther’s only frame of reference for learning about herself as a queer person, it’s no wonder she believes she’s destined to cause harm to others and herself just by being who she is. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the most prominent stories available to you seem to reaffirm what you already believe to be true—that people like you can’t have happy endings—what reason do you have to hope?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s a profoundly moving conversation in the middle of the book wherein Amity, an “insurrectionist” the Librarians are smuggling to safety in Utah, dismantles Esther’s learned notions by forcing her to question where they come from. Esther admits they come from the books; Amity asks her where the books come from. Librarians gave her the books, but who gave them to the Librarians? And what do <em>they</em> want you to believe about yourself?</span></p>
<blockquote><p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;You might not have a happy ending coming to you&#8230; But if you come to a bad end, it won’t be </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">on account of what kind of person you fall for. I’ve seen a lot more of the world than you have, </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">and I can tell you upright: I’ve seen as many good ends as bad ones for your kind of heart.”</span></i></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I needed to hear these words as badly as Esther did, once upon a time. I know the same is true for so many young LGBT people coming to terms with who they are in a world that, still, is not always kind, and wants you to believe all the wrong things about yourself. If I have a single complaint about this book, it’s that I wanted way, way more of it—it’s a quick read at just about two hundred pages. I could happily have lived in this world of queer, gunslinging librarians fighting the patriarchy and falling in love for a long, long time. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
