<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Jan Stinchcomb &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/jan-stinchcomb/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:28:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>A Changeling in Our Midst: Lisa Carey&#8217;s The Stolen Child</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-changeling-in-our-midst-lisa-careys-the-stolen-child/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jan Stinchcomb]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 11:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes from Rapunzel's Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For my final review I am going straight to the fairies and the havoc they&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/StolenChild.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8631 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/StolenChild-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>For my final review I am going straight to the fairies and the havoc they wreak in the lives of mortals.</p>
<p>Lisa Carey’s <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Stolen-Child-Novel-Lisa-Carey/dp/0062492187/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1506709153&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=the+stolen+child+by+lisa+carey"><em>The Stolen Child</em></a> is set on Saint Brigid’s island off the coast of Ireland in the late 1950s. The conditions could not be more primitive or intimidating, with no electricity, no doctor and no harbor, but when an American woman named Brigid inherits her uncle’s property there, nothing can keep her away. She is strong and talented, a healer and a midwife. Because her Irish mother was raised on this same island, Brigid understands the language and knows more than the natives at first realize. She also has an agenda: there is something she wants on Saint Brigid’s, but to get it she must first enter into the lives of its secretive inhabitants.</p>
<p>While trying to create a life from the soil up, Brigid meets a pair of sisters, Rose and Emer, who are her link to the local culture. Rose is beautiful and well liked, while Emer is shunned and misunderstood. Emer is also a woman who has tangled with fairies. She holds them responsible for a childhood accident during which she lost an eye, and she lives in the fear that they will one day take her son, Niall. (She believes a <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/tree-3082498_1920.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9455 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/tree-3082498_1920-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a>fairy saved Niall shortly after his birth, and unfortunately fairies always come back to reclaim such children.) Niall appears to suffer from what might normally be considered a neurological disorder, and Emer won’t let him out of her sight. She would prefer to leave Saint Brigid’s and is one of the few people to support a government-backed evacuation and relocation project.</p>
<p>On this enchanting and sometimes menacing island Brigid discovers a culture that exists somewhere between the world of the fairies and that of the Catholic faith. Saint Brigid, after whom the island is named, has a dual nature, fueled by both Christian and pagan narratives. At first Brigid is puzzled by the contradictions in the people around her:</p>
<blockquote><p>“On the one hand they are superstitious, never walking past places where fairies might cause mischief, crossing themselves multiple times a day. On the other they seem pragmatic and dismiss notions of fairies when it suits them. Rose will talk of Emer as if she is cursed and then act as if she is just regrettably sour. They seem to respect some parallel world at the same time as they brush the very idea of it away.”</p></blockquote>
<p>In this parallel world Brigid will find the answers she seeks, which are linked to her own dark past and family history.</p>
<p>Brigid learns the location of the island’s sacred well, said to “cure illness and infertility and protect babies’ souls,” only after she enters into an intimate relationship with Emer. She wants a child and needs a miracle to address the specific cause of her infertility. Unfortunately, the lesbian relationship in this novel is of the depressing and shame-ridden variety, and it does not end happily. While I understand that the novel is set in Ireland in 1959, I still could not help but feel disappointed by this strand of the narrative. Overall, however, <em>The Stolen Child</em> is a well-constructed novel that earns its optimistic ending.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/ramdan-authentic-490594.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9456 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/ramdan-authentic-490594-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>This novel made me think about parenthood in a new way, through the lens of the other side. Changelings come from the fairy realm. They are exchanged for a human child, usually in infancy but sometimes later. Changeling tales exist all over the world, and in these stories the human family will typically go to great lengths to get the original child back. At the most basic level, <a href="http://www.pitt.edu/~dash/changeling.html#perspective">the changeling motif in folklore</a> reflects human fears of being lost or of losing one’s child. Carey demonstrates that the anxiety around the changeling entity in any culture stems from a painful awareness that our children don’t ever truly belong to us. We cannot guarantee their safety. The threat of separation and death is never absent from parenting territory.</p>
<p>If you enjoy this topic, two other important novels were published in 2017: Hannah Kent’s <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Good-People-Hannah-Kent/dp/0316243965/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1506709275&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+good+people+hannah+kent"><em>The Good People</em></a> and Victor Lavalle’s <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Changeling-Novel-Victor-LaValle/dp/0812995945/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1506709321&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=victor+lavalle+s+the+changeling"><em>The Changeling</em></a>. Another old favorite of mine is Keith Donohue’s <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Stolen-Child-Keith-Donohue/dp/1400096537/ref=sr_1_4?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1506709365&amp;sr=1-4&amp;keywords=keith+donohue"><em>The Stolen Child</em></a>.</p>
<p>This is where I leave you, in the realm of magic. I want to thank my editors at <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> and all my readers for giving me this column. I hope I have inspired you to keep this genre alive. Thank you for reading.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Girl Who Will Save Us: Katherine Arden&#8217;s &#8220;The Bear and the Nightingale&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-girl-who-will-save-us-katherine-ardens-the-bear-and-the-nightingale/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jan Stinchcomb]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 12:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes from Rapunzel's Tower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve been waiting all my life for a truly satisfying retelling of my all-time favorite&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/51DuDUQYWQL.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignnone wp-image-8518 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/51DuDUQYWQL-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>I’ve been waiting all my life for a truly satisfying retelling of my all-time favorite fairy tale, “Vasilisa the Wise,” and <a href="http://www.katherinearden.com/about">Katherine Arden</a> has delivered it in a novel that combines history, fantasy, and folk magic. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bear-Nightingale-Novel-Katherine-Arden/dp/1101885955/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1501086293&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=the+bear+and+the+nightingale"><em>The Bear and the Nightingale</em></a> brings Vasilisa, here called Vasya, into contact with Morozko, Russian folklore’s brutal Winter King. The result is a surprisingly modern heroine who transcends genre.</p>
<p>Vasilisa is a recurring character in Russian fairy tales. The best-known tale features her as a motherless young woman tormented by her stepmother while her father is away. She is sent to get fire from the dreadful, flesh-craving <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/baba-yaga/">Baba Yaga</a> but emerges triumphant with the help of a magic doll her mother gave her, and in most versions she marries the tsar himself. Arden’s Vasya lives in a northern village in medieval Russia under Ivan II. Her mother, Marina, dies shortly after giving birth and leaves her to the care of a trusted servant. Vasya’s noble family lives far enough from Moscow to stay clear of most court intrigue and closer to the old ways, particularly the spirit world of pagan times. And those old beliefs, to which Vasya dedicates her life, are at the heart of this novel.</p>
<p>Vasya does not merely believe in the Russian spirit world, she is an active participant. She is friends with a water sprite (rusalka); she works with her household spirit (domovoi) to protect her family from evil; and as an accomplished equestrienne she has a devoted relationship with the spirit who inhabits the stable (vazila). Her stepmother, the pious Anna Ivanovna, also believes in spirits but is tormented by them and feels safe only in churches. The arrival of a certain Father Konstantin to their village pits the Russian Orthodox Church against the pagan spirit world, and the central conflict of the novel is thus established.</p>
<p>Regardless of her spiritual beliefs and practices, Vasya is a social misfit and a threat to patriarchal order. In a world where girls must marry or join a convent, Vasya does not conform: “All my life . . . I have been told ‘go’ and ‘come.&#8217; I am told how I will live, and I am told how I must die. I must be a man’s servant and a mare for his pleasure, or I must hide myself behind walls and surrender my flesh to a cold, silent god. I would walk into the jaws of hell itself, if it were a path of my own choosing. I would rather die tomorrow in the forest than live a hundred years of the life appointed me.” No self-sacrificing female, she is constantly snatching food and running off to take care of herself or to commune with nature. She freely admits to being “bad” and failing to fulfill the requirements for femininity in her patriarchal culture, and, as we are reminded by so many male characters, she’s not even pretty.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/nikolay-vorobyev-470715.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9185 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/nikolay-vorobyev-470715-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Vasya needs all her strength to battle certain shadowy figures who have been tracking her movements since childhood. Village tensions mount throughout the novel, and Vasya finds herself in increasing danger as men like Father Konstantin deem her gifts and “wild” temperament as evil. Arden even adds vampires to this charged folklore blend, and there is a battle scene at the novel’s end that can hold its own alongside any other in epic fantasy. It’s what Arden does with the figure of Morozko that takes this novel to new places and imagines an interesting destiny for Vasya. Arden keeps us guessing to the very end: will the Winter King be the death of Vasya or will he save her? Is he the evil entity that has been plaguing her since girlhood? I won’t reveal Arden’s solution, but I am happy to announce that Vasya does not get married. She mounts the fabulous horse Morozko has given her and sets off with the intention of traveling the world.</p>
<p>Arden’s particular strength results from blending history with fairy tales, and this becomes the key that allows us to enter into the mentality of the past. She takes us to a time when spirits were real and lived alongside us. It is easy to imagine that certain people, like Vasya, communicated directly with them. One could be in dialogue with the other side, and it was possible to be a pagan and a Christian at the same time. At the end of this novel we are left with an important question: does evil rise up when we fail to strike a balance between old and new gods, between one set of fairy tales and another?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wilhelm Grimm&#8217;s Girl Next Door: The Wild Girl by Kate Forsyth</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/wilhelm-grimms-girl-next-door-the-wild-girl-by-kate-forsyth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jan Stinchcomb]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes from Rapunzel's Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kate Forsyth challenges the notion of the woman-as-muse in The Wild Girl, a novel that imagines the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/51N4NdTzckL.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignnone wp-image-8391 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/51N4NdTzckL-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a><a href="http://www.kateforsyth.com.au/">Kate Forsyth</a> challenges the notion of the woman-as-muse in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Wild-Girl-Novel-Kate-Forsyth/dp/1250047544/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1493152806&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=the+wild+girl+kate+forsyth"><em>The</em> <em>Wild Girl</em></a>, a novel that imagines the relationship between <a href="https://www.biography.com/people/wilhelm-grimm-21085173">Wilhelm Grimm</a> and his neighbor, <a href="https://www.wikitree.com/wiki/Wild-349">Dorothea Wild</a>. Known as Dortchen, this woman did more than inspire Wilhelm Grimm: she told him many of the tales that would eventually appear in the collection that made him famous. In Forsyth’s novel the couple endures various hardships before they marry, including Napoleon’s occupation of the German kingdom of Hessen-Cassel and a long battle with an ogre in the form of Dortchen’s abusive father.</p>
<p>In <em>The Wild Girl,</em> storytelling functions to further the romantic relationship between Dortchen and Wilhelm. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/63143au.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8986 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/63143au-186x300.jpg" alt="" width="186" height="300" /></a>As she recounts and he records, the old tales become a seduction and a celebration, an excuse to spend time together, and a declaration of citizenship and love of culture. Telling stories is also a way for Dortchen to retain some power in this relationship. She is not a scholar and has little time to read, but she provides the material that builds Wilhelm&#8217;s career. Wilhelm leaves much to be desired as a suitor, due to his poor health and financial dependence on his brother and collaborator, Jacob. When Wilhelm fails to give Dortchen any credit after the first edition of the fairy tales comes out, he causes a rupture that nearly destroys them. Ultimately the stories are what save them as a couple. And when Wilhelm and Dortchen work together, they become part of a greater project to promote German culture. As Wilhelm explains, “You see, that’s why it’s important to preserve the old stories, before all our ways are smothered by the customs of the French. Those who remember the old tales are getting fewer all the time. If we don’t save them, they’ll be lost forever, and that seems sad to me.”</p>
<p>Scholars generally agree that Dorothea Wild told Wilhelm Grimm a fourth of the stories that appear in the first collection of the Grimm tales, including “The Wild Swans,” “Hansel and Gretel,” “Rumpelstiltskin,” and “The Frog King.” In her long relationship with Wilhelm, Dortchen plays many roles, and it soon becomes apparent that she functions as his editor. The simple act of remembering and retelling is significant: Dortchen chooses which tales to tell Wilhelm, and these stories go on to take a permanent place in world literature. Her most important suggestion to Wilhelm pertains to marketing, which is always at the core of publication concerns: “There are more children in Germany than scholars . . . So why not write a book for children, in the hope you will get more sales?”<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/22917.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8985 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/22917-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Against the backdrop of war, poverty, and continual regime change, the true antagonist to the couple’s happiness is Dortchen’s abusive father. Forsyth admits that the scenes of horrific sexual abuse are her own invention, but it does make one wonder about the violence of the original, unedited tales. Can the physical horror of the Grimm universe be read as a metaphor for what children, especially females, suffer under patriarchy? Dortchen is a classic survivor, blessed with many skills, in addition to storytelling, which promote household success and prosperity. She is an excellent cook and good with children, but she is also an herbalist who combines her training as an apothecary’s daughter with her instincts for finding medicinal plants in the soil of her homeland. On several occasions throughout the novel she literally keeps other characters alive or lessens their suffering.</p>
<p>Wilhelm may be a disappointing leading man, but aside from Napoleon himself, he is one of the few characters in the novel to leave an enduring legacy. He finds success not only in publication but in furthering the triumph of the human spirit: “The whole reason for telling the fairy tales is to awaken the heart. To help people <em>believe</em> that misfortune can be overcome and evil conquered. If the fairy tales are to do their work, they must shine.” In one of the novel’s most poignant moments, Dortchen goes to a poorhouse to hear a toothless old woman, known as the Story Wife, share “Cinderella” with a group of mistreated orphans. Here Forsyth takes us to the heart of all storytelling: not only do we recognize &#8220;Cinderella&#8221; as one of the most famous fairy tales, but we feel its power when told to the audience that needs it the most.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fairy Tales for the New World Order: Circuits and Slippers, edited by Jaylee James</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fairy-tales-for-the-new-world-order-circuits-and-slippers-edited-by-jaylee-james/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jan Stinchcomb]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 17:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes from Rapunzel's Tower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7951</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is both gratifying and heartbreaking when reality begins to resemble sci-fi and fantasy: genre&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/CircuitsAndSlippers.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7971 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/CircuitsAndSlippers-200x300.jpg" width="200" height="300" /></a>It is both gratifying and heartbreaking when reality begins to resemble sci-fi and fantasy: genre fiction gets an unexpected upgrade as the predictions of mere writers come true. This collection of twenty sci-fi infused fairy tales, published in September of 2016, came at exactly the right time. Now that dystopia is becoming the new normal, these stories are disturbingly relevant, and close reading is often a painful experience. The heroines/heroes of these tales&#8211;many of them competent scientists and engineers&#8211;challenge our understanding of gender norms and identity while saving the day, or at least fighting for clarity. As a further bonus <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Circuits-Slippers-Jaylee-James/dp/1537375903/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1485371454&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=circuits+and+slippers"><em>Circuits and Slippers</em></a> draws from classic and lesser-known tales from various world cultures. Appropriately, “Rapunzel,” “Little Red Riding Hood” and “The Princess and the Pea” each get two re-tellings.</p>
<p>A sampling of what you will find: a new “Jack and the Beanstalk” set in a dystopia struggling with a food shortage; a truly interesting Red Riding Hood, who is both hunter and hunted in a fragmented, fascist society; a new version of “The Princess and the Pea” featuring a hybrid who must outwit the queen in a high-tech pea test; a zoo-specimen Rapunzel who believes herself to be the last of our species; a Goldilocks who is part of an “experimental procedure” that forces questions about her identity and the nature of reality; and my favorite, a retelling of “The Little Mermaid” stars a male cyborg in a beautifully rendered seaside setting.</p>
<p>Disaster, or any life-altering crisis, is always a crucial element in the landscape of dystopia. An illness or epidemic can serve as an equalizer in the power dynamic that controls human destiny. Doctor Paige Bell, the heroine of L.G. Keltner&#8217;s “Treating the Beast,” a retelling of “Beauty and the Beast,” is forced to reconsider history and the meaning of evil. She has no choice but to treat a corrupt official from a privileged background, Chancellor Beaumont, whose family is guilty of involvement with terrorists and a subsequent cover-up. Paige’s unwillingness to condemn his fascist actions is both poignant and infuriating: “There had been so many times when she would have given anything to tell this man just what she thought of him. Yet now, faced with the perfect opportunity to tell him that people were right to see him as a monster, the words wouldn’t come. Was it compassion on her part, or weakness? Was she right to question her assumptions?”</p>
<p>Paige is a scientist, trained to be objective. She is living in a world where she cannot be too careful and where she is still called upon to perform her duties as a doctor. But I prefer to cling to the advice that Paige’s dissident father gave her before his arrest: “Be brave. Act confident, even when you’re not. The world is too cruel for self-doubt.” I urge everyone to follow his advice, to keep writing and speaking out. There is so much work to be done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The True Story of Hansel and Gretel, a Novel of War and Survival (Louise Murphy)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-true-story-of-hansel-and-gretel-a-novel-of-war-and-survival-louise-murphy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jan Stinchcomb]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 17:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes from Rapunzel's Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7388</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I don’t know about you, but lately I’ve been thinking a lot about World War&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/61dEBCxYPOL.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7402 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/61dEBCxYPOL-169x300.jpg" alt="61debcxypol" width="169" height="300" /></a>I don’t know about you, but lately I’ve been thinking a lot about World War II and the Nazis. This election season has been the perfect time to rediscover Louise Murphy’s novel from 2003, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/True-Story-Hansel-Gretel-Survival/dp/0142003077/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1476225853&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+true+story+of+hansel+and+gretel"><em>The True Story of Hansel and Gretel </em></a>. An account of a brother and sister who survive the Holocaust, this novel follows the structure and reinvents the stock characters of the famous fairy tale. The witch is an old Romani woman, an outcast and a keeper of secrets, who takes the children in. The stepmother encourages abandoning the children but then reappears when she is most needed, to perform an unselfish act. The woodsman is both pariah and hero. Hansel and Gretel themselves are two Jewish children who must give up their real names and heritage and then rely on the forest, and the decency of strangers, to teach them everything.</p>
<p>Murphy’s novel examines the brutality of the SS and is very much like a Grimm tale in its violence, including unfortunate but necessary scenes that depict the mutilation of children. The source of evil in this novel is the doomed Nazi project of assimilation, which does nothing more than prove the impossibility of purity. Here the Nazis are the real witches, stealing children with Aryan features to populate their new Germany. Children in danger are the stars of the fairy tale genre, and Murphy will have you holding your breath as you see what happens to these siblings.</p>
<p>The author’s ingenuity in reworking certain fairy tale motifs is exceptional. A tank painted white for winter camouflage becomes a swan that ferries the children to safety. The infamous oven of the original tale plays multiple roles, including hiding the children to keeping them safe. Later the &#8220;witch&#8221; character ends up in another famous oven, at Birkenau. Breadcrumbs are sprinkled throughout the novel, linking hunger, loss and family love. They lead Hansel back to his father after a journey that has taken the children out of the forest and all the way to the refugee center in the city of Bialystok:</p>
<blockquote><p>“He was crying now. He moved away from his sister and crouched on the floor, sweeping the crumbs up and putting them in his pockets, trying to get every one. He followed the trail of flakes from the dozens and dozens of loaves of bread brought out of the ovens, and he was determined to pick up all the bread, all the luck that he had dropped and thrown away. He crawled across the floor, white-faced, intent, not missing a crumb.”</p></blockquote>
<p>In Murphy’s hands the ancient <a href="http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/33">Bialowieza Forest</a> becomes so much more than a setting. It is a place to hide and a place to be lost. It provides refuge to Hansel and Gretel and to the partisans who, despite their own differences, fight the German forces. It is a site of violence against animals and humans and at the same time a place of joy, miracles and forgiveness.</p>
<p>Whether you see the original “Hansel and Gretel” as a fairy tale about hunger, or a story of family politics, Murphy&#8217;s retelling never ceases to impress with its originality and depth. Human cruelty exists alongside acts of courage and selflessness. This “Hansel and Gretel” ultimately concerns the reinvention of the self, a constant theme for those who fled Hitler’s Europe. It is no accident that we are never told the children’s real names.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lock Up Your Daughters: The Girls at the Kingfisher Club by Genevieve Valentine</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lock-up-your-daughters-the-girls-at-the-kingfisher-club-by-genevieve-valentine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jan Stinchcomb]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 16:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes from Rapunzel's Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the fairy tale “The Twelve Dancing Princesses” a king offers a reward to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/index-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6956 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/index-2.jpg" alt="index" width="182" height="277" /></a>In the fairy tale “The Twelve Dancing Princesses” a king offers a reward to the man who can solve a mystery involving his daughters: though they sleep alone in a locked room every night, the worn soles of their shoes suggest they’ve been having adventures in the outside world. Aided by a witch, a lowly soldier finds the answer, marries the eldest daughter and becomes king (He wisely refuses to drink a sleeping potion and follows the sisters to a castle, where he witnesses them dancing with twelve princes until dawn).</p>
<p>I am always excited when an author revisits a less well-known tale, and Genevieve Valentine’s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Genevieve-Valentine-Novel-Kingfisher-Hardback/dp/B00LZ0QRV0/ref=la_B00481263Q_1_12?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1463941556&amp;sr=1-12"><em>The Girls at the Kingfisher Club</em></a> brings this story into the Roaring Twenties, with its smoky speakeasies and shifting social mores. The Hamilton sisters are twelve individual disappointments to their father, who has always wanted a son. Their mother, so viciously dominated by their father that she has very little presence in the household, dies early on, and everything comes to depend on the eldest sister, Jo. Jo orchestrates the sisters’ secret nighttime voyages to the bars of Manhattan, where they can experience the outside world, and she is the one who must stand up to their father when he tries to marry them off. Only on the dance floor do these young women finally begin to live. The stakes are turned up when their father discovers, after inviting several prospective “princes” into the household, how his daughters have been spending their nights.</p>
<p><em>The Girls at the Kingfisher Club</em> is essentially an examination of the motif of the maiden in the tower. This figure dates back to ancient Greek mythology and has recurred throughout the centuries in various national literatures, according to Kate Forsyth in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Rebirth-Rapunzel-Mythic-Biography-Maiden-ebook/dp/B01CJ0G99Y?ie=UTF8&amp;keywords=kate%20forsyth&amp;qid=1463941297&amp;ref_=sr_1_10&amp;s=books&amp;sr=1-10"><em>The Rebirth of Rapunzel: A Mythic Biography of the Maiden in the Tower</em></a>. Often these maidens are controlled by a patriarchal figure, one who is frightened of their power, yet at the same time they are portrayed as passive. Genevieve Valentine offers us twelve sisters, led by the eldest, who must get out of a tower that is more than metaphorical. But instead of relying on a prince or magic, they draw on a combination of courage and community connection to change their lives.</p>
<p>What are Jo and her sisters actually doing? Over the course of their lives, and especially after their escape, they are learning to be financially independent. Several of the sisters go to work, either as seamstresses or stenographers, or, in the case of the three most adventurous, Hollywood actresses. Jo herself becomes a hostess at a bar. What they are doing on a nightly basis, however, in addition to dancing, is soaking up the atmosphere of the time in which they live. Talking to men. Learning how to be safe in the world. Becoming the kind of women who are comfortable in the city at night&#8211;and I don’t mean prostitutes. They are staking their claim to the same public life that is granted without question to their male counterparts.</p>
<p>Valentine demonstrates that confinement can be cognitive or emotional as well as physical. The sisters&#8217;  attic rooms are both physically drab and feel stuck in time: the space itself keeps these women under an age-old patriarchal spell and deprives them of agency. Refusing to educate women or teach them a trade freezes them in a childlike state; there is no terror like that of a penniless woman in a capitalist society. When Jo and her sisters flee the family house, they put themselves in financial peril and physical danger. Their flight is an act of self-preservation, however, for when their father discovers their nightly misdeeds, he threatens them with that other famous site of female confinement, the insane asylum (His claim that he can commit them on the basis of something called “hysterical alcoholism” would be amusing if it didn’t demonstrate his lethal misogyny).</p>
<p>The figure of Jo, who makes painful emotional choices for the good of her sisters, alternates between independence and self-sacrifice. In assuming the role of matriarch, she reminds us that women with children are never free. When she takes a rare solo walk through the city, we see how things as basic as solitude and personal liberty have been lost to her:</p>
<blockquote><p>“She walked without thinking, past the house on Seventy-Ninth that looked like a palace in a Gothic fairy tale, turning onto Lexington when the sharp blue awnings of a chemist caught her eye, ignoring the ache in her feet. She was angry enough that it thrilled her to be lost, with no one to answer to, no one to keep track of, without anywhere to be or anyone to tell where she was going.”</p></blockquote>
<p>This fairy-tale novel, told in a realistic mode and set in the progressive 1920s, should continue to please a wide audience.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Survival of Small Children: Gretel and the Dark by Eliza Granville</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-survival-of-small-children-gretel-and-the-dark-by-eliza-granville/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jan Stinchcomb]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 16:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes from Rapunzel's Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When we read the classic tales of good versus evil, it is natural to identify&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/9781594633959.jpeg" rel="attachment wp-att-6002"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6002 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/9781594633959-200x300.jpeg" alt="9781594633959" width="200" height="300" /></a>When we read the classic tales of good versus evil, it is natural to identify with the victor, especially if that character is an underdog. Of course, anybody can do this with any story. The NRA recently released some <a href="http://www.nrafamily.org/articles/2016/1/13/little-red-riding-hood-has-a-gun/">fairy tale rewrites</a> featuring such groan-worthy updates as a shotgun-wielding grandmother in “Little Red Riding Hood.” Before reading Eliza Granville, I did not know that the Nazis made their own <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/history/world-war-two/7594061/Nazi-fairy-tales-paint-Hitler-as-Little-Red-Riding-Hoods-saviour.html">fairy tale propaganda films</a>, targeted at children, often placing Hitler in the role of rescuer. <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18242996-gretel-and-the-dark"><em>Gretel and the Dark</em> </a>is inspired in part by the Third Reich’s appropriation of this art form as an expression of nationalism. Granville&#8217;s heroine is a child who lives under the Nazi regime and uses these classic tales to make sense of her nightmare.</p>
<p>This ambitious novel, bolstered by fairy tale themes and plot lines, is composed of two narratives. The first is set in Vienna in 1899, where we follow the exploits of Joseph Breuer, a real life physician who made the first forays into what would come to be known as psychoanalysis. When the novel opens he has acquired a new patient, a beautiful woman he names Lilie, who refuses to discuss her origins but appears to have suffered a trauma. There is one topic she is willing to discuss: she keeps referring to some monster she must destroy before he can do damage. Who is Lilie? Where did she come from? And what is happening in the Vienna, violent and anti-Semitic, that holds the answer to her secret?</p>
<p>The second narrative, told in the voice of a motherless little girl named Krysta, takes place in Nazi Germany. The horrors she endures are filtered through a child’s consciousness and stitched together with actual fairy tales, many of them recognizable to the modern reader, others specific to German culture, and some fabricated for this book. The Krysta sections of the novel are a remarkable achievement: evocative and seamless, mysterious yet eerily familiar, and as satisfyingly horrific as any Grimm tale. Krysta and her father have recently moved into a big house with a garden that would seem idyllic but for the fact that her father has come here to work in a strange, unnamed hospital based on the infamous Ravensbrück concentration camp. In this place, with the help of a series of menacing female figures, he struggles to raise the willful Krysta. Her preferred caregiver, a girl named Greet, is physically absent but lives on through the tales she once told her young charge.</p>
<p><em>Gretel and the Dark</em> is primarily about storytelling, how it helps us to survive terrible ordeals while ensuring that our dark times are never forgotten. As explained by Hanna, an important character Krysta meets after she has lost everything, storytelling is a way to prevent erasure:</p>
<blockquote><p>“‘[S]oon I shall go from here and everything that I have seen or heard, felt, smelled, tasted, enjoyed, loved, will be extinguished and forgotten. There will be nothing left of me but a number on some ledger. And so, I give the Earth my memories.’ She laughs. ‘It’s my talking cure.’”</p></blockquote>
<p>I won’t disclose the connection between Lilie and Krysta. I spent much of the novel trying to figure out how these two narratives, and these two heroines, could possibly come together. At first I was convinced that Krysta grows up to become Lilie, despite the fact that 1899 Vienna comes before Nazi Germany. The resolution, a magical meta-fictive spell, nearly brought me to tears. <em>Gretel and the Dark</em> is an homage to the fairy tale genre, a highly sophisticated work of historical fiction, and an important contribution to Holocaust literature.</p>
<p>Originally published in 2014, this novel is now available as a <a href="http://www.penguin.com/book/gretel-and-the-dark-by-eliza-granville/9781594633959">Riverhead Books paperback</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Appreciating Helen Oyeyemi: Boy, Snow, Bird and Mr. Fox</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/appreciating-helen-oyeyemi-boy-snow-bird-mr-fox/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jan Stinchcomb]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 17:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes from Rapunzel's Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For several months I avoided doing a post on the work of Helen Oyeyemi, one&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For several months I avoided doing a post on the work of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helen_Oyeyemi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Helen Oyeyemi</a>, one of the most obvious choices for this column, because she intimidates me. Oyeyemi’s work is of such high quality, in terms of structure and language, and her re-imagined worlds are so complex, that I could not see how I could possibly describe her contribution in a short blog post.</p>
<p>So I won’t. I will warn you that her novels are challenging yet irresistible, and I will defy you to stay away from them. Now you’re on your own. If this sounds like a fairy-tale lure, it is.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/18079683.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-4641 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/18079683-200x300.jpg" alt="18079683" width="200" height="300" /></a>Last year’s <em><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18079683-boy-snow-bird?from_search=true&amp;search_version=service">Boy, Snow, Bird</a></em> was lauded by many people in the world of speculative fiction. Both Karen Russell and Kelly Link referenced it when they spoke at AWP 2015 (Association for Writers and Writing Programs). This novel is a retelling of “Snow White,” but it quickly expands into an exploration of race, beauty and identity, all of which is done with grace and originality. Family relationships are rendered in their true complexity; allegiances and empathy&#8211;or lack thereof&#8211;evolve over time. The setting, divided between different American cities of the 1950s, is at once recognizable and weird. At the most basic level this is a novel about young women finding their way in the world. The letters exchanged between half-sisters Snow and Bird, which form a good portion of the novel, are genuine and intelligent, a cross-checking of emotion and shared experience.</p>
<p>I especially admire what Oyeyemi has done with Boy, the “wicked” stepmother, always a tricky character for modern readers and writers. We don’t want to dismiss her as purely evil, and we don’t want to excuse her often violent behavior. As Boy explains, in the opening lines of the novel, she herself is a victim of a culture that places enormous stock in that which is only skin-deep: “Nobody ever warned me about mirrors, so for many years I was fond of them, and believed them trustworthy.”</p>
<p>It matters so much what a woman looks like. Skin color matters too much. And that is perhaps the lasting legacy of “Snow White”: you can never rely on what you see in the mirror, and you can&#8217;t always control what is reflected back at you.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/10335337.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-4640 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/10335337-198x300.jpg" alt="10335337" width="198" height="300" /></a>There is so much to say about <em><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10335337-mr-fox?ac=1">Mr. Fox</a></em> (2011). It is a re-examination of “Bluebeard,” focusing on the relationship between an author and his muse, with plenty of interference from his confused wife. Saint John Fox is an author who tends to kill off his heroines, and his muse, Mary, has to assert herself in both the artistic process and in Saint John&#8217;s marriage to the long suffering Daphne. Oyeyemi maintains a playful tone despite the potentially deadly subtext of this material in scenes that range from poignant to hilarious.</p>
<p><em>Mr. Fox</em> is told in several voices with frequently shifting viewpoints. Sprinkled throughout the narrative is an assortment of other tales, some of which reference “Bluebeard” directly, while others don’t (my favorite occurs at the very end of the novel and involves an actual fox and a woman). A narrative this demanding usually makes the reading experience that much richer for me but may be confusing for some readers.</p>
<p>This novel is now my favorite book about writing. It shows what goes on inside an author’s head and how the products of one&#8217;s imagination can be both liberating and tyrannical. Saint John’s troubling relationship with Mary constantly returns to the question of art versus life. There is a choice to be made here, no matter how hard Saint John tries to avoid it. As Mary advises our writer hero, “Your wife loves you. Turn to her. Properly. Stop fobbing her off and being a counterfeit companion. It would be good if, after all this, just once you wrote something where people come together instead of falling apart. Just show me you can do it and I’ll leave you alone.”</p>
<p>It is well worth the sometimes perplexing, always charming journey through this novel to discover the solution to Mr. Fox’s problem.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Girls Who Prefer the Company of the Witch: Baba Yaga&#8217;s Assistant by Marika McCoola, illustrated by Emily Carroll</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/girls-who-prefer-the-company-of-the-witch-baba-yagas-assistant-by-marika-mccoola-illustrated-by-emily-carroll/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jan Stinchcomb]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 17:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes from Rapunzel's Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have something to tell you: I had a Slavic grandmother, a Russian-Polish woman whose&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Baba-Yaga.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-4226 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/Baba-Yaga-213x300.jpg" alt="Baba Yaga" width="213" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>I have something to tell you: I had a Slavic grandmother, a Russian-Polish woman whose parents met in Bessarabia. She was born in Harbin, Manchuria, where there was a Russian colony, and then her family immigrated to the U.S. I went through a serious Russian phase in the nineties, trying to learn the language and living there three times. I’m not sure if this makes me particularly well qualified to review this book or already biased in its favor, but you don’t need my background to be fascinated by Baba Yaga, the most famous witch of the Russian fairy tales, an entity as multi-faceted as she is dreadful.</p>
<p>The Baba Yaga tales are being rewritten all the time, especially by women authors. Marika McCoola’s heroine, Masha, is a young woman who has lost her mother, much like Vasilisa the Wise, of the Russian version. Adjusting to a new family dynamic, which Masha must do when her father remarries, is a daunting task in and of itself. Naturally, there is a stepsister in the mix, and she is the troublemaker here. Masha’s efforts to untangle the little girl’s misdeeds will ultimately unite these new sisters.</p>
<p>What’s so special about Masha? Not only is she unafraid of Baba Yaga, she actually seeks her out. Nobody sends her into the dark forest: she goes of her own accord, after answering a classified ad placed by the witch. She has her magic doll, of course, but she also has an excellent understanding of the guile necessary to contend with Baba Yaga. And she has more power than she at first realizes, which, we come to discover, is part of her inheritance.</p>
<p>There is a lot of work waiting for Masha, all of it in the setting that many of us know by heart. We have the famous house on chicken legs, the skulls, and the witch herself, rendered here by the inimitable Emily Carroll in delicious tones that belong to the night. The tasks Masha must perform are a nightmare version of the cooking, cleaning and general caretaking that underscore the hard labor of domesticity. McCoola adds her own creative touch to Baba Yaga’s arsenal of magic. Who can resist such details as powdered eels, drowned maiden’s hair, harpy feathers, or bleeding hearts? Juxtaposed with magical scenes in the witch’s hut are Masha’s flashbacks to her mother’s death and what it was like growing up without her. We aren’t allowed to forget that the loss of the mother is one of the earliest sources of darkness.</p>
<p>McCoola’s Baba Yaga is unusually personable and even funny. (Youth potions are her specialty!) This book is for ages ten and up, but I think it’s really for all the girls, of any age, who want to go into the forest and keep company with the witch. We are the ones who, when we read the fairy tales, are more intrigued by the witches than by promises of beauty, wealth, and marriage. We know the witch has something to teach us and we would jump at the chance to be her assistant.</p>
<p>This book is scheduled for release in August, but you can boost a debut author and an ancient witch by pre-ordering here:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Baba-Yagas-Assistant-Marika-McCoola/dp/076366961X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1429025324&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=baba+yaga%27s+assistant">http://www.amazon.com/Baba-Yagas-Assistant-Marika-McCoola</a></p>
<p>Or bookmarking it here: https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24727085-baba-yaga-s-assistant</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short Story Collections of Note: The Witch and Other Tales Re-Told by Jean Thompson; The Rental Heart and Other Fairytales by Kirsty Logan</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/short-story-collections-of-note-the-witch-and-other-tales-re-told-by-jean-thompson-the-rental-heart-and-other-fairytales-by-kirsty-logan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jan Stinchcomb]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 15:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Notes from Rapunzel's Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jean Thompson is a former National Book Award Finalist, which will come as no surprise&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20821269-the-witch-and-other-tales-re-told?ac=1"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1407708927l/20821269.jpg" alt="" width="228" height="344" /></a>Jean Thompson is a former National Book Award Finalist, which will come as no surprise after you have finished the first story, “The Witch.” By the time you process a story like “The Curse” you will want to read more of Jean Thompson’s books and wonder why she hasn’t yet reached rock-star status. (I read countless short stories every year. “The Curse” was my favorite for 2014.) These stories both are and are not retellings of fairy tales. It is easy to recognize tales like “Hansel and Gretel”, “Cinderella”, “Little Red Riding Hood” and “Bluebeard” in these pages, but the fairy-tale themes are so subtly rendered that the emotional impact is doubled. The question: what came first, the fairy tale or the human condition? The answer: these tales are eternal. End of discussion.</p>
<p>Romance and family relationships are the core subjects of so many genres. Jean Thompson treats this familiar territory with a wry wisdom that knows just when to recede and let the looming darkness speak for itself. As the doomed hero of “The Curse” says, “Do you ever feel like, even when everything’s going all right, or especially when it’s going all right, that there’s some horror movie version of your life that’s going to come sneaking up behind you?” Not to worry, though, as this collection ends in a blaze of imaginative optimism with “Prince,” a story which proves that love, sometimes from an unexpected source, still can save the day.</p>
<p>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20821269-the-witch-and-other-tales-re-told?ac=1</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1381809115l/18623474.jpg" alt="" width="267" height="409" />Kirsty Logan’s exquisitely weird book won the Scott Prize, the Saboteur Award for Best Short Story Collection, and is now long-listed for the Frank O&#8217;Connor International Short Story Award. Logan has clearly earned her spot in the world of speculative fiction with these twenty stories, which are sophisticated and demanding, but well worth the effort. Though not all the stories are fairy tales in the strict sense of the word, you will recognize many characters and motifs, not to mention the endless struggle for power and autonomy, found in the classic tales.</p>
<p>“The Rental Heart” explores the limits of technology in the chancy territory of love. “Underskirts” offers an intimate examination of female desire and subversion by focusing on an unconventional lady of the manor. If you are looking for an original, unsentimental take on hybrids, then “Una and Coll Are Not Friends” is the story for you. “Matryoshka” is an expression of pure beauty and yearning. The best Baba Yaga rewrite ever&#8211;at least for this month&#8211;appears in “Witch.” And the simplicity of “Origami,” where a woman folds her way out of loneliness, challenges us to reconsider the demands of intimacy and fidelity. Here is a sample of what Logan has to offer, from the story “Girl #18”: “The girl is standing as I left her, and I want to say that she looks exactly the same except that she doesn’t. It’s like I’ve been away for months, years even, and in that time she’s grown and matured way past anything I could ever be. She’s an adult. A woman. That’s the thing about girls: they’re never really girls at all. They’re always women really.”</p>
<p>https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18623474-the-rental-heart-and-other-fairytales?ac=1</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
