<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Carol Holland March &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/carol-holland-march/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 22:48:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Get Your Stories Published</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/how-to-get-your-stories-published/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carol Holland March]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 20:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Creative Soul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For years, I wrote without trying to get my stories published. Not very hard anyway.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For years, I wrote without trying to get my stories published. Not very hard anyway. I would occasionally send something out. When it was rejected, I took it personally, figuring I wasn’t a good enough writer for that market. I was the epitome of an amateur writer with zero confidence.</p>
<p>Gradually, I toughened up, and realized that I needed to do more research to find the markets open to the kind of stories I write. Many of my stories are borderline magical realism and don’t fit neatly into the fantasy and/or science fiction category. I often write about gay and lesbian characters, which is another challenge.</p>
<p>It turns out that, in addition to developing a (much) tougher skin and getting to the place where my self worth as a writer was not tangled up in whether my stories were accepted, I had a lot to learn about the marketplace for fiction</p>
<p>As I got more serious about publishing, I asked several questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Did the publication print the type of stories I was writing?</li>
<li>Was the style and level of writing of their published stories comparable to what I was producing?</li>
<li>If I wasn’t yet writing at their level, could I step up my game and get there with a reasonable amount of time and effort?</li>
<li>Did the publication give constructive feedback? (these are golden opportunities to learn from editors, even if they only provide a line or two of comment)</li>
<li>Was the publication open to alternative voices and lifestyles? (many indicate that on their submissions page)</li>
</ul>
<p>The way to research is simple. READ, READ, READ. Previous editions of the publication, their submission page, their blog, interviews by the editor, and anything else you can find.</p>
<p>Another road to publishing is to investigate writing contests. There are numerous contests, some very prestigious. Some pay very well, others not so much. Some provide that golden feedback from editors. <a href="http://http://www.christopherfielden.com/short-story-tips-and-writing-advice/short-story-competitions.php">Chris Fielden</a> runs a site with useful links on contests. Often you can research who the previous winners of contests are as well as the judges, which can help you choose (or fine tune) an appropriate story to enter.</p>
<p>Of course, learning how to write better goes without saying. There is a steeper learning curve to writing publishable fiction that many realize. This has nothing to do with the creativity that gave you the story in the first place. It’s about the craft necessary to birth the story into the world. Creativity is free and unfettered. Craft must be learned over time.</p>
<p>The more I was rejected, the more I learned. I now have a (slightly) better sense of where to submit my work. There are markets I am aiming for, but know I’m not quite ready for yet. The operative word is “yet.” Every editor and publisher I’ve communicated with has taught me something about craft. I learn from reading books on craft. And from reading excellent writers who have mastered craft. It’s truly the never ending story</p>
<p>Just remember that writing isn’t enough. Persistence counts. Research counts. Experience counts a lot. You can do it if you’re willing to put in the time and effort. And the only place we can start from is where we are now.</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Resources for Writers</strong></p>
<p>If you write about monsters, real or imagined, submit to the open call of Monsters,an anthology coming out from <a href="http://http://greymatterpress.com/submissions/current-calls/">Grey Matter Press</a>. Short stories to 7500 words.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.tmcc.edu/meadow/submit/">THE MEADOW NOVELLA PRIZE</a> has a $15 entry fee.<br />
The winner of the contest will receive $500 and publication in our annual print edition of the journal. Deadline February 1, 2015. Submissions between 18,000 and 35,000 words.</p>
<p>Anne Allen has a great <a href="http://annerallen.blogspot.com/2014/11/8-bogus-rules-new-writers-tell-each.html">blog article</a> on bogus rules that new writers tell each other</p>
<p>A virtual book marketing event is coming up from <a href="http://authormarketinglive.com/">Author Marketing</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Persistence Counts</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/persistence-counts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carol Holland March]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 16:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Creative Soul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently  my first novel, The Dreamwalkers of Larreta, was accepted for publication by Ellysian Press,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently  my first novel, <em>The Dreamwalkers of Larreta</em>, was accepted for publication by <a href="http://www.ellysianpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ellysian Press</a>, a traditional small press that produces both print and ebooks.</p>
<p>I have been writing and marketing this book for several years, but not until I shortened it to 90,000 words did it sell. This says more about my continuing education in how to structure a novel that anything else. When I mentioned this to a friend, she nodded and said, “that was your practice novel.” I guess we all have one. The novel we’re burning to write and do, but without really knowing how the heck to do it.</p>
<p>I rewrote <em>Dreamwalkers</em> at least four times, and that does not include the copyedits and proofreading. Finally, I thought I had it, and the answer is, almost. As part of Ellysian’s editing process, I have agreed to pick up the pace in the second act and slow down the ending (I can’t tell you how thrilled I am to have someone tell me what the book needs to be more marketable). I am happily preparing to embark on the next round of edits.</p>
<p>As part of a creativity class, I advise that students stop “thinking” about being creative and start “doing.” Even if the doing is not exactly what they want. Any creative act fuels the furnace and gets you closer to that center where we all want to live.</p>
<p>While using my own process with Dreamwalkers I realized that I had followed the steps I was teaching my students.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Conceive the project</strong>. That’s easy. I have a long story itching to be told.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Vision the specific end result</strong> you want. That wasn’t hard either. I knew how it started and how it ended.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Describe current reality</strong>. Am I writing every day? Do I have the knowledge and resources to write a novel?</li>
</ol>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Take Action</strong>. Without over-planning, get going. This is what NaNoWriMo is about. Just do it. Edit later. Get it out of your head.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="5">
<li><strong>Adjust/Learn/Evaluate/Adjust</strong>. This is the rewriting, dealing with structure, character arcs, plot points, and all the rest of turning raw copy into a readable book.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="6">
<li><strong>Build Momentum. </strong>As many wise writers have said, experience matters. Working over time matters. You learn. You build skills. Epiphanies occur. This is what makes you a professional.</li>
</ol>
<ol start="7">
<li><strong>Completion</strong>. You decide when a creation is complete.</li>
</ol>
<p>None of this is new, but it emphasizes what I believe are the critical elements in any creative work. Vision, Act, Learn, Evaluate.</p>
<p>If you wait until you have it worked out perfectly in your head, your life will go by. The creative process is messy and often disorganized. No first draft comes out the way you envision it. Writing is rewriting. And wow, is it fun.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>MARKETS AND RESOURCES </strong></p>
<p>If you have a holiday story in the hopper, Flash Fiction Online is an example of a regularly publishing site open to holiday submissions (note the holiday instructions in their guidelines). Open genre. Accepts 500-1000 word stories. Pays $60/story.<br />
<a href="http://flashfictiononline.com/main/submission-guidelines/">http://flashfictiononline.com/main/submission-guidelines/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.childrenswriter.com/guidelines.htm">http://www.childrenswriter.com/guidelines.htm</a><br />
For beginning to well-established professional writers interested in learning more and keeping up-to-date on writing for children, selling their writing, and the juvenile publishing industry. Features 1,700 to 2,000 words pay $300.</p>
<p>The blog<a href="http://%20strangerviews.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> The Stranger View</a> is looking for books to review. They also accept book reviews.</p>
<p>A Valentine anthology of lesbian fiction is accepting short stories until November 15.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thelizmcmullenshowcom/category/bedtime-stories/">http://www.thelizmcmullenshowcom/category/bedtime-stories/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Planning Creative?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/is-planning-creative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carol Holland March]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 17:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Creative Soul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Writers often self-select themselves into one of two categories:  plotters or pantsers. If you haven’t&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Writers often self-select themselves into one of two categories:  plotters or pantsers. If you haven’t run across those terms, they refer to the amount of planning the writer does before beginning a project.</p>
<p>Some writers can’t start until they know how a story will end and all the plot points they will cover. Pantsers are horrified at the thought of outlining and start writing with only a vague sense of where they’re going. The fun for them is learning the story while they write.</p>
<p>Both methods work. My first novel was written without an outline. I had no idea about plot points, inciting incidents, turning points, or how a novel should be structured. That was okay, because I was so nervous about writing it at all that I didn’t dare stop to plot for fear I wouldn’t finish. I re-wrote the novel at least six times before I was satisfied with it.</p>
<p>For my second novel, in progress, I swore I would educate myself more thoroughly about fictional structure so I didn’t have to go through that again. And I have. I read many books and talked to many people about plot and dramatic structure. I learned a ton, and have also calmed down about writing, so I was able to create an outline, in three-act structure, no less, that guides my writing. It is not written in stone; I change it frequently, and I don’t feel at all hampered by it. In fact, knowing my plot points makes it easier to write the scenes that need to be there.</p>
<p>If you’re writing anything longer than a short story, planning can make your life easier, and does not have to reduce your creative impulses one whit.</p>
<p><strong>You can learn about dramatic structure from many of the fine books available</strong>. I am currently reading <em>Write Your Novel from the Middle</em> by James Scott Bell, and what a revelation that was! I never realized that the emotional epiphany of the POV character occurs at almost exactly the midpoint of a well-plotted novel. I found myself searching through some of my recent favorites to find it.</p>
<p>K.M. Wieland’s excellent, concise, and easy to digest book on plotting, <em>Structuring Your Novel</em> is also worth reading. For you fantasy writers, there’s <em>The Hero’s Journey, Mythic Structure for Writers</em> by Christopher Vogel. If you’re into something a bit more complex, <em>Story: Substance, Structure, Style and the Principles of Screenwriting</em> by Robert McKee (the principles work equally well for novelists) is invaluable. Another book I like, <em>A Story is a Promis</em>e is by Bill Johnson, who talks about the promise of a novel being about the emotional journey the POV character takes.</p>
<p><strong>Some simple things can help you be more organized, and more creative with your writing time.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Set manageable goals. How many words can you write in a day? Keep track. Try to increase them. When I track my productivity, it goes up. Set goals for how many pages or chapters you will complete in a week or a month and put them into a chart or spreadsheet. If you consistently fail to meet your goals, change them. The idea is to succeed, not beat yourself up.</li>
<li>If possible, work at the same time every day. There’s a lot to be said for routine.</li>
<li>If you can’t write when the floor is dirty or the dishes are piled up, do your chores first. Turn off the phone. Get a program like “Freedom” which keeps you off the Internet while you’re writing. When it’s time to write, do that and only that.</li>
<li>Take consistent action. If you need to do research, write something unrelated. Research is not an excuse not to write. Don’t stop writing to research something. Make a note what you need to find out and keep writing.</li>
<li>Trust yourself to know when to plan and when to write without stopping. You do know what you’re doing.</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>_________________________________________________________________________________________________</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>Publishing Opportunities</strong></em></p>
<p>NEW VISIONS AWARD<br />
https://www.leeandlow.com/writers-illustrators/new-visions-award<br />
NO ENTRY FEE.<br />
TU BOOKS, the fantasy, science fiction, and mystery imprint of LEE &amp; LOW BOOKS, announces the second annual NEW VISIONS AWARD. The NEW VISIONS AWARD will be given for a middle grade or young adult fantasy, science fiction, or mystery novel by a writer of color. The Award winner receives a cash prize of $1000 and our standard publication contract, including advance and royalties for a first time author. An Honor Award winner will receive $500. Deadline October 31, 2014.</p>
<p>STORIES OF RESILIENCE CONTEST<br />
http://ourstoryproject.herokuapp.com/pages/contest<br />
NO ENTRY FEE.<br />
In recognition of October as Domestic Violence Awareness Month, the greater community is invited to add their voices through the &#8220;Stories of Resilience&#8221; contest. Submissions are sought that reflect the broad impact of abuse &#8212; through stories, personal essays or poems. First prize of $500 and two second prizes of $100. Deadline October 20, 2014. We are interested in a wide range of submissions, from very brief to a maximum of 1,500 words. Survivors, friends, family, coworkers, neighbors, children &#8211; all perspectives on the effects of domestic abuse are welcome.</p>
<p>THE FEMINIST WIRE<br />
http://thefeministwire.com/2014/06/feminist-wires-1st-annual-poetry-contest/<br />
$10 ENTRY FEE.<br />
The winner will receive publication in The Feminist Wire and $200. The 1st runner up will receive publication in The Feminist Wire and $100. Deadline October 1, 2014. Submit up to 3 poems (no more than a total of 5 pages)</p>
<p>HERSTORIES PROJECT &#8211; MOTHERING THROUGH THE DARKNESS</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="UwDXhAeSVP"><p><a href="https://www.herstoriesproject.com/next-call-submissions-writing-contest/">Mothering Through the Darkness: A Call for Submissions and a Writing Contest</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Mothering Through the Darkness: A Call for Submissions and a Writing Contest&#8221; &#8212; The HerStories Project" src="https://www.herstoriesproject.com/next-call-submissions-writing-contest/embed/#?secret=uBJo3CAlbj#?secret=UwDXhAeSVP" data-secret="UwDXhAeSVP" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe><br />
$10 ENTRY FEE.<br />
The HerStories Project will award $500 to one submission for Best Essay and $100 to two runners-up. All three essays will be published in the book, and each winner will receive a paperback copy. Previously unpublished stories between 1,500 and 3,000 words. Deadline December 1, 2014. Mothering Through the Darkness: Stories of Postpartum Struggles will be a unique anthology with the goal of breaking that silence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing Conflict</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-conflict/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carol Holland March]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 21:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Creative Soul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Years ago, a friend years ago gave me the manuscript of her paranormal romance novel&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Years ago, a friend years ago gave me the manuscript of her paranormal romance novel to read. The writing was good, but the main character did not change from the beginning to the end. She was also suspiciously similar to my friend (this is a &#8220;Mary Sue&#8221; which is an idealized character based on the author&#8217;s life─usually she&#8217;s way too good to be true to life). When I mentioned that a character in a novel needs to progress through conflict for a story to be interesting, my friend explained that the character was already perfect and so she didn&#8217;t need to change. Needless to say, she never published it. I think writing it gave her all the satisfaction she was seeking.</p>
<p>Looking back, it was an easy problem to spot in someone else&#8217;s writing, but the issue of how much conflict is enough has plagued me as a writer. I have a tendency to get attached to my characters, and have to force myself to put them in difficult situations.  This is a personality defect, I realize, one that I am working hard at correcting.</p>
<p>In one story, it occurred to me that the main male character had to go through a public humiliation in order to make sense of what he does later. My first thought was, how can I do that to him? My next thought was, if I don&#8217;t, I’m going to be sorry. I did humiliate him. It worked. He survived. So did I.</p>
<p>Now, whenever I finish a draft, I go back and look at it from the perspective of rising conflict. Yes, every writing book in the world talks about it. It isn&#8217;t a terribly complex idea, but it&#8217;s one of the lessons you must learn and learn well. For literary or genre fiction, the main difference is degree and the proportion of internal/external conflict. But conflict there must be; otherwise, no matter how beautiful your prose, people may find your work (gasp!) boring.</p>
<p>Conflict is akin to plot, but it&#8217;s also integral to character. No one is excited about a character who knows exactly what&#8217;s happening at every moment, or who is in perfect control, unless that control is going to be her downfall. We enjoy characters who are troubled, confused, in denial, uncertain, and sometimes plain scared stiff. One easy place to look for conflict in your stories is to see if you&#8217;ve put the internal conflicts your character is facing on the page. Not in your head. On the page.</p>
<p>You can think of a story as about some need your main character has and what she does to satisfy it. Is the need fulfilled or thwarted? What happens if it is thwarted? If it is, what other need comes into play?</p>
<p>Many stories are about an emotional journey, and in that case, the problem needs to be stated early on. Not explicitly, of course, but the reader needs to know that the story will be exploring the character&#8217;s loneliness, for example, or need to belong. Whatever is posited at the beginning of the story must be fulfilled by the end. The middle details all the obstacles, inner and outer, that the character faces on her journey. And that is the conflict!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p>Funds for Writers, a newsletter published by  Hope Clark is a great resource for publishing opportunities, grants, fellowships, agents, and other links for writers. She is the author of The Shy Writer Reborn, which I found very helpful.  http://www.fundsforwriters.com/</p>
<p>Sparks Creative Anthology is running a contest, Monsters and Marvels.  The theme for this contest invites open interpretation: are monsters physical manifestations of evil, or the internal demons that plague us all? Marvels: fantastic bestiary creatures, or the resilience of human spirit?  Go to <a href="http://sparkanthology.org/contests/seven/">http://sparkanthology.org/contests/seven/</a>  for the details.  Deadline is October 1.</p>
<p>Critters is an excellent online critique site for fantasy, science fiction and horror writers. If you analyze at least one ms every week, you can get critiques from 10-15 other writers on your short story or novel. I&#8217;ve used them for years and found them very helpful.  http://critters.org/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It Came to Me in a Flash of Light</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/it-came-to-me-in-a-flash-of-light/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/it-came-to-me-in-a-flash-of-light/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carol Holland March]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 15:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Creative Soul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=1884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Flash of Light? Actually, that has happened to me. Once in a while. A brilliant&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Flash of Light? Actually, that has happened to me. Once in a while. A brilliant idea falls from the ether into my mind, and I am enthralled at the possibilities it suggests. An image has appeared. It must mean something. There must be a story there. The truth is, sometimes yes, sometimes no.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve heard all those clichés about the Muse. Books have been written about her. Movies produced. She is young and beautiful. There are three of them, daughters of Zeus, Memory their mother. No, wait, four. Or nine, depending on who is counting. They are the source of all knowledge. They are water nymphs.</p>
<p>From Homer until the present day, the idea that artistic expression is the result of deliberate courting of a deity who may or may not deign to grace us with the information we need to produce art has been with us. We wait for her. We flatter her. We sit patiently, hoping she will notice us.</p>
<p>She is a goddess. And she is also the excuse par excellence for writers who are not willing to notice that habit and consistency are the keys to learning craft and producing work.</p>
<p>Not that inspiration doesn&#8217;t count. It does. My favorite comment on this subject came from a working writer who stated that he shows up at his keyboard at eight am and stays there until 5 pm. &#8220;That way,&#8221; he said, &#8220;If inspiration strikes, I&#8217;ll be there. Meanwhile, I&#8217;m working.&#8221;</p>
<p>What I&#8217;ve noticed with my own writing is that inspiration is easy. Thoughts about writing and story ideas are not hard to come by. And they&#8217;re free. What is hard is the day to day work of crafting characters and plot and constructing scenes that make the stories work.</p>
<p>Maybe you&#8217;re the genius who can tap out a first draft that doesn&#8217;t need re-writing, but I sure am not. I re-write, edit, put the manuscript aside, come back when it&#8217;s cooled down, am amazed at all the things I left out, re-write again, edit some more, and do that a few more times. This is creative work.</p>
<p>A boss of mine once put a sign on her wall that said, &#8220;Writing is re-writing.&#8221; I don&#8217;t know who said that first, but I&#8217;ve found it to be more true than I imagined when I started writing fiction for publication. I&#8217;m amazed at the errors I catch on the fifth or sixth or seventh draft. I&#8217;m shocked at the information I&#8217;ve failed to include in the third go around with the novel. What is wrong with me?</p>
<p>As it turns out, nothing. Most writers write like this. The inspiration of the Muse can get us through the first draft, writing like white-hot lightening (sometimes, if we&#8217;re lucky). But then the real work begins. As I&#8217;ve learned more about craft, especially with novel-length work, I realize that inspiration comes quietly as well in that flash of light. It comes in the realization that a character&#8217;s motivation is not well explained, or that a scene needs to be set differently. Creative inspiration comes in those all-important details as well as in the big picture.</p>
<p>The dreaming self can solve the larger problems in a story. Most of us have had the experience of waking up and saying, &#8220;aha! That&#8217;s how I can solve that plot problem.&#8221; But it&#8217;s just as creative when you&#8217;re crafting the words that make that inspiration sing on the page.</p>
<p>So, the next time you&#8217;re tempted to excuse yourself from your manuscript because you&#8217;re waiting for the light bulb to go on, the Muse to get back from the Mediterranean, or inspiration to strike, take a deep breath, sit down at the keyboard and start typing.</p>
<p><em>All things come to she who waits, if she who waits works ceaselessly while she waits. </em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p>The Women&#8217;s <a href="https://womensfictionwriters.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Fiction Writers Association</a> offers support and resources for writers who create stories about a women&#8217;s emotional journey. They have contests, a mentorship program, critique groups, online workshops, and other resources.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://http://www.speculativeliterature.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Speculative Literature Foundation</a> is another resource worth a look. They offer resources for specfic writers, awards, grants and other programs. Their mission is to &#8220;promote literary quality in speculative fiction, by encouraging promising new writers, assisting established writers, facilitating the work of quality magazines and small presses in the genre, and developing a greater public appreciation of speculative fiction.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/it-came-to-me-in-a-flash-of-light/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Creative Soul</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-creative-soul/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carol Holland March]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 14:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Creative Soul]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=1880</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is my first blog post for LSQ, and I&#8217;m honored to share my thoughts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is my first blog post for LSQ, and I&#8217;m honored to share my thoughts on women and creativity with the talented women who read and write for LSQ. I will be writing about the creative life and the particular challenges and inspirations for women who live it.</p>
<p>As I thought about what is needed for creative work, several things came to mind.<strong> First, desire</strong>. We must have an impulse, a longing, maybe even a calling to communicate something to the world. We may not know exactly what it is, even after years of writing, but if the calling is there, we hear it and continue to unravel the message that is ours to share.</p>
<p><strong>Second, we need commitment.</strong> With the busy lives most of us lead, this may be the most important. Our creative work must rise to the top of the priority list if it is to be more than a dream. Creativity requires hard choices. We can&#8217;t do it all, and may have to accept that our lives will be different when we choose to live as creative women.</p>
<p><strong>We need time.</strong> You may need to hack it out with a metaphorical machete, and then guard it like a precious jewel. For creative work to flourish, you must practice.</p>
<p>We also need a<strong> place to work</strong>. Maybe not a whole room, although that&#8217;s ideal, but a corner that is ours, with the tools we need and the books we love, a place where we are, above all, WRITER.</p>
<p><strong> We need determination.</strong> The call to write may be inborn, but the craft must be learned, and that requires us to make the decision over and over. To write when you really don&#8217;t feel like it. When you&#8217;d rather be doing something else. When you&#8217;re tired and discouraged.</p>
<p>The good news is that to produce a story, a poem, a play, or a novel is the greatest feeling in the world, and worth the sacrifice. To finish, to send out your work, to see it published, that&#8217;s the payoff. And what a payoff it is! Your name in print!</p>
<p>Writing speculative fiction is the joy of my life, and I&#8217;ve struggled with all the issues I&#8217;ve mentioned. The next piece of good news is that we&#8217;re living in a great time for women writers. There are a lot more of us now, and more opportunity than in the old days when some women used initials when submitting work to conceal their identity.</p>
<p>Still, women work in a different world than our male cohorts. I believe that women are more intrinsically creative, but also have more constraints on our time and energy. Many still have confidence issues that slow them down or stop them entirely.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d like to know your challenges as a writer. Time? Priorities? Balancing family, relationships, and creativity? Finding markets open to the type of work you are producing? Send me a message with any subject you&#8217;re interested in hearing more about so this column can address your interests. If you care about a subject, more than likely others do too.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> ***</p>
<p> When I recently heard that all the Nebula award winners were women, I thought, Wow! What a great time to be a writer. A woman writer. A woman writer writing specfic.</p>
<p>The Nebulas are the annual awards given by SFWA, the professional organization for fantasy and science fiction writers. You must be a member to vote, and to be a member you must have published in approved markets. If you&#8217;re interested, membership information is listed <a href="http://www.sfwa.org/about/join-us/sfwa-membership-requirements/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p>
<p>The list of Nebula winners is<a href="http://www.sfwa.org/2014/05/2013-nebula-awards-winners/#comment-160932" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> here</a></p>
<p>Some great writers were honored this year, including <strong>Ann Leckie</strong> (her novel <em>Ancillary Justice</em> beat out Gaiman&#8217;s <em>The Ocean at the End of the Lane</em>), <strong>Vylar Kaftan</strong>, <strong>Aliette de</strong><strong>Bodard, and Rachel Swirsky.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>Another interesting project featuring women in speculative fiction is the kickstarter anthologies spearheaded by writer and editor Christie Yant at Lightspeed Magazine. She got sick and tired of hearing that women can&#8217;t write &#8220;real&#8221; science fiction and this anthology is the result─short stories, flash fiction and reprints. <em>Women Destroy Science Fiction</em> is now available in all formats. I just got my electronic copy and am really excited to read so much science fiction by woman, all in one place!  I was particularly moved by the story <em>A Word Shaped Like Bones</em> by Kris Millering, about a woman artist on a spaceship to a distant planet, creating art for an alien civilization.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s available at Amazon and all the usual places. Upcoming anthologies to look forward to include <em>Women Destroy Fantasy</em> and <em>Women Destroy Horror. </em>Lightspeed is a pro market that has always been open to women writers, but anthologies of ALL WOMEN is pretty groundbreaking.  Thanks, Christie!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p>Carol Holland March writes speculative fiction and blogs at <a href="http://CarolHollandMarch.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CarolHollandMarch.com</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
