<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Writing While Woman &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/writing-while-woman/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 21:18:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Writing While Woman: Letting Go</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-while-woman-letting-go/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffany Meuret]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 10:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing While Woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you have ever read any of my other articles, you’ll come to the quick&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you have ever read any of my other articles, you’ll come to the quick conclusion that I am highly neurotic. There are a multitude of reasons for this, including my clinically diagnosed obsessive-compulsive disorder (Neurotic? You don’t say!), existing in a pandemic, and also <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24787 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/brett-jordan-x5RwfZH04GA-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/brett-jordan-x5RwfZH04GA-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/brett-jordan-x5RwfZH04GA-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/brett-jordan-x5RwfZH04GA-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/brett-jordan-x5RwfZH04GA-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/brett-jordan-x5RwfZH04GA-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />because I am a writer. The common thread here is that many aspects of each of these are wildly out of my control. I can’t simply stop my obsessive thoughts any more than I can make publishing do things I wish it would do. I can’t make my book a bestseller by sheer force of will. I can’t stop delays and rejections or bad news. I can’t stand on a street corner shoving my custom bookmarks in people’s faces (well, I could, but it is ill-advised).</p>
<p>There are a lot of cannots in publishing and in writing, so much so that it is easy to be overcome by an apathetic malaise. You toil over this novel, sometimes for years. Maybe decades. You query it. You submit it to publishers. You publish it and send it into the world of readers. You make beautiful swag that you can’t fathom a person wouldn’t want. Writing consumes you so much that the very idea that the rest of the world isn’t waiting with bated breath to marvel at the fruits of your labor is inconceivable. So when that happens (or feels that way to you) one might become disillusioned as to question the whole process itself. Why do this at all?</p>
<p>Another thing I can’t do is answer that question for you. It is an intimate question with a very personal answer. What I can tell you, as someone who has survived their debut in the age of COVID, is that there are some things you are just going to have to let go. Allow yourself to breathe. You can’t be all things to all people—a master marketer, a publicist, a writing machine, a parent, a spouse, a hard worker. The list goes on. You also can’t control people, nor their reactions to your work. For the longest time, your work was yours and yours alone. Then maybe you let a friend or two in. Then maybe an agent and editor. But at some point, your work ceases to only be yours (a piece of it will always stay with you, don’t worry). The day will come when it belongs to readers, too, and John Q. Public isn’t always going to handle it the way you envisioned. That’s okay. In fact, that’s ideal in some ways. Your work will begin to take on a new life, a different life. It will touch people in ways you could have never predicted, which will be both frustrating and beautiful. Like people are.</p>
<p>Once you reach this stage, letting go will be your greatest tool in which to survive it. Kick your book baby out of the nest, let it fly, and then turn your attention to that new story just beginning to gestate. It needs more of your attention anyway.</p>
<p>Happy writing, friends.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing While Woman: Finding Your Crew</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-while-woman-finding-your-crew/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffany Meuret]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing While Woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=23009</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Writing is lonely work, at least that’s how I feel. I hole myself up in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23022 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-594090_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-594090_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-594090_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-594090_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-594090_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-594090_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Writing is lonely work, at least that’s how I feel. I hole myself up in my brain, divining and imagining, my mind often lost to a plot point that is months away from the page. Then there’s querying and submission, and the inevitable slog of waiting. Waiting for rejections. Waiting for an acceptance. Waiting to hear that we need to wait some more. Waiting for a validation.</p>
<p>I’m here to tell you that there’s always another horizon to meet, another mountain to climb, another literary star in which to compare yourself, and the way we survive the trek is not by a constant stream of successes (lol), but rather from the people you find along the way. Your crew. Your writerly soul mates.</p>
<p>We writers are cliquey, but it’s not without reason. Writing is such a personal endeavor, which is then pummeled relentlessly by the brutality of capitalism. We therefore have to be very careful about who we allow to hold our fragile egos and trust not to break them. We are perpetually being broken and rebuilding ourselves as it is in this industry, so we need a stable, reliable, and ride-or-die kind of crew to help us through it. This doesn’t mean we make a few friends and then stop trying, but the longer you trudge, the tighter and smarter you become with your feelings, and therefore are less eager to hand them over to someone new.</p>
<p>So how does one find their crew? There is no magic formula, but if I might speak from experience, I found mine over the course of years. I met one of my longest writer friends at a conference in 2015, simply because she happened to take a seat at my table during our sandwich lunch. I met others on Twitter as we shared stupid gifs or joined the same private slack group started by mutual friends. I met more at a writing retreat as we critiqued each other’s work<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23023 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-593344_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-593344_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-593344_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-593344_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-593344_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/startup-593344_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> (and even one that attended the same retreat, but I did not meet at the time, us only connecting years later via a mutual friend). Each of these relationships took time to curate before realizing that we were, in fact, now part of something a bit more meaningful than Twitter mutuals passing in the night. It took months, if not years, of messages, texts, emails, and reading each other’s work to get there. Over time, trust was established.</p>
<p>So if you happen to congregate with other writers or industry people, either in person or virtually, and wish you could be part of that group over there with all the inside jokes and laughter, maybe head over and say hi. They might have a you-shaped opening waiting! But if not, understand it’s not because they think little of you, but because they, we, all of us, are freaking fragile. Then look around the room. Guaranteed there is at least one other person feeling the same way, that is in the same spot as you, that can grow and learn alongside you. That is your beginning to ride-or-die crew membership. And you will build it together.</p>
<p>(Here&#8217;s a list of upcoming <a href="https://thewritelife.com/writers-conferences/">writing conferences</a> to get you started!)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing While Woman: NaNoWriMo as the World Burns</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-while-woman-nanowrimo-as-the-world-burns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffany Meuret]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 11:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing While Woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I haven’t participated in NaNoWriMo in 6 years, and it wasn’t because I wasn’t writing,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-22100 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Logo_of_National_Novel_Writing_Month-206x300.png" alt="" width="206" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Logo_of_National_Novel_Writing_Month-206x300.png 206w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Logo_of_National_Novel_Writing_Month.png 261w" sizes="(max-width: 206px) 100vw, 206px" />I haven’t participated in NaNoWriMo in 6 years, and it wasn’t because I wasn’t writing, but because I found the entire concept stressful beyond all belief. Missing a day of writing would send me into small panic sessions over my failure, and as the days passed, I would become even more despondent as I slipped further behind my 50,000 word goal. It stands to reason that in this current climate I’d be even warier of launching into a project that used to make me anxious, yet it’s opposite. Maybe 2020 has hardened me (no), or maybe I’ve grown more confident in my skills as a writer (also no), or maybe the distraction factor of NaNo has finally outweighed the stress (yup).</p>
<p>So, for all of you other wayward authors out there wondering what in the world to do with your anxious selves, I welcome you to join me in my 2020 NaNoWriMo adventure. There are only two rules:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Set a reasonable goal that works for you</strong>. As for me, I shan’t be writing 50k words in a month. I don’t foresee me ever accomplishing such a feat, no matter the circumstances. Some people, magicians perhaps, hit the 50k goal at the end of November, some of them year after year. YOU ARE AMAZING. Others only manage a few thousand words, if that. YOU ARE ALSO AMAZING. You are writing. You’re doing it, and I’m proud of you.</li>
<li><strong>Be kind to yourself. </strong>Didn’t write today? Big whoop. Only eked out 26 words in your recent session? Cool, that’s 26 words more than you had before! 26 words closer to the end of whatever you’re writing. NaNo is a tool, not writer law. However, there is something comforting in knowing you aren’t alone on your journey. Even if at a distance, you are part of something larger than just your world and your words, and that’s pretty rad.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>None of this is to say that you should be writing if you aren’t in the right frame of mind to do so. I know I haven’t been for most of the year. But if you’re up for it, maybe NaNo can be the gentle nudge to get your thoughts out of the doom and gloom, if only for a moment.</p>
<p>Here’s to happy writing. You’re doing great.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Some links to get you going:</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://nanowrimo.org/">https://nanowrimo.org/</a></strong></p>
<p><a href="https://blog.reedsy.com/guide/nanowrimo/"><strong>https://blog.reedsy.com/guide/nanowrimo/</strong></a></p>
<p><a href="https://company.overdrive.com/2019/11/01/8-bestselling-books-written-during-nanowrimo/"><strong>https://company.overdrive.com/2019/11/01/8-bestselling-books-written-during-nanowrimo/</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing While Woman: Writing, Deadlines, and Pandemics. Oh my!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-while-woman-writing-deadlines-and-pandemics-oh-my/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffany Meuret]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 11:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing While Woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Everyone. I am here to inform you that I have no earthly idea what I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everyone. I am here to inform you that I have no earthly idea what I should be doing right now. I, like many other creatives, am on a deadline. Revisions are due in a few weeks, and I have accomplished exactly 23 pages worth of revisions. On a novel. An entire novel. I don’t know, I guess it’s something.</p>
<p>Now, don’t get me wrong, I am absolutely beyond chuffed to have a deadline, because<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-19265 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/elijah-o-donnell-t8T_yUgCKSM-unsplash-169x300.jpg" alt="" width="169" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/elijah-o-donnell-t8T_yUgCKSM-unsplash-169x300.jpg 169w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/elijah-o-donnell-t8T_yUgCKSM-unsplash-576x1024.jpg 576w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/elijah-o-donnell-t8T_yUgCKSM-unsplash-768x1365.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/elijah-o-donnell-t8T_yUgCKSM-unsplash-864x1536.jpg 864w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/elijah-o-donnell-t8T_yUgCKSM-unsplash-1152x2048.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/elijah-o-donnell-t8T_yUgCKSM-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px" /> that means I have sold some work that people will one day read (I still can’t believe it), but as I indiscriminately wave my hands in the direction of this dumpster fire of a world, I find myself stagnating on my editorial duties. Like everyone else my emotional well is barren, which mutates even the tiniest decisions into insurmountable tasks (Should I have used a semicolon here instead of an em dash? Do I care? Does the reader? Will I have a job tomorrow?). Despite the dramatics, deadlines wait for no man, so I am here to pass along the few things that have helped me focus while operating under extreme duress.</p>
<ol>
<li>Nibble, Don’t Feast: This is time-honored advice, and yet every writer I know struggles to accept it. It is okay to work in small bursts. It is more than acceptable to get a single sentence done at a time. It doesn’t seem like much, leaving many feeling as if they’d not accomplished anything at all, but they have. And so have you. It’s okay to go a little slower when marathons aren’t achievable. I promise, it’s okay. It’s perfect. You’re doing great.</li>
<li>Find Your Reset: Just like parents distract their picky eater children with airplane spoons, we adults need to drag our brains out of their usual rut. My go to is sitting somewhere as isolated as possible (dogs and kids make that an adventure on its own) and putting on music that allows my mind to wander. Sometimes it’s a curated playlist for whichever manuscript I’m working on, sometimes it’s Toto’s Greatest Hits, but either way it acts like a reset to whatever bullshit I was previously obsessing over. Light exercise, dancing, singing, or listening to podcasts also do the trick.</li>
<li>Read: Reading right before I write never fails to inspire. Usually it’s because whatever I am reading is just so damn brilliant it makes me desperate to create. It’s like tapping into the reservoir that made me want to write to begin with—I wanted to create something other people loved as much as I loved [insert fandom here]. Try to keep it a short read&#8211;some poetry, short fiction, or a chapter or two, lest you get yourself in too deep and forget to write all together.</li>
<li>Get Off Twitter: For reals. Here’s some <a href="https://www.reviewed.com/smartphones/features/10-apps-that-block-social-media-so-you-can-stay-focused-and-be-more-productive">social media blocking apps</a>, if you’re<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19266" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/adrien-robert-FguerUFGEJI-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="159" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/adrien-robert-FguerUFGEJI-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/adrien-robert-FguerUFGEJI-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/adrien-robert-FguerUFGEJI-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/adrien-robert-FguerUFGEJI-unsplash-1229x1536.jpg 1229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/adrien-robert-FguerUFGEJI-unsplash-1638x2048.jpg 1638w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/adrien-robert-FguerUFGEJI-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 159px) 100vw, 159px" /> interested.</li>
<li>Time Yourself: Be it five minutes or fifty, watching a clock tick down not only activates that competitive drive to complete something and win, but also give you an ending to look forward to. It’s less intimidating that opening the manuscript in its monstrous entirety and watching yourself sputter out after 10 pages of 300+.</li>
<li>Forgive yourself: We are not machines, lab created with specific output algorithms. We are human, and we are collectively struggling in both life and art. In the immortal words of internet memes, “You’re doing great, sweetie.”</li>
</ol>
<p>Now, as I venture back into depths of my own work, let’s see how much of my own advice I actually use.</p>
<p>For more reading about creating during the time of COVID, here’s a link- <a href="https://news.northeastern.edu/2020/06/24/heres-how-three-artists-are-creating-art-and-surviving-during-the-covid-19-pandemic/">https://news.northeastern.edu/2020/06/24/heres-how-three-artists-are-creating-art-and-surviving-during-the-covid-19-pandemic/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing While Woman: The Unlikeability Quiz</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-while-woman-the-unlikeability-quiz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffany Meuret]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 10:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing While Woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is your woman-identifying character truly unlikeable? Or are they simply a woman? Below is a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18008 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-1-300x197.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="197" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-1-300x197.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-1-1024x673.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-1-768x505.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-1-1536x1009.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-1-2048x1346.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Is your woman-identifying character truly unlikeable? Or are they simply a woman? Below is a handy quiz to help you figure it out!</p>
<p>Directions—Place yourself in the mind of an authority figure in your character’s life (a doctor, a boss, or a police officer, for example), then answer the questions below as that authority figure.</p>
<ol>
<li>Circle the words your authority figure would use to describe your main character:
<ol>
<li>Emotional, Flighty, Mouthy, Bitch, Frigid, Honey, Cute, Annoying</li>
<li>Passionate, Eccentric, Confident, Assertive, Professional, Sir, Nice, A &#8220;Go-Getter&#8221;</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li>Your character uses profanity when speaking. Does your authority figure:
<ol start="2">
<li>Admonish the language</li>
<li>Overlook it entirely, or laugh</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
<li>Your character does not have any current romantic attachments. Does your authority figure consider them:
<ol start="3">
<li>A lesbian (???)</li>
<li>Solitary and/or mysterious</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p>By now, you might be getting a sense of whether or not your character is unlikeable or simply a woman, however, there is one final question every author must ask themself before making a final decision:</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Who exactly describes this character as unlikeable? Do you wish to align yourself with their ideas of unlikeability, or would you be proud to reject them?</li>
</ol>
<p>Unlikeability is a fluid, subjective thing, and women, people of color, LGBTQ+, and other marginalized groups are much more likely to be labeled &#8220;unlikeable&#8221; in some way. This translates to our writing and to reviews of our writing. <em>Pacific Standard</em> touched on the <a href="https://psmag.com/social-justice/gender-bias-in-book-reviews">gender bias in book reviews</a> as well, stating, “Women are less likely to receive reviews when writing about topics that aren&#8217;t deemed ‘feminine.’”</p>
<p>In an article for Book Riot, Kelly Jensen delves into young adult literature specifically, stating, “…data showed that despite YA being a category of fiction where more women publish more books each year than men<a href="https://bookriot.com/2018/01/09/gender-bias-trade-reviews-ya-books/">, it was men who bring home awards</a> like the Printz most frequently.”</p>
<p>While this quiz is obviously meant to be facetious, please take special note of question 4. Not every person will like your work, but understanding who exactly decries it the most will not only help you as an author to reconcile poor reviews, but might also help to hone your target audience and refine your work to appeal to said audience.</p>
<p>Obviously I’m not saying anything new—there are oodles of blogs/article/essays on dealing with sexism in business and in art—but sometimes it helps to hear it again. It helped me to write it. I hope it helped you in some tiny way to read it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visualizing the Scene</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/visualizing-the-scene/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffany Meuret]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 11:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing While Woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I read an interview this morning with Andrzej Sapkowski, author of The Witcher books, that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17181 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I read an interview this morning with Andrzej Sapkowski, author of <em>The Witcher</em> books, that struck a surprising chord. In it, he states, <a href="https://io9.gizmodo.com/i-do-not-like-working-too-hard-or-too-long-a-refreshin-1841209529?utm_source=io9_twitter&amp;utm_medium=socialflow&amp;utm_campaign=socialflow_io9_twitter">“Believe or not, when I write I don’t see any pictures. It is not a visual process with me. I see letters only and I work with letters.”</a></p>
<p>As a writer myself, I was floored. I mean . . . what? I operate so unflinchingly opposite to this that I had to stop a moment and collect myself. Visualizing my work is the very first thing I do, long before putting a finger to the keyboard. Usually, it begins with a song. Music is a huge influence on my writing (or is it that my writing is a huge influence on my music tastes?). Music was my first creative outlet and I wanted to be a musician from a young age and into my late-teen years so it stands to reason that it would still impact how I create. I’ve created entire books from a single song that inspired a single scene that unwound itself into a fully-fledged world. I can easily visualize each scene, clear as if I had witnessed it in real life. It is absolutely integral to how I create, and from my many discussions with other writers both online and in person, I am not alone here.</p>
<p>Visualizing scenes is one of the primary tenets of writing in many ways. <em>Show, don’t tell</em> is something preached to both inexperienced and experienced authors alike. What does the character see? Smell? Hear? We’re drilled over and over to visualize and contextualize a scene with specificity in order to avoid unnecessary telling, so that to have an author proclaim that they do not see images when writing makes my own writer brain melt.</p>
<p>As reported by <em>The</em> <em>New York Times</em>, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2014/06/19/science/researching-the-brain-of-writers.html">The University of Greifswald in Germany</a> performed a study in 2014 on the creative writing process, where the brains of participants were monitored while both copying a script and creating their own stories. “Some regions of the brain became active only during the creative process, but not while copying, the researchers found. During the brainstorming sessions, some vision-processing regions of volunteers became active. It’s possible that they were, in effect, seeing the scenes they wanted to write.”</p>
<p>The entire article is a fascinating piece, but the final line stood out the most. “The very nature of <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17182 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mimi-thian-VsEKvmOkS3M-unsplash-300x222.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="222" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mimi-thian-VsEKvmOkS3M-unsplash-300x222.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mimi-thian-VsEKvmOkS3M-unsplash-1024x759.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mimi-thian-VsEKvmOkS3M-unsplash-768x569.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mimi-thian-VsEKvmOkS3M-unsplash-1536x1139.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/mimi-thian-VsEKvmOkS3M-unsplash-2048x1519.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />creativity can make it different from one person to the next, and so it can be hard to see what different writers have in common. [One author] might have activated the taste-perceiving regions of his brain when he recalled the flavor of a cookie. But another writer might rely more on sounds to evoke a time and place.”</p>
<p>Creativity is not a tangible item to be dissected and there is no one correct way to write, yet my foundations are still shaken to imagine writing a scene without actually imagining it. But there is power and beauty in culling the image from a word, something that potentially gets lost in translation when scheming up an entire book with points of view and protagonists and antagonists, tension and backstory. It might be why many, many readers find poetry so intimidating—where every word is its own powerhouse, carefully molded so that no other word might ever be exchanged. It’s complex in its simplicity, it makes us <em>work</em> for the image (if there even is an image). The words are no longer in service to a larger narrative, but in service to themselves. In poetry we are not being led anywhere, but thrown into a tornado and left to forge our own way to enlightenment (whatever that may be).</p>
<p>I don’t claim to understand any part of Mr. Sapkowski’s writing process, and as of now he has afforded a level of success with his stories that I could only dream of, and perhaps his method is one reason why.</p>
<p>Or perhaps not.</p>
<p>What I <em>do</em> know is that I will never be able to look at any of his pieces again without thinking of this interview. We writers already agonize over word choice more than most, and I look forward to continuing the tradition with even more panic-stricken vigor. Who will join me?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Joy of Writing</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-joy-of-writing/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-joy-of-writing/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffany Meuret]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 11:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing While Woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Look, we all got into this game for a reason. I started writing in my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16561 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/frank-busch-g7uPG8w1XV8-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/frank-busch-g7uPG8w1XV8-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/frank-busch-g7uPG8w1XV8-unsplash-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/frank-busch-g7uPG8w1XV8-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/frank-busch-g7uPG8w1XV8-unsplash-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/frank-busch-g7uPG8w1XV8-unsplash-2048x1363.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Look, we all got into this game for a reason. I started writing in my early teens, adventuring into some short lived stories that died minutes after they began as I realized writing was not as easy as writers made it seem. I likely would never have taken it further if not for one spectacular professor who not only taught me the basics of crafting a scene, but also encouraged me more than I deserved, instilling in me the very buds of self-confidence that would guide me through the much harsher waters that is publishing today. I don’t think I need to remind anyone reading this that publishing is tough—it’s unpredictable, unfair, and as this <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/publisher-news/article/81637-is-publishing-too-top-heavy.html?fbclid=IwAR0YOdo8NNCKzWntMSPSudRPD-PSPZzwWr6f-y259NkdVcSciy3iO5M8Hv4">recent article by Publisher’s Weekly</a> points out, becoming even more top heavy than it already was. Baby fish  (like me, like most of us) have to swim harder and faster than ever in order to be seen, constantly dodging and weaving the countless rejections on the way. It’s tough. Publishing, in a word, <em>sucks</em>.</p>
<p>It is an intrinsic fact that publishing sucks. Any publishing professional will tell you it sucks. Every writer has their own horror story of publishing suckiness. Every single one. (And if you don’t have one yet, so sorry to tell you that you one day will. Gird your loins now.)</p>
<p>And yet, here we are, wading through the bullshit anyway. Why?</p>
<p>Because we love writing. We love it dearly. We love crafting stories, breathing life and purpose into new people and worlds. We love the art of sentence rearranging, of witty metaphors, of our own trauma and wonder and joy and fury being translated into something tangible, something that makes sense both to us and to others.</p>
<p>It is the closest thing we have to magic, if you ask me. But it’s a fragile magic, one that is so <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16562 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/huyen-nguyen-ccaQyDwMCZ0-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/huyen-nguyen-ccaQyDwMCZ0-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/huyen-nguyen-ccaQyDwMCZ0-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/huyen-nguyen-ccaQyDwMCZ0-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/huyen-nguyen-ccaQyDwMCZ0-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/huyen-nguyen-ccaQyDwMCZ0-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />integral to our hearts that the downfalls can seem catastrophic. It is easy to become lost, but it is in those darkest hours that we must remember what brought us here to begin with. For me, I remember that professor, Laura. I remember telling her that a short story I had written had placed in a writing competition. I remember the quizzical look on her face as she said, “Of course it has,” as if there was never a doubt in her mind that I would succeed. I remember saying to her, a question wrapped in a statement, “Wow, I think I can really <em>do</em> this.” And I remember her slight smile, and her slow yet emphatic <em>yes</em>, drawn out a few extra beats so that there was no mistaking her sincerity.</p>
<p>As lovely as that all sounds (and it is lovely), that doesn’t always work when I’m in a serious funk. In the darkest times, my go to tactic is to stop writing all together. Maybe a week. Maybe a month. Sometimes nearly a year has passed between putting words on a page. But every time I throw myself into a hiatus, no matter the length, I always find myself scrambling back. I just can’t not write. Just a scribble here, a character there, a conversation in that place there, and boom, here comes the rest of it. Usually with a vigor that I’d thought I had lost.</p>
<p>I’d love to know what works for the rest of you. Us writers need all the tips and tricks we can get. I’m 13 years into this game and still learning stuff daily. I also put a couple links at the bottom for inspiration, if you need it.</p>
<p>If you take nothing else from this though, just please don’t forget that you are a writer, and you are magic. And you aren’t alone.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nownovel.com/blog/rediscovering-the-joy-of-writing/">https://www.nownovel.com/blog/rediscovering-the-joy-of-writing/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://thewritepractice.com/joy-of-writing/">https://thewritepractice.com/joy-of-writing/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-joy-of-writing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing While Woman: Celebrating Your Wins</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-while-woman-celebrating-your-wins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffany Meuret]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing While Woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15934</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Writing can be slog. It is a craft we often hone between day jobs, parenting,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16038 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/miguel-bruna-TzVN0xQhWaQ-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/miguel-bruna-TzVN0xQhWaQ-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/miguel-bruna-TzVN0xQhWaQ-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/miguel-bruna-TzVN0xQhWaQ-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />Writing can be slog. It is a craft we often hone between day jobs, parenting, education, bills, grocery shopping, and other everyday life obligations. One in which the successes often mean more work (draft one done, now to start draft two). Writers become accustomed to operating the shadows of other immediacies, pouring their souls into works that might never leave the safe cocoon of their computer screen. So when a win comes along, however small and seemingly inconsequential (trust me, it’s not), there is a tendency among most of us to brush it off, to minimize it to the outside if we even expose it at all, to internalize it because there is just so much more to do.</p>
<p>This is me telling you to knock that the hell off.</p>
<p>I remember my very first short story acceptance. At that point I had been writing for 11 years and had yet to have a published anything to my name. I was elated and excited and beyond myself with the idea that there would be a physical book out there with my name and my words inside. I could hardly contain myself, and then my husband asked me about it and I said something to the likes of, “Yeah, it’s cool, but it’s not a big deal really.” But it was a big deal. It was a huge deal. Looking back, after a few more successes, it’s still a big deal and a memory I cherish. So why do we hold onto this nefarious first instinct to demean it?</p>
<p>Look, the goal posts are always going to shift. Say you want a book deal, the hot minute you get one you’ll be looking sidelong at the authors that scored bigger advances, then to the authors that get multiple book deals, then to the authors that become best sellers, then to the authors that win prestigious awards, then to the authors that have books optioned for movies, etc., and so forth. There’s always more. Bigger. Better. But think about where you were a year ago, or two, or three. Wouldn’t you have dreamed to be where you are now? Back then, didn’t you look up to people like your present self? Now look at what you have done in that span of time. I guarantee you deserve a pat on the back.</p>
<p>As women we are trained from early ages to remain modest, humble, and sweet, and being loud and proud and boisterously celebratory of one&#8217;s own accomplishment runs counterintuitive to those oppressive teachings. Well, screw ‘em. You deserve it. You didn’t write through sleep <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16039 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/ambreen-hasan-E9ANYNkN4Sc-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/ambreen-hasan-E9ANYNkN4Sc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/ambreen-hasan-E9ANYNkN4Sc-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/ambreen-hasan-E9ANYNkN4Sc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />deprivation, through pain and trauma, in between unrelenting schedules and jobs and responsibilities, in the wee hours of the night, or in the face of outright societal and industry hostility just to shrug your shoulders when you hit a goal post. Shout it, let yourself and others you feel safe with bask in all your glory. Those that balk can kindly let the door hit them in the ass on their way out.</p>
<p>Celebrations are infectious. They make you want more, they drive you to not only move your authorial goalpost but to hit the new one too. They help you to remember why you’re doing this to begin with, because it’s not because you enjoy feeling alone and bad about yourself all the time. We write for many personal reasons, but a sense of fulfillment is generally a driving factor behind most of them. And in the face of a wrathful political climate and even more wrathful actual climate, we need our wins more than ever. So take them, own them proudly, cling to them and wear them as the badges of pride and honor that they are. Let them provide a respite to the bullshit, if even for a moment.</p>
<p>And if anyone tries to take that away, pay keen attention, and never be afraid to show them the door.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you don’t believe me, check out these links for further reading-</p>
<p><a href="https://www.thewriterslounge.co/joyfully-j/2018/6/23/how-to-celebrate-writing-success-when-it-seems-hard-to-do">How to Celebrate Writing Success</a></p>
<p><a href="https://writehanded.org/blog/2014/06/22/depression-and-writers-the-great-myth-of-romantic-pain/">The Great Myth of Romantic Pain</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kathycaprino/2017/04/24/5-ways-humility-is-keeping-women-stuck-and-afraid/#66d020a7568c">5 Reasons ‘Humility’ is Keeping Women Stuck and Afraid</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing While Woman: Actually Writing</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-while-woman-actually-writing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffany Meuret]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 20:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing While Woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“How do you manage your work-life balance?” That question is the scourge of all women&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“How do you manage your work-life balance?”</p>
<p>That question is the scourge of all women writers everywhere. It’s often asked during interviews, during panels and conferences, by readers and other writers alike. Often a hot button topic, the mere asking of it is enough to set women creatives on edge for a plethora of nuanced reasons, many of which aim to drive the conversation away from their art and their passions, and instead focus more on their domestic duties as if that’s all we are good for. On top of its inherent demeaning nature, it’s also a lazy question, and no one who invests hundreds upon hundreds of hours into a singular body of work wants to be asked, “That’s great, but what about your laundry?”</p>
<p>It’s a loaded question with an equally loaded answer. In her stand up special on Netflix, writer and comedian Ali Wong gives the perfect answer to why men are not asked how they keep their work and personal life balanced. It is simply, “Because they don’t.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-15246" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-14-at-10.59.15-AM-300x169.png" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-14-at-10.59.15-AM-300x169.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-14-at-10.59.15-AM-768x432.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-14-at-10.59.15-AM-1024x576.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Screen-Shot-2018-05-14-at-10.59.15-AM.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Let me give you a rundown of my average work day, as it stands right now.</p>
<ul>
<li>6:30am, wake up, start getting ready for the day</li>
<li>6:45-7am, get kids up, make breakfast</li>
<li>7:15am-7:30am, pack school lunches, scream at kids from my bathroom to do very basic tasks like brushing teeth or putting on shoes.</li>
<li>7:35-7:45am, kids have done none of these things, panic</li>
<li>7:45-8am, take kids to school, go to work</li>
<li>8:15am-4pm, work my day job</li>
<li>4:30pm, Pick up kids from afterschool care, go home</li>
<li>4:45pm-7 pm, make dinner, homework time (3<sup>rd</sup> graders have obscene amounts of homework)</li>
<li>7pm-7:45pm, coax 9 year old out of existential crisis, clean up after dinner maybe, feed the dogs, kids inevitably start fighting over a Happy Meal toy from 3 months ago, aka my time to “relax”</li>
<li>7:45pm-8:30pm, bath time, read <em>Harry Potter</em> to kids, bed time</li>
<li>8:45pm, whew, I did it, time to &#8212;
<ul>
<li>Nevermind, someone heard a weird noise or needs a drink or is demanding a new pair of socks or needs a tissue or &lt;insert ridiculous claim here&gt;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>9pm to whenever I pass out on couch watching reruns of <em>Frasier</em>&#8211; Me time</li>
</ul>
<p>Not included in this list are any school functions, doctors appointments (unless I took off work to take them during the day), laundry, cleaning, basic household managerial tasks, and simple pleasures like reading a book.</p>
<p>Now let me lay out my husband’s day.</p>
<ul>
<li>Wake up whenever he wants (job has no specific start time)</li>
<li>Work day job</li>
<li>Come home</li>
</ul>
<p>This isn’t to say he doesn’t help; he does do most of the grocery shopping and he’ll fill in on a certain kid duty when I need to tap out, and he gets on a laundry kick on occasion which is always nice, but that’s the thing—he manages exactly NONE of it. Who/what/where/when/how is all kept inside my mental Rolodex. If I need help, I ask. If I leave for a work trip, I have to leave detailed notes on the basic care and management of our house, and am still inundated with calls.</p>
<p>An article in <em>Psychology Today</em> states that, &#8220;Some studies suggest that <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/so-happy-together/201709/who-s-cleaning-the-house">women have almost three times the workload of their husbands</a>. Interestingly, these proportions stay about the same, regardless of whether a wife has a full-time job, and whether or not her husband is currently working.”</p>
<p>Another article in <em>The New York Times</em> goes further by suggesting it will be “<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/05/04/opinion/sunday/men-parenting.html">another 75 years</a> before men do half the work.” Interestingly though, same-sex couples <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/16/upshot/same-sex-couples-divide-chores-much-more-evenly-until-they-become-parents.html">divide chores more evenly</a> (until the kids come, that is).</p>
<p>So I ask you, fellow women writers, how DO we manage our writing-home-work life? It seems to me that this question, in all sincerity, is a valid one. Because I have no damn clue how any of us get anything done. My writing is usually executed in explosive little bursts, usually between 15 to 45 minutes. Sometimes more, sometimes less. The weekends are a little more flexible, but all this comes at a cost—my house is never as clean as I’d like, the laundry piles up, and sometimes the kids eat pop-tarts for dinner (not all the time, but let’s get real here). My spouse is exceedingly supportive of my writing and does make a concerted effort to keep the house in order so I might have a sliver of peace, but in that respect I am very lucky. Many are not. So, truly, how the hell do we do it?</p>
<p>I suppose I don’t have much of answer, because what works for me does not work for everyone. My only advice would be to take whatever time you can get, learn to sprint write the best you can, and don’t sweat being a “slow” writer. If the words come, then you’re doing it.</p>
<p>And you’re awesome for it. Seriously. You. Are. Awesome. As in inspiring awe. Don’t you forget it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing While Woman: Getting It Wrong</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-while-woman-getting-it-wrong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tiffany Meuret]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 11:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing While Woman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s been a lot of uproar in the bookish Twittersphere of late about people (usually&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There’s been a lot of uproar in the bookish Twittersphere of late about people (usually white) stepping in piles of their own privilege and, instead of giving that rank shoe a good scrub (or tossing it in the trash all together), they are pasting a diversity sticker over the filth and carrying on with their lives. As a white woman writer trying to carve my <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nathan-dumlao-263787-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12889 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nathan-dumlao-263787-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>own slice of the publishing kingdom, I find the behavior of my fellow authors rather upsetting most of the time, so with this little space I’ve been afforded, I’d like to announce that I am coming for my fellows. It is time to collect your bags and get that shit organized, and a first of many steps to this is knowing how to behave when you get things wrong.</p>
<p>Because you will. You have already. If you’re old enough to be reading this, you have gotten many things wrong. Since this is a writing column, we will be discussing things like problematic representation and outright racism (unintended, most likely, as the defense usually goes) in your words. We white people, no matter our circumstances, have been steeping in a potent tea of privilege since birth, a concoction so concentrated that we are often unable to distinguish it from reality. This is how books like <em>The Continent</em>, <em>American Heart</em>, and <em>The Black Witch</em> come to not only exist, but be championed by various facets of the industry. This is how publishing con men like <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/02/11/a-suspense-novelists-trail-of-deceptions">Dan Mallory</a> not only skirt around the edges of consequence, but thrive in their mediocrity and deception. Sometimes it is an intentional act of ignorance and hatred, and sometimes the author has no idea what they’re doing it until it blows up in their face.</p>
<p>There are many times when I do see how a prejudiced act was unintentional. Perhaps I see it as a mistake I myself have at one time made, or something I never considered outside the sphere of my own whiteness. But here’s when things get hairy—because while I understand how it happens, it does not excuse the happening. It’s usually at this point where white authors scrawl long, pleading half-apologies about their intentions or long, rage-laced defense testimonies bemoaning political correctness and artistic censorship. The main connective tissue between both screeds is a total mystification on the author’s part that they were not categorically accepted despite their faults. We white people, white women as much as men, are so used to being excused for our bad behavior that it absolutely astounds us when other people demand we confront and atone for our biases.</p>
<p>A reckoning is coming, and many of us are desperately under-trained in the arts of humility, grace, and self-betterment. And we are all the worse for it.</p>
<p>There might not be one singular right way to confront such heavy topics, and this is not meant to serve as some “Four Easy Steps to Assuage White Guilt” kind of article, but I felt it prudent to discuss considering the simmering tensions between authors and readers alike, and because of the outright attacks made against many people of color <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/neonbrand-395901-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12890 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/neonbrand-395901-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>daring to speak out. The burden of education and growth should not always be on the shoulders of the victims of such bad representation. We white people need to be accountable for our own growth, and so here we are.</p>
<p>So, say you find your words on the receiving end of criticism. How should you proceed? Here are my recommendations, for whatever they are worth.</p>
<ol>
<li>Shut your word hole for a minute. Too many bad takes and lazy “apologies” have come on the heels of defensiveness and shock. Trust me, you are not helping yourself or the community at large by lashing out in the hot seconds following sincere critique. With this in mind, see step two.</li>
<li>Check your emotions. Anger and defensiveness are masks for other, deeper feelings, such as embarrassment, disappointment, and fear. Start at the top and drill down. You will not learn, and you will not grow if you continually refuse to uproot the rot. So do it. It might mean coming to a conclusion about yourself that you do not like, but that is the point, isn’t it?</li>
<li>Educate yourself. Read. Do not go screaming to the internet demanding to be taught. Teach yourself. There is an infinite amount of resources at your fingertips able to help you process your own failings and teach you how to correct them. Do the work. (I have included a few links at the bottom of this article as good starting points)</li>
<li>Take action. This is where your mileage may vary. Taking action could mean making a sincere apology. It could mean major revisions to your work. It could mean pulling the work from publication all together. And before you say it, NO, THIS IS NOT CENSORSHIP. This is called accountability, and just because you may not see the issues in your work does not mean you get to blithely shoot harmful words at the world like fabric out of a t-shirt cannon. There are consequences to free speech, my friends, and when white people start baring teeth over things like “censorship”, what they’re really saying is that the consequences should not apply to them. They never have before, and they resent it happening now. If you’re still hung up on this, please repeat step two before moving on.</li>
</ol>
<p>We writers are all on a journey. We all have a story, and we all want to share it with the world. Why not do it spectacularly?</p>
<p>Do the work. Learn. Your craft will thank you for it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Links to get you started:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sealpress.com/titles/ijeoma-oluo/so-you-want-to-talk-about-race/9781580056779/">So You Want to Talk About Race</a> by Ijeoma Oluo</p>
<p><a href="http://www.beacon.org/White-Fragility-P1346.aspx">White Fragility: Why It&#8217;s So Hard for White People to Talk About Racism</a> by Robin DiAngelo</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
