<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Katherine Tomlinson &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/katherine-tomlinson/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:12:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Where do you get your ideas?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/where-do-you-get-your-ideas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 17:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye of the Kat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Where you you get your ideas? Harlan Ellison used to answer that question by saying&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_7289" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7289" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/newsmedia-luna-station-quarterly.jpg" rel="left-image"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7289 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/newsmedia-luna-station-quarterly-300x200.jpg" alt="newsmedia-luna-station-quarterly" width="300" height="200" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7289" class="wp-caption-text">Stevepb/404 images</figcaption></figure>
<p>Where you you get your ideas? <a href="http://harlanellison.com/home.htm">Harlan Ellison</a> used to answer that question by saying “Schenectady.” As a former reporter, I used to get a lot of ideas just from the news—a mention of a particular trend or the name of an interesting person—would be enough to set me off in search of a story that I could craft just for my readers, who were usually most interested in local stories. It was a kind of “think globally, act locally” kind of writing where I would take ideas and make them accessible to the readers of the magazine or newspaper I was working for.</p>
<p>With fiction, the process is a little different but the source remains very much the same. I no longer read two newspapers a day, but I cruise news sites obsessively and not just what is now known as “mainstream media.”  There are always ideas to be found online and sometimes those ideas are pure gold.</p>
<p>My most anthologized story, “In the Kingdom of the Cat,” was inspired by a local network news story about what happens to unclaimed bodies in Los Angeles. The comments section contained a link to a video and as I watched it, tears dripping down my face, the story came to me as an almost completed piece. I wrote the first draft in one sitting, revised it the next day and the story’s been out there ever since.<span id="more-7288"></span></p>
<p>Sometimes I’ll see a news item and know there’s a story there but also know it’s not the story for me. I ran across a reference to “bunny hunters” on CNN not long ago and when I discovered the term referred to a certain kind of online child predator, I felt the familiar prickle of a story waiting to be born. And I knew I could probably get a good story out of my take on that topic but I also knew it would be a story that would make me want to take a scalding hot shower and then immerse myself in a vat of melted chocolate before I would feel human again. That is not a story I want to write.</p>
<p>But I have wanted to write a crime thriller in the vein of <em>Gone Girl </em>or <em>Girl On a Train</em> or James Patterson’s <em>Honeymoon</em> for a while now and while reading a TMZ story (don’t judge) about a murder suicide, I suddenly keyed in on a phrase—<em>A woman presumed to be his wife</em>.</p>
<p>I played that phrase over and over in my mind for nearly a week and then one night, just before I fell asleep, I suddenly knew how my novel could open. I saw the characters. I saw the situation. And I knew that I had something I could spin into a 60,000-word book with a plot that had absolutely nothing to do with the original crime that had attracted my attention.</p>
<p>Where do I get my ideas?</p>
<p><em>Everywhere</em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Identity Crisis</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/identity-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 16:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye of the Kat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alice Bradley Sheldon, the Bronte Sisters, Amantine-Lucile-Aurore Dupin, Mary Ann Evans, Louisa May Alcott—all of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/male-female-mask-2.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7187 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/male-female-mask-2-300x225.jpg" alt="Surreal schizophrenic theater mask depicting mixed emotions" width="300" height="225" /></a>Alice Bradley Sheldon, the Bronte Sisters, Amantine-Lucile-Aurore Dupin, Mary Ann Evans, Louisa May Alcott—all of these women writers published under men’s names and some, as in the case of Alice Bradley Shelton, died without their readers ever knowing the real name of the author they admired. Shelton, who was the award-winning science fiction writer James Tiptree, Jr., had been dead for ten years before her secret came out. Up until then, she’d been praised as a male author who really understood women. In one of her most famous stories, a woman chooses to leave earth and live among aliens because she hates the role that women are assigned on earth. (Read an excerpt from Julie Phillips’ biography of Alice Shelton <a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=6468136">here</a>.)</p>
<p>Like women writers before her, Shelton apparently adopted a male nom de plume for commercial reasons. She wrote science fiction and in the mid-20<sup>th</sup>century, male writers dominated the genre.</p>
<p>Sadly, things haven’t changed much.<span id="more-7186"></span></p>
<p>In the past 50 years, only eleven women have won the Hugo Award for best novel. Several of them—Ursula K. Le Guin, C.J. Cherryh, Connie Willis, and Lois McMaster Bujold—have won multiple times, with Bujold winning two Hugos back to back and another two in the next decade. (The year Connie Willis won her third Hugo (for <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6506307-blackout"><em>Blackout: All Clean</em></a>), she beat out Lois McMaster Bujold, who has been nominated ten times.)</p>
<p>Only one woman of color, this year’s winner N.K. Jemisin (for <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19161852-the-fifth-season?from_search=true"><em>The Fifth Season</em></a>), has won in the last 50 years. (A <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hugo_Award_for_Best_Novel">look</a> at each year’s nominees shows that often, a woman isn’t even nominated in that top category.) So, sci fi still seems to be a boy’s club.</p>
<p>The fantasy landscape mirrors that of science fiction. Only eleven women have won the Nebula Award for best novel since 1966, with Ursula K. Le Guin, Vonda N. McIntyre, and Lois McMaster Bujold winning multiple times. And, as with the Hugos, only one African-American writer (Octavia E. Butler) made the cut.</p>
<p>With those kinds of numbers, should a female writer working in the genres of F &amp; SF consider using a ‘sudo? Would she find more commercial success? More artistic acclaim?</p>
<p>I write under several different names but I don’t make a secret of these writerly alter-egos. My science fiction and fantasy stories come out under the pen name “Kat Parrish.” My crime and horror is written under my real name. I split the work up to keep readers from getting annoyed because they’ve picked something up that’s not to their taste. (Who needs a one-star review?)</p>
<p>I write a lot of different kinds of stories and someone who enjoys one of my HEA fairy tale retellings might not enjoy one of my hard-edged horror pieces, which tend to be very dark. When I started writing my crime fiction, I thought long and hard about writing under a male name. I even had one picked out—R. Lee Parrish. R for my father’s first name; Lee for my brother’s middle name, and Parrish for my middle name. It had a nice ring to it, and crime fiction, despite mega-best-selling female authors, is still perceived by many as a genre reserved for the boys.</p>
<p>In the end, I decided that writing in my favorite genre under a made up name that hid my (gender) identity wasn’t for me. The Bronte sisters wrote in the 19<sup>th</sup> century. Here we are, two hundred years later, and some female writers still feel the need to do the same.</p>
<p>I really hope in 2216 an author gender won’t matter anymore.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>If A Tree Falls</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/if-a-tree-falls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 16:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye of the Kat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To say that I have mixed feelings about promoting my work is an understatement. “If&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To say that I have mixed feelings about promoting my work is an understatement.</p>
<p>“If a tree falls in a forest and no one is around to hear it, does it make a sound?” I’ve heard this philosophical question my whole life but it never really resonated with me until I began publishing my work as an indie author.</p>
<p>Back in 2011, when indie publishing was a new thing, it was still possible for writers to sell a lot of books just on word of mouth alone (Props to you Amanda Hocking!).</p>
<p>But those days are gone, and with them, so are the hopes and dreams of many a would-be indie author.</p>
<p>Nowadays even if you are a successful writer—and for the purposes of this post, I’m defining “successful” as someone who pays her rent with her royalties—you can’t depend on those sales remaining steady, even if you’re working 24/7 to produce a new novel ever four weeks.</p>
<p>Two years ago, Tech Crunch estimated that twelve new books were being added to Amazon every hour. That’s a new book every five minutes.</p>
<p>A new book. Every. Five. Minutes. Or to put it another way, 288 new books are being added every day. Just to Amazon. Who knows how many books are out there on other platforms?</p>
<p>That’s not a rising tide of competition, that’s a tsunami. And the “if you write it they will buy” sales model is no longer working.</p>
<p>If a book is published and no one makes a sound, it’s going to sink under the surface without a ripple.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Screen-Shot-2013-11-10-at-1.02.43-PM.png"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6671 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Screen-Shot-2013-11-10-at-1.02.43-PM.png" alt="Screen-Shot-2013-11-10-at-1.02.43-PM" width="294" height="181" /></a>And that’s where promotion (shudder) and advertising (ghak) come in.  Books + promotion = sales.</p>
<p>Promotion used to feel  … icky to me. I couldn’t quite shake the sense that when I was out there promoting something I’d written, I was no better than a snake oil salesman hawking cheap nostrums and patent medicines to a crowd of gullible yokels.</p>
<p>At best, it seemed undignified.</p>
<p>I knew a lot of writers who agreed with me and whose sole reason for wanting a publishing deal with a traditional publisher was so they didn’t have to handle those marketing and promotion chores themselves. “I’ll have a whole marketing department behind me,” they said, “I won’t have to do that.”</p>
<p>Isn’t it pretty to think so?</p>
<p>Most publishers now want writers to submit a marketing plan along with their manuscripts because they need all the help they can get.</p>
<p>Even Stephen King is out there hustling his wares. So is James Patterson. So is Janet Evanovich. So is Debbie Macomber—who is, by the way, kind of a genius at social media. These are writers who have the full force of a publisher behind them and marketing teams and probably scores of assistants. And they still hustle like they’re selling encyclopedias door to door.</p>
<p>They don’t think it’s tacky to let readers know about their latest book (or in the case of King, books).</p>
<p>So I got over myself.</p>
<p>I try not to be obnoxious (check out the books I write under the pseudonym<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3158107.Kat_Parrish"> Kat Parrish</a>) but I have embraced the promotion.</p>
<p>And you should too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s Time to Bite the Bullet: Taking Responsibility for Violence in Fiction</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/its-time-to-bite-the-bullet-taking-responsibility-for-violence-in-fiction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 15:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye of the Kat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sexual, racial, gender violence and other forms of discrimination and violence in a culture cannot&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em>Sexual, racial, gender violence and other forms of discrimination and violence in a culture cannot be eliminated without changing culture</em>—Charlotte Bunch</p></blockquote>
<p>I didn’t know who <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charlotte_Bunch">Charlotte Bunch</a> was the first time I read this quote but it has resonated with me for a long time. And I have been thinking a lot about the necessity of changing the culture for a while too. I make my living with words and at a certain point, I began to be aware of just how casually we integrate violence into every aspect of our conversation without even realizing it. “I don’t want to beat a dead horse,” we might say when we don’t want to belabor a point. “Kill me now,” we might moan as we’re forced to do some distasteful task. “That’ll kill two birds with one stone,” we observe when it looks like doing something will be a win/win situation.</p>
<p>Scientists have been making connections between acts of violence and violent entertainment for decades. I remember back in 1986 when the movie <em>Heat</em> came out, it took a lot of flak for a scene depicting violence against some homeless men. When that scene was mimicked in real life, a chorus of voices rose condemning Hollywood for its violence. Thirty years on, that movie looks like an episode of <em>Mr. Rogers’ Neighborhood</em> compared to mainstream movies and cable content. <em>Heat</em> came out thirteen years before the high school shooting in Columbine ushered in a new and terrible era in gun violence, a wave of crimes that has broken over the American psyche like a tsunami and left wrecked lives and seemingly endless debate, in its wake.</p>
<p>I used to scoff at the idea that violent entertainment bred violent acts in real life. Paul Verhoeven was criticized for the violence in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zbCbwP6ibR4" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>RoboCop</em> </a>and famously had to trim a crucial scene where a robot shot a boardroom of people to pieces (the scene goes on so long that it becomes grotesquely comic, a lesson that Quentin Tarantino took to heart in his gleefully violent movies). I didn’t bat an eyelash when I saw <em>RoboCop</em>, though I remember being horrified in college by a similar scene in <em>The Godfather</em> where a mobster gets pulverized by bullets. It upset me enough I had to look away.</p>
<p>What a difference a decade makes.</p>
<p>It’s like the famous <a href="http://www.lessons4living.com/wmaz_week200.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">“boiling the frog” analogy.</a> By the time I realized that I’d become desensitized to violence, I had become part of the problem.</p>
<p>One of the drawbacks of writing crime fiction as “a girl” is that there’s a perception we’re not as tough as the men. And that pressures us to be more hard-boiled than a plate of deviled eggs.</p>
<p>Never one to accept pigeon-holing, I rose to the challenge. A lot of my fiction was dark, much of it was violent, either emotionally or physically. My characters rarely used guns, but there are many ways to “skin a cat” as yet another common saying goes, and I dealt murder and mayhem like a Vegas croupier.</p>
<p>I won some contests with that writing.</p>
<p>I even won a few awards.</p>
<p>But a few years ago I stopped scoffing at the idea that writers were responsible for inciting acts of violence.</p>
<p>And I kept thinking about that Charlotte Bunch quote and wondering what role I should play in that change in the culture. And I wonder where that leaves me as a writer of crime fiction. Does that mean I should only write cozies?</p>
<p>Kill me now.</p>
<p>Except don’t.</p>
<p>I’m still trying to figure it out. And in the meantime, I write blog posts about gun laws and vote for candidates who share my concerns, and write checks to organizations like the Brady Campaign to Prevent Gun Violence and Americans for Responsible Solutions.</p>
<p>And when I write a violent scene in one of my stories, I make damn sure that it’s there for a reason. There’s too much mindless violence in real life, I don’t want to add my voice to that cacophony.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting Real</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/getting-real/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 16:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye of the Kat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I used to write a lot of crime and horror fiction and the horror, especially,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I used to write a lot of crime and horror fiction and the horror, especially, was pretty dark. While there were often supernatural elements involved, much of the horror was derived from human behavior. These were not cheery little stories. I placed a lot of these stories in anthologies—almost none of them offering pay—and then I put them up on Amazon in case someone wanted a quick shot of short horror to read during lunchtime or on a bus.</p>
<p>I didn’t sell many of these stories.</p>
<p>That was disappointing because I actually thought some of those horror and crime stories were pretty good. And I’m a harsh critic of my own work.</p>
<p>I continued to write my crime and horror stories—because I really enjoy the genre but I noticed that sometimes when I finished one of my dark stories, I’d feel a little depressed and not with the creative post-partum depression that you get.</p>
<p>I’d be feeling cranky and wouldn’t be able to put my finger on it.</p>
<p>And then one day my brother asked me if I ever wrote any happy stories.</p>
<p>And I realized I didn’t.</p>
<p>I really didn’t.</p>
<p>My stories didn’t have happy endings, they had twist endings. My plots weren’t just cynical, they were misanthropic. My characters didn’t just have flaws, they were flawed. Deeply flawed in most cases.</p>
<p>And their stories were depressing. Deeply depressing in some cases, as several reviewers pointed out when I published them in a collection called <em>Toxic Reality</em>. I’ve since pulled that collection, along with one called <em>The Poisoned Teat</em> because the reviewers were right.</p>
<p>I kept writing my dark little stories and while I could give them away, nobody seemed that interested in actually paying for one.</p>
<p>And I started thinking.</p>
<p><em>Maybe no one reads my stories because they aren’t the kinds of stories people want to read.</em></p>
<p>Could it be?</p>
<p>Maybe another writer would have decided that she simply wasn’t very talented and given up altogether, but I really didn’t want to come to that conclusion. So rather than quit, I decided to do something radical. I decided to stop being self-indulgent and act more like a professional.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/be-a-happy-writer.png" rel="attachment wp-att-5669"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5669 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/be-a-happy-writer-300x200.png" alt="be-a-happy-writer" width="300" height="200" /></a>I decided to lighten up.</p>
<p>Maybe that sounds like selling out but here’s the thing—I’m a full-time freelance writer. I actually pay my bills with my writing. You know those ebooks on trending topics like “oil pulling” and the latest new diet? I write those. I also ghost-write blog posts for several social-media impaired clients, and write white papers and reports.</p>
<p>It’s just as exciting as it sounds, and when a client says she wants forty thousand words (plus recipes) to help sell some new kitchen gadget, I don’t have the option to say, “Sorry, I’m not feeling it. How about I write an expose on conspicuous consumerism and pricey kitchen gadgets instead?”</p>
<p>So as I said, two years ago I decided to lighten up. I’d always written fantasy and romance under my pseudonym Kat Parrish and I started spending more time with the fantasy and romance and less time with the crime and horror.</p>
<p>And a funny thing happened.</p>
<p>Beginning with a Cinderella spin on a vampire tale I called <em>Bride of the Midnight King</em>, I started selling my fiction. And not just to people related to me. Although my best friend’s mother read it and recommended it to all her friends.</p>
<p>I wrote another fairy tale, this one only a novelette, and it started selling too. An anthology that had accepted a futuristic fairy tale from me fell apart before publication and I put that up for sale as a stand-alone too. That one doesn’t sell as well, but people in the Kindle Select program seem to like “borrowing” it.</p>
<p>I’m now finishing up a contemporary romance that I’m publishing just before Christmas. It also has a Cinderella spin but it’s not completely devoid of reality. There are Syrian refugees and LGBT characters and people who die too soon. But in the end, what it is, is a bright and shiny love story that suits the season. I hope it will sell but who knows?</p>
<p>The one thing I do know for sure is that it made me happy to write it.</p>
<p>I’ve come to believe in the validity of an old bumper sticker sentiment, “Reality is for those who lack imagination.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Place as Character</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/place-as-character/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 15:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye of the Kat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5092</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I grew up all over the place but I came of age in Los Angeles.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I grew up all over the place but I came of age in Los Angeles. I moved there when I was 22 and left decades later; older, wiser, and many shades blonder.</p>
<p>For years, Los Angeles was the setting of my first fiction: the crime stories, the urban fantasies, the dark tales I concocted for <a href="http://nohonoir.blogspot.com/"><em>NoHo Noir</em></a>, the serial novel I wrote for America Online, two episodes a week for a year.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Los_Angeles_Region.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5096 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/Los_Angeles_Region-300x200.jpg" alt="Los_Angeles_Region" width="300" height="200" /></a>L.A. was my go-to location for stories, a backdrop as varied as the city’s neighborhoods but as familiar as my own bedroom. I drew inspiration for characters from the wide cross-section of people I interacted with every day—the recovering addicts dosing on methadone at the clinic next door to the drive-through Starbucks, the poly-lingual nursing student from Morocco who managed my apartment building, the wannabe screenwriters walking their dogs at the dog park with one eye out for possible celebrity encounters that could be turned into opportunities. Anyone who crossed my path got tucked away in the file drawer marked “potential” and when I sat down to write a story, I opened that drawer and rummaged through it pulling out little bits of character stuffed in there without much attempt at organization.</p>
<p>L.A. was a rich wellspring for my fiction. I found stories in every corner of the city—the quirky human interest news, the bizarre true crime reports, the random collision of culture that raises bloody blisters.</p>
<p>I was never short of material.</p>
<p>And then I moved.</p>
<p>I moved to a beautiful town in the Pacific Northwest that is laced with urban trails that thread through green spaces and parks and ramble past waterfalls and haunted cemeteries. I live in a house that faces a small stand of birch trees, a tiny wood that is home to deer and black squirrels and, if the local rumors are to be believed, coyotes as well.</p>
<p>At the height of summer, the air smelled like hot blackberry wine, the fruit hanging heavy in opportunistic brambles so thick they turned paths into impassible walls of green thorns.</p>
<p>I thought of “Briar Rose’ and “Cinderella.”</p>
<p>I thought of a lot of my favorite fairy tales and how I might re-tell them for a collection.</p>
<p>I jotted down notes but I haven’t yet written the stories.</p>
<p>I saw an anthology call for paranormal stories set in the Pacific Northwest (the title of the antho is <em>Blood on the Rain</em>, and I can’t wait to read it).</p>
<p>I wrote a first sentence for a story in which a murder victim is found in a ditch—a ditch that’s actually in my neighborhood. But I didn’t get any further.</p>
<p>And then the deadline passed.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/whatcom-falls-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5093 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/whatcom-falls-2-300x225.jpg" alt="whatcom-falls (2)" width="300" height="225" /></a>I went out to my favorite city park, the one with a mossy old stone bridge over a waterfall and I soaked in the atmosphere and luxuriated in the smell of cold water splashing against old stone. I thought of Rivendell. I could feel the magic hovering but it was just out of my reach, like a glimpse of something seen from the corner of your eye that disappears when you turn to look at it full-on.</p>
<p>I know that waterfall has a story for me.</p>
<p>But I don’t know what it is.</p>
<p>I know the history of this place that is my new home. I have read about its maritime past and wicked ways during Prohibition when it was a conduit for illegal whiskey coming down from Canada. I appreciate the place it is now: a liberal community in a liberal state where neighbors look out for neighbors and buying organic is easy because the local farmers sell their produce directly to the grocery stores. Bicycle theft is a nuisance here and other low-rent property crimes as well. But this is a community that looks after its have-nots. Every single weekend seems to host a few charity events and during the winter there are food drives and warm coat collections, and opportunities to volunteer in every sort of way. . And they <em>really</em> like the Seahawks here, as you can tell on Fridays when everyone wears their Hawks gear during football season.</p>
<p>I bought a t-shirt.</p>
<p>I wear it on Fridays.</p>
<p>And I blend in like a native.</p>
<p>But I cannot seem to find the heart of a story here.</p>
<p>Sometimes I’ll look out my window and see the sun setting over the bay and marvel at the spectacle, a riot of colors more delicate than the pollution-driven technicolor sunsets of L.A.</p>
<p>Sometimes I’ll listen to the wind soughing in the woods behind the house or catch a glimpse of a doe and her dappled fawn and it gives me an almost physical ache to capture the feeling and the moment and the experience.</p>
<p>But I haven’t been able to do it yet.</p>
<p>If anyone asks me how I like living here, away from the hustle and the crush and the sheer meanness of Los Angeles, I tell them I love it, and that’s the truth.</p>
<p>But I can’t seem to write this place to save my life.</p>
<p>And until I can, it won’t feel like home.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A New York state of mind. Only not.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-new-york-state-of-mind-only-not/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 16:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye of the Kat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Can I tell you a secret? If I never read another love story set in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-4601 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/retro-la-palm-tree-image-249x300.jpg" alt="landscape with palm-trees and moon on brown old textured paper" width="249" height="300" />Can I tell you a secret?</p>
<p>If I never read another love story set in New York City, I’ll be fine.</p>
<p>If I never see another movie where the lovers meet at the top of the Empire State Building or go walking in Central Park or skating at Rockefeller Center, I won’t shed a tear.</p>
<p>And it’s not that I hate New York.</p>
<p>I get that “New York City” is cultural shorthand and stands for X, Y, and Z when it comes to setting and backdrop and mood. That’s why it’s been used so much.</p>
<p>And that’s why I’ll probably never write a story that takes place in New York.</p>
<p>Because although I’ve never lived there, I feel like I have lived there too long and it’s time to move.</p>
<p>Seriously, New York does not have a lock on romantic places. Yes, they have Central Park but D.C. has Rock Creek Park, Los Angeles has Griffith Park, San Francisco has Golden Gate Park. Even Richmond, Virginia has the beautiful Maymont Park. In the Pacific Northwest they have city parks with waterfalls. Does New York City have a waterfall? I think not. (But wait, you say, there are at least five waterfalls in Central Park. That’s true but they’re all man-made and the water that flows through them is piped in. That doesn’t count.)</p>
<p>Nor is New York the only place in the U.S. where you can get that authentically Gothic creepy feeling. Leaving out New Orleans, which is a city in a league of its own, there are lots of places where a writer might set a ghost story or a story of demonic possession or a tale of supernatural horror. Many, many, many places. And yet, somehow, we always end up back in New York City.</p>
<p>And I’m bored with that.</p>
<p>One of the interesting things about the House of Night books is that mother/daughter writing duo P.C. and Kristin Cast have set it in Tulsa, Oklahoma. They make good use of the location and also of Native American legends, including the “Raven Mocker,” which is part of one of the most dramatic subplots in the series. House of Night would have been just another series about young vampires if it hadn’t been for those elements, which set the books apart.</p>
<p>And that, I think is the lesson.</p>
<p>I don’t think writers should be afraid to use their own settings for their stories, even if they don’t live in one of the big cities. Every place has its secrets, every place has its charms.</p>
<p>And you will never know a place as well as you know your own home, no matter how many YouTube videos you watch or how many websites you research.</p>
<p>I think writing “where you know” is as important as writing “what you know.”</p>
<p>I spent most of my adult life in Los Angeles, and most of my fiction is set there, even the paranormal/urban fantasy stories I write.</p>
<p>I lived there so long I felt like a native, and I lived in so many of its different neighborhoods, that I feel like I can capture the authentic voice of the place, whether it’s multicultural slang or show biz jargon.</p>
<p>So my love stories take place in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>And my urban fantasies take place there.</p>
<p>And so does most of the horror I write.</p>
<p>I’m not a New Yorker and I never will be, so why should I set my stories there?</p>
<p>And why should you?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>In praise of E.L. James</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/in-praise-of-e-l-james/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 15:31:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye of the Kat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I know a lot of people who couldn&#8217;t wait for the movie version of 50 Shades&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know a lot of people who couldn&#8217;t wait for the movie version of <i>50 Shades of Grey</i> to open. Not because they looked forward to seeing Dakota Johnson and Jamie Dornan bring the characters to vivid life, but so they could heap scorn on it. They fully expected the movie adaptation to live down to their expectations, which were low. They didn’t like the book—even though many of them didn’t actually read it—and they have nothing but disdain for the woman whose “midlife crisis writ large” spawned a trilogy that has to date sold 100 million copies worldwide. To put that figure in context consider this: James did not publish her first book until 2011 and it was self-published to begin with, available as an ebook and in print on demand.</p>
<p>That’s right, while Kindle millionaire Amanda Hocking was getting the press and the praise for turning her paranormal romances into big bucks, E. L. James (real name Erika Mitchell) was quietly making the transition from writing fanfic to crafting the erotic novel that would become a worldwide sensation.</p>
<p>And she was doing it the hard way—as an indie author.</p>
<p>I celebrate E. L. James’s success.</p>
<p>She was 48 when she published <i>50 Shades of Grey</i>. She is two years older than J.K. Rowling, who published the first Harry Potter novel when she was 34, and 12 years older than Stephenie Meyer, who was 32 when <i>Twilight</i> was published in 2005. James deserves to be part of that trilogy of powerhouse writers because she achieved her 100 million sales with just three books while Meyer wrote four <i>Twiligh</i>t novels and a novella and Rowling’s series spanned seven books over the course of a decade.</p>
<p>Of the three women, who I would argue transformed the literary landscape, only Rowling gets any respect, which she richly deserves. Not only did she create a terrific universe populated by a wide and diverse cast of characters, but in real life her charitable works have made her an admirable role model.</p>
<p>I (heart) J.K. Rowling.</p>
<p>But I also have a lot of respect for Meyer and James. I’ve read both women’s work and you won’t find me among those who reflexively bash their books. (That goes for the Suzanne Collins haters, too. If you don’t like the <i>Hunger Games</i> books, you should read her Gregor the Underlander series, which has some of the best characters you’ll ever meet in a book).</p>
<p>I first heard about <i>Twilight</i> from a friend’s daughter, a teenager with writing ambitions of her own. She loved the book and recommended I read it.</p>
<p>I first read <i>50 Shades of Grey</i> when one of my best friends—who rarely read anything longer than a People magazine article—told me how much she’d liked it. I figured a book that captured (!) and held her attention had to be worth a look.</p>
<p>And it was. James, by sharing her own fantasies, had tapped into a deep, dark vein of female longing that had really only been explored before in Nancy Friday’s landmark book <i>My Secret Garden</i>. And <i>that </i>book came about—if the writer of the Wikipedia article is to be believed—because Friday had included a woman’s sexual fantasy in a novel she’d written and an editor had objected.</p>
<p>When I hear the dismissive phrase “mommy porn” applied to James’s books, I find myself sighing and wondering if things really haven’t changed all that much in 40 years.</p>
<p>But mostly what annoys me about much of the criticism leveled at James (and to a certain extent at Stephenie Meyer as well) is that it’s disguised as “litcrit.” The blogsters bashing this writer are doing so as if her prose has personally offended their high standards of what a written entertainment should be. They gleefully extract paragraphs and quote lines in their reviews to demonstrate just how clumsy James’ writing is or to illustrate whatever point they want to make about her shallow characterization and superficial plotting.</p>
<p>This intellectual snobbery might be more persuasive if these same writers were reviewing works of true literature on their blogs and sites—if, say, they were showcasing the latest novel by Herta Muller, the German novelist who received the Nobel Prize in Literature in 2009. More often than not, though, these same writers are waxing rhapsodic about an episode of a cult television show that changed their lives.</p>
<p>There’s a disconnect there—like native New Yorkers who dismiss Los Angeles as a cultural wasteland, not because they can’t find great museums and theater and symphonies and restaurants, but because they miss the bagels they used to purchase on their way home after a night of serious hipster hijinks.</p>
<p>I think of James as the natural successor to romance novelist Jackie Collins, whose first book, &#8220;The World is Full of Married Men&#8221;, was published in 1968 and immediately slammed by Barbara Cartland, the best-selling romance novelist of all-time (one billion books sold) as “nasty, filthy, and disgusting.” But Collins’ books combined sex and celebrity in a way that caught on and almost 50 years later, she’s sold more than 400 million copies of her 29 novels.</p>
<p>To put that into perspective, the combined sales of Stephen King’s 54 novels is in the 350 million range. He doesn’t get the respect he’s due either, but he gets more than Jackie Collins ever did.</p>
<p>Or Stephenie Meyer.</p>
<p>Or E.L. James.</p>
<p>If you didn’t like <i>50 Shades</i> or <i>Twilight</i> (or <i>Hunger Games</i>), you are entitled to your opinion. But you are not entitled to belittle the people who did.</p>
<p>Because your opinion is not worth more than anyone else’s.</p>
<p>It really isn’t.</p>
<p>And you should probably think twice before you get personal and bash a writer who wrote a book that connected with a worldwide audience in a visceral way.</p>
<p>E.L. James is a writer who is living the dream that many aspire to.</p>
<p>I celebrate E. L. James.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gender Bender</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/gender-bender/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 17:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye of the Kat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some of the most enduring female characters in literature were created by male authors—Miss Havisham&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some of the most enduring female characters in literature were created by male authors—Miss Havisham and Madame Defarge (Charles Dickens), Becky Sharp (William Makepeace Thackeray), Anna Karenina (Leo Tolstoy), and Daisy Miller (Henry James). Almost any list of memorable literary heroines is top-heavy with female-centric titles written by men, from Gustave Flaubert’s Madame Bovary to Daniel DeFoe’s Moll Flanders to Steig Larsson’s The Girl With the Dragon Tattoo filling in the gaps between Jane Austen and the Bronte sisters and Harper Lee.</p>
<p>If you want to switch the gender up and enumerate the great male characters written by women the list seems to be a lot shorter. There’s J.K. Rowling’s Harry Potter, and Edith Wharton’s Ethan Frome and there’s not a lot in between. (And even those women whose male characters would make the list often wrote under a male pseudonym or their initials to disguise their sex like S. E. Hinton and George Sand and James Tiptree, Jr.).</p>
<p>I’ve been thinking a lot about perceived gender in writing lately because I have a client who has written a terrific paranormal romantic adventure. The story is told from multiple points of view, three of them female. The writer is male and he’s very, very worried that female readers will not give him a chance because he’s writing in a niche where most writers are either women or men hiding behind female pseudonyms. I have tried to reassure him that his fears are groundless but … are they?</p>
<p>There’s a lot of talk in the crime fiction community about the bias against female writers and yet some of the most celebrated mystery writers of all time were not only women, they were women who created male series characters. The list begins with Agatha Christie’s Hercule Poirot and continues with Dorothy L. Sayers’ Lord Peter Wimsey, Ellis Peters’ Brother Cadfael, Josephine Tey’s Alan Grant, M.C. Beaton’s Hamish Macbeth, and Louise Penny’s Armand Gamache and beyond.</p>
<p>It seems to me that crime fiction readers are more open to inclusive points of view than readers of other genres, but maybe I’m biased because I write a lot of crime fiction and have never felt discriminated against because I use my own name. I’ve never really wondered if using a more gender neutral byline like K. Lee Tomlinson (borrowing my brother’s middle name) might have widened my reading audience. Maybe I’m the product of a generation for which gender is irrelevant in a way it never was before. Maybe I’m a cock-eyed optimist.</p>
<p>Is it presumptuous of a writer of one sex to use the voice of the opposite sex? Do you find it distracting if a narrator in a first-person point of view is not the same sex as the writer? Would you read a paranormal romance written by a man? Would you read a techno-thriller written by a woman? What do you think?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sisterhood is powerful in &#8220;Family Matters&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/sisterhood-is-powerful-in-family-matters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katherine Tomlinson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 17:34:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Eye of the Kat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In this latest collection of short stories by members of the New York Tri-State Sisters&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22812277-family-matters?ac=1"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1406217702l/22812277.jpg" alt="" width="188" height="290" /></a>In this latest collection of short stories by members of the New York Tri-State Sisters in Crime, editor Anita Page—whose story “Their Little Secret” anchors the antho—has assembled 20 tales from veterans and newbies alike, tying them together thematically with Tolstoy’s famous line about all “unhappy families being unhappy in their own way.”</p>
<p>Each story distills the bitter essence of sick secrets exposed, sibling rivalry unleashed, and patience coming to an end. Kate Lincoln’s visceral “The July Rebellion” blends seamlessly with Leigh Neeley’s “My Brother’s Keeper,” and Triss Stein’s “Eldercare.” The writing throughout the collection is so strong that it comes as a genuine surprise that Ellen Quint’s accomplished and self-assured “Crossing the Line” is her first piece of published fiction. Here’s how her jaded heroine reacts to her latest client:</p>
<p><em>Millie reached down, opened her bottom desk drawer, pushed aside the Glock and pulled out the tissue box, offering it to her newest client—this mess of a female who had just confessed that she suspected her husband of cheating. Millie knew how this one would end. Of course the putz was having an affair, and of course this sobbing, pitiful woman would be just another friggin’ forgiver. That’s what Millie called them and she could spot them as soon as they crossed her threshold.</em></p>
<p>These stories all have a distinct and specific sense of place, whether they unfold in the middle of the New York Marathon (Dierdre Verne’s cinematic “Dead Last”) or at a lonely beach house (“Their Little Secret”). Thomas Wolfe famously said, “Only the dead know Brooklyn,” but these writers prove him wrong, with their insider’s look at the borough and other locations in the city that never sleeps.</p>
<p>In addition to a sense of place the stories have an acute sense of time as well, whether it’s an endless holiday slog that strands a narrator on Throg’s Neck Bridge on Thanksgiving or the paranoid Cold War backdrop of Clare Toohey’s “Stealing Home.” Many of the stories are riffs on the recession, adding a dire sense of economic reality to the post-millennial mayhem of the crimes being committed. Money and murder are as inextricably entwined in family matters as the DNA responsible for hair and eye color and hatred begins at home, or so it seems.</p>
<p>Speaking of time and place—Fran Bannigan Cox’s story, “Everything in its Place,” and its depiction of a woman with OCD is a terrific story about a woman whose mania for organization lulls her into a false sense of security.</p>
<p><em>No time like the present, I always said. I got the twine from the utility drawer in the kitchen. The tape, string, and wire drawer had everything I needed for wrapping handfuls of new cutlery, a separate bundle each for forks, knives, and spoons. Twine for metal things, color-coded string for all others. I’d had a work drawer in every room for ages. No one could say I wasn’t tidy. Nothing worse than things out of place.</em></p>
<p>After reading this collection, you may find yourself with a renewed appreciation for your own family’s foibles—or at least be profoundly grateful that none of your relatives have a homicidal bent. That you know of.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
