<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Fandom Files &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-fandom-files/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 03:34:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Hugo Awards and the AO3</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-hugo-awards-and-the-ao3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 10:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fandom Files]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15150</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In early April, the World Science Fiction Society announced the nominees for the 2019 Hugo&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15353 alignleft" src="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/1200px-Hugo_Award_Logo.svg_-200x300.png" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/1200px-Hugo_Award_Logo.svg_-200x300.png 200w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/1200px-Hugo_Award_Logo.svg_-768x1152.png 768w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/1200px-Hugo_Award_Logo.svg_-683x1024.png 683w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/1200px-Hugo_Award_Logo.svg_.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />In early April, the World Science Fiction Society announced the <a href="http://www.thehugoawards.org/2019/04/2019-hugo-award-1944-retro-hugo-award-finalists/">nominees for the 2019 Hugo Awards</a>. This happens every year, but when looking through the list, it was obvious what people would be really interested in it this year. The massive fanfiction site, the <a href="https://archiveofourown.org/">Archive of Our Own</a> (known colloquially as the AO3) had been nominated for “Best Related Work,” finally, officially, joyfully cementing the importance of the massive project that receives more traffic than most other digital libraries. For reference, Alexa (the website ranking system) puts AO3 in the 630s. Project Gutenberg is 4,913, HBO.com is at 2,498, Fanfiction.net is 967, JSTOR is 907. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But the Hugos aren’t popularity contests. What makes the Archive worthy of inclusion is hard to quantify with numbers, but it’s easy to see why an archive dedicated to the preservation of fanwork, which has for so long gone hand-in-hand with science fiction of all kinds, would be considered for a nomination. The Archive is also a non-profit entity, free to use, browse, and easy to be a part of. The archive is built to facilitate community involvement, but it doesn’t have social media structures: no real dashboard, chat feature, or &#8220;following&#8221;. You can subscribe to authors, but that means you will get an email whenever the author starts a new fic or posts a new chapter. Ultimately connecting over the Archive is difficult, but that’s fine. That’s not really what the AO3 was built for. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Archive was built for fans, by fans, developed, run, and owned totally by volunteers and monetarily supported through a majority of small, micro-donations during annual drives. The Archive is a project of the Organization for Transformative Works (OTW), which also supports other fannish projects like Fanlore (a wiki of fandoms, fanwork, meta, fanart, artists, vidders, authors, and zines), the Fan Studies project, and Legal Advocacy for fans, which keeps places like the Archive protected, and protects the rights of fans to draw, write, talk, and vid about their favorite characters using pieces of an already-established IP. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a primer. Let’s get down to why the Hugos decided that now was a good time to nominate not the OTW, but the Archive specifically. Besides the sheer traffic and scope of the project, the infrastructure needed to support what fans are looking for is desperately complicated, open-source, and created almost entirely by volunteers. When a fan creates a work, they often use ‘Tags’ to describe what they are doing. Tags are used as both descriptors and search terms, which means that the tags one person uses for a Spock/Kirk fic could be totally different than what another user applies to their own Spock/Kirk fic. The interior logic of those two users might be different, but if you are using the Archive to search for Spock/Kirk fic, you want to be able to see both fics, even if the tags are totally different. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And the surprising, amazing, beautiful thing is that you can find both fics, even if you search <img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15354 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/markus-spiske-518966-unsplash-300x196.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="196" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/markus-spiske-518966-unsplash-300x196.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/markus-spiske-518966-unsplash-768x501.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/markus-spiske-518966-unsplash-1024x668.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />‘K/S,’ ‘I Believe in the Premise,’ ‘James T. Kirk/Spock,’ or ‘Spirk,’ one of the most unfortunate portmanteau ship names in existence. The reason I get all these fics and more is that the Archive has created a series of tag associations that are systematically updated behind the scenes by volunteers known as Tag Wranglers. Wranglers need to be well-versed in the fandom, active enough to keep up with trends, and clever enough to decipher what a person means to say and what they intend for people to use within their search for the perfect Spirk hurt/comfort fic. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The search functions of the site are so massive and the demand is so varied, expansive, and specific, that the Archive has gone to extreme and unparalleled lengths to create a database that will allow a user to craft a search for the most specific kind of fic. For example, </span><a href="https://archiveofourown.org/works?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;commit=Sort+and+Filter&amp;work_search%5Bsort_column%5D=revised_at&amp;include_work_search%5Bfandom_ids%5D%5B%5D=27&amp;include_work_search%5Bfandom_ids%5D%5B%5D=223663&amp;work_search%5Bother_tag_names%5D=&amp;exclude_work_search%5Bfandom_ids%5D%5B%5D=205859&amp;exclude_work_search%5Bcharacter_ids%5D%5B%5D=2675&amp;work_search%5Bexcluded_tag_names%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bcrossover%5D=T&amp;work_search%5Bcomplete%5D=T&amp;work_search%5Bwords_from%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bwords_to%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bdate_from%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bdate_to%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bquery%5D=&amp;work_search%5Blanguage_id%5D=&amp;tag_id=Boondock+Saints+%28Movies%29"><span style="font-weight: 400;">this search</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> shows only completed fics within the Boondocks Saints fandom, crossed-over with the Supernatural fandom, excluding the character Castiel, and without any crossover with The Walking Dead, sorted by the last date updated. Just as an example, this sort of structure is incredible. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This system alone is deserving of an award (or several) but the infrastructure of the site is not the only reason the Archive is up for a Hugo. The fact is that so many fans have contributed to this site, in a beautiful, inspiring, indulgent, and ultimately, selfless way. Many people cut their teeth on fic, many more only write fic, some scrub their fic of all references to the original IP and sell their reskinned work to a major publisher. The Archive is an incubator for the next round of authors and writers, and it’s all built within a community that supports creators and content in a way that protects their right to write whatever they want, in whatever kind of fandom they want to create for themselves. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fact is that larger media companies and private ventures will always have censorship laws that limit the kind of work that is hosted on its servers. The AO3 was built and conceived with the express goal of not allowing private interests, advertisers, or stakeholders to make demands of the content allowed on the Archive. This mission is surprisingly more controversial and more progressive than ever thought. So many sites stress censorship for the sake of protecting audiences, but this is a site that directly asks creators and audiences to engage with whatever content they want to engage with. This is tricky, of course, and the Archive has set up safety measures within their tag system to create warnings and notes so that people can understand exactly what they’re getting into when they click on a fic. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15355 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/tianyi-ma-1066731-unsplash-300x198.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="198" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/tianyi-ma-1066731-unsplash-300x198.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/tianyi-ma-1066731-unsplash-768x508.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/tianyi-ma-1066731-unsplash-1024x677.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Fans and volunteers who work on and contribute to the Archive didn’t need the validation of a Hugo award, but it does feel good to see. The Hugos have always been fan friendly, and many of the nomination categories include Best Fanzine, Fancast, Fan Writer, and Fan Artist. It makes sense that eventually the largest archive of fanwork on the planet would be nominated for an award. The fact is that it’s not just the technical aspects of the AO3 which merit inclusion, but the fanwork that’s hosted on the site is, on its own, worthy of praise. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fanwork, fandom, fanfic, and ultimately, fans, deserve to be given a Hugo award for the sheer dedication and love they have for their media obsessions. The love of fandom is hard to understand unless you’re in it, unless you’ve written over 50K words for a single fic, unless you’ve cried over a character’s death in a fic, unless you’ve printed out a fic and read it over and over, unless you’ve had to hide your Kindle while on public transit, unless you’ve seen fandoms flare and die within months. There are so many aspects of fandom that there is no exclusivity or accessibility test for the Archive. You can be a part of it without any gatekeeping, judgment, or social pressure. You can enjoy what you want, you can find what you want, and you can contribute as much (or as little) as you want. All for free, all for fans and by fans. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This article might be a love letter to the Archive of Our Own, but all this praise is deserved. The fans on the Archive absolutely deserve an award for their work, both behind the scenes and on the Recently Updated page. Fingers crossed we get it. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Many Manys: Flame Con, Fandom, and Joy</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-many-manys-flame-con-fandom-and-joy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 10:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fandom Files]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was halfway through Flame Con, eating breakfast Sunday morning before I caught a train&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was halfway through Flame Con, eating breakfast Sunday morning before I caught a train uptown, and I decided to text my friend <a href="https://twitter.com/zforzelma?lang=en">Kelsey</a>. She had run a panel the day before—the first panel I attended at the convention—and I wanted to let her know how meaningful it was. Kelsey moderated a discussion about the need for queer joy in media. The full effect of this talk, which seemed fairly obvious at first, didn’t sink in until later in the day, when I started going through the main showroom, attending more panels, and visiting more workshops. What Kelsey had said in her first panel—there is a deep, spacious, massive need for the beauty of simply being happy—had only been emphasized over and over throughout the rest of the day. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.flamecon.org/">Flame Con</a>, for those of you that may not know, bills itself as the world’s largest LGBTQ+ Comic Convention. It <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/josh-wilburne-501963-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11412 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/josh-wilburne-501963-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>usually takes place in late summer, in New York City, and this year, it spanned two floors of a large hotel. There are hundreds of vendors, three to four workshops or panels for every time slot, and a dedicated Gaymer Lounge, where tabletop, trading card games, and a video game station are all set up and happening. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The con started with gay actor <a href="https://twitter.com/CecilBaldwinIII?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor">Cecil Baldwin</a>—the voice of gay character Cecil Palmer of <em><a href="http://www.welcometonightvale.com/">Welcome to Nightvale</a></em>—introducing everyone to Flame Con. He reminded us that fandom and comics were increasingly becoming more and more queer, diverse, and experimental. There is space for us, and there is a need for us. The ability to be in community with other fans who are Like You is a powerful thing. Baldwin’s speech—upbeat, joyful, proud—reminded everyone of the power in Queer gathering. We were there, and we were empowered by ourselves. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The diversity of the room was obvious and not-obvious. People wore pronoun tags, dressed as their favorite queers, queered their favorite straights, and showed up with creativity and power. Baldwin finished by pointing out that there was so much difference in the room. Difference in who we were, in what we loved, but ultimately the many differences were what made us strong, powerful, and beautiful. “We are the many manys. And our stories are here, in this room.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I went out into the con and saw those many manys. I tried to go to as many panels as possible where I would learn about the different, beautiful ways that my community creates art, stories, and community. I’ve already mentioned The Subversive Simplicity of Queer Joy, but it fully defined what it meant to be queer and happy. Kelsey Hercs, the moderator, recently wrote a play in which a fabulously gay party occurs. She wanted to show that “joy is accessible” to queer people. So often it isn’t, or isn’t shown on screen. <a href="http://www.snakewife.com/">Stan Stanley</a> also touched on why she loved the villains so much. They are usually queer-coded, and she said that “villains are usually the happiest queers on screen. Lets make them our  heroes.” <a href="http://www.mustachebabs.com/">Barbara Perez Marquez</a> mentioned that “there is a freedom in finding your own joy.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This active reclaiming of queerness and joyfulness was another theme. Cosplay, drag, and performances of queerness express publicly what many people already know and see as an art form. It’s showing people that we can exist in all bodies, and in all people. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some of the most joyful panels spoke to the queer experience of growing up queer—and not really knowing it. “Let’s Talk About Scouts, Baby!” was a large panel moderated by <a href="http://kateleth.com/">Kate Leth</a>, all about how <em>Sailor Moon</em> was a queer-coded show that expressed intimate, platonic queer female friendships. As one of the panelists said, you could always tell when another Senshi (Sailor) showed up, because Usagi (the main character) would always say how hot they were. The panelists all spoke about how <em>Sailor Moon</em> was joyful, empowering, and fun. It was an escapist, female fantasy, and it was so needed in the lives of young queer folk. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another great panel was about how <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em> was a part of the queer experience. Specifically, “playing a tiefling warlock is a queer mood.” (<a href="https://twitter.com/definitelyvita">Vita Ayala</a>.) This panel was so well-attended that they were turning people away at the door. People talked about how they explored their sexuality and gender through their characters, how they developed bonds with their own imagination, how they learned to love and represent themselves. Once you get into a<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/sharon-mccutcheon-677023-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11413 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/sharon-mccutcheon-677023-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a> groove with your friends, anything goes, and the power to explore parts of yourself and your characters can lead to incredible revelations and understandings of your own self. Sar, better known by their art name &#8220;<a href="http://littlecorvusart.com/">Little Corvus</a>,&#8221; told the panel that they had played a non-binary <em>DnD</em> character for a year before they came out as non-binary themselves. The idea of a game where anything can happen, where you can be anything and nobody can tell you no because it’s <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons</em>, is a very powerful sandbox. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ultimately, the found-folk of queer gathering was a joy-filled and uplifting experience. Panels full of queer people, a room full of art that reflects you and your experience, storytelling that expresses your own life. It was a remarkable celebration of the society and culture that queer folk have created for themselves, filling the huge absence left by straight narratives in media. We want to see ourselves on screen, we want to be present in the conversations about love, happiness, joy, and representation. The familiarity of experience that was reflected in the creative and heartfelt output of the many manys was so powerful and overwhelmingly beautiful. The radical inclusivity of Flame Con was inspiring and hugely joyful. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was feeling emotional and grateful at the end of the first day of Flame Con. At breakfast, as I used the swipe keyboard on my non-fruit phone, to tell Kelsey how much her panel meant to me, the word ‘hope’ had come up instead of ‘joy.’ I corrected it, but that word stuck with me throughout the remainder of the con. Ultimately, what Flame Con expressed was a hope for better, and the dedication of creators, fans, and organizers who believe that queer joy is possible, that it will happen, and that we are visible and important. Queer creators are the future. Queer creators are here. Queer creators will not be silenced. We will tell our own stories, and we will uplift those around us. We are powerful, fantastic, fabulous, and we will not make ourselves smaller any longer. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fanfilms, Authority, and Accessibility</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fanfilms-authority-and-accessibility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fandom Files]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11091</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[People are often aware of fandom and fanwork through the lens of fanfiction. Sometimes fanart&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11092 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/58705_hours-the-best-fan-films-ever-made-star-wars-dvd_18-212x300.jpg" alt="" width="212" height="300" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People are often aware of fandom and fanwork through the lens of fanfiction. Sometimes fanart makes its way into the public consciousness, but more often than not, these two expressions of fanwork are the most commonly recognized. Some other methods of fandom expression, such as podfic, fanvids, and cosplay, are also well known, but an area of fanwork that’s overlooked and not understood very well is fanfilms. </span></p>
<p>Fanfilms are films, usually shorts running from 5 to 25 minutes, but are sometimes feature-length. Fanfilms usually have a narrative story and a script of some kind, which can separate them thematically from fanvids. Fanfilms are shot, produced, acted, edited, and distributed much like any piece of original film. They are written and crafted, and some are played in small theaters, and very often at fan conventions. There are also fanfilm awards and archives, and often big-name franchises like Star Wars will endorse fan-made creations, hosting the <a href="https://www.starwars.com/star-wars-fan-awards">Star Wars Fan Awards</a> which honors fanwork that uses Lucasfilm assets. It’s interesting to note that while they accept films, fanart, and photos, no writing of fanfic is allowed. Some other fanfilm networks, such as the <a href="https://fanfilmawards.com/about/">Fanfilm Awards</a>, do allow submissions of screenplays.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The acceptance of fanfilms as legitimate fan labor is very different from the way that fic as perceived. There are a few reasons why this could be. One is sexism; the fact that fan films usually revolve around the stories created by men, are rewritten to be about male character, and are usually written, produced, and distributed by men, whereas fic and many other derivative fanwork is </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-fanfiction-is-female/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">overwhelmingly female</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Another possible reason is that, unlike fic, there are actual costs associated with fanfilms; whether that’s paying the actors and crew, paying to produce the film professionally and allow for distribution to small theaters, or submission entry fees into fanfilm contests. Films are more likely to be noticed by producers and Intellectual Property holders, as they require large crews and collaboration, and can be easier to monetize by the original IP owners. This can lead to endorsements of fanfilm and even promotion of fanfilm from the original media’s creators and owners, creating greater visibility through accessibility of films and the viral nature of videos.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fanfilms have been around for almost a century, almost as long as film itself. The first known fanfilm is from 1928, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anderson Our Gang</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and the 1922 film </span><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0013472/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our Gang</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Many amateur filmmakers have created fanfilms for fun, whether with friends or a larger more experienced crew. Like many things, <em>Star Trek</em> and the rising popularity of cons in the &#8217;70s allowed more fanfilms to be shown, and also allowed more people into the hobby. Until the early 2000s, technology and production costs severely limited the kinds of fans who could produce fanfilms. Recently fanfilms have been made by people of all levels of experience and professionalism, from critically acclaimed </span><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1301303/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">live-action Aragorn prequels</span></a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PN_CP4SuoTU"><span style="font-weight: 400;">to animated shorts.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The advent of accessible technology has led to an increase in the production, popularity, and distributions of fanfilms as fan work.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Much like fic, fanfilms seek to explore nuances in characters and storylines that are either not identified, addressed, or glossed over in the original work. A lot of fanfilms don’t have the budget or production to create intricate battles, CGI, or special effects; so often this means that fanfilms must rely on sharp storytelling, minimal effects, and off-screen implications. While fic often seeks to represent underrepresented people, fanfilm usually seeks to tell another story within the world of the original franchise. Very rarely does fanfilm venture into alternate universes, domesticity fic, or extremely ship-centric work. Fanfilms rely on accuracy to convey a message. Productions will recreate props, costumes, and settings with as much detail as possible in order to maintain the illusion of being a part of the original film franchise. Actors are chosen to represent characters based on the original look of those characters. A fanfilm in the 1980s originally had George Takei signed on to reprise his role as Sulu, adding to the reality of the work. This attention to veracity and the ability to mimic the original is often seen as a measure of how good a film is. There is a core idea that the purpose of a fanfilm is to make it extremely believable and immersive in a way that creates total continuity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prequels and sequels are very popular fanfilm subjects. The previously mentioned Aragon prequel, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Born of Hope</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as well as </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eQRgVZ4jZyM"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Daywalker: Blade Origins</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RXVJfBnG0bw"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Von Doom</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, are well known origin story fanfilms.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fanfilms exist in a strange in-between space of gray legality. While not technically protected, neither the appearance nor existence of fanfilms necessarily threaten the monetary gain or impact of the original work. Fanfilms are by necessity predicated by the popularity and reach of the original piece of media. Often fanfilms will be ignored by Intellectual Property owners, and it’s only in the very rare instance where a film could be seen as damaging or derogatory when IP owners make threats or deliver cease-and-desist letters in order to remove or suppress a fanfilm. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Much like fic, money seems to be the driving force for leniency. According to Paul Levitz, DC’s president, “we [DC] are not against things where people use our assets if they don’t do anything monetarily with them.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/maxresdefault.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11094 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/maxresdefault-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>Ultimately, fanfilms are growing in popularity because people consider this type of fan work appropriate for portfolios and resumes, as well as a labor of love. Again, because of the difference in legitimacy-via-IP owners and the way  fanfilms are viewed, they are considered more &#8220;justifiable&#8221; pieces of fanwork. Although it feels like the accessibility and understanding of fanfilms is becoming more mainstream, the presence of IP owner authority and awards with regards to fanfilms makes this kind of fanwork not as subversive as fic, nor as representative. I believe that fanfilms will continue to expand in popularity, and allow for greater representation of marginalized communities, but I doubt that we will ever see the intense rewriting and reinterpretation of original media in fanfilm that we see elsewhere in fandom. If this sort of radical derivation happens, I believe that we will either see IP owners back away from film support, or we will see an increased acceptance and accessibility to this mode of fanwork. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to watch some amazing fanfilms, you can start by browsing the (somewhat out-of-date) </span><a href="https://www.fanfilms.net/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">fanfilm archive</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. YouTube is a haven for fanfilmakers, and a quick search of fan film [insert fandom here] will reveal a treasure trove of good work. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Queer Fandom</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-queer-fandom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fandom Files]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10844</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the direct aftermath of Pride Month, seeing proud queer people and seeing people fight&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/233499524_7704a552f1_o.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10847 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/233499524_7704a552f1_o-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>In the direct aftermath of Pride Month, seeing proud queer people and seeing people fight and protest and stand up to tyranny, I’m reminded again of the importance of Queer Fandom. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the queer content that proliferates in many parts of creator-forward fandom spaces, a majority of places where fandom congregates and occurs is still obviously and overwhelmingly catered to straight white men. Unfortunately a lot of preconceptions about who the fans are and who should </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">own </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">certain properties still affect the way that people react in these spaces. Comic cons have had to adopt <a href="https://www.bustle.com/articles/33470-geeks-for-consent-petition-comic-con-to-just-adopt-anti-sex-harassment-policies-already">specific anti-harassment policies</a> for female cosplayers. The culture of Hollywood has fostered rampant sexual assault and the #MeToo movement has allowed for limited consequences to a select few.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here’s the thing: people in power will generally refuse to give up power. They want to maintain authority, or ownership, or be the sole keeper of fan media. Video games, comics, superhero movies, and science fiction genres have always had women at the helm of the fandom, and often at the helm of the creation of the media. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The problem is that when people see something that they relate to, it’s easier to claim that only people similar to them can relate to that piece of media than to consider the ways in which others can relate to the same piece of media. It’s easier to say ‘this is mine’ as opposed to ‘this is ours.’ </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There have been studies which show the difference between white male fandom gatekeepers and those who do not believe that fandom is created for them. This is the idea of a collector verses a creator. A collector gathers facts, collectibles, editions, covers, and trivia. A creator tends to focus on a method, such as art, writing, fanvids, or any other productive fan activity which results in something new and derivative. Both are valid ways of interacting with fandom and becoming a fan, and I use the term productive as a way of conveying the product, and not the intense diligence needed for either method. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So what happens when white men control the narrative? In the late &#8217;80s and &#8217;90s, fan culture became isolated and strangely insular, catering mostly to the white men who were the most vocal and obvious consumer. In an effort to appeal to this audience, especially in comics and movies, hyper-macho characters were introduced alongside hyper-sexualized women; the only gaze becoming a male gaze. Comics, already a niche market, became even less approachable.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are some exceptions to this, as there always are, but this was also the time during which comics produced their lowest sales, comic shops began shuttering their doors, and Diamond Distributors became really the only place where you could purchase comics for your shop. Comic shops became gatekeepers to nerd culture, and these places were primarily run by men, and thus turned into a boy’s club. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So how did people who weren’t necessarily invited to the party attend? There was still a lot of good stuff happening in comics and nerd culture. . . who can ignore <a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/Dana_Scully">Dana Scully</a>? Xena? Buffy? The advent of internet fandom allowed for the dissemination of cultures beyond the single point-of-view embodied in comic shops. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_10848" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10848" style="width: 232px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/Legends_(Star_Trek:_TOS_slash_anthology_zine)"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image wp-image-10848 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Legends_5_Cover-232x300.jpg" alt="" width="232" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10848" class="wp-caption-text">Legends, a slash anthology Zine Cover, from the 5th edition, 2009.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is ours,” became the rallying cry of online fandom, and women and queer people quickly flocked to a space where they could rewrite their favorite characters to be more explicitly representative of who they were. The importance of queer fandom and queer representation went hand in hand with better female representation and better representation of people of color. Older, female-led fandoms such as <em>Star Trek, Sentinel, Blake’s 7</em>, and <em>Starksy and Hutch</em> paved the way for derivative works that featured queer couples at the center of many stories.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Queer fandom has always been ignored, pushed off as a splinter cell of larger groups of fans. However, it’s undeniable that queer fandom has succeeded because it offers a viewpoint intensely and immediately different from what is being sold in comic stores or shown on screens. Queer fandom is making up the difference in representation through fanwork, leveling the playing field the only way that we can: through explicitly and obvious occupation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is the presumption that many queer fanworks are inherently erotic. There are many reasons for this, but one of the biggest reasons is, in my opinion, the desire for confirmation. To see representation only in subtext is awful. To see representation explicitly shown, yes, sometimes to the point of erotica, is a powerful thing. It takes back the narrative, and it shows that yes, this is ours too. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The need for queer fandom and queer-only spaces is not to silo queer representation but to allow more variety, and eventually allow for more representation across all media. Support for queer stories is still relegated to niche markets, while the white male’s POV is still considered universal. In order to uplift the community and explore the parts of queer culture that make us unique, beautiful, and worthy of mainstream stories, we need to have a safe place to do so. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is no wrong way to be a part of a fandom. There is no one way. But to accept the status quo, and allow a single point of view to dominate our conversations and our media is intolerable. Queer spaces need to arise, and queer creators need to be supported alongside queer fandom. The change is happening, and I can’t wait. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Power of Collaborative Fandom: Challenges, Bangs, and Charities</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-power-of-collaborative-fandom-challenges-bangs-and-charities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 10:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fandom Files]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fandom is not an isolation chamber. It is created and built in places like convention&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fandom is not an isolation chamber. It is created and built in places like convention halls, online communities, mailing lists, social media groups, theaters, and bookshops. Fandom is created when people dress up for the Harry Potter book release, when fanartists create genderbent or racebent versions of their favorite characters, when fic writers post a new chapter. Fandom thrives in a communal, collaborative, constructive environment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/marten-bjork-623852-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10332 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/marten-bjork-623852-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>When zines were passed out at conventions, there were collating parties and meetups with the actors at cafes. The scene was just small enough that you felt like everybody could tug on a few strings and know anyone else. Now certain convents are so large and sprawling that it wouldn’t be hard to get lost in between a signing booth and a merch table. Community creation is harder to do in-person, and has migrated heavily to digital platforms, most commonly in spaces that encourage following and re-sharing content, such as Tumblr and Twitter. Old forum-based community sites like Dreamwidth and Livejournal are still around, but legal action taken against the client base has greatly reduced their usage. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So how do online communities create collaboratively? There are a lot of ways that fans can meet and speak to each other online, but one of the ways that prioritizes fanwork creation and fandom development is called a fandom challenge. Challenges can vary widely, but usually there are two or more fancreators involved who ‘challenge’ each other to create a new piece of fanwork. This fanwork can be centered around a theme, pairing, media, or even just a single character. Fanwork can consist of fanfic, fanart, podfic, playlists, or graphics. Each challenge has a different set of rules, requirements, and structure. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Challenges and fanwork exchange is certainly not new to the online fandoms; there is a record of the<em> Star Trek</em> fandom engaging in Fic-a-Thons, where writers were challenged to write a fanfic in a certain amount of time. Sometimes these were called Thing-a-Thons, wherein art and other work would be allowed in. Many times Trek fic writers would submit pieces to zines based on previously published pieces of art, and some times art and fic would be submitted together, both produced by different artists. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Online communities took this kind of collaborative creation and made it more accessible and easy to enter. There are many different kinds of challenges, focused on many different kinds of media. An extremely common challenge is called a Bang. Usually the way a Bang challenge works is a group of mods create a community (on Tumblr, Dreamwidth, or Livejournal) dedicated to the bang. They ask fan writers to write a new fic based around a certain theme, and then they allow artists to claim fics. The writers and artists collaborate to create a finished piece of fanfic and at least one (sometimes multiple pieces) of accompanying fanart. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bangs have many iterations; Big Bangs usually have require high word counts; Reverse Bangs ask the artist to submit pieces first; Podfic Bangs encourage writers and podficcers to work together; Flash Bangs encourage microfiction and collaboration without claims. Community is built through these sorts of exchange and collaborations. There is usually space to discuss your work, your experiments and trials, and you get to see what the rest of the fans are creating while you are also working. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is an incredibly important part of fandom-building. When people are in small fandoms that don’t get attention from other fans, they feel isolated and can be easily discouraged. When there is no feedback and no audience, fandom cannot be maintained. The opportunity to engage with other fans, even after a show has been finished, or a book series concluded, is essential for the growth and longevity of fandom. Sometimes it takes a new version of a musical, or a single interview to reactivate a fandom, but unless there is active creation of some kind &#8212; whether through discussion, fanwork, or just conversations at conventions, fandoms lose fans and are not longer enjoyable to even longtime fans. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/bonnie-kittle-186235-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10333 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/bonnie-kittle-186235-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re interested in looking at the nitty-gritty of bang challenges, here are some excellent challenges that have produced some amazing fanwork and community; </span><a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/Yuletide"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yuletide</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (for lesser known fandoms and pairing, given every year around Christmas, has been occurring annually since 2003); the I</span><a href="https://i-reversebang.livejournal.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">nception Reverse Bang</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (a great example of an active community that has lasted far beyond the initial media release); the Merlin fandom has a huge numbers of bangs and challenges; you can view </span><a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/Category:Merlin_Fests_and_Challenges"><span style="font-weight: 400;">an incomplete list </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">on Fanlore. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The last thing I want to shed some light on is the way that fan communities can often coalesce around a cause or an event. Charity challenges are a huge part of fandom, and some of the best well known fandom examples are </span><a href="https://fandomtrumpshate.tumblr.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fandom Trumps Hate</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (where fans offered to create fanwork for other fans based on donations to specific charities, which has raised over 50K in two years) and </span><a href="https://www.randomacts.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Random Acts</span></a>,<span style="font-weight: 400;"> a charity championed by </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Supernatural’</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">s Misha Collins, has also benefited from fandom action. </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GISHWHES"><span style="font-weight: 400;">GISHWISHES</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a for-profit company started by Collins, has donated almost all proceeds to Random Acts for six years, and has been able to give over 50K to Random Acts. It has been described as a collaborative, non-centrist, democratic, all-media event.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Collaborative community creation is the lifeblood of fandom. Interactions and multiple editions of fanmade creative work are integral to the health of a fandom. Feedback will certainly keep creators invested, but in order to draw new people into a fandom there needs to be time allowed for them to integrate into a fanbase and there needs to be space made for new work to be published, promoted, and distributed to other like-minded and interested fans. Often writing, drawing, and other methods of fanwork creation can be an extremely isolating experience: you are alone at your computer. Bangs and challenges help tie together all the individual threads of fanwork, and keep fandoms strong, thriving, and creative. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bringing Back Issues (Zine Culture)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/bringing-back-issues-zine-culture/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 10:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fandom Files]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fan-made zines have been made and distributed since some of the first inceptions of fandom&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fan-made zines have been made and distributed since some of the first inceptions of fandom culture. In a way, zine culture is fandom</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10147 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/apple-coffee-couch-6666-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> culture, and it’s almost impossible to separate zines like <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-fandom-history-primer-part-ii/"><em>Spockanalia</em> </a>from Star Trek itself. Zines were the place where fans could show off and explore the parts of media they loved and wanted to see more of. While modern zines have roots in the commonplace books young girls kept in the late 1700s and early 1800s, fanzines and pamphlets existed in the Sherlock fandom in the late 1800s and early 1900s. Zines in their modern form truly emerged around the science fiction fandom. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the Star Trek zines weren’t the first to be published and distributed at cons, they are certainly some of the most well known. Other fandom</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">s that had a large zine subculture in the mid century include Sherlock, Dr. Who, and the Professionals. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the way that zines worked. Dedicated fans would get together and write fanfic, commission artists, and network with other writers via traditionally published science fiction magazines. Zines would be compiled, copied, and collated. Zines would be sold at cons, or traded with other zine publishers. Often zines would be ordered, and publishers and authors would keep dedicated mailing lists so that they could take preorders, network with new authors, and create a postal community of fans and zinesters. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the 1970s and 80s, zines were usually black and white, with some illustrations and lots of stories. In the 90s, with more graphic design tools available and digital art libraries expanding, zines tended to look more and more professional, imitating traditional publishing. There were even publishing houses that would produce and distribute fan novels, sometimes for profit, sometimes with all proceeds going to charity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zines were still underground until the 90s, passed around at cons and traded for other pieces. Since zines were the place where early fanfic writers distributed the majority of their slashfic, they tended to be secretive, subvert things. Some people used their real names, some used fake names or chosen sobriquets such as ‘Artemis’ or ‘Red Noun,’ rather than any kind of traditional pseudonym. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the internet became more prolific, many authors and slashfic publishers turned to blog sites to host their work independently. The audience for fic expanded as dissemination became free for consumers. Zines were still being produced, but it was not considered cost effective, and it was no longer the only means of sharing fic and developing<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/adult-banking-bar-5908.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10146 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/adult-banking-bar-5908-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a> fandom communities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zines have begun to rise in popularity within the last ten years. Using social media, people are getting in touch, organizing, and creating more zines than ever! Platforms like Tumblr and Twitter are allowing artists, organizers, and writers to get in touch and organize.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Older zines are not forgotten, and in fact, there are multiple places that catalog and record zines published in the 70s-90s. </span><a href="https://zinedom.tumblr.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zinedom </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">is working to catalog and archive stories published during this time, and has a </span><a href="https://zinedom.tumblr.com/post/172562230889/meeedeee-what-to-do-with-your-fanzines-before"><span style="font-weight: 400;">lot of recommendations </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">for where you can send your old zines so that universities and other organizations can archive and catalog fanwork. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re interested in modern zines, check out </span><a href="http://zinesubmissions.tumblr.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ZineSubmissions</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="http://zine-scene.tumblr.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zine-Scene</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><a href="http://zinehunter.tumblr.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ZineHunter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><a href="https://fandomzines.tumblr.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">FandomZines</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, all of which periodically post calls for submissions and updates on zines that are being organized. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So join in the fun! Draw, write, and purchase more zines! And don’t forget to share. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning a Fandom Around: Self-Critique, Siloism, and the Failure of Satire</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/turning-a-fandom-around-self-critique-siloism-and-the-failure-of-satire/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fandom Files]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fanfic is, at heart, a derivative retelling or restoration of a story that has already&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/aaron-burden-521422-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9822 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/aaron-burden-521422-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>Fanfic is, at heart, a derivative retelling or restoration of a story that has already been published and distributed. It can be a personal experience, and fic can be private and unshared, relegated to static pieces on a desktop, or it can be posted in a space where the fandom at large can read and view it. The communal nature of fandom, and specifically fanfic, which can create additional material for consumption beyond fanart or fanvids, creates massive communities of creators, writers, and consumers within fandom. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When a consumer/creator fandom is especially active, such as <em>Star Wars, Harry Potter</em>, or <em>Star Trek</em>, there will naturally be cultural aspects of fandom that affect fic. People who are in fandom will have positions on shipping, critique, and how to best portray certain characters. Tropes and common themes will develop in certain fandoms. For example, common tropes in the <em>Harry Potter</em> fandom include “Aurorfic”&#8211;where fic explores the lives of one or all of the main trio after their adventures in Hogwarts while working as Aurors&#8211;and “Re-Sorting AU”&#8211;where a fic will write a what-if scenario exploring what would have happened if Harry had actually been Slytherin, or Draco a Gryffindor.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fandom culture is fascinating and ever-changing. There is a subsect of the Sherlock fandom that firmly believes that they are involved in a game with the show runners of Sherlock, in which the show runners originally</span><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20141025064332/http://nowreallifehasnoappeal.wordpress.com/2014/08/17/johnlock-101-an-introduction-to-the-johnlock-conspiracy-tjlc"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> meant to make the gay pairing of Sherlock Holmes and John Watson canon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but were silenced by the influence of BBC. These fans call this the Johnlock Conspiracy, and it centers around the idea that there is a final episode that was never aired that canonizes the pairing. Fans believe that show runners hid clues to the ship in each episode, and that if they uncover enough of the clues, they will be shown a way to access this episode, colloquially called </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Lost Special</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is natural then, that a culture catalyzed around such a massive media success will include fans that have different views on aspects of the source material. Using <em>Harry Potter</em> as a reference again, there are a group of people who ship Harry/Hermione, and a group who ship Ron/Hermione, and while often these groups are disparate and do not usually interact with each other, there can be fandom feuds that occur over the ‘rightness’ of a certain ship over another. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If this sounds petty to you, you are not alone. Many members of fandom think that these sorts of ‘ship wars’ and controversies are not productive and often damaging to fandom culture. However, we cannot discount these fandom arguments, as they are so intrinsically tied to the ways in which people relate to and connect with the things that they love and pour so much of their heart into. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fandom critique of fandom has always been around. There are records of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Achilles_and_Patroclus#Classical_views_in_antiquity">philosophers in ancient Greece arguing</a> over whether or not Achilles was a top or bottom when having sex with Patrocles. Fandom culture often takes on a life of its own, separate from the original work that inspired it. I know quite a few people who saw fanart, started reading and writing fic, and <em>then</em> watched the source material movies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is also a genre of fanfic that is written in direct response to other fanfic, or in response to fandom itself. It will use fandom tropes, controversies, and popular fic to create another piece of work that directly addresses another part of fandom, where the understanding of the fic does not come from knowledge of the original material, but from fandom and community knowledge. One of the best and most well-known examples of this is </span><a href="http://www.ealasaid.com/misc/vsd/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Very Secret Diaries</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a <em>Lord of the Rings</em> diaryfic inspired by a brief mention in another piece of fic, wherein Legolas steals Aragorn’s diary. This led to the natural question . . .what on earth did Aragorn write in this diary?* <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/oliver-thomas-klein-207908-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9823 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/oliver-thomas-klein-207908-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is a lot of satire inherent in fanfic. The very existence of fic is reclaimatory and subversive, and it lends itself very well to poking fun at the source material. However, when fic turns in on itself, and begins to address issues within a fandom, the satire-of-satire nature of this sort of fic can be extremely damaging. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many issues in fandom are so divisive that often bringing up the topic results in little dialogue, and is reduced to camps divided, shouting at each other via text messages. This is not really a solely fandom problem, as any Twitter user can tell you what happens when an <em>Onion</em> article is taken seriously, or a <em>Borowitz Report</em> strikes a little too close to home.</span></p>
<p>A piece of fic that has come up time and time again as a subject for debate is the iconic <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Immortal_(fan_fiction)">My Immortal</a></em>, which people have argued about for years. It is either the worst fanfic ever written, or the one that satirized fanfic the best. I remember reading it as it was being posted, and I personally believe it to be a very intentional satire of Harry Potter fanfic, and the way that female characters were written at that point in time. No matter what your take on <em>My Immortal</em>, it stands as an undeniable mirror for the other fanfic in the Harry Potter fandom.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One clear example of satirical fanfic is the three-part series</span> <a href="https://archiveofourown.org/series/814845"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Most Unproblematic Series Ever</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which is less than 300 words and tangentially addresses and pokes fun at a lot of the negativity and upset in fandom over <em>Star Wars</em> ship wars, and how characters of color are represented in fandom. Nobody would leave </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Force Awakens </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">and think to write this. It’s in clear and direct conversation with fandom as a whole, which is made obvious by the comments on the fic. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tying all this together, there is an interesting dichotomy in between fandom and fanwork, simply because people will all take in the source material differently, and when shown discrepancies in opinion, it can be personally affecting. So many people care so much about their fandoms that it’s hard to stay objective and learn from other parts of fandom. Satire is often lost in fandom, and is thus extremely rare. There is merit to the theory that all satire produced in fandom circles is in bad faith, as it is usually poking at another sect of fandom that is perhaps even more excluded than the satirist. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Satire usually understands and provokes the overarching powers of oppression and subjugation by making them into the surreal and unbelievable, but when fans turn on their own fandom&#8211;whether through a casual lens like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unproblematic Series</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or a much more damaging and obliquely racist take, such as </span><a href="https://archiveofourown.org/works/13481277/chapters/30911193"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fences</span></i></a>&#8212;<span style="font-weight: 400;">it doesn’t serve to shine light on how fandom can improve, but rather highlights the negative aspects of an online community of people who, at their core, just want to enjoy things. This is not to say that satire is an inappropriate response, but rather that fandom satire is almost never aimed at critiquing a fan&#8217;s own experience, but rather the experiences of others. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So how does fandom self-critique? The short story is that fandom usually doesn’t, it just subdivides further into niche categories where people congregate and collect their own fic catered for their own interests, without any real inclination to move fandom forward in a ‘positive’ direction. Fandom is not really a place for collective discourse, but rather it serves as a place for people to explore their own desires. Because of this inherent siloism, the essentially critical nature of fandom, and each fan’s ability to modify their own fandom experience to reflect a certain viewpoint or story line, there is no real way within the current fandom model to produce satire in a way that can combine humor and critique constructively and respectfully. Each attempt to revise fandom will be seen as an attack, and every fan will bring their own experience to the table, which leads to a feeling of personal offense when any other fan attempts to point out problematic behavior. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/alexis-brown-82988-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9824 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/alexis-brown-82988-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>So what now? In order for fandom to evolve it needs to engage in a dialogue that directly addresses the nature of privilege and power both within and outside of fandom. While this might not ever happen on a large scale, I believe that fandom meta, discourse, and the rise of chat groups on platforms like Slack and Discord will lead to a more comprehensive understanding of the emotional, invested fandom. Fandom is, at heart, for and by the fans, driven by a need for more, to address a lack in material. I hope that in the future, fandom as a whole strives to make fandom a more inclusive, understanding, and accepting place for all fans.</span></p>
<hr />
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">*A note on this fic. It was written by known/suspected plagiarist Cassandra Clare, of <em>Shadowhunter</em> fame. However, this piece of fanfic is hilarious and I highly recommend any <em>Lord of the Rings</em> fan read it. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Fandom History Primer (Part II)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-fandom-history-primer-part-ii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 11:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fandom Files]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[(This is the second of a two-part series on fandom. Read the first part here.)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>(This is the second of a two-part series on fandom. Read the first part <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-fandom-history-primer-part-i/">here</a>.)</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Star Trek</em> launched fandom into the public spotlight once again. Fan conventions, slash zines, articles, meta, analysis, and praise &#8212; all of this came into the collective lexicon of the fan in the late &#8217;60s. The very first all-<em>Star Trek</em> fanzine was launched and written in 1968, named the </span><a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/Spockanalia"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spokanalia</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Conventions <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/igor-ovsyannykov-277756.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9577 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/igor-ovsyannykov-277756-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>were held, the actors revered, and <em>Star Trek</em> launched an incredible amount of interest in science fiction and space fiction that has never stopped. I want to add in, just as an aside, that while Sherlock fandom seemed to be indiscriminate of gender, the actual fandom activities that fans participated in while involved in the <em>Star Trek</em> fandom seemed to come from a majority of women authors, illustrators, and convention planners. The derivative nature of these pieces of work had an extremely gendered slant.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a few more places on the fandom timeline we must mention. For a long time, many creators knew, and even encouraged fanwork of their media. Gene Roddenberry, creator and head <em>Star Trek</em> writer, said that “</span><a href="https://fanlore.org/w/images/a/a0/Spockanalia_3_roddenberry_letter.jpeg"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spockanalia</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was “required reading” in our offices</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.” Then the internet came around, and the distribution of media was suddenly not limited by how many zines one could afford to produce, or how many fans sent in their own stories, or if you could get a zine from a friend of a friend at a convention, but instead, fandom exploded onto forums and fansites in the early &#8217;90s.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-9473"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With this increased exposure came increased scrutiny from authors. Many vibrant fandoms went underground because authors started reacting against it. Most notably, in 2000, Anne Rice employed lawyers to start going after <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/drawing-1603625_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9578 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/drawing-1603625_1920-238x300.jpg" alt="" width="238" height="300" /></a>fanfiction writers, claiming that they were infringing on her copyright. </span><a href="http://www.angelfire.com/rant/croatoan/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vampire Chronicles</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> fandom hid their sites</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and fanfic was called ‘spec’, and the term helped nominally protect these authors from Rice’s lawyers. In 2005, </span><a href="http://www.robinhobb.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Robin Hobb</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a noted fantasy author, posted a scathing anti-fanfic, pornophobic </span><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20050630015105/http://www.robinhobb.com/rant.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">rant on her website</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Very recently, in late 2013, </span><a href="http://sharonleewriter.com/2013/10/the-second-answer/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sharon Lee stated </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">that she absolutely does not want anyone reinterpreting or touching her characters. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few notable places where fandom thrived: besides the individual fansites, newsgroups, and specific genre and media forums, were larger group-based websites. </span><a href="https://www.livejournal.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">LiveJournal </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">was one place that collected fandoms, and it was incredibly popular in the early 2000s. Fanfiction archives, most notably <a href="https://www.fanfiction.net/">fanfiction.net</a> (est. 1998), started enacting stricter rules about what was or wasn’t allowed on the site, and in 2002 banned NC-17 work, causing more people to head to LiveJournal to post their fic. Despite this, participation slowly declined, starting around 2007 as the site was sold to various companies (the latest a Russian-owned organization) which led to new restrictions, rules, and was a much less secure website. All this drastically decreased the membership and activity on the site and left people searching for a new home for fandom. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">LiveJournal was also not intuitive or user friendly. You had to know what to look for before you were really able to participate. While LJ succeeded in creating a decentralized fandom, it also made it hard to enter fandom at all. There was a focus on shorter work, there was little restriction on whether or not work needed to be ‘complete’ in order to be posted, and people often competed for attention. These are some of the reasons why people began to migrate to Tumblr and Twitter for fandom activities in the late 2000s.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If LiveJournal started the trend of decentralization of fandom authority, Tumblr solidified it. There were no exclusive spaces in Tumblr, and trends, memes, rec lists, and meta were shared across all fandoms, depending on who you followed. Focus shifted from writing to fanart, graphics, edits, and gifs, and creators were again not limited by the restrictions on explicit material or publication issues. </span><a href="https://archiveofourown.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Archive of Our Own</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (also called AO3), established in 2008, has always had a no-holds-barred policy on what kind of transformative fic people are allowed to post. This means that AO3 allows explicit material, exempt from censorship or any kind. The Archive has also made adjustments to allow podfic and fanart to be posted. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/ricardo-gomez-angel-252099.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9579 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/ricardo-gomez-angel-252099-300x252.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="252" /></a>AO3 is also taking steps to actively preserve fan culture from all corners of the internet and beyond. They are working to record some of the first SkySolo Star Wars fic, old fanzines, interviews with creators, and more. While they are the go-to resource, they are also crowdsourced and essentially non-authoritarian, giving all the power back to the fans and the authors.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which is where we are now.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Modern fandom has roots past Sherlock, (</span><a href="https://www.academia.edu/182834/Byron_Commonplacing_and_Early_Fan_Culture"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a fascinating academic article </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">makes the argument that the commonplace books of teenage girls created the first fandom around Lord Byron’s poetry) but it is essentially because of two reasons I assert again that Sir Arthur Conan Doyle’s creation is the true granddaddy of fandom. The first reason is that there was a widespread, non-academic group of people sharing derivative works and participating in active fandom. The second reason is that there was a serialized and specific method by which the pop culture was delivered and disseminated. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So go forth, young fanfic writers, and remember that yours is a long and storied history. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Fandom History Primer (Part I)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-fandom-history-primer-part-i/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 11:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fandom Files]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’ve heard the word ‘fandom’ used often in modern media and until recently, many people&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/graffiti-1015952_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9572 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/graffiti-1015952_1920-300x191.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="191" /></a>We’ve heard the word ‘fandom’ used often in modern media and until recently, many people were unaware of the term. If they were aware of its use, many would associate it with the science fiction fandom or, more specifically, the <em>Star Trek</em> fandom. So what is fandom?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fandom is defined in various places as a loose association of people who share a common interest in a piece of popular culture. These fans participate in fandom activities, whether it’s a group getting together to watch new episodes, the individual or group creation of fanwork, or the academic analysis of the piece of media. Fanwork can be a lot of things in this context and examples include fanart, fanfic, playlists, meta, and graphic manipulation. Fandom is not restricted to serialized television shows, although it is because of the popularity of <em>Star Trek</em> that fandom has become intrinsically linked to sequential media.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-9471"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite the modern connotations, the word fandom </span><a href="http://www.jessesword.com/sf/view/431"><span style="font-weight: 400;">has been in use since the 1890s</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and was probably established in modern English at least a decade earlier. It was originally used as a sports term, but quickly grew to encompass additional groups of fans, specifically those writers and readers of science fiction and speculative fiction. It was an umbrella genre term, rather than a word that fans of specific works applied to themselves as a definition of their enthusiasm.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So where did the modern fandom&#8211;fans of a specific media canon&#8211;begin? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The answer, my dears, is not extraordinary, but elementary. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>It started with Sherlock Holmes</em>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The stories of the now-infamous detective were not originally published as novels, but rather distributed in monthly fiction magazines. These short stories were serialized and people waited in anticipation for the next installment, much the same way that people count down the months until the next </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Game of Thrones</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> season. Many fans, who called themselves Sherlockians, came together in groups to analyze the text, trying to find clues and figure out “the great game” that the author had presented to them. People were so invested in Sherlock Holmes that after Doyle killed off his detective, hordes of people protested by marching in the streets with black armbands. The fervor was intense.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A particular genre of celebratory fiction, called </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">pastiche </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">by the fandom at the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sherlock-2640292_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9573 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/sherlock-2640292_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>time, was published and distributed in zines. Pastiches were pieces of fiction, authored by people other than Doyle, that used the characters and setting of the Sherlock Holmes stories and placed them in different settings or dramas.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, we would call this fanfiction. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The earliest retrievable pastiche of Sherlock Holmes is an 1892 story by a then-anonymous author titled “</span><a href="https://www.arthur-conan-doyle.com/index.php?title=My_Evening_with_Sherlock_Holmes"><span style="font-weight: 400;">My Evening with Sherlock Holmes</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.” Later that same year, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Peter Pan </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">author, J.M. Barrie, took credit for the work, and even revealed himself to Doyle at a dinner party, asking what he thought of the skit. Doyle, by most accounts, barely cared about this, or any other pastiche published. He seemed to realize that these short tributes wouldn’t affect the sales of the collected works of Sherlock Holmes, and any attention paid to the pastiche made his own star rise and kept his bank account happy. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sherlockian pastiche jumped in popularity and in publication after the death of Sherlock Holmes in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Final Problem</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Academic papers were written, more and more people came together, convinced that not only was Sherlock Holmes alive, but that Sir Arthur Conan Doyle had hidden clues to his resurrection in the series itself, giving birth to intricate and often bizarre modes by which Sherlockians analyze their given text. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is particularly fascinating, because this is a very clear departure from the author’s intent. Often earlier academics argued about the purpose of the author in writing a piece of work, but Doyle was still alive at the time when these conversations were taking place. He explicitly stated that the Holmes stories were over, and that he never wanted to write another story with his infamous detective again. Fans, however, seemed to think that he was joking, or that there was some deeper clue hidden in his work. So they continued to search for meaning. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(Ironically, interestingly, or even fascinatingly enough, a subset of this has occurred in the current iteration of Sherlock fandom, occurring mostly on Tumblr, wherein fans search for hidden clues in the BBC <em>Sherlock</em> episodes. History truly repeats itself in marvelous ways.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So here is modern fandom: a group of fans coming together to participate in fan activities, during the serialized production of the media which is the focus of their intense praise and scrutiny. This sort of mass gathering of fans doesn’t really occur again in pop culture until the late sixties. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/mitch-rosen-203803.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9574 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/mitch-rosen-203803-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>I believe that the reason for this hiatus in the history of fandom comes from two places. The first is that authorship and the cult of the producer emerged around specific writers who published non-serialized novels (think Hemmingway, F. Scott Fitzgerald). The second reason is the world-wide conflicts of the twentieth century occupied the collective consciousness for decades, leaving little space for fan culture. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the emergence of extremely popular serialized comic books in the late &#8217;40s, popular culture again looked forward to pieces of fantastic narrative media that could be kept in hand and redistributed. Although television and radio programs were popular, I think that the advent of comics and the illustrations that remained so solidly speculative and within-world, without delving into the awkward first try of special effects, allowed for people to really follow along with stories. Not to mention the ability to share and redistribute media is always a defining point of fandom. There was a galvanizing point in the mid century that really solidified the new kind of fandom. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enter <em>Star Trek</em>. </span></p>
<p>[Part II tomorrow . . .]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Hands Say in The Last Jedi</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-hands-say-in-the-last-jedi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Codega]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 21:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Fandom Files]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the Star Wars universe, hands are pretty important. There’s rarely a movie where a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Wars </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">universe, hands are pretty important. There’s rarely a movie where a hand isn’t cut off, replaced, or repaired. Besides this fixation on the physicality of ‘having’ hands, they are often conduits of the Force. Both Jedi and Sith use hand gestures to control this mystical energy. Cameras focus on hands, gestures have power, and many characters speak with their hands &#8212; pointing and using some kind of makeshift sign language when language barriers rise. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We get it. Hands are big deal.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Last Jedi</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> doesn’t lose<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/cherry-laithang-312590.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9476 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/cherry-laithang-312590-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a> this focus. One of the first shots is a continuation of the final scene of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Force Awakens </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">when Rey holds Luke’s lightsaber out to him. This is just the start. We see how important hands are throughout the film: when Leia’s hand moves in the dead of space; when Hux points at ships and demands they be shot out of the sky; when Rey, and then Luke, slam their hands on the meditation pedestal after or just before a connection with the Force. Hands and gestures are not just precursors to action but are important acts themselves.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-9304"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides hands as a source of action in these films, hands are also a method of communication, both with the self and with the other. When hands are pressed flat, either against other hands, or against a surface, it is indicated that there is a deep, spiritual, and loving connection between individuals, as if there is no part of one that wishes to be apart from the other. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Force Awakens</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we see this occur between Poe and Leia. When Leia is in her coma, we see it when Luke tilts Leia’s head down to kiss her forehead. Poe also grabs onto Finn when he first recovers from his coma, shakes Rey’s hand immediately, and he is constantly affectionate with his droid, BB8. There’s another time when Leia and Holdo hold each other’s hands before Holdo sacrifices herself for the survival of the Resistance that truly shows the depths of their relationship and establishes some of the trust and respect they feel for each other. It happens another time when Finn and Rey are embracing &#8212; both have their hands pressed flat against each other’s backs and shoulders. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These are just some of the instances that I remember from my re-watch of the film. These are all moments when people are using their hands to connect to other people in a deep and meaningful way. These open hands have friendship, respect, and understanding tied to them. I don’t remember any time when a member of the First Order is shown to so much as shake hands with another person. There is no trust there, no truth or honesty at all within their connections. It’s all superficial, driven by greed and power. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ian-dooley-325437.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9478 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/ian-dooley-325437-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hands pressed flat against surfaces is also incredibly important. We see Finn slam his hands against the clear surface of the med tank after he wakes from his coma in a fit of startled awakening; we see Poe slam his hands against the glass when he sees Resistance ships being blown up. Even through these surfaces, these characters are desperate to connect to others. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rey is a huge part of this, and the main subject of this piece. She has very little contact with anyone in this film, unlike in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Force Awakens</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, where she actually comes into physical contact with a lot of characters, most notably Finn. She holds Finn’s hand multiple times throughout the film, and even hugs him a few times. Rey also has a lot of contact with other characters. She hugs Leia at the end of the film, and is touched by both Maz Kanata and Han Solo. In </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Last Jedi</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, she might not have as much contact with Finn, but her hands are just as expressive as the other characters’, and gives us a great insight into her character and how she relates to the others in the film. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, let’s look at when her hands are <strong>flat</strong>. She does this at a few points very clearly. When she exits her meditative state after her first lesson with Luke, her hand slams down on the meditation stone, jolting her and the viewer out of her reverie that Luke had been powerless to draw her back from. Throughout this scene, her hands were used as a conduit for the power of the Force, but it’s only when she presses her hand flat that any action is taken. This is a sign of power, strength, and self-control, as she is the one who pulls herself away from the Dark Place, and comes back to question Luke about his place within the Force. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next, her hands are flat when she pulls herself up from the Dark Place. Again, a source of action and power, pushing herself away from a dangerous situation. I consider this a less important instance of hands, but a good example of how Rey’s own power overcomes her fears. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The next part of this argument comes when her hands are not flat, but just <strong>lightly touching surfaces</strong>. When there are just brushes of this connection it doesn’t indicate a love or a deep respect, but asks a question or sets the stage for an expectation. With Rey, her outstretched hands are common and powerful. She is always questioning and striving for greater. Her hands are in this position of openness and connection in relation to other people in two instances: once in the Dark Place, and the other time when she is sitting in front of Kylo Ren during their Force-powered Skype date. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/xandtor-453169.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9479 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/xandtor-453169-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>This expression of light touching is not the connection of love, but rather the connection of mirrors and introspection. In the Dark Place her fingers press against the crystalline cave wall, and she asks for a simple thing: to see where she came from. It turns out at the end of it, there is only herself. The Dark Place is a mirror, an infinite fun room of self-reflection and the loss of expectations. She must be good enough because she’s the only one there. It’s only her, but she’s enough. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This mirror comes back again when Rey and Kylo Ren are speaking over their connection. Now, while Kylo Ren might not have made overt sexual overtures, </span><a href="http://people.com/movies/adam-driver-shirtless-scene-star-wars-last-jedi/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rian Johnson has admitted </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">to creating sexually charged situations between the two of  them in order to make Rey feel uncomfortable. Besides this as an explanation for the shirtless Kylo scene, it also explains that the only time we see Kylo Ren take off his glove is in Rey’s presence. Helmets aren’t sexy; </span><a href="http://faculty.virginia.edu/theorygroup/docs/stallybrass-and-white.the-glove.2001.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">gloves are</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While Kylo Ren might want to reach out and grab Rey’s hand, they merely brush fingertips. Again, this is not the sign of passion or love, but in the manner presented as canon in this story, it is as if they are reaching for a mirror. Over and over people attack mirrors in films and art; they also touch them gently, they caress them, they try to find the truth and the clarity hidden there. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Last Jedi </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is no exception, and Rey’s hands are searching for mirrors and truth, even in Dark Places.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mirrors have long been in folklore as methods of reaching the ‘other side’ or even the ‘dark side’ of things. Rey’s choice to touch the mirrors she finds may speak to a desire to know the other side in order to become a new kind of grey Jedi, one who sees herself in all things. Her intimate moment with Kylo Ren is not, as Rian Johnson might have led us to believe, a moment of passion or burgeoning love, but the kind of intimacy one finds when they look into a mirror, when one side of a coin recognizes the other. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If this were a moment of passion, why not grasp hands, why not make a move towards that? They don’t even try, and they can’t, because Rey is not looking for love from this man, and Kylo Ren is incapable of anything but realizing his own ambitions. They are separated when Luke, in a burst of power, breaks them apart with the Force. He does this with a gesture from his hand that he has not done (we presume) in years. (There is another mirror here: Luke’s hands when he breaks apart the domed cell versus Kylo Ren’s when he brings down the cabin at the Temple.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This all speaks to the power of hands in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Last Jedi</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Rey is searching for clarity, truth, and honesty, all features that mirrors have been used to symbolically portray. Her search takes her onto the Supremacy itself, but when Kylo Ren offer his hand a second time it is no longer a mirror of her own, but closed off, gloved, and selfish. He is no longer a mirror, but a man standing in his own image. Rey refuses to take it because she is a different kind of person, one who will reach out with bare, open hands, and love without conditions. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
