<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 033 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-033/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 12:54:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 033 Author Interview: Katharine Coldiron and &#8220;C-A-L-L-A-S&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-katharine-coldiron-and-c-a-l-l-a-s/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-katharine-coldiron-and-c-a-l-l-a-s/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 10:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 033]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 033 author Katharine Coldiron explores a dystopian future where her protagonist hunts down a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-033/">Issue 033</a> author Katharine Coldiron explores a dystopian future where her protagonist hunts down a once simple but now almost impossible pleasure: the sound of opera. Go read her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/c-a-l-l-a-s/">C-A-L-L-A-S</a>&#8221; first, then continue below to our conversation with Katharine about her story and writing in general.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Your dystopian future created by an infectious agent is very unique given the bacteria in your story don&#8217;t appear fatal, just linguistically so. How did this idea come about? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Katharine: I don&#8217;t remember where I was exactly when the seed of this story came to me, but I was somewhere full of collective human conversation, like a restaurant or a coffee shop. In half-eavesdropping on a few different conversations, I grew astonished, because I considered most of the words being spoken around me totally unnecessary. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/clem-onojeghuo-97709-unsplash.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10427 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/clem-onojeghuo-97709-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>So many dumb conversations, people saying cliched things that anyone could say, instead of saying something, anything that mattered. I started wondering what circumstances could exist that would make people think about their words, and choose them carefully. I believed the answer was scarcity &#8211; the idea that any word could be the last one you speak. From there it was just coming up with a set of circumstances in which this was possible.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I placed this set of circumstances in a dystopian future mainly because I&#8217;d been reading the <a href="http://margaretatwood.ca/maddaddam-trilogy/">MaddAddam trilogy</a> [by Margaret Atwood], and dystopia seemed so likely. I genuinely tried to imagine what an American society would look like after a few generations of ever-accelerating technology, unequal wealth distribution, and global warming (plus the voice-eating bacteria thing), and this story was the result. I don&#8217;t think our world will end, but I do think we&#8217;ll have to make agonizing adaptations. Imagining what those would look like was equal parts fun and depressing.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I added the opera element after thinking about what would be precious in a society wherein the human voice was rare. I&#8217;d been wanting to write something about opera anyway, and in a story about the human voice, it seemed a good fit. After that, I let Solomon and the story take me where they wanted to go.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: There&#8217;s an eerie resemblance to Lenore and the prostitution of her voice &#8212; is this what you intended? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Katharine: I did intend for Lenore&#8217;s use of her voice and the payment she tries to extract for it to resemble prostitution. When a commodity is scarce, people are going to offer and pay for that commodity in all kinds of unpleasant ways, especially if it&#8217;s scarcer than the demand. In my story, I wanted to demonstrate the sanctioned way the commodity of voice is valued and traded (the speechmakers) as well as the more black-market ways (Lenore).</div>
<div></div>
<div>I think it&#8217;s been this way throughout human history. Bodies in Babylon, Barbies in the Soviet Union, a song in the distant future.</div>
<div></div>
<div>For the record, I didn&#8217;t mean much by naming her Lenore. I&#8217;m no Poe fanatic. If I hear that name out in the world, my mind automatically supplies &#8220;the lost Lenore&#8221;, and the Lenore I wrote certainly is lost, but that&#8217;s about all.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have a background or interest in opera? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Katharine: Background, no, interest, yes. I love, love, love opera. It wasn&#8217;t something I was introduced to by my family &#8211; I came to it in adulthood &#8211; so it feels like a treasure of my own. I was encouraged to write this story by <a href="http://tanaudel.wordpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://tanaudel.wordpress.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1526423809783000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGEGRqwsXfFlvv5nmItL7VZZUK3Rw">a friend</a> who told me that, no matter how self-conscious I felt at the start, I needed to write stories about my own passions, the things I love in my life, not topics that I thought I should write about. She was right.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most difficult aspect of this story to write? What came easiest?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Katharine: At the time I wrote this story, more than five years ago, I had a lot of trouble simply making scenes interesting. I had major uncertainty about what to put in and what to leave out, especially when blocking scenes <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/josh-rocklage-617948-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10428 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/josh-rocklage-617948-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>physically, and how to make the prose sing. My work has moved in very different directions since then. As I look back on this story, I have great affection for it, but if I wrote it now, it would scarcely resemble what appears in <em>LSQ</em>.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The first finished draft had a whole lot more prose in the first couple of pages, and I didn&#8217;t figure out how to trim it down until it&#8217;d collected half a dozen rejections. I had a hard time putting in background and world-building without making it hopelessly dull. But eventually I decided that my lengthy exploration of Dystopian Napster could probably go in the trash, and it became a better story.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Writing about Callas herself, and describing the Willow Song, was the easiest part. The ending, too, came fairly easy. Deciding to take a chance on Capone and his very specific weirdness was tough, but I&#8217;m happy with that choice.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Katharine: Only about a zillion! I&#8217;m hardest at work on a hybrid essay collection, where each of the essays incorporates fiction, memoir, and film criticism. Two of the essays have been published (&#8220;<a href="http://therumpus.net/2017/02/the-girl-on-the-bike/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://therumpus.net/2017/02/the-girl-on-the-bike/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1526423809783000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGGxPHDUxwDDGgp6gNa_4O2q8Tz4A">The Girl on the Bike</a>,&#8221; which was nominated for a Pushcart, and &#8220;<a href="http://rivetjournal.com/underside-by-katharine-coldiron/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://rivetjournal.com/underside-by-katharine-coldiron/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1526423809783000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF33ZuJ2BV4EBKs_lU6ZlV7YFNGRw">Underside</a>&#8220;), and I&#8217;ve written two others, with several more to go. I&#8217;ve got an essay about Nigel Kneale to put on paper as well as one about Louise Brooks. I&#8217;m also trying to find time to write a novel about Ilsa from <i>Casablanca</i>, and I&#8217;m shopping a couple of finished manuscripts, but in the meantime I write a lot of book reviews. Information about a lot of this work is on my website, <a href="http://kcoldiron.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://kcoldiron.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1526423809783000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFjhV5OVSlCznggAYH1dqHksg_ZPQ">kcoldiron.com</a>, which has links to <a href="http://fictator.blogspot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://fictator.blogspot.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1526423809783000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH9PlPiW2CM_rjjuda9b9mlTrTgHw">my blog</a> and <a href="http://eepurl.com/cNaPAD" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://eepurl.com/cNaPAD&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1526423809783000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE423Nd8dmOd9qCg8SkKp3UnFx1WA">my newsletter</a>.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-katharine-coldiron-and-c-a-l-l-a-s/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 033 Author Interview: Arkady Martine and &#8220;Adjuva&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-arkady-martine-and-adjuva/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 10:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 033]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s another chance to get to know one of our Issue 033 authors a little&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here&#8217;s another chance to get to know one of our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-033/">Issue 033</a> authors a little better &#8212; check out Arkady Martine&#8217;s story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/adjuva/">Adjuva</a>&#8221; then read her thoughts on her writing process below:</p>
<p><b><em>LSQ: Given your background as a historian of the Byzantine Empire, what about this era and setting fit with the telling of this story?</em> </b></p>
<p>Arkady: I would not have been able to tell this story without being the sort of historian I am; it is a story very deeply rooted in Crusader history, medieval Western Christian theology, and a (Jewish) Byzantinist’s problem with both. Much of this story comes straight out of medieval accounts of the First Crusade; what doesn’t is my attempt to grapple with what Crusading legends do, how they effect historical memory, how they distort time.</p>
<p>A distortion that Michel and Thomas are well-aware of, by now.</p>
<p><em><b> <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/eddie-stigson-168278-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10231 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/eddie-stigson-168278-unsplash-300x201.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="201" /></a>LSQ: Thomas and Michel &#8212; are they caught in Purgatory? Are they traveling through time? Can you comment on the mystical nature of this story line and the relationship between these two characters?</b></em></p>
<p>Arkady: Thomas and Michel are certainly caught in <i>some</i> sense. And they experience time out of sequence, and over and over. I don’t want to specify whether the way that they are caught is a time loop, or a religious process, or a series of hallucinations – or both, all, none of these things. The importance is that they are caught. Or – Michel is caught, and Thomas may or may not be, but has chosen to be caught alongside Michel.</p>
<p>If I might ask a question in return: would it make a difference if Thomas was real or a figment of Michel’s imagination? Or if Thomas was or was not human?</p>
<p><em><b> LSQ: The history of the Crusades in Antioch, returning again and again in dreams, the brutal dryness of the desert &#8212; this story has a timeless feel to it. Is there a theme you&#8217;d like the reader to pull out of this? </b></em></p>
<p>Arkady: This story is less <i>timeless</i> than it is <i>timeslipped</i>; deserts are deserts, aren’t they? No matter when. Right? (Or not right: deserts are hollow spaces that can be variously filled.) I opened this story with a quote from Jabes for very specific reasons: <i>wandering creates the desert</i>. It is not the desert that is changeless. It is the wanderer seeing the desert that sees changelessness.</p>
<p>Is that a theme? If you like.</p>
<p><em><b> LSQ: Has Turkey or the Byzantine Empire made its way into other works of yours? Does this setting/era lend itself to speculative fiction in a way readers might not be aware of?</b></em></p>
<p>Arkady: So I ran an entire conference about Byzantium in SFF this past summer at Uppsala University in <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/blaque-x-338387-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10232 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/blaque-x-338387-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>Sweden, because Byzantium and byzantinism is hidden all throughout speculative fiction. Byzantium is a site of familiar otherness. The thematic elements of post-Roman imperial formations and the literatures which they produced – including but not limited to decadence, the post-Roman world, the problem of defining <i>barbarian</i> and <i>citizen</i>, and the use of &#8216;Byzantine&#8217; settings and symbology as codes for the foreign or exotic – are <i>everywhere</i>. (So are Byzantinists. I am not the only one: Harry Turtledove holds a PhD in Byzantine history as well.)</p>
<p>I myself use Byzantium less as a setting and more as an influence. My debut novel, with comes out in early 2019 from Tor Books, was heavily influenced by my academic work on the 1044 CE Byzantine annexation of the Bagratid Armenian city of Ani. I spent a lot of time thinking about who benefited from that annexation, and what it might be like to be a person who contributed to the devouring of one&#8217;s own homeland by a rapacious, compelling empire… and wrote a space opera, which is called A MEMORY CALLED EMPIRE, that not only deals with those questions but makes explicit use of Byzantine-esque literary culture as an imperial trait.</p>
<p>I’ve also written what I’d call a ‘SF saint’s life’, “<a href="https://lackingtons.com/2016/04/27/contra-gravitatem-vita-genevievis-by-arkady-martine/">Contra Gravitatem</a>”, which appeared in <i>Lackington’s </i>a bit ago – which again, was highly influenced by Byzantine literature, but is not at all a story about Byzantium.</p>
<p><em><b> LSQ: Who are some authors that are influencing your work or inspiring you at the moment?</b></em></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/heather-shevlin-180898-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10233 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/heather-shevlin-180898-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" /></a>Arkady: This is a very long list, so the short version is: Elizabeth Bear, CJ Cherryh, Raymond Chandler, William Gibson, Tana French, and Jorge Luis Borges.</p>
<p>I am very interested in procedurals right now. And in telling detail coupled with internality and lyricism.</p>
<p><em><b> LSQ: Are you working on other projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</b></em></p>
<p>Arkady: Currently I have just begun the sequel to A MEMORY CALLED EMPIRE, which is about incomprehensibility and impossible wars; I am also working on a couple of short stories, one on ghosts in the New York City subway, one about an AI and a semi-haunted desert house and a murder, and one about what would happen if you entered a prize drawing and won a free marriage to the Raven King.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 033 Author Interview: Emily Lundgren and &#8220;The Last Shaper at the Witch City&#8217;s Waypoint&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-emily-lundgren-and-the-last-shaper-at-the-witch-citys-waypoint/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 033]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We have yet another fabulous author interview up today. This time around Emily Lundgren spoke&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We have yet another fabulous author interview up today. This time around Emily Lundgren spoke to us about her <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-033/">Issue 033</a> short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-last-shaper-at-the-witch-citys-waypoint/">The Last Shaper at the Witch City&#8217;s Waypoint</a>&#8220;. Check out her story and what she has to say about it.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your story, in a way, is about languages and communication not only among those of the same kind, but also between those of different kinds. Can you comment on this? </strong></em></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/ross-sokolovski-100010-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10123 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/ross-sokolovski-100010-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Emily: I think it’s Bahktin who theorizes something along the lines of “storytelling creates community/culture,” and I had that idea in mind when I was writing this piece. I’m a firm believer that writing, especially in the genres of science fiction and fantasy, should carry some kind of meaning—because I believe that the stories we tell ourselves, tell ourselves (actually I think, that’s a <a href="https://english.ua.edu/user/84">Michael Martone</a> quote). Besides that, Kit’s only link to the others is through reading. When he meets Shar, it’s the books that bind them together. In that way, the story itself is also a relationship between the writer and the reader.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: You&#8217;ve accomplished an intricate and nicely rendered combination of a mystical and futuristic setting. Does this reflect the types of stories you like to read? What are some pieces that have greatly influenced you, either for this piece or in writing in general? </strong></em></p>
<p>Emily: Thank you! Yes, it definitely reflects the types of stories I love to read. Just recently, I’ve been enamored with <a href="https://www.tor.com/2017/06/20/unveiling-the-world-map-for-jy-yangs-fantastical-tensorate-series/">JY Yang’s Tensorate series</a> (from Tor), <em>The Black Tides of Heaven</em> and <em>The Red Threads of War</em>. I should also include the <em>Binti</em> trilogy (also from Tor) by Nnedi Okorafor. What I love about both—but especially Yang’s, is their ability to bind together tropes of fantasy and tropes of science fiction into their world building. Angela Carter’s <em>The Bloody Chamber</em> was also life-changing for me in terms of the style/lyricism that I use in my writing.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The shapes that the main character, &#8220;Kit,&#8221; shifts to are predominantly canine. Was there any particular reason for this? </strong></em></p>
<p>Emily: It just so happens that I’m currently in my last year, last semester at the Northeast Ohio MFA program, so the thesis I’m working on is a collection of short stories. Each story is meant to stand alone with its own cast of characters, but they do have overarching themes or motifs that are reoccurring. Actually, I have one other short story called “<a href="https://www.shimmerzine.com/trees-struck/">Trees Struck by Lightning</a>” from last year in <em>Shimmer</em>, and it has reverse werewolves. It just so happens both of my “shaper” stories from my collection found wonderful homes!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: How was it to write this from the perspective of &#8220;Kit?&#8221; Was it challenging in any way to get into his character and see things through these naive eyes with his own language and own world? </strong></em></p>
<p>Emily: Funnily enough, I borrowed Kit from a novel project from very, very long ago that I’ve never been able <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/mario-taferner-404912-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10124 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/mario-taferner-404912-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>to finish. I got frustrated that I had him floating around and never got to “use” him, so I picked him up again as a narrator for this story, just to relive the glory days. I was surprised though, with how easy it was slipping back into his narration. Coming up with ways to describe things (especially technology) from narrators who don’t recognize it is always difficult, though! I think you have to strike a balance between authenticity to your character, and not boring the reader with dramatic irony (they’ve figured it out, but the narrator hasn’t).</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most difficult aspect of this story to write and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emily: Out of my entire thesis collection, this is the weirdest, most “experimental” story in the bunch because it doesn’t follow a traditional story structure. I deliberately began writing to showcase language/style first. Normally, character comes first for me, then world, then plot. So I think the scariest part was mixing up that order—letting my sentences do the work first—then world, then character (last). I’m so glad to see it find such a perfect home at <em>Luna Station</em>. [editor&#8217;s note: aw, shucks]</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emily: Just the thesis, though my thesis ends with a weird west novella that is a prequel to a novel project I’ve been working on since 2011 (not the one with Kit, though). Finishing that novel is priority #1 after I graduate this spring. Looking forward to getting back to it—and getting it finished up!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 033 Author Interview: Kat Weaver and &#8220;On Your Honor&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-kat-weaver-and-on-your-honor/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-kat-weaver-and-on-your-honor/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 033]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9944</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Captive birds in space. Need we say more? Well yes, actually. And Issue 033 author&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/lovebird_1522346882.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-9964" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/lovebird_1522346882.jpg" alt="" width="1" height="1" /></a><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/parrot-1271428_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9965 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/parrot-1271428_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Captive birds in space. Need we say more? Well yes, actually. And <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-033/">Issue 033</a> author Kat Weaver helps us. Read on for our interview with Kat as she tells us the secrets behind her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/on-your-honor/">On Your Honor</a>&#8221; from our current Issue 033.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: There&#8217;s almost a Renaissance-like feel to the characters with their large, extravagant dresses, proprietary manners, gossip, and background of aristocratic behavior. Tell us how you weaved this in with an otherwise futuristic story line.</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kat: Worldbuilding isn’t actually my strong suit—not fantasy or sci-fi worldbuilding, at least, as I mostly tend to write historical fiction. For awhile now I’ve been working on a series of illustrations featuring ladies with parrots in space. Since it was supposed to be fun, I could just toss in whatever I loved drawing—architecture, fashion, birds, attractive nebulae. I was concentrating more on a cohesive aesthetic than whether a world like this would actually make sense, and I’m still okay with that. (Shout-out to my beta readers, though, for helping me figure out worldbuilding logistics!)<b></b></p>
<p dir="ltr">This particular story, about this particular portion of society in this particular time, owes more than a little something to late 18th-century Britain, especially Duchess Georgiana and the whole situation with her husband and Bess Foster. Thinking of that period’s industry and government and resource management, it’s on a space-and-magic scale, rather than a single planet.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: What made you choose birds for the role of the oracles? Your descriptions of their colors, behaviors, and personalities give the reader the impression you either have experience and/or interest in them. Is this so?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kat: The birds themselves actually came before their role! It was important for me to work out a <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/parrot-4078_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9959 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/parrot-4078_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>way that these parrots in space—in captivity—could lead interesting, fulfilling lives. The oracular games the interpreters set up are meant to be intellectually stimulating, and there’s plenty of opportunity for socializing. If a parrot outlives its interpreter, it will be cared for, and given the chance to bond with someone new.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I grew up with my brother’s cockatiel, but it wasn’t until we’d graduated college that my girlfriend and I got a bird of our own. (We didn’t stop at one, but Mister, our diamond dove, is much less high maintenance.) Papaya is our peach-faced lovebird, a very small and yellow tyrant who rules our lives. Many people are surprised at how much personality even little parrots have, and how intelligent they are. Paya knows how to ask for water—it’ll tap its beak on the inside of a cup with an accusing look—and it scolds good friends of ours who it hasn’t seen in awhile. Parrots are social animals! Large parrots in particular are a full time job.<b></b></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The names of the birds: &#8220;On-Your-Honor&#8221; and &#8220;I-Beg-Your-Pardon&#8221; — where did these come from?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kat: In my experience, there are certain kinds of phrases, said in a certain tone of voice, that best attract parrots’ attention. They’re fairly short, with an identifiable rhythm—for instance, “Who’s a good bird?” It’d be to the interpreters’ advantage to be able to teach their oracles names they can repeat—and names that rich supplicants would find charming. (This mainly applies to birds who do imitate human speech and/or sound, but the tradition would still encompass lovebirds like Honor.) I was also thinking of thoroughbred racehorses, who have their official stable names, and then the names that their owners/trainers actually call them. I’m dead certain the interpreters have all sorts of weird in-joke nicknames for their oracles.<b></b></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The concept of manipulating the &#8220;messages&#8221; of oracles through bribes (i.e. paying for what you want to hear) as well as the concept of marriage as a ploy for political gain prove in your story to be as true in the future as they ever were in the past. Can you comment on this?</strong></em><b></b></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kat: I’m not sure I’d call this a futuristic world—I don’t think it’s an outgrowth of any Earth as we know it. There’s terraforming and spaceships, and there’s magic, and there’s a commercial aristocracy and gossip journals. People who have power, from wherever that power derives, are going to devise ways to keep it. People are going to do each other favors based on personal alliances rather than an ultimate good, and people are going to look out for their own. I don’t want to be too cynical, but I am interested in characters who actively try to balance their self-interest with a broader concern for what’s right.<b></b></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Paseia&#8217;s love for the birds balanced with the desire to see a real world in a universe where everything is being used up says quite a bit about her character in subtle undertones. Can you tell us more about Paseia?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kat: Paseia is proud of being an interpreter, and proud of doing her job well. She enjoys a certain amount of status and privilege—she’s friends with the Abbess, she wears nice clothes, she’s occasionally invited offship to parties and plays. She’s very conscious of her place, which means she’s also conscious of her isolation. She rationalizes her interest in the outside world as a means to an end, a way to serve her supplicants, but she has a genuine desire to be part of something. As you said, she’s discovering that she values what’s real. Ecosystems, animals, genuine intentions. Maybe true things are all the more valuable to her because of their scarcity.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/woman-58558_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9966 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/woman-58558_1920-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>LSQ: What was the hardest part about writing this story? What came easiest?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kat: Honestly, nothing about writing comes very easily to me—except maybe the parts about birds and clothes. This story was one whole exercise in exiting my comfort zone, and creating a “new” setting (cobbling together influences) that requires explanation in order for the story to work. Which is not to say that historical fiction doesn’t need explanation—it’s just different.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other projects? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kat: There’s a novel or two to be written in this world, and I just have to unearth them—I’m still at the brainstorming stage. Maybe more short stories ought to come first, and definitely more illustrations. I’m also revising a historical novel about gay revolutionaries in 1830s France and Italy, which I hope to send out on another round of queries soon.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-kat-weaver-and-on-your-honor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 033 Author Interview: Heather Morris and &#8220;There&#8217;s No Need to Fear the Darkness&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-heather-morris-and-theres-no-need-to-fear-the-darkness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 033]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9940</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Right, so, here at LSQ we love our authors and get really jazzed when we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Right, so, here at <em>LSQ</em> we love our authors and get really jazzed when we get to pick their writerly brains, not unlike zombies. But non-violent zombies. Really just zombies who love reading. On that note, we&#8217;re excited to share our chat with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-033/">Issue 033</a> author Heather Morris where we talked about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/theres-no-need-to-fear-the-darkness/">There&#8217;s No Need to Fear the Darkness</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal"><em><strong>LSQ:</strong> <b>The title sets, in a way, a hopeful tone and made me think of the story in a more benevolent light than I may have given another title. Did you intend for this?</b></em></p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal">Heather: Not particularly. I have a really hard time landing on titles, and this one was especially difficult for me. To me it actually felt kind of sinister—so I’m interested to see a different reaction to it!<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/death_1522260605.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-9951" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/death_1522260605.jpg" alt="" width="1" height="1" /></a><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/hand-3257945_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9953 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/hand-3257945_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal"><em><strong>LSQ:</strong><b> Some authors struggle with how much background, how much origin story, to put in their pieces whereas with this piece, you just dove right in. Was that a conscious decision, or did you make cuts in earlier drafts? In other words, did you have the background of this piece (how things got this way) in your head, or were you able to just jump right in?</b></em></p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal">Heather: The background, particularly in this story, was a pretty organic process. I kind of let Brenda start “talking” to me and she told me what she wanted to say. I’m a builder rather than a pruner; I tend to add things to each subsequent draft rather than cutting. So I didn’t really plan out much. I just started with Brenda reading an evidence file, but as she was doing that she told me where she had been and where she was going to go.</p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal"><em><strong>LSQ: </strong><b>This question sort of depends on your answer to #2, in a way: why only three people with this gift? </b></em></p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal">Heather: Because I was writing a relationship between three people and I wanted them set apart in some way while still connected to each other. I didn’t want Brenda to be completely alone in her talents, but more people having the ability would mean an entire new subset of humanity and that would be a story on a different scale than I wanted to tell.</p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal"><em><strong>LSQ: </strong><b>Your story explores various ways such a gift could be used. It&#8217;s interesting your characters choose not to charge for their gift. Why is this and what does it say about these people?</b></em></p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal">Heather: Well, they’re the good guys (even when they’re thirsty for fame, like Cade). I can easily imagine people monetizing such a power, only giving access to the super-wealthy, holding it as a sort of threat over others to gain power, etc. But when it comes to these three, I think they were all a bit lost and at loose ends and this suddenly gave them purpose. They’re still coming to terms with it, figuring out how best to use it, but they’re always going to be the good guys.</p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal"><em><strong>LSQ: </strong><b>Where did this idea come from?</b></em></p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal">Heather: This one was written sometime during the turbulence of 2016, and I honestly don’t have a clue where it came from. Usu<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chad-madden-265851-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9955 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chad-madden-265851-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>ally I at least remember what spurred the first line or scene, but I think I just sort of serendipitously happened upon this one.</p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal"><em><strong>LSQ:</strong> <b>Where did the idea of calling bodies &#8220;Blanks&#8221; come from? </b></em></p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal">Heather: Being dead bodies they’ve become more “object” than person, but Brenda’s abilities put them back into something of a liminal state. They’re not who they used to be, but they have the potential to become something else. So I thought “Blank” worked rather well to convey that.</p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal"><em><strong>LSQ: </strong><b>What do you see as your strengths and weaknesses as a writer and did any of these exemplify themselves in the writing of this story? </b></em></p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal">Heather: It’s so hard for me to judge my own skills and process, especially when I know I have a lot of growing to do. I suppose one of my weaknesses is a tendency towards vagueness—whether its that I want readers to come to their own conclusions or just don’t know how to deal with a particular issue, I will often leave things unsaid (for instance, in this piece I wanted to convey that Brenda is non-gender-conforming in some way, but I leave it to the reader to decide exactly what that means). Another weakness I’m trying to work through is my tendency to start things and then abandon them—I have dozens and dozens of opening pages on my hard drive but if the plot peters out or I lose interest I go to the next shiniest thing. So I’m trying to get better about just *finishing*.</p>
<p class="m_-7005613562904891416ydpc16f09beMsoNormal">As for strengths this is of course completely subjective but I think I’m really good with characters. I’ve written lots of different voices and lots of different types of people, but I always try to give them some aspect that will help readers empathize with them. I’m not very good with people in real life, but I think I’ve got a knack for fictional ones.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 033 Author Interview: Diana Hurlburt and &#8220;The Palm Bride&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-diana-hurlburt-and-the-palm-bride/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-diana-hurlburt-and-the-palm-bride/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 033]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9864</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re excited to bring you another Issue 033 author interview today, this time with Diana&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/drew-coffman-98464-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9884 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/drew-coffman-98464-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>We&#8217;re excited to bring you another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-033/">Issue 033</a> author interview today, this time with Diana Hurlburt as she talks about the haunting history of her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-palm-bride/">The Palm Bride</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Is the Palm Bride based on existing folklore? Or something similar?</strong> </em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Diana: Archaeological sites in the region of Florida where I grew up (including <a href="http://stars.library.ucf.edu/ahistoryofcentralfloridapodcast/1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://stars.library.ucf.edu/ahistoryofcentralfloridapodcast/1/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521418440873000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG1ZmTaNID6aqDAweoPoadLnXGTnQ">Windover</a>) suggest that Native groups in the area might have had water mortuary cults, a concept seen further <a href="http://ngm.nationalgeographic.com/2013/08/sacred-cenotes/guillermoprieto-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://ngm.nationalgeographic.com/2013/08/sacred-cenotes/guillermoprieto-text&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521418440873000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE2o8B4Vae3kij92b93VGv9ZBCaJQ">in Central America</a> that I’ve always found fascinating. There’s also a custom in Ireland and in some modern pagan groups of a doll created on the feast day of Brigid, a goddess/saint fusion associated with holy wells. These are a few of the pieces of folklore that were in my mind when I was drafting this story.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Reconstruction and the growing spiritualism movement is such a fantastic era in US history to set a story. What was it about this time period in the US that made you pick it compared to other historical time periods?</strong> </em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Diana: Oddly, my school education in the Civil War and Reconstruction didn’t center Florida as having much part in the conflict, and I grew up with the popular but erroneous attitude that Florida isn’t “part of the South.” As an adult, I’ve tried to catch up on reading about Reconstruction-era Florida and how the civil rights movements in particular affected the state. As far as spiritualism goes, this story came about because I tried and failed to write an 1800s AU <em>Ghostbusters</em> fanfic about seances and suffragettes! (If anyone out there writes this, please link me.)</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Were you already familiar with the spiritualism movement in the mid to late 1800s or did this story require research?</strong> </em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Diana: I knew a bit about the broad spiritualism movement and other religious movements that arose chiefly in the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/vishal-banik-539799-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9885 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/vishal-banik-539799-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>Northeast in the 1800s, but wasn’t sure how much reach the most popular movements had, or whether they would’ve had adherents in the South&#8211;how Southern Christian influence and the diasporic religions which came to the US with enslaved peoples might have shaped those movements. St. Augustine is <a href="https://www.ghostsandgravestones.com/st-augustine/haunted-places.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://www.ghostsandgravestones.com/st-augustine/haunted-places.php&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521418440873000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGDPA9kYgSRH49-ruH1eTtxASwUSw">a haunted city</a>, so it seemed reasonable that people in the area might have an interest in seances and the otherworld. <a href="http://nationalhumanitiescenter.org/tserve/nineteen/nkeyinfo/cwsouth.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://nationalhumanitiescenter.org/tserve/nineteen/nkeyinfo/cwsouth.htm&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521418440873000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEPpiwvWKRHllG1EMBvDhoZp-WLVw">This article</a> made me think specifically about the effects of the Civil War on those who remained, how their views of death changed.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: You&#8217;ve created a very interesting relationship between Mrs. Cobb and Miss Butler &#8212; not only in race at the time of the story, but also as suggested lovers. Can you comment on their relationship?</strong> </em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Diana: Mrs. Cobb and Miss Butler are involved, as Miss Randolph observes. It’s important to me to include LQBTQIAP+ relationships in historical fiction and speculative writing, because we have always existed. The complicated status of Mrs. Cobb after the Civil War, as a freed black woman in the South, is discussed somewhat in that the house the women live in is assumed to be owned by Miss Butler, who is white. She is also a former Bostonian, a hat-tip to “Boston marriages.” A white Northern woman living in a formerly glamorous estate with a black servant would have drawn less attention than a black free woman owning a house like Villa Reina.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: This story speaks in many ways of roles of women: &#8220;What was any woman but coarse matter fit only for fueling another&#8217;s flame?&#8221; and &#8220;I can&#8217;t recall a time when women were not left to clean up a mess.&#8221; Do you consider this a story firstly about a seance with the background of women or firstly a story about women with the background of a seance?</strong> </em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Diana: Most of my stories are about women, generally and specifically, and then the secondary purpose is whatever circumstances and time those women find themselves in. “The Palm Bride” in particular is about women because of the extreme and majority-male death toll of the Civil War, because of that time period in which abolition and suffragist movements were gaining traction, and because spiritualism carved out a space for women prophets and practitioners and had a lot of overlap with progressive political and social movements.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Seeing as you live in Florida, can you describe some ways in which it, as a location and a character itself, fits into your story? Does the region surface in other works of yours?</strong> </em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kristen-sturdivant-475268-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9886 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kristen-sturdivant-475268-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Diana: Florida is my favorite place to write about! I love stories where the setting is its own character and try to create those as often as possible. “The Palm Bride” inhabits a Florida almost like ours, a space where I’ve been building a regional mythology that takes into account the state’s singular geographic features, its patchwork history, and its diverse populations. As a kid I loved a lot of European-inspired fantasy, but when it came time to create my own speculative world, I balked at including established otherworldly elements like elves and fairies. Instead I tried to take concepts like kelpies and mermaids and grow them in Florida. Ada Nuit, the mischievous spirit at the center of “The Palm Bride,” derives her name from a corruption of “as da nuite,” the ghost procession featured in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Santa_Compa%C3%B1a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Santa_Compa%25C3%25B1a&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521418440873000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFvprj3xQ9REUHBVix_KtGfvnFnFA">some Spanish myths</a>. As a white writer, it’s not my place to rewrite Florida prehistory or co-opt the myths of the state’s extant Native groups; however, I hope the stories I create illuminate some of what is so spectacular and unique about Florida’s culture and natural beauty.</p>
<p dir="ltr">You can find other Florida stories (including more Ada Nuit!) <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34724315-equus?ac=1&amp;from_search=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34724315-equus?ac%3D1%26from_search%3Dtrue&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521418440873000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHq9VTI4BzuJfKy2VDxvyZH8Hb-Tg">here</a>, <a href="http://www.bodypartsmagazine.com/diving-for-the-cross.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.bodypartsmagazine.com/diving-for-the-cross.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521418440873000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHego0xBmAbEif8qx8ZNKiBiZ8jtg">here</a>, <a href="https://gumroad.com/l/yiRvE" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://gumroad.com/l/yiRvE&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521418440873000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEIsQ5QKt5rHF4O5dpABUEfDeu2nA">here</a>, and <a href="http://dianahurlburt.tumblr.com/post/166979035900/the-chimney" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://dianahurlburt.tumblr.com/post/166979035900/the-chimney&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521418440873000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGNDT2Z9Rv46M99t6RJUE-Kp7lpOQ">here</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: What was the biggest challenge in writing this story? What did you enjoy the most about writing it?</strong> </em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Diana: Plot is not my strong point as a writer, so crafting a compelling conflict for the women to deal with was first on the to-do list. Atmosphere and character come more naturally to me, so writing about a place I love and find evocative (visit St. Augustine if you get a chance!) was appealing, and differentiating the three women in the story was a pleasant challenge. Miss Randolph’s dry internal superiority-complex was especially fun.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-diana-hurlburt-and-the-palm-bride/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 033 Author Interview: Meghan Cunningham and &#8220;Borrowing Ark Sutherland&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-meghan-cunningham-and-borrowing-ark-sutherland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 10:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 033]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Want to know more about the behind-the-scenes of the short stories in Luna Station Quarterly?&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Want to know more about the behind-the-scenes of the short stories in <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em>? Of course you do! We talked with author Meghan Cunningham whose story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/borrowing-ark-sutherland/">Borrowing Ark Sutherland</a>&#8221; appears in our current <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-033/">Issue 033</a>. Go check it out, then come back and read about Meghan&#8217;s story behind the story.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The concept of borrowing a body for a finite amount of pleasure feels both gruesome and inhumane and yet . . . somehow believable. What does this say about the objectification of our bodies?</strong></em></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/alex-iby-434004-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9878 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/alex-iby-434004-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Meghan: Objectification and commodification and quantification of the body were definitely things I was turning over when the central concept of this story came around. I was thinking a lot about debates around other body-markets: certainly sex work and porn, but also surrogacy and pay-for-plasma. For that matter, anyone who’s worked a twelve-hour retail shift knows that most low-wage jobs make demands on your body in exchange for a paycheck. I wanted to explore this weird corner of those debates without necessarily coming down on one side or another; there’s always a tension that can’t be resolved easily between choice and coercion in these cases.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The overall setting of your story is sometime in the future, with novel technology and gadgets, but the age-old war between the haves and have-nots as well as worker versus The Man remains. It feels as though these basic conflicts will never change. Can you comment on this?</strong></em></p>
<p>Meghan: It’s certainly hard to get away from imagining the future. I find it kind of interesting that somebody like Carnation can get away with maybe not even <em>having</em> a body, whereas physical labor and effort is so intrinsic to low-wage jobs. Even today, when we talk about the jobs that are going to escape (at least the first wave of) automation&#8211;jobs that require creativity and collaboration and so on&#8211;they’re very white-collar jobs, jobs that are not necessarily accessible to a person without the right credentials in our current model. Where does that leave people who don’t have those credentials? That sense of being left behind was something hovering in the air for me as well when I was throwing down ideas for the setting and economic system.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The reader&#8217;s view of Happiness from his introduction to the end of the story changes from inferred malevolence to (maybe?) some level of benevolence. What is it about this character that made you want to develop him in this way?</strong></em></p>
<p>Meghan: For the most part, when I thought about reasons why somebody would want to borrow a body, other than the possible therapeutic applications of the technology, the emotions I was coming up with were pity and contempt in different measures. Really I suspect that Happiness just doesn’t have a holistic understanding of the chain of production, as it were. He doesn’t think about the person on the losing end of the transaction. And to be honest, part of the reason I feel so little outright antipathy toward Happiness&#8211;other than the whole cult leader thing&#8211;is because probably everything I own also involves a dose of cruelty at some point along the chain. The chains are so big we almost can’t avoid it. If a Bolivian farmer flew up tomorrow to confront me in my home about my pack of quinoa, I would probably be surprised too, but who’s to say they wouldn’t be justified?</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Is there any hidden intention behind the name &#8220;Happiness&#8221; and his longing for freedom?</strong></em></p>
<p>Meghan: When I was first drafting this story I honestly just thought it was funny to have this character who’s obsessed <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/daniel-zacatenco-363505-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9879 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/daniel-zacatenco-363505-unsplash-300x196.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="196" /></a>with America as a kind of myth in a world where I’m not sure the USA as we know it today even exists. (For all I talk about economics here, a lot of stuff in this story originally happened because I thought it would be funny.) But as the story evolved it became more and more about the trade-offs we do and don’t get in an economic system, so maybe it’s natural that the antagonist has these motifs of a country that is obviously famous for its brand of capitalism.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Early in the story, the older man is more concerned with STIs than the bioethics of borrowing and using someone else&#8217;s body. The immediate (although in hindsight) concern of the individual versus a broader set of concerning morals feels like a classic take on human nature. Did you intend this?</strong></em></p>
<p>Meghan: In a way this is also Happiness’s problem. (Carnation is probably just kind of a rich jerk.) Immediate personal things are much easier to think about, question, and control, and we live in such a big interconnected world—the characters in this story even more so—that maybe we’ve outpaced our own capacity for moral action in some ways.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the hardest part of this story to write? What came easiest?</strong></em></p>
<p>Meghan: When I was first letting this story percolate I debated with myself a lot about what combination of genders the “client” and the “body” should be. In the end I felt like when both participants were men it left the most conceptual space open for what I wanted to explore. I knew I wouldn’t have been able to resist making the F/F version about the relationship femininity has with the body and its value. And then there were a lot of complications to untangle with a cross-gender body-borrower, because in any direction, casting this client as pitiful or villainous created unpleasant implications about gender-crossing in general that would have required a lot of care. All the options were such different stories and I was sad to let go of them.</p>
<p>But I loved the freedom this setting gave me to rapid-fire possible future-isms. Part of the fun of an intentionally eclectic and piecemeal world is getting to just throw stuff at the board and see what sticks. Like, I have no idea what data nursing is or how Indonesia acquired part of Mindanao, but sure, that sounds interesting, let’s run with it.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Meghan: I’ve been focusing on short stories for the past half year. My . . . romantic? . . . story “You Two Should Feel Very Lucky” about two women spliced together in a teleporter appears in the Jan/Feb issue of<em> Iridium</em>, and I have a weird little piece of magical realism flash in the upcoming anthology <em>Broken Metropolis: Queer Tales of a City That Never Was </em>from Mason Jar Press. There’s a lot of short-form stories I’m excited to tell and share, but I am also letting ideas percolate for long-form stories&#8211;including a long-form version of this concept!&#8211;and I’m interested in developing games and interactive fiction in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 033 Author Interview: Brittany Pladek and &#8220;Notes from an Unpublished Interview&#8230;&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-brittany-pladek-and-notes-from-an-unpublished-interview/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 033]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9799</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mondays can be a bear, so why not start your week off with an interview&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kris-atomic-39750-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9802 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/kris-atomic-39750-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Mondays can be a bear, so why not start your week off with an interview with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-033/">Issue 033</a> author Brittany Pladek as she tells us about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/notes-from-an-unpublished-interview-with-mme-delave-fairy/">Notes from an Unpublished Interview with Mme. Delave, Fairy</a>&#8220;?</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The sense of time and place is eloquently presented in your piece &#8212; you&#8217;ve managed to capture both the French Revolution and early 20th century Manhattan. Do you have a particular interest in either era? What was it about the French Revolution that prompted its inclusion in this piece (say, as compared to some other revolutions or social upheaval)? </strong></em></p>
<p>Brittany: I study the era of the French Revolution, though as a literature scholar rather than a historian, and with a focus on England rather than France (so apologies to any actual historians who read the piece and find my inevitable errors). But I’m fascinated by the post-French Revolutionary period and the early twentieth century because they’re both eras of profound disillusionment. They’re times when people had to figure out how to continue working towards the good despite feeling like their hopes had been shattered. Those are instructive moments, I think.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The interest of the fairy to massive social change (&#8220;What courage, to attempt such a spell!&#8221; Mme. says) I think says something very potent about society&#8217;s ability to sometimes make huge changes. Can you speak to this? Is there perhaps something in the current state of events that echoes these thoughts? </strong></em></p>
<p>Brittany: Yes. This is the bluntest allegory I’ve ever written. It’s 2018, I live in the United States, and I’m too tired for subtlety: I’m watching a country that was at least nominally a republic become an autocracy. I wrote this story to try and keep my own hopes up and to remind myself that losing faith in the possibility of change is a sure way to keep it from happening. It’s so easy to lock yourself out of a world where revolution is possible.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The narrative style of this piece (mostly newspaper interview) is somewhat unique. Did this story naturally lend itself to this format, or was it something that you carved out gradually between edits? Do you have any experience or background in journalism or digging through archives? </strong></em></p>
<p>Brittany: I do spend a lot of time in the archives for my research. But I also love fiction that incorporates documentary artifacts, like Ursula K. Le Guin’s <em>The Left Hand of Darkness</em> and N. K. Jemisin’s <em>Broken Earth</em> trilogy, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stevie-ekkelkamp-62770-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9803 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/stevie-ekkelkamp-62770-unsplash-201x300.jpg" alt="" width="201" height="300" /></a>which use archival fragments as part of their world building, or Sofia Samatar’s short fiction, which is often crafted from different (imaginary) texts layered together. This piece was a deliberate formal experiment following those models. It takes some pretty big liberties with the interview format—for example, I doubt any seasoned reporter would take such flowery notes.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Fairies come off somewhat hedonistic in your story &#8212; also as tricksters and something more sinister. Can you comment on the state of fairies as portrayed in your view versus perhaps the &#8220;Disney&#8221; version of fairies that the general public may hold? How do you view the benevolent nature of the &#8220;modern&#8221; fairy versus the darker version of fairies in older fables?</strong></em></p>
<p>Brittany: There are so many different fairy traditions! The one this story references is very specific, though. It&#8217;s a tradition popular in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries—think Lord Dunsany’s <em>The King of Elfland’s Daughter</em>—that uses “Faerie” to express nostalgia for a vanishing world (usually coded as more mystical, hierarchical, agrarian, and conservative). The fading of Faerie symbolized the loss of that world. As an emotion, I find that nostalgia very compelling, though I don’t miss the world Faerie represented for people like Dunsany. But I’m fascinated by how powerful nostalgia is, and how complicated, as a type of desire. This story was an attempt to turn Faerie nostalgia towards something different, and it got grim pretty quickly. Nostalgia usually presumes you can’t get the thing you’re pining for back. Mme. Delave’s nostalgia for the days of revolutionary possibility means she believes they’re gone for good.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most difficult aspect about this story to write and why? What inspired this idea? Have you written about fairy lore before? </strong></em></p>
<p>Brittany: The most challenging aspect of this story was deciding how much of the reporter’s personal life I wanted to include. In the end, she ended up being pretty marginal so I could focus on Mme. Delave. As for inspiration, I’d just finished a novel by John Crowley, whose most famous book, <em>Little, Big</em>, is a revision of the “fading of faerie” myth.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you currently working on other writing projects? If so, could you tell us about it? </strong></em></p>
<p>Brittany: I’m working on a few short stories and revising a post-apocalyptic novella about a city where every year, a group of debaters have to convince god not to destroy humanity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 033 Author Interview: Holly Schofield and &#8220;Heart Proof&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-author-interview-holly-schofield-and-heart-proof/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 11:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 033]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9761</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the recent release of Issue 033 comes interviews of the nine authors found within&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>With the recent release of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-033/">Issue 033</a> comes interviews of the nine authors found within its pages (or pixels, depending on your media of choice). We start with author Holly Schofield and &#8220;Heart Proof&#8221; which is this issue&#8217;s featured story. Here&#8217;s a tip on how to best enjoy these interviews: it&#8217;s a two-part process like this: a) go read &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/heart-proof/">Heart Proof</a>&#8221; and b) now read what Holly has to say about it.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong><span class="im"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/ybrayym-esenov-48616-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9762 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/ybrayym-esenov-48616-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>LSQ: The concept of sacrificing a culture&#8217;s greatest treasures instead of memorializing them, say, in a museum is key in your story but is presented as a benefit to society. What made you think of these actions in this way? Does this speak to today&#8217;s culture whereby via technology, almost everything seems to be kept nowadays?</span></strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Holly: My hope is that the reader will finish the story and contemplate our rampant consumerism, our chase of the &#8220;new and improved&#8221;, and our rapidly-growing  disinterest in antiques. And that they will think about those things in conjunction with concepts of planned obsolescence, respect for handcrafted products, and &#8220;bespoke&#8221; items (which, I predict, will be an increasingly growing trend due to the advent of 3D printers). The concept of &#8220;detachment&#8221; from material goods that appears in Buddhism philosophy and other belief systems is also intertwined in the story.</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The concept of religious doctrine shaping a culture is ever present in your story. Was this modeled on any particular real-life examples?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Holly: The transference of knowledge and skills from one generation to the next is a complex issue that no culture has yet perfected. I find it fascinating to think how much information is now stored in the cloud and how much could be lost due to the decline of printed books. I wanted to explore a method of knowledge transfer that was counter-intuitive and see how it played out.</div>
<div>I think that organized religion&#8211;or, rather, overly-strict doctrines and overly-rigid interpretations of well-intentioned philosophies&#8211;has caused huge difficulties in our maturation as a species. I&#8217;m sure that every reader can think of several global and local examples.</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Can you speak to the title of this piece?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Holly: I do like using puns in titles and hiding them in stories. Since this story has a more serious tone than some of my pieces, I restrained myself and simply let the wordplay between the heatproof nature of her invention contrast with the emotional resistance in her heart.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Forging iron, the volcanic landscape for the sacrifices, Kamik&#8217;s fireproof box &#8212; can you comment on the theme of fire in this piece?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Holly: I wanted to portray a female craftsperson rebelling against a destructive imaginary religion. Her <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/katya-austin-301667-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9763 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/katya-austin-301667-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>occupation and the setting (which is based on the drive-through volcano on St. Lucia combined with various Canadian hotsprings) served both those needs.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was most challenging about writing this piece?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Holly: The combination of how female roles are cast in society, old age grinding a person down &#8220;like spices in a pestle&#8221;, and the death from cancer meant it intersected in my personal life in several dimensions.</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Was there anything in particular that inspired this piece or drove it forward in your mind?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Holly: My starting point was a female blacksmith in a culture where that was unremarkable. Then I simply listened to what Kamik was telling me. I hope you enjoying reading it as much as I enjoyed writing it.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 033 Release! Cover artist interview</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-033-release-cover-artist-interview/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 11:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 033]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s the day! Luna Station Quarterly is thrilled to announce the release of Issue 033!&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s the day! <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> is thrilled to announce the release of Issue 033! In it, you&#8217;ll find nine stories by amazing female authors and on its cover, well. See for yourself:</p>
<figure id="attachment_9686" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-9686" style="width: 225px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Blindcircus_900px_72dpi-kirbi_web.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-9686 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Blindcircus_900px_72dpi-kirbi_web-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-9686" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Blind Circus&#8221; by Kirbi Fagan</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="http://kirbifagan.com/">Kirbi Fagan</a> (@KirbiFagan) is our cover artist for this issue and she&#8217;s delivered the goods with a piece titled &#8220;Blind Circus.&#8221; We were lucky enough to snag Kirbi for a moment and pick her creatively amazing brain. Here&#8217;s what she had to say.</p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p1"><em><b>LSQ: Please tell us about Issue 033&#8217;s cover art, &#8220;Blind Circus.&#8221; What&#8217;s going on in this picture? Who is this person, does she have a story? What inspired you to create this?</b></em></p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p2">Kirbi: This artwork was commissioned by Clark Huggins creator of the &#8220;Reckless Deck.&#8221; The deck is an idea-generating set of cards. I cherry-picked the first card, &#8220;Fantasy Hero&#8221;, and the other two cards, “Blindfold” and “Circus Attire”, where chosen at random. I ran with it! I tried dozens of ideas and found this image. When creating, too much freedom can be daunting. I’m an artist that likes to be put in a box. Give me an ocean and I’ll drown! At first I was using “Blindfold&#8221; in my sketches as part of a circus act, being blindfolded added a level<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/RD-ArtCard-web.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9687 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/RD-ArtCard-web-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a> of suspense. However, covering up a face I quickly lost the intimacy of the character and my favorite part to paint. I thought having a blindfold interpreted visually as a strong stream of light blinding across the eyes would be neat. When that didn&#8217;t work out this led me to using a shadow across the eyes. I thought it gave the character a mysterious narrative. Especially as shadowy faces are usually associated with evil characters. This challenged me to use light, color, and white &#8220;magic&#8221; to communicate that this character, though mysterious, is not &#8220;evil.&#8221;</p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p1"><em><b>LSQ: You&#8217;ve done some covers for Marvel Comics. Is there a different process in creating art for an established comic versus creating something that&#8217;s totally your own? How do you put a bit of yourself into these covers? </b></em></p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p2">Kirbi: Not so different at all! Working as an illustrator, the artwork is always constrained by the client&#8217;s needs and wants. In the best situations, like with Marvel, those needs and wants align with my interests and some really special things can happen. When I’m trying to inject myself into a commission that feels too much like work, I try to focus on two things. First, the pure joy of painting and second, I try to put something in the image that I enjoy. I keep a huge working list of things that I enjoy visually and add to it often. I go to this list and see what might work with the project. The list can include all sorts of items such a bonnets, moss on red bricks, and 1950s Oldsmobiles.</p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p2">When I’m creating for a client, my sketch is completely thought out. Creating the final feels much like painting by number. When I’m on my own I often don’t commit to a sketch which causes me to flounder. Clark gave me a lot freedom; many things were added that were not in the original sketch. In this animation you can see there is a bit of “searching” that wouldn’t happen with other client work.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/kirbifagan.gif"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="center-image aligncenter wp-image-9688 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/kirbifagan-225x300.gif" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p1"><em><b>LSQ: Please tell us a bit about how you&#8217;ve grown as an artist &#8212; excluding technique, are there aspects you do differently now as opposed to when you were younger? Have your tastes changed or remained the same?</b></em></p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p2">Kirbi: I don’t waste time struggling! If I can’t get an area right it’s usually because I don’t have enough information. I’m unapologetic about seeking out more information which might mean going to see the object in person or posing in front of a camera. When I was younger I was extremely academic and “safe.” I’m not scared of ruining an in-progress work like I used to be. I’m willing to sling paint and do whatever it takes to make the work the best it can be. Lately, I’ve been working on some images that have more expression and to do so I’m sacrificing a bit of the realism I’ve been known for in the past.</p>
<figure id="attachment_9691" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-9691" style="width: 214px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Alternative_space_Program_kirbi_fagan_6x9_72dpi_web.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-9691 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Alternative_space_Program_kirbi_fagan_6x9_72dpi_web-214x300.jpg" alt="" width="214" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-9691" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Alternative Space Program&#8221; by Kirbi Fagan</figcaption></figure>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p1"><em><b>LSQ: Tell us a bit about the importance of creating art featuring female leads. Can you comment on the level at which these characters are occurring both on the covers of comics and other media? </b></em></p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p2">Kirbi: I find it so empowering to be a real influence on how women are represented in media. Most publishers are very aware of their newly liberated audience and in response many are seeking out female voices&#8211;like me&#8211;to be creators. It’s crucial young girls get to see themselves in the stories they read and even more important for boys to see girls outside of their paperback cliches. There have been situations where I didn’t like the way a young girl was represented and I was able to convince the publisher to show her in a stronger, less sexist and more flattering light and . . . they went for it! I’m truly in the trenches, trying to make changes and be passionate about it. In children’s publishing it’s common to hear, &#8220;girls will be a fan of a story about a boy lead but a boy rarely will read a story with a female lead.&#8221; The publishers&#8217; solution is to create two different markets. It’s up to creators to get more creative. Create a character so fantastic we all love her! It’s up to the publishers to take a risk which I don’t feel they are all willing to do at this time.</p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p1"><b><em>LSQ: Among all your pieces, do you have a favorite? If so, which is it and why? If not, why not?</em><br />
</b></p>
<figure id="attachment_9692" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-9692" style="width: 201px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Damsel_72dpi_web_Kirbifagan.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-9692 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Damsel_72dpi_web_Kirbifagan-201x300.jpg" alt="" width="201" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-9692" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Damsel&#8221; by Kirbi Fagan</figcaption></figure>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p2">Kirbi: Whatever piece I&#8217;m currently working on is my favorite. In my mind, there are two types of artists: one who works for a finished product they love and another who loves the labor of that product. I love the act of painting more than I love *a* painting. Does that make any sense? Many people don’t realize that the paintings I’m doing right now won’t see the light of day for some time and the work I did last year won’t be out till later this year or next.</p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p1"><em><b>LSQ: From the start of the creative process to the finished piece, do you have a step that is typically the most difficult for you? </b></em></p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p2">Kirbi: In the last few years I&#8217;ve moved in to a place in my development where I feel solid in my process and my process hardly ever wavers. When a client is involved, it&#8217;s about getting a non-visual person on board with the concept. When a client trusts my aesthetics, those are always my best pieces. I really have to sell my idea and create a sketch that captures what I envision the final looking like which is not always easy.</p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p1"><em><b>LSQ: Are there recent books or comics that have influenced some of your work? </b></em></p>
<p class="m_7948330703482955074gmail-p2">Kirbi: The world of writing and art can often derail me more often than inspire me. It’s easy to get caught up in looking at artwork and different styles. That’s something that I don’t think many people admit: I like so many different things (most artists do!). What influences me the most is my passionate students at the College for Creatives Studies in Downtown Detroit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
