<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 047 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-047/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 02:00:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 047 Author Interview: Phoenix Roberts and &#8220;Relapse&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-047-author-interview-phoenix-roberts-and-relapse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 047]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26335</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here it is, dear readers, our final Issue 047 author interview! We have Phoenix Roberts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here it is, dear readers, our final <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-047/">Issue 047</a> author interview! We have Phoenix Roberts wrapping up with the answers to our questions about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/relapse/">Relapse</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What a delightfully creepy story! The “other” is just hinted at near the beginning, and grows (literally) as your story unfolds. What drew you to this kind of reveal and how did it further your plot?</strong></em></p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26427 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/marten-newhall-20nRrCBtBaA-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/marten-newhall-20nRrCBtBaA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/marten-newhall-20nRrCBtBaA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/marten-newhall-20nRrCBtBaA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/marten-newhall-20nRrCBtBaA-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/marten-newhall-20nRrCBtBaA-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Phoenix: Thank you!</p>
<div>I like horror that waits to show its hand because it&#8217;s lightest on the suspension of disbelief ropes. If I were to start off like: &#8220;Hello, person reading this story, there&#8217;s an evil legion of slugs from the void, the entrance to which is in a soda dispenser, pretty spooky, right?&#8221; the person in question would rightly go: &#8220;Well, no, not so much spooky as patently absurd, and you clearly don&#8217;t take this seriously, so neither will I.&#8221; It&#8217;s more interesting for all parties involved to non-didactically ask whether we ought to laugh at the absurd or tremble about it.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Your main character ends up comparing different types of hunger: one self imposed, and one imposed on her. What made you choose hunger as the catalyst for this story?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p>Phoenix: I got a craving for a story unlike most other intentional-hunger fiction I&#8217;ve met, which skews towards the tragic rather than horrific, towards the upper-class-teenage-<wbr />protagonist, and towards the cause-confident. I&#8217;m sure the appeal of writing against a tragic hero narrative of disorder speaks for itself. I&#8217;m sure the same is true about the appeal of writing against harmful demographic lies.</p>
<div></div>
<div>On to the maybe less obvious: something that fascinates me about eating disorders is that, like the rest of being sentient, we don&#8217;t understand them as well as we think we do. Like fifty-ish years ago, dudes who got paid to watch people struggle and have opinions about it went: &#8220;Clearly this is caused by social pressures to be thin, maybe compounded by childhood trauma and personality type. Investigation over. Well done, boys.&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div>Then we found evidence of genetic susceptibility, and the water got all murky, and now we&#8217;re back to square one of: &#8220;We don&#8217;t actually know how or why some people&#8217;s brains do this, we only know some stuff that wakes up the propensity for it.&#8221; That&#8217;s terrifying! Accounting for the terrifying can make it less so. That&#8217;s why I didn&#8217;t spend words on Katherine&#8217;s childhood, or on encounters with purveyors of beauty myths, or any other balms for the unpleasant weirdness of her experience. There was just like this hankering for cause-anxiety and cause-disinterest.</div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us more about the table and what it means to your MC.</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p>Phoenix: On-the-nose-ly: meals happen at tables.</p>
<div></div>
<div>Off-the-nose-ly: one incentive to recover from behavioral health problems is to make room for other stuff. Some people recover to impressive careers, gargantuan accomplishments, instagram-able families, and so on, and that&#8217;s sick. Also, though, any expression of dignity and autonomy a recoverer can find in their daily life, which may or may not be conducive to happenings worth writing home about, is equally sick.</div>
<div></div>
<div>When we overestimate the good times on the other side of most demons, we accidentally lend credence to the internal monologue of: &#8220;My material circumstances are such that a life without the problem couldn&#8217;t possibly be worth living anyways, so I may as well keep the problem.&#8221; It&#8217;s better to be honest that for most of us, we just pay too much rent until eventually we don&#8217;t, and in the meantime occasionally having some fun is preferable to consorting with a decidedly un-fun beast.<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26426 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/clem-onojeghuo-hdW4rZPHe2g-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/clem-onojeghuo-hdW4rZPHe2g-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/clem-onojeghuo-hdW4rZPHe2g-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/clem-onojeghuo-hdW4rZPHe2g-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/clem-onojeghuo-hdW4rZPHe2g-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/clem-onojeghuo-hdW4rZPHe2g-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div></div>
<div>So Katherine chose DIY carpentry as her way to have some fun. I think that was an excellent choice, and I&#8217;m glad that at least for a while she got to do that instead of being hungry.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Is horror a genre you usually write in? What other genres or projects are you drawn to?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Phoenix: Yes. In my opinion, horror is the very best fun to be had responsibly. I also like fantasy. I have in the past liked drama and poetry, and I guess there&#8217;s no way to know for sure that I won&#8217;t like those things again. I worry my saying this contradicts the hard-won claims to legitimacy snatched from the jaws of power by people way smarter than myself, but I like horror and fantasy best because they facilitate the silly and ridiculous, which are objectively better qualities than serious or important.</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 047 Author Interview: JL George and &#8220;Bluebell Song&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-047-author-interview-jl-george-and-bluebell-song/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 11:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 047]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Issue 047 author interviews are coming to a close, but we still have a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-047/">Issue 047</a> author interviews are coming to a close, but we still have a couple left up our sleeves! Today we bring you JL George&#8217;s answers to our questions about &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/bluebell-song/">Bluebell Song</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: </em></strong><em><b>Having the characters use wax to stuff their ears to block sound reminded me of sailors avoiding the song of the sirens. How much comparison is there between the sirens and the story’s bluebells in beauty and danger? Or is there another origin?</b></em></p>
<div><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26339 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/click-and-learn-photography-3VBg9zmZUOY-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/click-and-learn-photography-3VBg9zmZUOY-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/click-and-learn-photography-3VBg9zmZUOY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/click-and-learn-photography-3VBg9zmZUOY-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/click-and-learn-photography-3VBg9zmZUOY-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/click-and-learn-photography-3VBg9zmZUOY-unsplash-2048x1367.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />JL: My mum (who was a librarian until she retired) was always bringing mythology books home from the library for me when I was a kid, and the story of Odysseus and the sirens was one that stuck with me, so that definitely influenced the story to some degree. In British folklore, bluebell woods are enchanted places where the fair folk trap unwary humans in their world, something which seemed rather enticing to me as a fairy-obsessed child! So the story is really a combination of the two. The fascination with something that can be both beneficial and deadly is an old one, going back to the Greek idea of the <i>pharmakon, </i>which is bound up with human sacrifice as well as healing and poison, so I guess there are a lot of cultural ideas floating around that I osmosed at some point and that ended up influencing the story.</div>
<p dir="ltr"><em><b>LSQ: As a healer, Achan knows about herbs and medicines. It is interesting that she is relying on a different aspect of healing &#8211; music and vision. Is the difference of healing what makes the healing so potent? Or is it more what your MC needs to give up?</b></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">JL: Music can be incredibly life-affirming, and I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s saved my life on occasions when my mental health has been bad, so I guess in a way you could call it a kind of medicine. But I think it was more about the idea that magic has a cost, which is incredibly common in fantasy stories. On a smaller scale the cost might just be the ingredients for a spell, or the work that goes into performing it, but power over life and death requires something more.<br />
<b></b></p>
<p dir="ltr"><b><em>LSQ: Achan is very close to her family and desperately wants to help. How much does Mira know about Achan’s ultimate aim?</em><br />
</b></p>
<p dir="ltr">JL: I think she knows she&#8217;d do just about anything to save her daughter, though maybe she hasn&#8217;t thought too much about the implications of that. Not questioning these things too deeply can be a way of protecting ourselves, after all.<br />
<b></b></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><b>LSQ: The ending leaves a little ambiguity as to the ultimate healing of Tiwan. How much of Achan is living in her daughter? What did her sacrifice buy? Also, what role will the bluebells have in the life of Tiwan in the future?</b></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26340 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jez-timms-ikgmBELD7PQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jez-timms-ikgmBELD7PQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jez-timms-ikgmBELD7PQ-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jez-timms-ikgmBELD7PQ-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jez-timms-ikgmBELD7PQ-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jez-timms-ikgmBELD7PQ-unsplash-2048x1367.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">JL: Well, the ambiguity&#8217;s deliberate, and I don&#8217;t want to ruin it by telling people what to think! There&#8217;s definitely something a little eerie about Tiwan going forward, maybe some power that she didn&#8217;t always have. She seems ready to step into her mother&#8217;s shoes as a healer by the time she recovers, but you also probably wouldn&#8217;t want to cross her&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 047 Author Interview: Robin Kirk and &#8220;Home&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-047-author-interview-robin-kirk-and-home/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 047]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26052</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Can&#8217;t get enough of our Issue 047 author interviews? Then you&#8217;re in luck! Today we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Can&#8217;t get enough of our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-047/">Issue 047</a> author interviews? Then you&#8217;re in luck! Today we bring you our interview with Robin Kirk, author of the sci-fi story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/home/">Home</a>&#8220;.</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: “Home” seems very much like an homage from the parent of a teenager: the bittersweet perspective of children growing up. Is this derived from a personal story?</strong></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div class="gmail_default">Robin: Yes! I&#8217;ve been writing a space opera that deals with humanitarian questions&#8230; but in SPACE! I was in my bedroom thinking about what it would be like to face issues involving refugees and displacement&#8211;human challenges that will continue to exist regardless of where we are&#8211;when my son returned home. I behaved as the mother did in this story, listening for where he was going in the house and what he was doing and not wanting to hover or interrupt. The mother here is a stations commander, so has power in her world. Yet her son&#8217;s safety&#8211;and by extension, the safety of the other humans she&#8217;s responsible for&#8211;is a worry that constantly weighs on her. I think science fiction gives writers some interesting tools to examine commonly shared human experiences from fresh angles.</div>
<div dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The mom worries about her son’s docking, the acid clouds surrounding the planet, and of course, the superheated plains. Starting with the mom’s opening dream, I wonder if she experienced the alluded accident or she viewed it though her child’s eyes, as connected as she is to him.</strong></em></p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div class="gmail_default">Robin: In this story, the father has died in an accident. The mother&#8211;as all parents and guardians must&#8211;has to figure out how to allow that child to become an adult and have freedom, even if it means coming to grief. She can express concern but also wrestles with that worry privately and constantly. I think most people who have teen and adult children feel this viscerally. Your heart is your own but it&#8217;s also out there and at risk. You have to learn to live with the constant possibility of that loved one coming to harm. That&#8217;s true on Terra or in space.</div>
<div dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The mom does what she can to make her son comfortable, including lowering the temperature of the ship and giving him the space he needs. She would like nothing better than to fling open her door, but she instead shows restraint. How does the science fiction setting change the depiction of the parent-child relationship?</strong></em></p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div class="gmail_default">Robin: I don&#8217;t think the approach through science fiction changes that core depiction. On Terra or in space, we are all human and face human challenges and dilemmas. Putting this in space, for me, allows some fun world-building, but the personal drama is the same. That said, I get a triple-heartbeat when I write about interstellar travel, rocket ships, and alien worlds. To me, it&#8217;s exciting and challenging to put my characters in these wild settings and see what they do.</div>
<div></div>
<div class="gmail_default"><em><strong><span style="color: #3d3d3d; font-family: 'Open Sans', sans-serif; font-size: 17px;">LSQ: How important is setting in stories you write? Are you more character or plot driven?</span></strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div class="gmail_default">Robin: As much as I love and delight in world-building, for me, everything is rooted in character. As one of my teachers at Vermont College of Fine Arts, Margaret Bechard, once said to me, the characters do have to hit their stage marks occasionally, meaning plot does matter. But the reader has to be on board with that character and what that character does has to interact with that world in a compelling and meaningful way. My writing is a lot of staring at the screen and wondering, &#8220;so what WILL this character do next?&#8221; The answer is almost always a bit of a surprise that at the same time ends up being exactly right for the plot.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 047 Author Interview: A.M. Faller and &#8220;After the Storm&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-047-author-interview-a-m-faller-and-after-the-storm/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 047]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Issue 047 author interviews are still going strong! Today&#8217;s featured author is A.M. Faller,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-047/">Issue 047</a> author interviews are still going strong! Today&#8217;s featured author is A.M. Faller, who talked to us about genre, suspense, and ambiguous endings in her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/after-the-storm/">After the Storm</a>.&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: &#8220;After the Storm&#8221; is SFF, but also part mystery with the discovery of the additional bio-shield and the uncertainty of Aza’s parentage. As an author, how do you add suspense and mystery to an already genred piece?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26272 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/robert-metz-i2GfC7zzMIM-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/robert-metz-i2GfC7zzMIM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/robert-metz-i2GfC7zzMIM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/robert-metz-i2GfC7zzMIM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/robert-metz-i2GfC7zzMIM-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/robert-metz-i2GfC7zzMIM-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />A.M.: I love stories that span multiple genres, especially when the story has sci-fi roots. Technology is fantastic—I love it as much as anyone—but I&#8217;m much more interested in characters, and characters are going to have things going on in their lives. Suspenseful, horrifying, mysterious, romantic things. Sci-fi is a fantastic way to explore potential futures or to use an alien setting to analyze our present, but in order to get any of those messages across, the characters still need to be doing interesting things. This is a long way of saying that I&#8217;m not sure I really thought about mixing suspense and mystery into Aza&#8217;s story—it seemed to belong in her world as much as the sand and wind.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The idea of a bio-shield against a raging desert storm is such an interesting one, seeming to link technology with nature. Where did the concept originate for you?</strong></em></p>
<p>A.M.: The idea for the bioshields initially came from the fact that trees are a natural sound barrier, and they do a great job of cutting wind, as well. I&#8217;m continually impressed with nature&#8217;s adaptability and variety, and I love nature-inspired engineering solutions. I like the idea of a moss-like substance acting as a natural filtration system and shield, and it seemed to meld well with a raw, plant-based society like the Capital&#8217;s in &#8220;After the Storm.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: A turning point for Aza was when she conceded she had been sent into the desert to die, regardless of her skills. It was also when she began to see the people before her in an entirely different light. How did you come up with the idea of the story’s caste system as it applies to Aza?</strong></em></p>
<p>A.M.: This is a hard question. There have been several points in my life in which I&#8217;ve realized that, no matter how good I am or how hard I try, I&#8217;m never going to fit in with some group. I don&#8217;t think this is a unique experience. It can be exclusion due to gender, appearance, race, sexuality, age, class, whatever—but you can&#8217;t change, and the group isn&#8217;t going to accept you the way you are, no matter how great you are. Every time I&#8217;ve had it, this realization hurts. It really hurts. (Probably less than being abandoned in the desert to die, but I can&#8217;t speak to that specific experience.) I guess that is where the idea for the class/caste system in &#8220;After the Storm&#8221; came from—being separated into a different (often less valued) group due to an inalterable characteristic isn&#8217;t right, and it isn&#8217;t fair, but it is a common experience, which makes it worth exploring in a story to me.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The addition of the other cruiser and the mention of more people in the nomadic group seems to end the piece with a hopeful future for Aza. Do you prefer to end your stories with positive outcomes for your characters? Or does it depend on where the story takes you?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26274 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/mohammad-bagher-adib-behrooz-MfVTOmc6LcY-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/mohammad-bagher-adib-behrooz-MfVTOmc6LcY-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/mohammad-bagher-adib-behrooz-MfVTOmc6LcY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/mohammad-bagher-adib-behrooz-MfVTOmc6LcY-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/mohammad-bagher-adib-behrooz-MfVTOmc6LcY-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/mohammad-bagher-adib-behrooz-MfVTOmc6LcY-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>A.M.: I don&#8217;t usually write &#8220;happy endings.&#8221; I think, so far, I&#8217;ve written a few stories that end ambiguously at best, but mostly I tend to write darker endings. This is a bit ironic since I prefer to read stories with happy endings. Then again, one of my favorite endings in the world is the conclusion of Cormac McCarthy&#8217;s <i>The Road,</i> which I read as mostly terrible with just a splash of hope. I definitely like ending with a hint of positivity at least, but I haven&#8217;t yet had a story that led me to a full-blown &#8220;happily ever after,&#8221; either. I guess I like ending stories similarly to real life—things so rarely wrap themselves up in nice, neat packages with all the ends properly tucked away and all the emotions in a pleasant, cohesive line. I think I like my story endings to be a bit open, to ask the reader what they want to happen next, and to give them a wide spectrum of emotions to choose from.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 047 Author Interview: J.M. Phillippe and &#8220;The Skulk&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-047-author-interview-j-m-phillippe-and-the-skulk/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 10:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 047]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You know what today needs? Another Issue 047 author interview. Good thing we just so&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You know what today needs? Another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-047/">Issue 047</a> author interview. Good thing we just so happen to have one! Today&#8217;s spotlight is on J.M. Phillippe and her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-skulk/">The Skulk</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Devlyn is terrified of Sael because he believes he is her servant. How does discovering he is her apprentice change their relationship?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26207 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/alexander-andrews-mEdKuPYJe1I-unsplash-205x300.jpg" alt="" width="205" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/alexander-andrews-mEdKuPYJe1I-unsplash-205x300.jpg 205w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/alexander-andrews-mEdKuPYJe1I-unsplash-700x1024.jpg 700w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/alexander-andrews-mEdKuPYJe1I-unsplash-768x1124.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/alexander-andrews-mEdKuPYJe1I-unsplash-1050x1536.jpg 1050w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/alexander-andrews-mEdKuPYJe1I-unsplash-1399x2048.jpg 1399w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/alexander-andrews-mEdKuPYJe1I-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1749w" sizes="(max-width: 205px) 100vw, 205px" />J.M.: Devlyn starts the story with a very low opinion of himself, reinforced by this idea that his family has sort of abandoned him to this stranger—this terrifying, powerful stranger—because they can’t afford to keep him. When he realizes that Sael chose him to be her apprentice long ago, he sees himself in a much more positive light. He goes from feeling like a burden to feeling like he’s special. As he starts to see Sael as a mentor instead of a master, the power dynamic completely shifts, and he finally can see how much she cares about him. It lets Devlyn be hopeful about his future in a way that he wasn’t before.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your world is a richly magical one that contains many levels. When you imagined this world, what were the most important elements? Which were your favorite elements?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">J.M.: It was important to build a setting that could look both imposing and beautiful so that the magic in my world could layer on top of it in a way that hopefully feels very natural. I loved creating a world with things that are both familiar and strange, adding a supernatural edge to animals that are already delightful, and throwing a mythical flower in among more common herbs. My favorite part was using Devlyn’s perspective and shifting feelings to show this same place as imposing, then mystical, and finally comfortable when he realizes it’s his home.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: Clever animal stories are always fascinating and the skulk sound just like the sort of allies an Apothecary would like to have. Were they based on a particular magic creature? Or just the wily reputation of the fox?</b></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">J.M.: I definitely built on the wily reputation of the fox to write &#8220;The Skulk.&#8221; I was looking up facts about foxes and learned that a group of foxes is called a skulk, which just sounded like something out of a fairytale to me, and inspired me to think about a magical version of the fox. Foxes are often shown as tricksters in legends and fairytales, sometimes malicious, sometimes benign, but always very clever. I wanted my version to have all those same attributes plus additional abilities, the kind of creatures that would be the perfect allies of a witch. I also wanted them to be somewhat unpredictable and with motives and desires of their own. I liked the idea that magic was something you win over and work with rather than demand or control, and the skulk in my story represent that.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What are your favorite genres and concepts to write in?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26208 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/giorgi-iremadze-tBC0lwWmvSc-unsplash-217x300.jpg" alt="" width="217" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/giorgi-iremadze-tBC0lwWmvSc-unsplash-217x300.jpg 217w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/giorgi-iremadze-tBC0lwWmvSc-unsplash-742x1024.jpg 742w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/giorgi-iremadze-tBC0lwWmvSc-unsplash-768x1060.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/giorgi-iremadze-tBC0lwWmvSc-unsplash-1112x1536.jpg 1112w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/giorgi-iremadze-tBC0lwWmvSc-unsplash-1483x2048.jpg 1483w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/giorgi-iremadze-tBC0lwWmvSc-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1854w" sizes="(max-width: 217px) 100vw, 217px" /></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">J.M.: As a social worker, I was taught to put human behavior in the social environment, understanding how their environment impacts the choices people make. So as a writer, I love playing with the interaction between setting and character, how the places we occupy can change how we see other people and ourselves. The more fantastical the setting, the more there is for a character to react to and navigate. It’s why I love writing fantasy and science-fiction because it lets me imagine how human behavior can look when we change other elements. You can start with a very wild “what if…?” and then still find very relatable characters because they represent that greater thing that makes humans human, no matter what kind of world they live in.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 047 Author Interview: Louise Hughes and &#8220;Look to the Future&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-047-author-interview-louise-hughes-and-look-to-the-future/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 10:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 047]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 047 is packed with 19 quality speculative fiction stories which means, aside from plenty&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-047/">Issue 047</a> is packed with 19 quality speculative fiction stories which means, aside from plenty of good reading, we also have lots of author interviews to share! Today we&#8217;re talking with Louise Hughes about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/look-to-the-future/">Look to the Future</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your opening lines are so striking &#8211; combining a hook and worldbuilding together. How important are those openers for your writing? Do you often put that kind of emphasis at the get-go?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Louise: As a very linear writer, I like to get the first line right from the off. It sets the tone and puts me on the path to where I’m going. If I start to struggle later on in the story, it’s something to go back to. So, the concept of the main character being able to see into the past came after I’d already written half of the story but it was floundering a bit. I went back to that first line.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: It is very interesting that your MC is more like those of us in our world (at least at first), though she is an anomaly in hers. What were your thoughts when you wrote about the contrast?</em></strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Louise: It was much the same as writing about someone who is neurodiverse in our world. The main character is someone whose mind doesn’t work quite the same as everyone else around her. The decisions she makes aren’t always trusted because people know that the information she has when making them isn’t the same as the information they would have in the same situation. It’s a familiar feeling, that sense that everyone else has some additional information that you’re missing, so it wasn’t that much of a leap. She adapts, she forms her own systems rather than listening to the advice of those who don’t have her experiences, and she takes a few risks.</p>
<p><em><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26187 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rachael-ren-U94eGGi_1ZY-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rachael-ren-U94eGGi_1ZY-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rachael-ren-U94eGGi_1ZY-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rachael-ren-U94eGGi_1ZY-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rachael-ren-U94eGGi_1ZY-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rachael-ren-U94eGGi_1ZY-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />LSQ: Though the people can see into the future, how alone they all are! Since Kat can’t find the MC in her future, she must not be a part of her life and stops contact. People drift away when they know someone is going to die. Is part of your theme that taking risks into the unknown is a way to bring us together?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Louise: I think Kat’s decision was in some ways an excuse for the inevitable drifting apart of friends after school. It allowed her to make that clean break and to give a reason for it. It also saves a lot of time and effort trying to make a relationship work when someone is no longer a present part of your life. They can look ahead and say that, no, this person isn’t going to be there in the future and it might be worth concentrating my emotional efforts elsewhere. I think it would also be inevitable that some people would want to minimize the grief of losing someone they were close to by making that break earlier and by their own choice. Sad, but inevitable. In the end, Kat was wrong. The main character was in her future. She just didn’t look in the right place and that was the problem, making a decision based solely on her vision of the future rather than the friendship built up in the past.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: In the end, the MC has a different gift, to see into the past, which ends up comforting those who eventually can’t see the future. Tell us more about the connection from the past to the future in your story. Do things apply to our world as well?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Louise: History, particularly social history, is my area of interest but there is a lot of focus on STEM subjects over the arts and humanities in the UK right now. There’s a sense that those more scientifically or technically based subjects are the future and more worthy of investment. So initially, this was simply about the importance of history and studying history. Not just for its useful and direct lessons, but for the interest and joy it brings. I think there are parts of history that are reassuring and helpful. And history obviously has a place in our future, just looking at its use in popular culture and media now. Neither should exclude the other. I would also love to be able to see directly into the past because it would answer so many questions. It might stop a lot of arguing about it!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 047 Author Interview: Amy Bennett and &#8220;Elixir of Life&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-047-author-interview-amy-bennett-and-elixir-of-life/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 047]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In today&#8217;s installment of Issue 047 author interviews, we bring you &#8220;Elixir of Life,&#8221; a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In today&#8217;s installment of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-047/">Issue 047</a> author interviews, we bring you &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/elixir-of-life/">Elixir of Life</a>,&#8221; a detective story set in space! Read on to see where Amy Bennett found her inspiration.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <b>Wow, what a twist! I’m stunned and thrilled in equal measure. I wish the story was longer—I didn’t want to leave this world so soon. Have you written other stories set on Black Agora Space Station?</b></strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26182 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-le-KNQEvvCGoew-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-le-KNQEvvCGoew-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-le-KNQEvvCGoew-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-le-KNQEvvCGoew-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-le-KNQEvvCGoew-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-le-KNQEvvCGoew-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-le-KNQEvvCGoew-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Amy: Thank you! &#8220;Elixir of Life&#8221; was initially meant to be a much bigger story involving more of the struggle between the mafia gangs (that Sergio and Kenji belonged to) and the Titan Corporation for control of the elixir drug. It got a bit complicated, though, so I had to trim it back, otherwise I would’ve definitely blown it out to a novella length. I think I like the ambiguous finality of Carina’s story, though, and I wouldn’t return to the world. But it certainly inspired me to tap into writing more about the stars and spaceships we chase in sci-fi.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <b>You do a great job of creating well-rounded characters in such a tight space. I’d love to know more about them, especially the enigmatic Theia. Which character came to you first as you thought about this story?</b></strong></em></p>
<p>Amy: It was definitely Carina who came to me first. A jaded, tough-talking detective with a penchant for falling for femme fatales—but set in space!—was such a fun idea to play with, and I had her world-weary voice pinned down from the start. There is a formula to private eyes we see in books or movies, so it really was just a process of fleshing her out as someone who lives on Agora. Theia, too, was really quite easy to conceptualize. I liked how little screen time she got. She was equal parts alluring and aloof; something like a dream, or a brief moment of awful clarity, lingering in Carina’s memory.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <b>This story has such a noir feel, and I love your hardboiled detective character. What made you decide to blend noir with science fiction? Did you draw inspiration from any other stories or authors in particular?</b></strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26184 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pylyp-sukhenko-J8s3vPtkjck-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pylyp-sukhenko-J8s3vPtkjck-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pylyp-sukhenko-J8s3vPtkjck-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pylyp-sukhenko-J8s3vPtkjck-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pylyp-sukhenko-J8s3vPtkjck-unsplash-1229x1536.jpg 1229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pylyp-sukhenko-J8s3vPtkjck-unsplash-1638x2048.jpg 1638w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/pylyp-sukhenko-J8s3vPtkjck-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /></p>
<p>Amy: It really came down to what media I was consuming at the time—crime novels and podcasts—and being in a stage of wanting to experiment with writing beyond my usual go-to fantasy. It was just a little glowing ember of inspiration that sparked into life when I was listening to the wry narration of Juno Steel, a Mars-bound private eye, in <i>The Penumbra Podcast</i>. I just hadn’t really entertained the idea of hardboiled crime in a sci-fi setting, or that it could work so well, and I fell right into the secret, mystifying gap between the merging of the two genres. And I don’t think I can ignore the pop culture importance of 1982’s <i>Blade Runner</i>, too, with imprinting such a vivid image of a futuristic world onto me. That kind of revolting harmony between urban and alien settings really helped to work out Black Agora Space Station, create a tone, and develop the world—or universe—beyond it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 047 Author Interview: Ai Jiang and &#8220;Jinli Yu&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-047-author-interview-ai-jiang-and-jinli-yu/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 047]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fear not, dear readers, we still have plenty of Issue 047 author interviews coming your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fear not, dear readers, we still have plenty of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-047/">Issue 047</a> author interviews coming your way! Today we&#8217;re sharing our chat with Ai Jiang, author of &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/jinli-yu/">Jinli Yu</a>,&#8221; about an old favorite: magic!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story has such a beautiful depiction of magic in it, the sort that’s both fantastic and mundane. The scene at the end where all the jinli yu simply climb out of the water and resume their regular lives was poetic. What inspired you to write this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Ai: Thank you so much for your kind words! Lately, I&#8217;ve been taking a greater interest in the myths and legends, along with the folklore of my culture. But not only the stories of the past, I&#8217;ve taken an interest in more contemporary forms of very mythical tales and stories. I&#8217;m a big fan of <i>Big Fish and Begonia</i> and <i>Spirited Away</i> and drew inspiration from these two animations for <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-26146 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/sora-sagano-Dksk8szLRN0-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/sora-sagano-Dksk8szLRN0-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/sora-sagano-Dksk8szLRN0-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/sora-sagano-Dksk8szLRN0-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/sora-sagano-Dksk8szLRN0-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/sora-sagano-Dksk8szLRN0-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />this piece along with myths surrounding the symbolic significance of the jinli yu—koi fish. The ideas of shapeshifters and distant palaces have always lingered in my mind. And I thought I&#8217;d use these imaginings to express the struggles of the mundane.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I really appreciate that the magic in this story is so subtle, which was also how it seemed to me to affect the lives of those who have it. What made you decide to make magic something that wasn’t enough, by itself, to let your characters swim up waterfalls?</strong></em></p>
<p>Ai: I wanted the magic in the story&#8217;s world to appear not as something that offers great powers and strength like in other high fantasy stories but almost as a crutch or escape—a small thing to indulge in that came with consequences and could be as easily taken away as it was given. Although humans are born with, at times, extraordinary skills—or gained them through efforts—appearances, or personalities, society often takes advantage of this—just like how the Huangdi takes advantage of his people&#8217;s jinli magic as a means of control and for his own self agendas given the myths surrounding the good fortune you receive by having jinli yu. Just like in current society, it isn&#8217;t enough to rely solely on certain &#8220;skills&#8221; to get by in life—will, determination, understanding are things we all need to make meaning in this life. For us to overcome barriers both mental and physical, it begins not with magic but with our mundane selves. In the story, to swim up a waterfall, it&#8217;s important to understand what you are and what you are not, along with your duties and responsibilities, even under oppression. For the characters in this world, rebellion is not the key.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your ability to build a fascinating world in few words is impressive. This story feels wonderfully complete, but at the same time I’d love to know more. Have you considered revisiting this? Would you write more about the jinli yu, or perhaps about Huangdi?</strong></em></p>
<p>Ai: I really love this world, and the story is but a fleeting gaze into it. I definitely have considered revisiting the world and perhaps writing a story that is set from the inside of the palace, featuring those who stand above the jinli yu, always looking down. Perhaps what they truly feel is envy for the common people&#8217;s magic where the wealthy only have their riches as their &#8220;magic&#8221; or power, to speak bluntly? Until then, I&#8217;ll allow the world to continue brewing in my mind, and hopefully it will come alive on published pages in the future.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 047 Author Interview: Olga Kolesnikova and &#8220;The Silent Decades&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-047-author-interview-olga-kolesnikova-and-the-silent-decades/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 047]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just can&#8217;t get enough of our Issue 047 author interviews? Neither can we! Today we&#8217;re&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just can&#8217;t get enough of our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-047/">Issue 047</a> author interviews? Neither can we! Today we&#8217;re bringing you Olga Kolesnikova&#8217;s answers to our burning questions about their story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-silent-decades/">The Silent Decades</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I love reading stories in different formats from the norm, and these have got to be the most fascinating endnotes ever. How did you decide on this format?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26140 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-kelley-hHL08lF7Ikc-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-kelley-hHL08lF7Ikc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-kelley-hHL08lF7Ikc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-kelley-hHL08lF7Ikc-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-kelley-hHL08lF7Ikc-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/thomas-kelley-hHL08lF7Ikc-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Olga: I wrote this story for my university course; the assignment was (surprise, surprise) to tell a story in an unusual format. Studying literary theory involves poring over endnotes and compiling bibliographies, and that’s what gave me the idea. I liked the challenge of telling a speculative story through this seemingly dry format. In fact, it seemed so dry that when I shared the idea with my supervisor, he doubted that it could work. I’m glad I believed in it enough to do it anyway!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Did the format influence the decision of what kind of story to tell, or did you have the story idea percolating and think of the unique format as a secondary consideration?</strong></em></p>
<p>Olga: The format came first. Once I decided to use a bibliography of some kind to tell a story, I looked at the endnotes in random books at the library for inspiration. Reading only the endnotes of history books left me with these strange, fragmented impressions of the past events the books were describing. I was inspired to create something similar, but with events from both the past and the imagined future.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I wish I could read that Rosie Sherwood book now. What was the hardest part about telling this story? Do you have a favorite endnote?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26141 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rey-seven-_nm_mZ4Cs2I-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rey-seven-_nm_mZ4Cs2I-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rey-seven-_nm_mZ4Cs2I-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rey-seven-_nm_mZ4Cs2I-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rey-seven-_nm_mZ4Cs2I-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/rey-seven-_nm_mZ4Cs2I-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Olga: It would definitely be fascinating to read “a new literary genre”! The hardest part would have to be the research I had to do for Part 1 of the story. Many of these first notes allude to real events, and I wanted to make sure I had the facts right and that the events appeared in mostly chronological order. But adding fictional future commentary to these factual events was a lot of fun! It was also difficult to decide whether or not to refer to the near future, as this could potentially lessen the story’s impact for anyone reading it in a few years – but then I thought about <em>1984</em> and <em>2001: A Space Odyssey</em>. As for a favorite endnote, I’d have to go with 34, because it might be the creepiest one!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 047 Author Interview: Jennifer Lee Rossman and &#8220;The Good Girl&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-047-author-interview-jennifer-lee-rossman-and-the-good-girl/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 11:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 047]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s Issue 047 author interview is both seasonally appropriate and gender explorative! Pull up a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-047/">Issue 047</a> author interview is both seasonally appropriate and gender explorative! Pull up a chair with us as we talk with Jennifer Lee Rossman about &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-good-girl/">The Good Girl</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Wow, this packs so much emotion into such a short space! I love how “good girl” comes to mean so many different things, and the way the vampire transformation varies so much depending on who’s turned. What gave you the idea for this story?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26069 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sammy-williams-HvqKdTFLkfw-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sammy-williams-HvqKdTFLkfw-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sammy-williams-HvqKdTFLkfw-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sammy-williams-HvqKdTFLkfw-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sammy-williams-HvqKdTFLkfw-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sammy-williams-HvqKdTFLkfw-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sammy-williams-HvqKdTFLkfw-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Jennifer: Questions like these always make me laugh because I want to give you some deep and profound answer… but really, it was <a href="https://twitter.com/jenlrossman/status/1255576896169000960?s=21">a joke I made on Twitter</a> about how the Tom Petty song &#8220;Free Fallin’&#8221; is about a transgender vampire.</p>
<div dir="auto">The main character in the music video never ages, even though it seems like decades have passed based on clothing styles. And while you see the reflection of the &#8220;good girl&#8221; in the photo at the beginning, you never see Tom Petty&#8217;s reflection even though he&#8217;s around a lot of glass and mirrors, which made me think the vampires mentioned in one line could be literal, not metaphorical. Once the &#8220;good girl&#8221; starts hanging out with them, dressing more androgynously, that’s when &#8220;she&#8221; got bit, realized he was a bad boy all along, and began his transition into the transmasculine person played by Tom Petty.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: This is a perfect example of how a main character doesn’t need a name or detailed physical description to still be intriguing and impactful. How much do you know about this bad boy, and how did you decide how much to share?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">
<p>Jennifer: I know absolutely as much as I wrote.</p>
<div dir="auto">Songs are a different kind of storytelling than traditional fiction writing, but they still manage to convey all the information you need with far fewer words than most authors would need to do the same. I think going into a story with the intention of matching it with a song, it lets the brain forget about explaining and describing.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Songs don&#8217;t tend to give you backstory. They just drop you in and tell you some pretty words that make you feel things. This story did that to me; just gave me some pretty words without much explanation as to what happened before or after.</div>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: Could you see yourself turning this short story into a longer exploration of this character and world?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26070 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/arun-sharma-9hyAUSKrfEg-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/arun-sharma-9hyAUSKrfEg-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/arun-sharma-9hyAUSKrfEg-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/arun-sharma-9hyAUSKrfEg-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/arun-sharma-9hyAUSKrfEg-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/arun-sharma-9hyAUSKrfEg-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/arun-sharma-9hyAUSKrfEg-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></div>
<div dir="auto">
<p>Jennifer: Maybe not this character or this world specifically, but I’m always ready to explore gender via monster stories.</p>
<div dir="auto">I’ve recently been able to finally put words to the way I’ve felt all my life, and I have realized I am nonbinary. I often call myself a guy because that’s the easiest way to describe it, but it&#8217;s more of a fluid thing that spends a lot of time on the masculine side but still dips towards the feminine side. And when you&#8217;re like me, comfortable in both worlds but knowing you’re still not entirely from either, that lends itself to a lot of monster allegories. I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if I write more stories about bad boys who thought they were good girls, good girls who knew they were never bad boys but didn&#8217;t know how to change, and those people in the middle who are good and bad and neither.</div>
</div>
<div dir="auto">
<div dir="auto"></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
