<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sarah McGill &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/sarahsarahmcgillwrites-com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 16:33:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>On Breaking Rules: The Inciting Incident</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-breaking-rules-the-inciting-incident/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah McGill]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On Breaking Rules]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The inciting incident is about as basic as it gets. Something or someone has to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The inciting incident is about as basic as it gets. Something or someone has to drag our protagonist out the door kicking and screaming and send them on their adventure. <em>The Hobbit</em> is the example par excellence: Bilbo is content to live in his hobbit hole forever, to never see the wider world or engage in its politics. But then Gandalf arrives with a pack of dwarves and insists Bilbo adventure with the dwarves whether he likes it or not, and he very much does not. The inciting incident is often called ‘crossing the threshold’ and that’s exactly what Bilbo does. He crosses the threshold out of his cozy, familiar world and into the much scarier world of dragons and dwarves and magic. The inciting incident is necessary because stories are about change and conflict. The protagonist must leave the normal world to go on a journey, either physical or metaphorical. The slice of life genre can most easily justify forgoing the inciting incident because they’re about life, where boundaries and change aren’t as clearly delineated. But there’s still usually some change, like the appearance of new characters in <em>Pride and Prejudice</em> or the death in <em>Thirteen Reasons Why</em> or someone vanishing in <em>Paper Towns</em> or a move in <em>Anne of Green Gables</em>. However, <em>The Memory Police</em> by Yōko Ogawa, as a book about inescapable and oppressive forces, forgoes the inciting incident entirely.</p>
<p>From the book jacket:</p>
<blockquote><p>On an unnamed island off an unnamed coast, objects are disappearing: first hats, then ribbons, birds, roses—until things become much more serious. Most of the island&#8217;s inhabitants are oblivious to these changes, while those few imbued with the power to recall the lost objects live in fear of the draconian Memory Police, who are committed to ensuring that what has disappeared remains forgotten.</p></blockquote>
<p>The novel begins as the unnamed protagonist – later a novelist – listens as her mother shows her disappeared objects. The novelist doesn’t understand these objects, but they’re clearly significant to her mother. The relative safety and slight confusion of childhood could be ‘the normal world’ that the novelist later leaves – entering a dangerous but predictable world – but there’s no divide between this moment and the rest of the book, except that of the time between childhood and adulthood. While the situation does become increasingly dangerous, the novelist’s childhood wasn’t particularly safe, as we learn later, and she never fully understands the disappearances. Instead, this world is the world, the only world.</p>
<p>In the second chapter, her parents are dead, but the deaths aren’t framed as particularly momentous. It’s only another sort of disappearance. Similarly, the disappearance of birds, the first disappearance we see on the page, isn’t particularly significant. In fact, for most people, the disappearances are distinctly insignificant. These drastic changes, which often cost people their pets, jobs, and precious memories, mean almost nothing. The characters breeze over them, disposing of the offending items, and then move on.</p>
<p><a href="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/memory-police.webp"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-26214 alignleft" src="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/memory-police.webp" alt="" width="191" height="293" /></a>The novelist lives in the world as it is and has always been, a world ruled by a fascist law so ubiquitous that arbitrary disappearances are not ordered by a faceless government, but stitched into the very fabric of the world. That world is suffocating and inescapable – quite literally, as they live on an island where the ferry is long since disappeared – and yet expected. It would be counter to the point for a specific event to force the novelist to deal with the world she’s already living in. The death of the novelist’s parents could’ve been an inciting incident, spurring her on to take action against the dictatorship of the world’s magic system, but they don’t because at no point does the novelist fight back. Her editor will eventually press her to fight back, but she never does. She is, in fact, incapable of doing so. She was born into this world and doesn’t know how to fight against it because she doesn’t know what else the world could look like.</p>
<p>There is no inciting incident because <em>The Memory Police</em> is about the customs and cultures of our world that we never considered problematic, but simply go along with day by day. It’s about oppressive forces that are so unquestioned we see them as laws of reality and, honestly, find them easy to live with, no matter how they wear us away. There is no moment that drags us into those forces; we already live in them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Breaking Rules: The Rules of Magic</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-breaking-rules-the-rules-of-magic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah McGill]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 11:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On Breaking Rules]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25854</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Brandon Sanderson has three laws of magic. The first is: An author’s ability to solve&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brandon Sanderson has three laws of magic. The first is: <em>An author’s ability to solve conflict with magic is directly proportional to how well the reader understands said magic.</em> This means a few things, which you can read more about <a href="https://www.brandonsanderson.com/sandersons-first-law/">here</a>, but I’m focusing on two aspects: magic has rules and magic is used to create problems, not solve them. This way we don’t end up in a Marvel-esque deus ex machina where suddenly our hero is extremely overpowered and disproportional to what we’ve seen previously. To give an example, and a spoiler for <em>Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them</em>, at the end of the movie, our heroes memory-wipe the entirety of New York with a small magic vial. It was frustrating because it felt lazy, boring, and overpowered and it was never established that you could do that to that scale. But most importantly, it was no more and no less <img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-25879 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/unicorn-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/unicorn-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/unicorn.jpg 315w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" />than an easy fix to a difficult problem. There’s no story to it, no examination of the effect wizards have on everyday people or what it means to have to keep your existence so secret. An example like this shows us that rules are very important. But let’s break them anyway. At the midpoint of <em>The Last Unicorn</em>, Peter Beagle breaks his magic system and does so in order to solve a problem.</p>
<p>From the book jacket:</p>
<blockquote><p>The unicorn had lived since before memory in a forest where death could touch nothing. But outside her wondrous realm, dark whispers and rumors carried a message she could not ignore: &#8220;Unicorns are gone from the world.&#8221; Aided by Schmendrick, a bumbling magician, and Molly, an indomitable spinster, she set out to learn the truth.</p></blockquote>
<p>At the midpoint of <em>The Last Unicorn</em>, the unicorn is being pursued by a surreal, fairy-tale caricature, the Red Bull. The wizard Schmendrick has very little control over his magic, and although he’s done one great feat of magic previously, there’s little rhyme or reason to when he’s able to tap into it. Yet now, desperately trying to help, he saves the last unicorn from the Red Bull by turning her into a human.</p>
<p>It is, in many ways, a deus ex machina. It’s a grand act of magic that saves the day, and not by any skill or rules, but because the plot demands it. His magic should be boring. And yet it’s wondrous and mysterious and fascinating.</p>
<p>The characters in <em>The Last Unicorn</em> spend a lot of time escaping bad predicaments, but they escape because people are too caught up in fake fantasies to see the real fantasy in front of them. The fantasies aren’t fun or even satisfying. A sense of foreboding hangs over everything and more and more it seems like escape isn’t worth it, like the unicorn never should’ve left her cozy forest in the first place.</p>
<p>Successes in <em>The Last Unicorn</em> are not cause for celebration. They are almost always sad affairs. The potential for success is always mired in the fear of failure. The joy of success is always tempered by the knowledge that you won’t be successful forever; you’ll have to keep going, you’ll get old, you’ll fail. During the encounter with the Red Bull, in solving the problem, Schmendrick’s magic creates many others. Namely, it sends the unicorn into an identity crisis where she nearly loses herself, her memory, and her purpose. For a while it seems he should have left her to the Bull, who at least who’ve allowed her to keep her form when he imprisoned her. What is the use in succeeding, it asks, if you have to change? Why not stay trapped, and the same, forever? Why not fall into the fake fantasy of an identity that never has to change or question its values, but rather can stay permanent forever?</p>
<p>Schmendrick’s magic works here because it creates story, and indeed raises necessary questions about the unicorn’s quest and decision to continue the quest at all. For all that Schmendrick saves the day, deus-ex-machina-style, it’s not a simple fix. It’s a fix that challenges the unicorn’s whole identity. In becoming a human, she has to engage with the impermanence and fleeting nature of humanity. She has to wonder what it is to feel love, to grow old, to die. She, who has always been at a distance, always removed in the woods, immortal and unconcerned, is brought close to the tragedy and triumph and roller coaster of existence. She has to decide if, after all the grief and love and banality, it’s worth saving the unicorns. If it’s worth, indeed, going on at all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Breaking Rules: Dark Night of the Soul</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-breaking-rules-dark-night-of-the-soul/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah McGill]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On Breaking Rules]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The caped defender broods on a rooftop. The alcohol-sodden cop returns to his bottles. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22752 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/window-5850628_1920-300x257.png" alt="" width="300" height="257" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/window-5850628_1920-300x257.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/window-5850628_1920-1024x876.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/window-5850628_1920-768x657.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/window-5850628_1920-1536x1314.png 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/window-5850628_1920.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><em>The caped defender broods on a rooftop. The alcohol-sodden cop returns to his bottles. The hero finds themselves alone. Everyone is dead. All is lost.</em> This is dark night of the soul, the last fall before the climax, and it is here to make the climax feel impressive and big and hard-won. Before the climax, a moment is needed when everything falls apart and our heroes return to their old vices so that finally, one last time, they can overcome them. They are most obvious in superhero movies. The ending of <em>Avengers: Infinity War</em> and beginning of <em>Avengers: Endgame</em> is really one big dark night of the soul, before the final triumph. But what if there is no triumph? What if no one learns anything? Such is exactly the case in <em>Thoroughbreds</em>, which doesn’t have, even can’t have, that moment.</p>
<p><em>Thoroughbreds</em> follows posh, upper-class high-schooler Lily, who strives to be as perfect as the multi-million dollar home she lives in, and her friend Amanda, whose lack of emotion quickly pegs her as a sociopath, as they scheme to kill Lily&#8217;s stepfather. I’ve seen it described as <em>American Psycho</em> meets <em>Heathers</em>, which feels like a pretty apt description. The movie’s tone is often flat, emotionless, and removed, and over the course of the film it asks us to consider: What does it really mean to be a sociopath?</p>
<p>I’m going to spoil this movie right up to the climax, so be warned. It seems obvious that Amanda will be pushing the murder. She suggests it in the first place, she brutally killed a horse, and she’s a sociopath. Lily, on the other hand, is normal, relatable, in a restricting and unpleasant family situation that garners her our sympathy. But over the course of the movie, it becomes clear that there’s more than one way to be a sociopath. Amanda may not care if Lily’s step-father is dead, but she wants Lily to kill him “because it’s the right thing to do,” not just because Lily’s upset. It turns out Amanda killed the horse because its leg was broken and her mother wouldn’t pay a vet to do it properly. Amanda had to do it. It was the right thing to do. Lily, however, has no empathy. It is, ironically, her stepfather, obnoxious, misogynistic, controlling, who understands best: “Because in your brain, all these people are just little offshoots of your consciousness. Just little helpers put there to give you things and to bolster your confidence. We’re all your maids, aren’t we? Your cleaning ladies. Your personal trainers.”</p>
<p>Which brings us to the climax. Amanda and Lily have failed to hire someone to kill Lily’s stepfather and after Lily’s step-father berates her, Amanda agrees with him: “I wouldn’t say empathy is your strongest suit…You’re just not a very considerate person.” In a different movie, this could be the dark night of the soul. No longer are the insults coming from an asshole we can ignore, but from a trusted confidant and friend. Lily must, terrifyingly, confront her worst flaws. But that’s not what happens. The tone is so flat that it doesn’t seem to really matter. It feels small. And, really, the critique isn’t coming from a trusted confidant because that would require Lily to see Amanda as a friend, instead of a tool.</p>
<p>But we’re not at the climax yet. Maybe there’s a dark night of the soul in the next scene. As Amanda and Lily watch a movie, Lily asks, “Do you remember that stuff you were saying to Tim the other day?…That stuff about how his life isn’t worth living?…Do you ever ask that question about yourself?…If you can’t feel anything. Like even happiness or…” She pauses, realizes how awful the question sounds, and apologizes. Again, this could be a devastating moment, a moment where Lily looks at Amanda’s shock and sees herself, sees how she’s betrayed her friend by viewing her life as worthless because it’s not like her own. Or Amanda could call her out and storm away. But Amanda, after a brief moment of thought, isn’t upset. She says she hadn’t thought about it. In the next moment, Lily admits that she drugged Amanda’s juice and intended to frame Amanda for killing her step-father. There’s another pause, a moment where it’s so tempting to read devastation in Amanda’s face, and then Amanda drinks her juice and settles in, <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22754 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/calm-2315559_1920-300x198.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="198" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/calm-2315559_1920-300x198.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/calm-2315559_1920-1024x677.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/calm-2315559_1920-768x508.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/calm-2315559_1920-1536x1016.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/calm-2315559_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />claiming she is only a skilled imitator at friendship – though of course it is Lily who is only imitating friendship. While Amanda’s line of dialogue suggests some wallowing, maybe even guilt, or at the very least some short-sightedness, it isn’t a reflection, a moment of loss and growth. It doesn’t spark something in Lily. Nothing has changed.</p>
<p>The closest moment we get to the dark night of the soul is actually after the climax, when it’s far too late. After killing her step-father, Lily smears blood on Amanda’s arm and face, and then climbs onto the couch, pulling Amanda’s arm around her. Her breath hitches, and she squeezes Amanda’s hand, but there is no comfort to be had. There never was because Amanda can only act out comfort. She can’t cradle Lily and feel her pain. And from Lily there is no true vulnerability, no possibility of change, because she’s only able to open up when she knows Amanda can’t see it.</p>
<p>There is no dark night of the soul because no one cares enough to be hurt. Neither can lose everything because they have no one to lose. They could have. Amanda could have built a friendship out of trust, mutual interest, acceptance, things other than emotions. Lily could have tried to understand Amanda, instead of filing her away as emotionless, and therefore meaningless and easy to betray. But in the end they don’t care about what they lost because their friendship is ultimately what they hold most dear, which isn’t saying very much at all.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Breaking Rules: The Debate</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-breaking-rules-the-debate/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-breaking-rules-the-debate/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah McGill]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On Breaking Rules]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a strong supporter of “learn the rules so you can break them,” I’m back&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a strong supporter of “learn the rules so you can break them,” I’m back to break more rules! This time, we’re talking about The Debate and how to (not) use it in your story. So let’s say <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18771 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/girl-111693_1920-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/girl-111693_1920-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/girl-111693_1920-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/girl-111693_1920-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/girl-111693_1920-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/girl-111693_1920.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />you’ve established <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-breaking-rules-the-normal-world/">The Normal World</a> and told us everything we need to know about our hero. Now it’s time to get to the action. The hero is called. Find the treasure! Save the world! Learn the true meaning of friendship!</p>
<p>But wait! Does the hero really want to go on this adventure?</p>
<p>This is The Debate. The Debate is when the hero turns the adventure down. The retired cop walks away from the case. The washed-up gunslinger tells the naive greenhorn to get lost. Frodo tells Gandalf to take the ring back. Our hero rejects the story.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll tell you a secret. This is one of my least favorite beats, because it&#8217;s often very repetitive. The hero is given an offer, they refuse, and then they show up on the job anyway. After all, if they didn&#8217;t, we&#8217;d have no story. Even if they do some soul searching, it often hits the same beats: do I continue with the status quo or &#8220;do the right thing&#8221;?</p>
<p>But that doesn’t mean The Debate can’t be done well. In China Miéville’s <em>Kraken</em>, a giant squid is stolen from a local museum and Billy, one of the employees, refuses to help the police. He rejects the story. And as is often the case when the hero keeps saying ‘no,’ something grabs them by the ankles and hauls them into the story kicking and screaming. Billy is kidnapped. But what I really like about <em>Kraken</em> is that Billy doesn’t end up joining the police. Someone else shows up with a far more compelling argument, so Billy joins them instead. He enters the story, but not in the way we expected.</p>
<p>In <em>The Haunting of Hill House</em>, Shirley Jackson initially replaces The Debate with an external conflict. Eleanor is invited to Hill House, but her sister won’t let her take the car. In their argument we learn how much Eleanor has been beaten down by her family, but her unwavering decision to take the car also shows how fiercely she needs to go. But she does have a debate nonetheless, a little later. As she drives up to the house, she thinks, almost unwillingly, as if the sight of the house has induced panic, “Why am I here?” When nearly turned away at the gate, she thinks, “I&#8217;m being given a last chance. I could turn my car around right here and now in front of these gates and go away from here, and no one would blame me.&#8221; Her internal debate, the use of ‘last chance,’ creates a sense of foreboding, of something coming that Eleanor could have escaped if she&#8217;d only taken the chance.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18772 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/grass-1209945_1280-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/grass-1209945_1280-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/grass-1209945_1280-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/grass-1209945_1280-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/grass-1209945_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />But what if the hero is raring to go? What if it makes no sense for them to doubt their decision? Really, as is true of most writing, the cardinal sin is being boring. This beat is here to create conflict and conflict is interesting, especially the warring emotions of a conflicted protagonist. But it isn’t the only way make a story interesting.</p>
<p><em>The Monster of Elendhaven</em> by Jennifer Giesbrecht relies on tension and vivid imagery to make the call to action interesting. In the opening chapters, a street-ruffian, Johann, pulls a knife on a sorcerer, Florian, and tells Florian to hire him. Johann doesn’t mull over his decisions, not even later when Florian tells him his vindictive plans. Johann is bold, rash, a casual murderer, and a self-identified monster. Rarely does he think twice. In addition, the scene is already interesting. Florian is terrified yet unflappable, an intriguing combination, and we don’t know what he’s capable of as a sorcerer. The scene has the classic push and pull. Johann wants Florian to hire him; Florian doesn’t want to hire him. And the scene climaxes when Johann takes a knife to his own throat and slits it open, only for the skin to knit itself together. The scene is tense, visceral, and it makes us want to know what will happen next.</p>
<p>At a more practical level, <em>The Monster of Elendhaven</em> is fairly short, some 120 pages. Shorter books frequently cut out beats (most frequently the turn at the midpoint) because works of that length don’t need as many beats. Constantly swiveling back and forth would create confusion and trip up the pacing. Novellas and middle-grade books tend to work with more straightforward stories that move at a jaunty pace and without a great deal of unnecessary detail (although I can think of exceptions, notably Catherynne Valente’s <em>Speak Easy</em>). Finally, as we learn at the end of the book, Johann was created out of Florian’s childhood grief and need. Johann is enthralled to Florian. He’s tied up with this man and cannot leave him. Doubting Florian or flinching away from him would be out of keeping with both the magic system and the intertwined, vicious nature of their relationship.</p>
<p>The Debate is a great way to create conflict and it can give us insights into our hero. It can be a moment for a character to prepare to face the coming challenge, or run from it. But not all characters have reason to shy from the adventure. Some of them want it more than anything and they will run into the fray without a second thought. In the end, this is a turning point for your character and the goal is to tell us something about the hero in an interesting way. When faced with the story, what do they do? And what does it tell us about them?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-breaking-rules-the-debate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
