<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>We Have Always Lived in the Citadel &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/we-have-always-lived-in-the-citadel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 01:47:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Hugos, Puppies, and Joanna Russ</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hugos-puppies-and-joanna-russ/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sara Amis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 17:24:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[We Have Always Lived in the Citadel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4258</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;It is a traditional and widely held Glotolog belief that the behavior and outward appearance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>&#8220;It is a traditional and widely held Glotolog belief that the behavior and outward appearance of the Spotty, Crescent-finned, Spiny, and Mottled Glotolog&#8211;as well as their relative non-success at the practice of <em>frument</em>&#8212;indicate that the central essence (or <em>nerd</em>) of these types differs from that of the Whelk-finned Glotolog, whose superior essence (<em>super-nerd</em>) enables it to constitute not only the artistic but also the social and economic aristocracy of the planet and thereby to enjoy advantages too numerous and varied to be listed here.</p>
<p>Needless to say, Intergalactic science has found among these typically self-deluded brachiopods only the usual minor differences, reproductive and chromatic, which have little direct bearing on behavior and certainly not the overwhelming importance ascribed to them by the Glotolog.&#8221; &#8211;from <em>How to Suppress Women&#8217;s Writing</em> by Joanna Russ</p></blockquote>
<p>I always intended from the beginning to write about Joanna Russ. How could I not? It just so happens, though, that she is particularly relevant right at this particular moment.</p>
<p>So, there are some shenanigans with this year&#8217;s Hugo awards. And by &#8220;shenanigans&#8221; I mean &#8220;cheating&#8221; in the finest, most self-righteous, letter-but-not-the-spirit-of-the-law, but-really-we&#8217;re-the-good-guys fashion.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;But some white women, and black women, and black men, and other people of color too, have actually acquired the nasty habit of putting the stuff on paper, and some of it gets printed, and printed material, especially books, gets into bookstores, into people&#8217;s hands, into libraries, sometimes even into university curricula.</p>
<p>What are we to do?&#8221; &#8212;-from <em>How to Suppress Women&#8217;s Writing</em> by Joanna Russ</p></blockquote>
<p>I might add, some of it gets nominated for Hugos, and even wins. <em>What are we to do???</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why I Don&#8217;t Dig the Singularity</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/why-i-dont-dig-the-singularity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sara Amis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 07:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[We Have Always Lived in the Citadel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I think that&#8217;s sort of Kurzweil&#8217;s vision — that we&#8217;ll be able to make our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>&#8220;I think that&#8217;s sort of Kurzweil&#8217;s vision — that we&#8217;ll be able to make our fantasies real. Why would you actually need another human being?&#8221; &#8211; Joe Quirk</p></blockquote>
<p>I was thinking about technology and the soul, recently. (Doesn&#8217;t everyone?) Which led to a story idea. Which led, inevitably, to research. I decided I needed to read up on the Singularity, which at its simplest is the idea that at some point technological and cultural change will become so rapid that there will come a point in history after which humans will become unrecognizable&#8230;a metaphorical cultural-historical event horizon. I don&#8217;t necessarily think the idea of the Singularity is wrong or impossible, and it may indeed be inevitable; serious expansion into space, or other strategies of long-term survival, may require adaptations that will indeed make our descendants very, very different from us. However, a kind of gee-whiz wannabe-post-human subculture has grown up around the idea of the Singularity as both absolutely inevitable and (mostly) unquestionably awesome. To catalogue all of my objections would require a book, but suffice it to say that I do not agree with many of the underlying assumptions I am seeing in that subculture; I find them either philosophically objectionable or simply factually wrong.</p>
<p>A good example of the kind of thing I&#8217;m speaking of is <a href="http://www.10zenmonkeys.com/2007/01/19/joe-quirk-author-singularity-sociobiology-sex/">&#8220;Why Chicks Don&#8217;t Dig the Singularity,&#8221;</a> an interview with Joe Quirk by RU Sirius. Points for the title (got my attention, didn&#8217;t it?) but the interview is so full of earnest, face-palmy foolishness (&#8220;There&#8217;s not a big female fan base for science fiction, right?&#8221;) it&#8217;s hard to see past it. I&#8217;ve come to think of evolutionary psychology as a logical fallacy masquerading as a field of study, and Mr. Quirk writes books on the subject; consequently the interview is full of pronouncements such as, &#8220;Women are early adopters of youth technology in terms of looks,&#8221; and &#8220;[women] want to get together at lunch with their friends and make eye contact and stand way too close to each other.&#8221; The problem there (and with evo psych in general) is not the observation; the problem is with the assumptions about <em>why</em>. It requires an utter disregard for the mountains of evidence that our brains and even physiology are actually pretty plastic, and an insistence on biology-is-destiny reification of gendered cultural behavior&#8230;all of which, Pangloss-like, serves to justify the status quo which conveniently enough favors men. Who are, I have to point out, the majority of evolutionary psychologists. Not because of any glass ceiling or gender bias in the field, of course, but because men evolved to hunt and think abstractly and women evolved to&#8230;oh, Jesus.</p>
<p>The most insightful comment in the whole thing is this: &#8220;I think male geeks in the futurist community assume that human nature is the same as the nature of male geeks in the futurist community. And it&#8217;s kind of become a little religion; we have our own Rapture and our own eschatology and all that sort of stuff. But I think the idea of merging with machine intelligence is not appealing to lots of different kinds of people.&#8221; This, I agree with. I would only add that it is possible that the disconnect between what male geeks in the futurist community believe about human nature and what the rest of humanity responds to is so wide because male geeks in the futurist community are simply wrong about human nature&#8230;including their own.</p>
<p><em>Human beings</em> are social animals. <em>Human beings</em> have a psychological and even physical need for direct contact that social interactions mediated by the Internet or similarly attenuating technology cannot (at this stage, and probably ever) fulfill. The fact that some people seem to think that they can get along fine without it is a kind of Platonic-dualism-induced hallucination, a desire to believe that they are &#8220;really&#8221; a refined intellect separate from and superior to the grunting, sweating, soft and breakable human body that lives, eats, emotes and defecates in meatspace. This fundamental mistake&#8230;that the mind and body are somehow separate&#8230;is arguably the big lie of Western culture. It&#8217;s also, not coincidentally, the basis for all hierarchies. Mind over body, civilization over nature&#8230;men over women. To the extent that women are somehow inherently inoculated against this particular delusion, it is because the facts of reproduction tie us to our mortal bodies by necessity more than men generally are, and also because those hierarchies rarely if ever work in our favor. But the reason men <em>in particular</em> are encouraged to think of their identities as essential and separate from their bodies is cultural, not biological.</p>
<p>A related, immediate, and serious objection is that while most of geek culture gives lip service to democracy, in practice many if not most online and geeky spaces are dominated by white middle-class men and boys&#8230;that is, they are kyriarchal and exclusionary. The more anonymous and removed from the possibility of face-to-face interaction the online space is, the more brutally the unspoken exclusionary rules are enforced. The mild end of the scale is micro-aggressions and relative status; the extreme end includes threats of real-world violence including rape. I see absolutely no reason to think that the magic of more and better technology will solve this problem, because the problem again isn&#8217;t technical, it is cultural. Even talking about it meets with a sullen wall of resistance.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the real reason I don&#8217;t dig the singularity: The mind and body are not in fact separate. Our consciousness is created by and inseparable from the structure of our brains, the input of our senses, the subtle and complex interactions with our biochemistry, our bodies as a whole. You cannot upload your consciousness to anywhere, because the process of doing so will change it fundamentally. At best, you could create a different being with some memories that resemble those of a human being (though even they will not be the same). But this is not, as some would have it, a road to immortality. The original human being will still be just as dead.</p>
<p>I can always be wrong, of course. But the other possibility&#8230;that our consciousness and will are actually separable from our bodied selves&#8230;means something <em>other than</em> the brain and body has to be at work, a notion that does not square with the materialism from which the notion of the Singularity sprung. It requires a mechanism that we do not understand and cannot perceive&#8230;that is, for lack of a better word, a soul. Now, I&#8217;m not against the idea of souls. I&#8217;m not even against the idea of machines having them; most days I am an animist. I do however emphatically think that souls are not logically consistent with a world view that posits a technological Singularity, and therefore the movement as a whole has a giant ineluctable blind spot. Not its only one, as I&#8217;ve mentioned. But when you&#8217;ve got a problem with the implications of your own metaphysics, what then?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday, Virginia Woolf</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-virginia-woolf/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sara Amis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 21:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[We Have Always Lived in the Citadel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;They published your diary And that&#8217;s how I got to know you The key to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>&#8220;They published your diary<br />
And that&#8217;s how I got to know you<br />
The key to the room of your own and a mind without end<br />
And here&#8217;s a young girl<br />
On a kind of a telephone line through time<br />
And the voice at the other end comes like a long lost friend&#8221;<br />
&#8211; &#8220;Virginia Woolf,&#8221; by the Indigo Girls</p></blockquote>
<p>I confess I was not a fan of Virginia Woolf as a young person. I first encountered her in the form of being assigned to read <em>Mrs. Dalloway</em> as a freshman in college. I was a baby feminist who had read Simone de Beauvoir and Gloria Steinem in high school and was in the middle of finding out that attending a women&#8217;s college was not the glorious experience I had led myself to expect; you might be excused for thinking that I would be an easy mark. But no. It might have had something to do with my professor, who later gave me a D for being a Cleopatra apologist, but in any case I can&#8217;t remember one single thing about the book except a general feeling of frustration and that the eponymous character was trying to throw a party.</p>
<p>Some years later however, I read &#8220;A Room of One&#8217;s Own&#8221; and was charmed. I read &#8220;Professions for Women&#8221; and laughed out loud (&#8220;What could be easier than to write articles and to buy Persian cats with the profits?&#8221;) She was droll, she was clever, she was interesting. She advocated independence for women writers, both intellectual and practical; to be honest I could have used some of her advice earlier in my life.</p>
<p>And then I read <em>Orlando,</em> the story of a four hundred year old gender-shapeshifting noble who has adventures including sword fights, lost loves, traveling with gypsies, and writing a masterpiece which takes centuries to finally complete. But wait, there&#8217;s more:  It was partially based on the life of her lover, Vita Sackville-West, who sounds like a hell of a lot of fun. <em>Orlando</em> is alternately dreamlike and funny, often both at once, and is a book every writer should read&#8230;for many reasons, not least of which is this:</p>
<blockquote><p>Anyone moderately familiar with the rigours of composition will not need to be told the story in detail; how he wrote and it seemed good; read and it seemed vile; corrected and tore up; cut out; put in; was in ecstasy; in despair; had his good nights and bad mornings; snatched at ideas and lost them; saw his book plain before him and it vanished; acted his people&#8217;s parts as he ate; mouthed them as he walked; now cried; now laughed; vacillated between this style and that; now preferred the heroic and pompous; next the plain and simple; now the vales of Tempe; then the fields of Kent or Cornwall; and could not decide whether he was the divinest genius or the greatest fool in the world.</p></blockquote>
<p>Any time I feel like a complete idiot, or despair of ever actually finishing one of the multiple absurd writing projects I have going at any given time (including a completed fantasy novel which needs to be rewritten because it stinks, and one-third of a science fiction novel which is only slightly smelly, plus a variable number of half-written short stories and non-fiction articles which threaten to grow into books I have no time to write), I reread this and think to myself, &#8220;Virginia Woolf is considered one of the greatest writers of the 20th century. And yet she absolutely knew what it was like to flail.&#8221; Not that the reverse is implied; flailing does not prove merit. But as comfort it will suffice.</p>
<p>She also wrote a historical fantasy novel. I mean, there&#8217;s no other way to describe it honestly. There&#8217;s a historical setting, a fictional character who interacts in various ways with real historical figures including Elizabeth I and Alexander Pope, and fantastic elements. You could call it magical realism but that&#8217;s just quibbling; such definitions are sometimes useful to marketing executives and literature professors but rarely are to writers. I attended a panel on magical realism at an Association of Writing Programs conference a few years ago in Chicago. As one of the panelists said, &#8220;I thought I was a realist, and then things got weird.&#8221; Virginia Woolf was not afraid to get weird.</p>
<p>I think those of us who write speculative fiction&#8230;and those of us who are women or members of any other marginalized group&#8230;need to remember that. Writing from the margins is always a struggle, but it&#8217;s an essential struggle, and any phantasms which appear and tell you that you aren&#8217;t worthy deserve an ink-pot to the head. Roaming about in the world one sometimes encounters the attitude that there&#8217;s such a thing as &#8220;genre fiction,&#8221; which includes everything from romance (but not the Romantics&#8230;or Jane Austen, for some reason) to &#8220;Sci Fi&#8221; and is generally seen as commercial, crass, and of little artistic or intellectual value; and also such a thing as &#8220;literary fiction&#8221; which is serious, artistic, and of course realistic, though not necessarily Realist. This attitude doesn&#8217;t bear much examination but it does exist, mostly in the form of a weak laugh in response when I tell people what I write. It&#8217;s worth remembering that this scoff, which can seem tolerably reasonable on the surface, even a charge with some weight behind it, is simply a new and more insidious form of the kind of disheartening belittlement that kept women off the shelves for so long&#8230;and still sometimes does.</p>
<p>I have never actually had the presence of mind to do this, but next time I hear that weak little laugh I plan to add &#8220;&#8230;.you know, like Virginia Woolf.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Four Whos, Three Avengers, and a Street Fighting Woman:  Crossplay at DragonCon</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/four-whos-three-avengers-and-a-street-fighting-woman-crossplay-at-dragoncon/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/four-whos-three-avengers-and-a-street-fighting-woman-crossplay-at-dragoncon/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sara Amis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 17:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[We Have Always Lived in the Citadel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2695</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[DragonCon is a whirling vortex of overstimulation.  I remember when it was just a wee&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_2696" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2696" style="width: 700px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/doctorswho.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-2696 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/doctorswho.jpg" alt="Patti Hendrix as Ten, Heather Maddard as Eleven, Erica Clifford as Five, and Christi Whitney as Four." width="700" height="464" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2696" class="wp-caption-text">Patti Hendrix as Ten, Heather Maddard as Eleven, Erica Clifford as Five, and Christi Whitney as Four. Photograph by George Chidi.</figcaption></figure>
<p>DragonCon is a whirling vortex of overstimulation.  I remember when it was just a wee little local gaming convention, but for the last couple decades it has been growing steadily and now it is huge, and I mean HUGE.  Pretty much everything is there; the trouble can sometimes be finding it amidst the haystack of everything <em>else</em>. So when I decided to write about gender-flipped cosplay, I was prepared to have to do some searching and spend most of the one day I planned to be at the con on it. I and my companion got our badges with surprising alacrity, and set out for the lobby of the Hyatt, a prime location for gazing at life&#8217;s rich pageant as it passes by. I hoped to snag a photo or two, perhaps an interview, and get started.</p>
<p>On the way there we spotted a young woman dressed as Mario, carrying a mushroom purse. Just inside the Hyatt, I spotted Thor. Not, Sarah Maefs pointed out, &#8220;lady Thor,&#8221; but male Thor, &#8220;although I am working with the artist to get a costume based on the new female Thor ready for New York Comic Con.&#8221; As I was talking to her, Alison Klesman as Captain America and Valerie Mikles as Hawkeye strolled up. I asked everyone what they thought the attraction of crossplay was for women. Valerie&#8217;s reason was pragmatic: &#8220;I&#8217;ve been doing this a lot lately, because girls wear heels.&#8221; Alison said, &#8220;I mostly just like male characters better&#8230;I really like Captain America.&#8221; Sarah expressed a similar sentiment: &#8220;Male characters are more abundant in comics and often given a more fleshed-out character and role in comics&#8230;Growing up, I idolized Thor the most, and identified with him more than any of the women, so when it came to do a costume, I really had no choice.&#8221;  We went on to talk about female comic book heroes as role models for little girls, the friendliness of DragonCon to cosplay at all levels, and the geek authenticity police.</p>
<p>I hadn&#8217;t even made it up to the main lobby of the Hyatt yet.</p>
<figure id="attachment_2704" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2704" style="width: 270px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/chunli.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image wp-image-2704" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/chunli.jpg" alt="Evah Destruction as Chun Li" width="270" height="481" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2704" class="wp-caption-text">Evah Destruction as Chun Li</figcaption></figure>
<p>Practically everywhere I went, I saw gender-flipped costumes.  I asked local Atlanta drag performer Evah Destruction (aka Alexander Surian), who was dressed as Chun Li from Street Fighter, why it seemed to have gained popularity.  &#8220;There&#8217;s a kind of bandwagon thing that happens&#8230;People see someone doing it, and they think &#8216;hey, I could do that&#8217;.  I think it contributes to a sense of overall acceptance, that you can be anything you want to be.&#8221;</p>
<p>The women I spoke to expressed the same idea as well, but for many women the reasons they dress as male characters are complex. A group of friends who started cosplaying together last year as Bilbo and some Dwarves returned this year as a quartet of Doctors Who.  &#8220;I just really love the character,&#8221; said Patti Hendrix, though she later added, &#8220;another reason we do this is that we don&#8217;t want to show skin.&#8221;  Her friends agreed. &#8220;Female superhero costumes are too revealing. I don&#8217;t want a costume that clings to every crevice,&#8221; said Erica Clifford, while Christi Whitney echoed what the group of Avengers had said earlier: &#8220;Male characters are often better written and you have more to work with.&#8221;</p>
<p>As a writer whose protagonists are mostly female, this causes me to shed a small tear.  The consensus seems to be that this state of affairs is improving as movie studios and comic book publishers and gaming companies realize there&#8217;s an audience of women (and money to be made), but for most of the women I spoke to, their childhood fictional heroes were generally male.</p>
<p>Several women also mentioned the issue of sexualization one way or another, including harassment and the &#8220;fake geek girl&#8221; phenomenon. Sarah Maefs was emphatic that showing skin or not shouldn&#8217;t be an issue, but acknowledged that it often was:  &#8220;Whether you want to dress as Captain America in a bikini, or go full armor like me and bind everything down, it&#8217;s all about expressing the character however you want&#8230;They tend to single out the bikini girls, because they think it&#8217;s just for attention.&#8221;  She said that when she dresses in more &#8220;sexy&#8221; costumes such as the Scarlet Witch, men are more likely to come up and quiz her on her knowledge of the character. &#8220;Sometimes you just have to tell them, &#8216;you do realize you are really disrespecting me right now.&#8217;  Nobody goes up to a guy wearing a Batman shirt and asks them how many Batman comics they&#8217;ve read.&#8221;</p>
<figure id="attachment_2699" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2699" style="width: 700px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/avengers.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-2699" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/avengers.jpg" alt="Valerie Mickles as Hawkeye, Alison Klesman as Captain America, and Sarah Maefs as Thor. Photograph by George Chidi." width="700" height="508" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2699" class="wp-caption-text">Valerie Mickles as Hawkeye, Alison Klesman as Captain America, and Sarah Maefs as Thor.<br />Photograph by George Chidi.</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/four-whos-three-avengers-and-a-street-fighting-woman-crossplay-at-dragoncon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mothering the Monster:  Mary Shelley</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/mothering-the-monster-mary-shelley/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/mothering-the-monster-mary-shelley/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sara Amis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 15:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[We Have Always Lived in the Citadel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;For we think back through our mothers if we are women.&#8221; &#8211;Virginia Woolf You may&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Frontispiece_to_Frankenstein_1831.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-2281 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Frontispiece_to_Frankenstein_1831-230x300.jpg" alt="Frontispiece to 1831 edition of Frankenstein" width="230" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;For we think back through our mothers if we are women.&#8221;</em> &#8211;Virginia Woolf</p>
<p>You may have heard the story. One summer nearly two hundred years ago a young woman traveled to Geneva with her famous and scandalous lover, to stay in a rented villa with his even more famous and scandalous (and considerably richer) friend. But the summer was cold and rainy; a volcanic eruption on the other side of the world had disrupted weather patterns. Later there would be crop failures and widespread starvation, but for the time being the group considered only how to overcome boredom. They told each other ghost stories until someone, looking around at the assembled literary talent, suggested that each one of them should <em>write</em> a ghost story.</p>
<p>The young woman had already borne her lover a child which died not long after birth; her own mother, yet another famous writer, had died eleven days after giving birth to her. Raised by her philosopher father, she was literally a child of the Enlightenment and a Romantic poet&#8217;s common-law wife, born at the historical moment when alchemy was becoming chemistry and occultism was becoming science. Intellectually curious, she had read about all of these things&#8230;from Henry Cornelius Agrippa to Luigi Galvani, from the search for the Philosopher&#8217;s Stone that would grant immortality to experiments with electrical currents and dead frogs. Unable to sleep one night, she found herself in a &#8220;waking dream&#8221;:</p>
<blockquote><p>My imagination, unbidden, possessed and guided me, gifting the successive images that arose in my mind with a vividness far beyond the usual bounds of reverie. I saw—with shut eyes, but acute mental vision,—I saw the pale student of unhallowed arts kneeling beside the thing he had put together. I saw the hideous phantasm of a man stretched out, and then, on the working of some powerful engine, show signs of life, and stir with an uneasy, half vital motion. Frightful must it be; for supremely frightful would be the effect of any human endeavour to mock the stupendous mechanism of the Creator of the world. His success would terrify the artist; he would rush away from his odious handywork, horror-stricken. He would hope that, left to itself, the slight spark of life which he had communicated would fade; that this thing, which had received such imperfect animation, would subside into dead matter; and he might sleep in the belief that the silence of the grave would quench for ever the transient existence of the hideous corpse which he had looked upon as the cradle of life. He sleeps; but he is awakened; he opens his eyes; behold the horrid thing stands at his bedside, opening his curtains, and looking on him with yellow, watery, but speculative eyes.</p></blockquote>
<p>She began to write.</p>
<p>That young woman of course was Mary Shelley&#8230;Mary Godwin at the time, daughter of William Godwin and Mary Wollstonecraft, lover and later wife of Percy Bysshe Shelley, all of them much more famous than she. The novel was <em>Frankenstein</em>. With it she made her own literary reputation which would grow over time and eventually eclipse all of them. She also birthed two literary genres in one swoop: modern horror, with its anti-heros and railing against mortality, and science fiction, strange twins who have traveled together ever since. She was eighteen years old.</p>
<p>While earlier works explored some of the tropes and ideas of science fiction, such as Margaret Cavendish&#8217;s <em>The Blazing World</em>, <em>Frankenstein</em> is widely accepted as the first real science fiction novel. The themes of unintended consequences of science and technology, the collision of same with human bodies, and exploration of the boundaries of what it means to be human by means of crossing them, are all characteristic science fiction themes and all fully present in <em>Frankenstein</em>.  Shelley&#8217;s treatment of them, especially the second, is also inherently feminist. Consider the matter of creating life in the first place. Victor Frankenstein is often said to be &#8220;playing God&#8221;; yet creating life is something women do all the time, via the &#8220;stupendous mechanism&#8221; of the natural order. Frankenstein&#8217;s offense then is not merely in creating life, but in an attempt to thwart the equally natural process of death and decomposition, in trying to seize control of bodily processes in a way that seems to strike the author (who had already been through the process of giving birth) as hubris.</p>
<p>Yet to my mind the central moral question of the novel&#8230;and Victor Frankenstein&#8217;s fatal flaw&#8230;is not bound up with how Frankenstein creates life, but what he does once he has accomplished it. The creature fills him with revulsion and he rejects it; instead of responding to its desire for human companionship and evident strong desire to learn, he repeatedly drives it away. Victor Frankenstein is a bad parent. Further, his own cold, callous nature is contrasted with that of his creation.  The creature, called Adam, is capable of responding to kindness and his destructive and violent behavior is a response to repeated rejection by others when they are confronted by his physical ugliness.  In a sharp critique of Romantic ideas about truth, goodness, and beauty, Frankenstein has none of the creature&#8217;s physical flaws but is nonetheless deeply morally flawed. Where the creature desperately seeks companionship, Frankenstein spurns it; where the creature is driven by pain and rage, Frankenstein acts from self-interest. To Shelley, what makes a person human is not a &#8220;natural&#8221; human body but the qualities of empathy and unselfishness&#8230;a perspective which has recurred in speculative literature many times over the last two centuries.</p>
<p>Consider that human &#8220;perfection&#8221; has generally been conceptualized as masculine. Women on the other hand historically and culturally are flawed, Other, monstrous and animalistic&#8230;tied to the body, mortality, birth and death&#8230;and the consequences of their subjugated state have long been proffered as justification for it. Mary Shelley was the daughter of the woman who wrote passionately and eloquently of the degradation of women by presumptions of their weakness, foolishness, and irrationality. Taking it further, writers like Barbara Creed can declare that &#8220;All human societies have a conception of the monstrous-feminine, of what it is about women that is shocking, terrifying, horrific, abject.&#8221; Others like Catharine MacKinnon can ask, in all seriousness, &#8220;Are women human?&#8221; pointing out that in terms of our society&#8217;s willingness to recognize our full humanity and autonomy, we are not. In some sense, we <em>are</em> the monster. Hence our tendency to empathize with monsters and to turn on their intellectual, idealized-human creators a sharply critical eye.</p>
<p>For every woman writing science fiction today, Mary Shelley is our antecedent, our monster-bearing foremother, who teaches us to both question what being human really is and insist upon our own humanity, while keeping sympathy for the monster who is us.  Every work of feminist science fiction is a dispatch from the edge of an ice floe.</p>
<p><em>&#8220;And now, once again, I bid my hideous progeny go forth and prosper.&#8221;</em> &#8212; Mary Shelley</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/mothering-the-monster-mary-shelley/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why we don&#8217;t need to fight for women to &#8220;break in&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/why-we-dont-need-to-fight-for-women-to-break-in/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sara Amis]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 17:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[We Have Always Lived in the Citadel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=1896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every so often, you will hear of some new outrage being perpetrated on women in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every so often, you will hear of some new outrage being perpetrated on women in speculative fiction, comics, the tech industry, or some other corner of geek culture. (Or the world at large, but I&#8217;m trying to keep focus here). Typically, it goes like this: Sexism happens.  <a href="http://www.comicbookresources.com/?page=article&amp;id=52103">A woman calls out said sexism</a>.  Then the Internet <a href="http://www.xojane.com/it-happened-to-me/janelle-asselin-comic-book-rape-threats">loses its collective mind </a>and issues everything from furious and voluminous apologetics to <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/hnigatu/why-the-fake-geek-girl-meme-needs-to-die">&#8220;fake geek girl&#8221;</a> memes to rape threats. Some men<a href="http://comicsalliance.com/sexual-harassment-online-rape-threats-comics-superheroes-lessons-men-geek-culture/"> are surprised by this</a>, and most women are not. Some of the men write <a href="http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2014/04/21/female-journalist-gets-rape-threats-over-comic-book-criticism.html">long thoughtful pieces</a> on the subject, and others write less thoughtful but heartfelt ones. Inevitably, there will be calls to help women &#8220;break in&#8221; to a previously masculine domain. Get some women in there! Storm the citadel! That will fix the problem!<span id="more-1896"></span></p>
<p>Except, it hasn&#8217;t yet, and we&#8217;ve been storming for quite a long time. The problem is that this approach is predicated on a false assumption, which is that these domains historically &#8220;belong&#8221; to men in the first place. They don&#8217;t. They never have. You will find women at the beginnings of every aspect of &#8220;geek culture,&#8221; which is another term for marginalized, innovative culture. Ada Lovelace and Grace Hopper. Mary Shelley and Margaret Cavendish and Jane Loudon. Nell Brinkley and Ramona Fradon and Elizabeth Holloway Marston. The truth is, because women artists and thinkers historically tend to work at the margins due to entrenched sexism, they also tend to be involved in innovation. They enter fields (like novel writing) that are disparaged, because nobody has too much invested in keeping them out. Once something becomes proven and lucrative, it becomes more mainstream, and then the troops start assembling to co-opt and declare it male territory only, no girls allowed.</p>
<p>We have always lived in the citadel. The problem isn&#8217;t getting in. The problem is that men keep trying to push us out. Why does this keep happening?  And why does it seem more and more ferocious&#8230;that it gets worse rather than better?</p>
<p>A clue can be found in N. K. Jemisin&#8217;s Guest of Honor speech for WisCon 38. The <a href="http://nkjemisin.com/2014/05/wiscon-38-guest-of-honor-speech/">entire thing is woven of wondrous gold</a>, but at the beginning she offers a quote from Samuel Delaney from <a href="http://www.nyrsf.com/racism-and-science-fiction-.html">an essay</a> on the topic of racism in science fiction which I find both pertinent and telling: &#8220;<span style="font-size: 15px; font-family: 'Times New Roman';">As long as there are only one, two, or a handful of us, however, I presume in a field such as science fiction, where many of its writers come out of the liberal-Jewish tradition, prejudice will most likely remain a slight force—until, say, black writers start to number thirteen, fifteen, twenty percent of the total. At that point, where the competition might be perceived as having some economic heft, chances are we will have as much racism and prejudice here as in any other field.</span>&#8221;</p>
<p>Substitute &#8220;sexism&#8221; for &#8220;racism&#8221; and contemplate these statistics, if you please: <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2014/may/14/women-technology-inequality-10-years-female">A Guardian article from May 2014</a> reported that women in &#8220;chief information officer&#8221; positions in the European Union has held at 15% for the last ten years. <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2013/04/29/178810467/blazing-the-trail-for-female-programmers">According to NPR</a>, about 20% of all computer programmers in the US are female. Also from the Guardian, <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/books/booksblog/2013/aug/08/science-fiction-invisible-women-recognition-status">32% of the science fiction manuscripts submitted to Tor UK last year </a>were from women. In other words, we are right at and sometimes above the threshold where Delaney predicts more prejudice, not less.</p>
<p>When we encounter backlash, when some young snot on the Internet tells us to make him a sandwich or we encounter the semantic equivalent from colleagues and supposed friends, it can be disheartening.  How long can this go on? Why aren&#8217;t things better than this by now? Why can&#8217;t we seem to get over the wall? But the truth is, things are better. They are much better.  Try watching <em>Mad Men</em>, and realize that they have watered it down. After just a few episodes, I wanted to go find every woman above the age of 60 I could locate, especially anyone who worked in a male-dominated profession, and give her a hug. And then I couldn&#8217;t watch it any more, because there was only so much of that I could stand. Better still, re-read <em>The Feminine Mystique</em>, and feel in your bones how radical it actually was. Realize that <em>The Left Hand of Darkness</em> won a Hugo and a Nebula just six years later, in 1969, and how amazing <em>that</em> was.  Then go re-read <em>How to Suppress Women&#8217;s Writing</em> by Joanna Russ, realize how applicable it still is, and get mad all over again&#8230;</p>
<p>And realize we are winning.  If we weren&#8217;t, certain people wouldn&#8217;t be so upset. Yes, it&#8217;s taking a long time. So long that we keep forgetting and buying into the story that we aren&#8217;t getting anywhere. It&#8217;s important to remember that we are, and also to light a fire under our own asses from time to time. We need sustenance along the way&#8230;history, facts, amusement, critique, rants, truthful voices. I hope to provide some of those things, talk about the history of science fiction and geek culture in general, and the role of women in same.  And remind you of something important:</p>
<p>We have always lived in the citadel. We belong there. It is ours.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
