<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Fleeing the Ivory Tower &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/fleeing-the-ivory-tower/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:20:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Power in Translation</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/power-in-translation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phoebe Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 16:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fleeing the Ivory Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am currently in my fourth semester at my MFA program, and for fun, I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am currently in my fourth semester at my MFA program, and for fun, I took an Old English class. Since I’m a Tolkien nerd, this class is a delight, even if I doubt I will ever use the information in my career. Even though this column is often about my frustration with academia or the Ivory Tower, this Old English class is nearly the epitome of the Ivory Tower—something so archaic and useless to everyday life that the only place to study it would be in the ghostly halls of academia. Yet, here I am, a hypocrite and totally enjoying the earliest form of the language I’ve studied on the page for over a decade.</p>
<p>Since my undergraduate years, I’ve held a yearning for the old European myths, particularly Norse mythology. Through Neil Gaiman’s <a href="http://www.neilgaiman.com/works/Books/American+Gods/in/183/">bibliography</a> for <em>American Gods</em>, I found and devoured <em>The Norse Myths: Introduced and Retold </em>by Kevin Crossley-Holland. This book led me to other ancient texts, including poems I now study in my Old English class such as “The Wanderer” and “The Seafarer.” Forces combined this February when Neil Gaiman’s retelling of the Norse myths was released and currently sits on my desk until I have a devoted span of time to read it. As I study translations of Old English texts and practice translating myself, a pattern emerges. Men. So many men.</p>
<figure id="attachment_8307" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8307" style="width: 292px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/10404723525_c29602eb81.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-8307 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/10404723525_c29602eb81-292x300.jpg" alt="" width="292" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-8307" class="wp-caption-text">By: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/21304538@N00/10404723525/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">madmrmox</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>But why? My Old English class is evenly split when it comes to gender (even though my program is not), and the professor is a woman. Yet, male scholars have written all the textbooks. I reviewed my bookshelf of translations of Norse myths, collections of folklore, and books of scholarship—overwhelmingly male. Are there truly so few translations of mythology and classic literature by women or has academia failed me by simply not supplying them?</p>
<p>I fell down the Google hole but didn’t have much luck. The clearest list came from an imprint of Hackett Publishing’s classical studies catalog, but men far outweighed the few women in the field. The texts they translated were often women-centered classics, such as <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Euripides-Alcestis-Medea-Hippolytus/dp/0872208222/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1491314056&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=Euripides++Diane+Arnson+Svarlien">Euripides translated by Diane Arnson Svarlien</a>. Surveying the classics imprint of Penguin, their <em><a href="http://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/series/BE3/legends-from-the-ancient-north">Legends of the Ancient Norse</a></em> series containing five titles were all translated by men. While the Penguin website proved impossible to navigate for the purpose of this blogpost, again, men seemed the go-to option, even in their newer editions.</p>
<p>The one place I regularly see women’s names pop up is fairy tale translations, such as Maria Tatar’s excellent and numerous titles. Penguin gets on board with their Penguin Classics Deluxe Edition of <a href="http://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/291163/fairy-tales-by-hans-christian-andersen/9780143039525">Hans Christian Andersen</a> being translated by Tiina Nunnally. If this observation is true, then that’s some weird sexism for you. Perhaps the gender disparity is because ancient epics are usually conceived as have to do with the deeds of men (I would argue otherwise), while fairy tales allows more room for female characters.</p>
<p>All of my “research” his pretty slap-dash, so dear reader, I would like to hear from you. Do translations of classic literature by women exist with more abundance? Is there a weird gender gap between the classics and fairy tales? And why? Does any of this matter today? I’ll try to come up with my own observations for next month.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ivory Tower Empathy</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ivory-tower-empathy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phoebe Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 16:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fleeing the Ivory Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of my MFA funding, I teach composition and a breakout creative writing workshop.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As part of my MFA funding, I teach composition and a breakout creative writing workshop. In these classes, one of my goals is to read and discuss with my students work by voices they aren’t familiar with—in other words, not white male middle/upper class writers. While I want my students to become better writers, my main goal is to encourage empathy. As an undergraduate, my English professors sold the major as a way to develop empathy.</p>
<p>I believe in the power of literature to create empathy due to my conversion from a conservative to a liberal after a course on African American Literature. My small liberal arts college offered one class that specialized in something other than period-specific literature (ex. Romantic Period). Once I was presented with literature outside my perspective and knowledge-base, my empathy developed at a life-changing level.</p>
<p>I’m critical of academia’s lack of diversity when it comes not only to professors (all the humanities professors at my liberal arts college were white during my time as a student), but also when it comes to the texts they present to students. How can students develop empathy if they aren’t presented with diverse readings? If academia neglects certain voices, genres, and people the students&#8217; chance to expand their worldview in those area shrinks. The books that changed my mind as a college student were written by diverse and usually female writers—<a href="http://www.tonimorrisonsociety.org/">Toni Morrison</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arundhati_Roy">Arundhati Roy</a>, <a href="http://www.harrietjacobs.org/">Harriet Jacobs</a>.</p>
<p>As a speculative writer, I’ve sunk my soul into the personal belief that fantasy and science fiction can create empathy on an even deeper level than literary fiction (fight me). To that end, I’m an advocate of bringing more speculative work into the classroom. My goal is to help students connect the world on the page to their reality and to expand their ideas of what reality is and can be. <a href="http://www.ursulakleguin.com/">Ursula K. LeGuin</a> has been one of my go-to writers due to the volume of her short work, and because as a graduate student, <em>Left Hand of Darkness</em> blew my mind for LeGuin’s ability to comment on gender issues through science fiction. Without spoiling the ending, the change in the main character was so profound as to further change my perception of gender.</p>
<figure id="attachment_8220" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-8220" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/8356003997_22db8d6da7.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-8220 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/8356003997_22db8d6da7-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-8220" class="wp-caption-text">By: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kkendall/8356003997/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">K. Kendall</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Some may theorize that a quick fix to the lack of diversity in English courses reading lists is to offer special topics courses. Don’t get me wrong, I love special topics courses and take as many as possible due to their laser focus, but it takes an interested student to sign up. College professors lose a whole swathe of students who need to develop empathy in a certain area. For example, a Literature and Gender course. A homophobic or misogynistic student isn’t going to take that class, but present this person with LeGuin’s <em>Left Hand of Darkness</em> in the gen-ed contemporary literature class, and maybe something will spark. While Faulkner and Hemingway are praised for their writing and storytelling, these are the types of voices students have been reading and hearing for decades—the white male view of the world.</p>
<p>As an instructor with too little time and too much grading, I get it. Finding and teaching authors outside of the usual cannon takes work, but each semester I interact with forty-eight students. If I can make them read and write about <a href="http://octaviabutler.org/">Octavia Butler</a> or LeGuin or <a href="http://crashwong.net/">Alyssa Wong</a>, I hope it’s a step in the right direction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reading &#038; Protest</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reading-protest/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reading-protest/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phoebe Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 17:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fleeing the Ivory Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8015</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National news outlets have been touting the rise in sales of George Orwell’s 1984. My&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>National news outlets have been touting the rise in sales of George Orwell’s <em>1984</em>. My Twitter and Facebook feeds have been sprinkled with comments about how it was time to reread the dystopian classic, particularly after “alternative facts” became a thing. People are following through with this desire to read <em>1984</em>, according to the <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/01/25/books/1984-george-orwell-donald-trump.html?_r=0"><em>New York Times</em></a>, who reported that orders had “[led] its publisher to have tens of thousands of new copies printed.”</p>
<p>Somehow, I missed George Orwell in high school, but my college fiction professor taught Orwell’s essays “A Hanging,” “Shooting an Elephant,” and “Politics and the English Language.” For the time period, I appreciated Orwell’s progressive views on colonialism and India, which lead me to read <em>Animal Farm </em>and <em>1984 </em>three years ago. At first, when Orwell started creeping across my social media, I considered rereading <em>1984</em> some weekend, but after walking across campus from a solidarity march with Black and Muslim students, I questioned, why Orwell? Was he really the only voice who had addressed these topics, these issues that are currently be created by a largely white, straight, male administration? Orwell did not speak for the fellow students I had marched with.</p>
<p>Instead of Orwell, I’ve been thinking of stories that speak to the political world Americans find themselves in every morning. Reiterating and reliving my own perspective is helpful as a fight song or anthem, but since many of the executive orders coming down the pipeline have been aimed a minorities, listening to outside voices is necessary as an ally. Orwell is the Ivory-Tower approved choice, so I began thinking about who Orwell’s voice might not have included.</p>
<figure id="attachment_4522" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4522" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/octavia-butler.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-4522 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/octavia-butler-300x236.jpg" width="300" height="236" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-4522" class="wp-caption-text">Quote from <em>Parable of the Sower</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Parable-Sower-Earthseed-Octavia-Butler/dp/0446675504/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1486836336&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=parable+of+the+sower"><em>Parable of the Sower</em> by Octavia Butle</a>r. Butler’s work has come up in conversation almost as much as Orwell’s novels. One of my favorite Women’s March signs was “Octavia Warned Us.” For her examination of climate issues, fascism, race, and gender, this novel hits all the harrowing headlines of today.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bitch-Planet-Vol-Extraordinary-Machine/dp/1632153661/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1486836358&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=bitch+planet"><em>Bitch Planet</em> by writer Kelly Sue DeConnick and artist Valentine De Landro</a>. This comic explores a dystopia where women who don’t “stay in their place” as 1950s house wives are sent to a giant prison. In the wake of the <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-fix/wp/2017/02/08/nevertheless-she-persisted-becomes-new-battle-cry-after-mcconnell-silences-elizabeth-warren/?utm_term=.e2939ba3afe4">“nevertheless, she persisted”</a> trend, this comic seems more relevant each day, especially as the characters represent a variety of voices, body types, and sexual orientations.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Handmaids-Tale-Margaret-Atwood/dp/038549081X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1486836380&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=handmaid%27s+tale"><em>The Handmaid’s Tale</em> by Margaret Atwood</a>. Explanation needed? Much of Margaret Atwood’s work could make a list like this one, but I’ve been thinking a lot about <em>Handmaid’s</em> due to the way fanatical religion has been braided with politics this past election.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ink-Sabrina-Vourvoulias/dp/0615657818/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1486836416&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=ink+by+sabrina+vourvoulias"><em>Ink</em> by Sabrina Vourvoulias</a>. This near-future novel explores immigration issues when a biometric tattoo is used to identify those in American on visas and recent citizens. While not a wall, a biometric tattoo seems like another insidious way to separate humanity. As Vourvoulias is an activist and journalist, she brings a credibility to the ideas of immigration and “the other” as presented in the novel.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reading-protest/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reflecting on Favorite Writers</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reflecting-on-favorite-writers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phoebe Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 17:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fleeing the Ivory Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the years, I’ve been embarrassed about my top ten favorite books, particularly the top&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the years, I’ve been embarrassed about my top ten favorite books, particularly the top five. The list changes every few years at the discovery of a new author or a favorite book, but my top five are pretty cemented: J. R. R. Tolkien, C. S. Lewis, Neil Gaiman, William Faulkner, and Brian Jacques. Sometimes, a different writer will edge out poor Jacques, but if I’m being honest, his books had as big of an influence on me as Tolkien’s work. Faulkner didn’t join the list until I took an undergraduate seminar were I read eight of his first and second tier books—hard not to fall in love with an author after studying his work so intently.</p>
<p>In undergrad, this list embarrassed me because none of these writers, sans Faulkner, were regarded as “literary” or “excellent” or truly “worth studying,” so I would mutter through them when somebody asked. Come junior year, I had a tattoo of Tolkien’s hand-drawn <em>Gates of Moria</em> so I couldn’t feel ashamed any longer, and grew proud of my fantasy influences, regardless of what people thought, name dropping them in my graduate school applications. If the Ivory Tower didn’t want me because I didn’t like Donna Tart, forget ’em.</p>
<p>Senior year of undergrad, a new worry crept on me, and I haven’t been able to shake it since then. Now in my second year of a three year MFA program, my favorite authors are all men, all straight (as far as scholars know), and all white. Sure, if I zoom out to my top ten, the next five are more diverse: Lin-Manuel Miranda, Ursula K. Le Guin, Octavia Butler, Kelly Link, and Virginia Woolf. Many of these are new additions. I didn’t read Le Guin or Butler until 2015. I listened to <em>Hamilton</em> for the first time in 2015, too. Kelly Link I’d started reading as a teenager, but only added her to the list when I realized I couldn’t shake her haunting stories in <a href="http://kellylink.net/books/pretty-monsters"><em>Pretty Monsters</em></a> and, later, <a href="http://kellylink.net/books/get-in-trouble"><em>Get in Trouble</em></a>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7764" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7764" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/4131076475_82e7a9e01d.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-7764 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/4131076475_82e7a9e01d-300x200.jpg" width="300" height="200" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7764" class="wp-caption-text">By: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/ccacnorthlib/4131076475/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CCAC North Library</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>As a feminist and ally, my first five trouble me. As a writer, I worry if the influence of five men, all dead except Neil Gaiman, have left the cracks of another time period, another viewpoint, in what I hope to share with my writing. But if I’m honest, when I need a comfort book or need to be grounded in my writing, those are the authors I pull off the shelf.</p>
<p>In reaction to my fave five, I’ve taken months, even years, where I avoid certain books, focusing instead on women writers, writers of color, or, for 2017, books from LGBTQ+ writers. Maybe I’m simply being self-conscious and should just embrace being a “bad feminist,” as Roxane Gay would put it. Maybe it’s just a vortex of the time period—the authors on my childhood fantasy shelf were men. The books we studied in my tiny liberal arts college were written by the classic male figures. My writing professors were, and still are, men—all feminists and allies on some level, but not actively handing me women, PoC, or LGBTQ+ writers.</p>
<p>In 2017, perhaps the best I can do is learn from new favorites in these writing communities and make sure other people know and have access to these writers, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Body of One&#8217;s Own</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-body-of-ones-own/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phoebe Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 17:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fleeing the Ivory Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My junior year in undergrad, a British Literature professor handed me Virginia Woolf’s Orlando. Published&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My junior year in undergrad, a British Literature professor handed me Virginia Woolf’s <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Orlando-Biography-Virginia-Woolf/dp/015670160X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1480006084&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=orlando">Orlando.</a> </em>Published in 1928, <em>Orlando: A Biography </em>follows the title character as a young man whose body is changed into a woman and gifted with a form of immortality. The book’s timeline stretches from the 16<sup>th</sup> century to the novel’s publication date, allowing the protagonist to experience life as a woman across the centuries, which includes love affairs with men and women as well as childbirth.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7601" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7601" style="width: 213px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/5316350758_47e53a673d.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-7601 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/5316350758_47e53a673d-213x300.jpg" width="213" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7601" class="wp-caption-text">By: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/39106736@N04/5316350758/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Betty B</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>While obviously speculative, Woolf is one of the earliest writers of a speculative work to focus entirely on gender issues. Even beyond feminism, the novel subverts cisgender romance and can be read as a transgender text. Also, Woolf is one of the first, if not <em>the </em>first, lesbian speculative writer—yet I’d never heard her name mentioned in conversations about early speculative fiction.</p>
<p>Perhaps Woolf’s <em>Orlando </em>undermines both literary fiction and SF. In <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28503846-the-big-book-of-science-fiction"><em>The Big Book of Science Fiction</em></a> by Ann and Jeff Vandermeer, a passing reference is made to Woolf in the introduction:</p>
<blockquote><p>“It is also worth remembering that in the wider world of literature writers outside of science fiction were trying to grapple with the changing nature of reality and technological innovation. After World War I, […] Virginia Woolf and others experimented with the nature of time and identity in ways that at times had a speculative feel to it.”</p></blockquote>
<p>I would respectfully disagree as to the description of Woolf’s <em>Orlando </em>as having “a speculative feel” rather than calling it straight speculative fiction (perhaps that definition would better fit a novel such as <em>To the Lighthouse</em>). Even if <em>Orlando </em>is just a one-off from Woolf, why does it not receive more recognition? Mary Shelley was a one-off as well, yet she maintains her figurehead as the mother of science fiction.</p>
<p>Perhaps the heteronormative society got in the way of Woolf receiving recognition for her time-travel novel. Even among her own progressive contemporaries in the Bloomsbury group, lesbians were looked down upon while homosexuality was more celebrated, as depicted by this interaction between Woolf and E. M. Forster: “He said he thought Sapphism disgusting; partly from the convention, partly because he disliked that women should be independent of men.” Considering science fiction in the 1920s, the pulps, and the following Golden Age, weren’t always forward thinking when it came to feminism, let alone non-binary characters, perhaps Woolf’s contribution to science fiction has been buried.</p>
<p>In the Ivory Tower, <em>Orlando: A Biography</em> is rarely mentioned in modern literature surveys and is relegated to women’s and gender studies classrooms. In my experience, Woolf was the token woman writer in the modernist section, with either <em>To the Lighthouse</em> or <em>Mrs. Dalloway</em> on display. While gender plays a part in both novels, it isn’t as revolutionary as <em>Orlando</em>.</p>
<p>Perhaps Virginia Woolf was too forward thinking for both SF and literary fiction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Greening the Ivory Tower</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/greening-the-ivory-tower/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phoebe Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 17:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fleeing the Ivory Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7121</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the spring, my graduate program brought in a well-known short story writer and novelist&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the spring, my graduate program brought in a well-known short story writer and novelist (as well as a writing professor) for a reading. While he doesn’t claim environmental writing is a genre—it’s all just story—his fiction is widely regarded as environmental. His reading focused on natural gas drilling in the 80s, and I walked out feeling hopeless about the destruction caused by men trying to get rich. What was a female, tattooed, fantasy-writing graduate student to do?</p>
<p>One of my biggest complaints when I’m browsing the literary section of a bookstore or attempting to pick up the latest literary rave is the melancholy. So rarely do I finish a piece of literary fiction, whether a short story or novel, and feel uplifted.</p>
<p>When it comes to environmental literary fiction, this hopelessness is often magnified. For example, Ann Pancake’s novel <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/586732.Strange_as_This_Weather_Has_Been"><em>Strange as This Weather Has Been</em></a> virtually has no ending as the progressing coal mining and mountain top removal continue to ruin a poor community 360 pages later. Possibly this circular hopelessness in fiction speaks to the fact that answers are still off in the distance. Today’s environmental issues are getting better in such tiny degrees it sometimes does seem hopeless and like an environmental apocalypse is right around the corner.</p>
<p>The literary and academic bubbles have had their turn, and while their art continues to acknowledge the problem, they are not imagining solutions. Enter SF. During the golden age of SF, that’s what some of the great writers did best—imagining what a technologically advanced world might look like. A few years later, Octavia Butler’s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52397.Parable_of_the_Sower?from_search=true"><em>Parable of the Sower </em></a>describes a world of environmental and economic collapse that seemed to come straight out of modern Detroit or any poor, marginalized community. SF writers have imagined the future and the future’s problems, but now that same imaginative engine is turning toward imagining solutions. While the SF bookshelves are still flooded with dystopia and post-apocalypse, there’s a positive movement spinning from the steampunk and cyberpunk realms—solarpunk.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7122" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7122" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/6266247413_3172e2ee93.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-7122 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/6266247413_3172e2ee93-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7122" class="wp-caption-text">By: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/kretyen/6266247413/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ken Bosma</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>In their submission guidelines, <a href="http://www.solarpunkpress.com/"><em>Solarpunk Press</em></a>, a paying genre market, explains they are looking for stories that <strong>“deal seriously with environmental crises, systematic oppression, global imperialism and other issues in dire need of solutions. […] Vitally, we want stories that are optimistic about these problems. They don&#8217;t have to be all solved as of the story’s present-day; they probably shouldn&#8217;t be; but we don&#8217;t want to publish stories that portray hope and effort as absurd or pointless endeavors.”</strong></p>
<p>In a recent interview, editor Faith Gregory reminded writers and readers alike about the power of literature in activism: “Literature is so important to activism, so having the genre reflect the movement, and the movement reflect the genre, are going to strengthen both.” One of the wonderful things about the SF genre is the (growing) inclusiveness. Speculative fiction stretches to the masses internationally and offers a chance to see environmental issues through the eyes of indigenous populations and those communities already becoming climate refugees. If, together, we can imagine solutions in stories, who knows what speculative fiction might be responsible for fixing?</p>
<p>While the above goals might sound a tad idealistic, I always remind myself of cell phones. In an old, science fiction TV show called <em>Star Trek</em>, the characters communicated with each other through handheld devices. The inventor of the first cell phone was inspired by those devices to create one of his own. When<a href="http://iowainformer.com/ames/2016/05/jennifer-knox-the-informer-interview/"> speaking about solarpunk</a>, poet Jennifer L. Knox said, “One [student] explained solarpunk to me this way: ‘You know how cool Star Trek was, how they would always find workarounds? We think that’s still possible,’ and I was like ‘Oh, thank God!’”</p>
<p>There’s room in speculative fiction for the warning and the uplift, for modern problems and futuristic solutions. No other genre has such a possibility to help humanity work through these timely environmental issues that will, someday, lead to disaster. But there’s still time to respond with our stories and solutions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stuck in Time</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/stuck-in-time/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phoebe Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 15:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fleeing the Ivory Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last semester, I had a conversation with a professor who, after expressing her dislike of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last semester, I had a conversation with a professor who, after expressing her dislike of Octavia Butler, stated that it was a shame that no women of color wrote science fiction and fantasy. I felt stunned, my brain scrambling to list names, though it, of course, failed me. As soon as I left her office, I started listing.</p>
<p>What about <a href="http://nalohopkinson.com/">Nalo Hopkinson</a>, publishing award-winning novels since 1998?</p>
<p>What about <a href="http://nnedi.com/">Nnedi Okorafor</a>, publishing regularly since 2007?</p>
<p>What about <a href="http://nkjemisin.com/">N.K. Jemisin</a>, who debuted in 2010 with the well-received <em>Inheritance</em> trilogy?</p>
<p>What about <a href="http://helenoyeyemi.com/">Helen Oyeyemi</a>, so often found in the literary section but sticking close to the fantastical with <em>Mr. Fox</em> and <em>Boy Snow Bird</em>?</p>
<p>There’s <a href="http://www.sofiasamatar.com/">Sofia Samatar</a>, whose novel <em>A Stranger in Olondria</em> was reviewed in 2013 by many high profile organizations (NPR, Kirkus, PW).</p>
<p>What about <a href="http://zencho.org/">Zen Cho’s</a> debut <em>Sorcerer to the Crown </em>that lit up bookshelves in 2015?</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Lightspeed_73_June_2016-200x300.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7377 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Lightspeed_73_June_2016-200x300-200x300.jpg" alt="lightspeed_73_june_2016-200x300" width="200" height="300" /></a>And that’s just a few names. A simple Google search brings up Lightspeed’s anthology <a href="http://www.lightspeedmagazine.com/ebooks/june-2016-issue-73-people-colour-destroy-science-fiction/"><em>People of Colo(u)r Destroy Science Fiction</em></a>, which includes enough women in the table of contents to keep an avid reader busy for a while.</p>
<p>A few months later, another professor said something similar, calling N. K. Jemisin a rare African American writer in the speculative genre. Yes, the science fiction and fantasy community was only white for a very long time, but that was the seventies, not 2016, the era many of those writers dreamed of on the page. Even with people like long time community member <a href="http://www.nisishawl.com/">Nisi Shawl</a> and 2015 Nebula award winner for short fiction <a href="http://crashwong.net/">Alyssa Wong </a>and a full spectrum in-between, academia refuses to catch up and simply shuts the ivory gates.</p>
<p>There’s a larger erasure at work in the libraries of the Ivory Tower when it comes to diversity in general, but what concerned me the most about my two interactions with these professors was they acted like they <em>knew</em>. As if the world of SFF hadn’t been experiencing growing pains since the last time they strolled through the genre section at Barnes and Noble. In the essay “Science Fiction and ‘Literature’—or, The Conscience of the King,” Samuel R. Delany discusses such academics, calling their ignorance a “rupture,” and provides a theory: <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/9004993292_3d8f026110.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-6692 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/9004993292_3d8f026110-300x200.jpg" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<blockquote><p>“The working assumption of most academics […] is that somehow the history of science fiction began precisely at the moment they began to read it. […] [These] notions accomplish the same thing; they obviate the real lives, the real development, and finally the real productions of real SF writers.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Erasing writers like Nalo Hopkinson and Nisi Shawl with Ivory Tower ignorance feels like an even worse insult than simply dismissing SFF as genre. These women of color are wonderful writers and deserve to be on class syllabi next to Atwood and (the rarer) Le Guin, but that can’t happen if academics assume they don’t exist in the first place.</p>
<p>Delany’s description of such ruptures occurred in the seventies. At least some of academia is still stuck back in time, even if the SFF community is slowly moving forward.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Term &#8220;Speculative Fiction&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-the-term-speculative-fiction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phoebe Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 16:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fleeing the Ivory Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Writers have argued and continue to argue over the term “speculative fiction.” I first used&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Writers have argued and continue to argue over the term “speculative fiction.” I first used the term as a college freshmen—a way to say I wrote fantasy but sound more “artsy” or important. My creative writing professor quickly said that all fiction is speculative and it was a bad term. Regardless of general opinion, the term has stuck, and, I believe, been transformed and reclaimed by the genre community. It’s not so easy as it was in the sixties when there seemed to be two brands of speculative genre—science fiction and fantasy. Even then, science fiction was a catchall term most writers ground their teeth over.</p>
<p>Currently, the genre has grown to such proportions that a term is necessary. Science fiction, fantasy, and horror <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/22125258.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-7200 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/22125258-200x300.jpg" alt="22125258" width="200" height="300" /></a>cannot contain the multitudes of the genre tree. Is Octavia Butler’s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52397.Parable_of_the_Sower"><em>Parable of the Sower</em></a> science fiction because it’s set in the future, or due to the lack of hard science, is it a fantasy? How does one classify a collection of Kelly Link’s work? Often shelved in “literary fiction” her latest collection <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22125258-get-in-trouble"><em>Get in Trouble</em></a> spreads across the genre realm from alternate history to fairytale. So the term speculative fiction comes in handy.</p>
<p>Typing in the term on Google displays its depth, a list populating with everything from Atwood to Le Guin to Joanna Russ. The term has become established since Robert Heinlein debuted it in 1941. Or so I thought.</p>
<p>In graduate school, I was informed in no uncertain terms that Margaret Atwood had created the term in reference to her work. While this moments is a great example of academic ignorance (which I discussed in more depth <a href="http://wp.me/p77ike-1JV">here</a>), it also speaks to the underlying <a href="http://io9.gizmodo.com/5650396/margaret-atwood-and-ursula-k-le-guin-debate-science-fiction-vs-realism">battle still being duked out </a>in the genre world, most notably by Atwood and  Le Guin.</p>
<p>Atwood’s essay collection, <em><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10356713-in-other-worlds">Other Worlds: SF and the Human Imagination</a>,</em> speaks to her desired distinction more fully. She recognizes the breadth of genre while calling for a distinction:</p>
<p>“Are [my] books ‘science ﬁction’? I am often asked. Though sometimes I am not asked, but told: I am a silly nit or a snob or a genre traitor for dodging the term because these books are as much ‘science ﬁction’ as <em>Nineteen Eighty-Four</em> is, whatever I might say. But is <em>Nineteen Eighty-Four</em> as much ‘science ﬁction’ as <em>The Martian Chronicles</em>? I might reply. I would answer not, and therein lies the distinction.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_7119" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7119" style="width: 232px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/4125856187_3e692a1aa4-1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-7119 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/4125856187_3e692a1aa4-1-232x300.jpg" width="232" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7119" class="wp-caption-text">By: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/tom1231/4125856187/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tom</a></figcaption></figure>
<blockquote><p>While I might personally say that yes, those novels are both a type of science fiction (especially since they speak to concerns of that time period, the only difference being a slightly different color palate, as it were), but these discussions cut out the backbone of the speculative genre: the working writer. In graduate school, my rejoinder to my professor’s adamant declaration was regardless of how Atwood used the term, it meant something different to working writers trying to sell stories they believed in.</p></blockquote>
<p>To writers without multiple bestselling books, the term “speculative” helps them find markets and discuss their work—especially if it doesn’t fit into the traditional definition of science fiction or fantasy. This genre has always been about imagination, and having an umbrella term allows writers to dream beyond the limits of science fiction or fantasy, to speculate. The crazy and unique ways the genre has grown beyond the term “sci-fi” is a testament to the creatiity of humanity. Trying to pin down a specific definition seems wasteful of our imagination. My professor was right—all fiction is speculative, but if the literary world doesn’t want to take advantage of the wildness and freedom of the term, why shouldn’t we?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Running with Wolves</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/running-with-wolves/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/running-with-wolves/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phoebe Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 15:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fleeing the Ivory Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While not in vogue, Joseph Campbell’s The Hero with a Thousand Faces still gets tossed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While not in vogue, Joseph Campbell’s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hero_with_a_Thousand_Faces"><em>The Hero with a Thousand Faces</em> </a>still gets tossed around in creative writing programs. A casual reader of myth probably has a copy on a shelf somewhere since Campbell&#8217;s theories are a favorite of filmmakers and the book pops up in shows like <em>The X-Files</em>.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/trh_the_heros_journey_artwork-2-_wide-3961291f3acc5368e4f0e9d350c786fc522543d7-s1000-c85.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-6953 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/trh_the_heros_journey_artwork-2-_wide-3961291f3acc5368e4f0e9d350c786fc522543d7-s1000-c85-300x169.jpg" alt="trh_the_heros_journey_artwork-2-_wide-3961291f3acc5368e4f0e9d350c786fc522543d7-s1000-c85" width="300" height="169" /></a>For most of my young writing life, writers and professors told me to read Campbell, so I did, scribbling angry margin notes about his sexism. Throughout his work, Campbell tried to create a mega-myth that all stories fed into. His mythological trope of the Hero’s Journey was part of that overarching mythology. Writers like his theory because it corresponds so well with literature—the Hero’s Journey is repeated in often male-driven stories (it is <em>Hero </em>after all) throughout the literary cannon, especially in classical stories such as the <em>Odyssey</em>.</p>
<p>I put Campbell back on the shelf feeling angry and tricked. Here was just another guy writing about heroes and excluding women to side roles or plot points on the Hero’s Journey. This voice didn’t belong in my work.</p>
<p>No professor or Ivory Tower guardian recommended <a href="http://www.clarissapinkolaestes.com/women_who_run_with_the_wolves__myths_and_stories_of_the_wild_woman_archetype_101250.htm"><em>Women Who Run With the Wolves</em></a> by Clarissa Pinkola Estés. I’d read a quote from the book on Tumblr and found a copy while rummaging in a used bookstore. The older woman at the checkout had tapped the tall, thick paperback and said, “This is a really important book.”</p>
<p>Estés eschews classical mythology for folklore and indigenous stories. For the first time, I read analysis of Baba Yaga, of Blue Beard, of Skeleton Woman. Like Campbell, Estés examined the structure of these stories, but not by confining them to one, large mega-myth like the Hero’s Journey, but by connecting these stories to different aspects of womanhood. She breathes fresh life into the tales by reminding the reader that these stories are still alive in women, to take strength from them. Part psychological self-help book, part analysis, part art, Estés demonstrates story and magic cannot be separated from life.</p>
<p>One of my favorite parts of the book was her chapter on Baba Yaga, a name I knew but without a story to connect with. In the tale, the young girl Vasalisa is sent by her evil stepmother and stepsisters to ask for some coals from the witch in the woods to light their hearth. The Baba Yaga requires Vasalisa to complete several tasks, which she does successfully with the help of a magic doll. Then, the Baba Yaga sends the girl home with a flaming skull on a stick, which is of course scary to a young girl, but the skull reassures her on the way home. In typical folklore style, the fiery skull kills the stepmother and stepsisters by burning them alive.</p>
<p>Estés interprets the fiery skull as a woman’s fierce intuition, exposing those people and voices that could or are harming. It also illuminates beauty.</p>
<blockquote><p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/4394641125_0b1916afe9.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-6687 size-medium alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/4394641125_0b1916afe9-300x197.jpg" width="300" height="197" /></a>“It is the mirror in which all things are sensed and seen. It is the deep wild nature.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Sometimes as a reader, writer, and woman, I’ve felt lost. The voices swirling around me in the media, in the bookstore, bleeding into my own work feel wrong, and my gut pulls somewhere else, often in a weirder and wilder direction. With a shuddering breath, I hold my fiery skull high and face the stories I feel the need to tell. As Estés writes, “It is worse to stay where one does not belong at all than to wander about lost for a while.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/running-with-wolves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Fold of the Map</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/another-fold-of-the-map/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Phoebe Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 16:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fleeing the Ivory Tower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Ivory Tower sounds like a place straight out of Narnia or a Robin Hobb&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Ivory Tower sounds like a place straight out of Narnia or a Robin Hobb novel. This term bridges the gap between fantasy (albeit not a happy one) and reality. College professors and grad students lob the idea back and forth when trying to decipher whether marking down for grammar is too Ivory Tower or simply part of teaching composition. It&#8217;s a metaphor of being separated from the real world, locked away with books that only the special few are allowed to touch if they can pass the entrance exam and afford the fees.</p>
<p>Sounds like something Draco Malfoy might dream up if he ran Hogwarts, doesn&#8217;t it? The Ivory Tower is academia at its worst, but at its best, it&#8217;s a noisy tavern full of storytelling and learning from experience and experimenting and discovering what you like and what you don&#8217;t like.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s hard not to get sucked inside these fantasies, especially once you have entrance. A lifetime in academia can mean decent pay, summers off, and tenure, which all adds up to time to write. I believed the Ivory Tower was a myth until I entered a Masters in Creative Writing program and realized how I&#8217;d formed my writing, my reading list, my likes and dislikes, all to gain entrance. I&#8217;d even called my writing speculative fiction or simply said mythology influenced my work when chatting up the gatekeepers of the Ivory Tower.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/7412273606_be8dc8866d.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6683 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/7412273606_be8dc8866d-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a>A year ago, I fled the Ivory Tower after listening to <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nerdcon/honing-your-craft-embettering-your-word-doing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a panel</a> at NerdCon: Stories, featuring Holly Black, Paolo Bacigalupi, Lev Grossman, Nalo Hopkinson, and Stephanie Perkins. Black, Hopkinson, and Perkins stand out in my memory, especially Holly Black&#8217;s electric blue hair. These women were some of the smartest, funniest, passionate writers I&#8217;d heard, and I felt more energized and inspired to write after that hour than I had during my first month at graduate school.</p>
<p>Why hadn&#8217;t I read their work or been told to read their work by my professors? The Ivory Tower library was incomplete. Voices had been lost, especially the voices of women. While not much genre work made it onto the shelves, my professors mentioned Asimov, Clarke, Delany, but not Octavia Butler or Ursula K. Le Guin.</p>
<p>So I went exploring. I scaled the walls with my adventurer&#8217;s pack and began a quest for libraries that didn&#8217;t just shelve Faulkner, Hemingway, Burroughs, Wallace, and maybe Woolf and Morrison. A whole world opened up, as if I&#8217;d unfolded another portion of the literary map. I started with Nalo Hopkinson&#8217;s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/57504.Brown_Girl_in_the_Ring"><em>Brown Girl in the Ring</em></a>. The story focuses on a young woman named Ti-Jeanne, a new mother, who is balanced on the knife edge of becoming what she is destined to be: a healer, a daughter of the elder trickster Legbaraor drawing back into the familiar, her boyfriend and their relationship.</p>
<p>Science fiction and fantasy are by their nature unfamiliar landscapes, and, like any choice, a writer can choose the safe decision, whether it&#8217;s to model one&#8217;s career for the Ivory Tower or simply avoid a story due to difficulty.</p>
<p>Change doesn&#8217;t come with complicity. It&#8217;s not easy or safe, but it&#8217;s much more fun to play jokes with Legbara. To truly escape the Ivory Tower, I needed to listen to new voices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
