<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>A.E. Ash &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/a-e-ash/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:20:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dr. Aphra Is a Meanie &#038; I Love It</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dr-aphra-is-a-meanie-i-love-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.E. Ash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dr. Chelli Lona Aphra: rogue archaeologist; erstwhile supplier of goods and intelligence to Sith Lord&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10682 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Doctor_Aphra_1_cover-198x300.png" alt="" width="198" height="300" />Dr. Chelli Lona Aphra: </span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">rogue archaeologist; </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">erstwhile supplier of goods and intelligence to Sith Lord Darth Vader and current acquirer/purveyor of rare (and horrifying) weapons; </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">partners with (re: indebted to) notorious Wookiee former gladiator, Black Krrsantan; </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">possessor of violence-happy droids Triple-Zero and BeeTee; </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">and, according to Beetee, ‘a genuinely horrible person.’ </span></li>
</ul>
<p>Oh, and even her own father notes that she has terrible taste in women.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Heck of a resume, yeah?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I just finished </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">tearing through</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the first collected volume (singles 1-6) of </span><a href="http://marvel.com/comics/series/22719/star_wars_doctor_aphra_2016_-_present"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dr. Aphra</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a character who debuted in Marvel’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vader </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">comics (which are awesome and you should read them but that’s a whole other post), and who has had her own comic since 2016. Though I’ve only read the first collection featuring writer <a href="http://gillen.cream.org/wordpress_html/">Kieron Gillen</a> and artist Kev Walker among others, I’m super impressed by the art and production quality, writing, and character complexity and designs. I won’t go into her Vader arc, or really much of anything specific to the stories I’ve read thus far. Instead, I’ll talk about why I love her and why I think characters like her are important. Firstly, just look at that description in the first paragraph&#8211;a resume of pure action-hero awesomeness. She is a scoundrel, wildly competent at her roguery too, and she is an exciting character to follow because of all these things she’s involved with.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10680 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screenshot_20180620-101349-169x300.png" alt="" width="169" height="300" /> <img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10681 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screenshot_20180620-101355-169x300.png" alt="" width="169" height="300" />Secondly, and to me more importantly, Dr. Aphra is a jerk. Yeah, I said it. She’s a real a-hole. She cheats (in huge ways sometimes), double-crosses, swindles, and yes, she shoots people. She even threatens her own father (who affectionately calls her &#8216;Boop&#8217;) but of course backs off because, as my fave panels so far show, even she has her ethical limits. And those limits are really important, as you see when she talks to her father&#8211;honestly, bitterly, and sadly&#8211;about the Death Star’s devastation of Alderaan. That does not change the fact that she is an anti-hero through and through, and does some terrible things and does them unapologetically.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why is it important to me that Aphra (she’d be yelling, “That’s DR. Aphra to you!”) is a jerk? Good question, thanks for asking. &gt;:D It’s because though media has been increasingly filled with exciting, diverse, and complex female characters (I mean, look at shows like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Orange is the New Black</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, or </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Expanse</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">), I still have a lifetime’s dearth of female scoundrels, rogues, and meanies but not horri-baddies to fill. Women aren’t always the good guys, or even nice, wuuuuuut? And though I read comics to escape, I love seeing this particular type of reality reflected even in fantastical narratives&#8211;i.e., the fact that women are complex and fully realized in such a stunning variety of ways.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Indeed, so much of what I’ve read in recent Star Wars narratives feeds this mighty need of mine. Arihnda Pryce, whom I first met in Timothy Zahn’s new </span><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/223651/thrawn-star-wars-by-timothy-zahn/9781101967027/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thrawn </span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">book and in the comic adaptation of the same name, is power-hungry, driven, effective, able, and merciless at times. And thoroughly fascinating to me because of it . . . I cannot wait to start watching </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rebels </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">because of characters like her (yeah, clearly I’m behind the times on keeping up with my pop media). Even going a bit further back to the <em>Clone Wars</em> series, I was able to experience characters like Asajj Ventress (I freaking love her interactions with Ahsoka Tano), who is one of my favorite anti-heroes to date . . .and yes, I consider her that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dr. Aphra takes readers on an adrenaline-fueled, at times hilarious, and other times deeply sobering set of adventures, and at least in what I’ve read so far, her anti-hero’s journey has not taken away the very essence of her character&#8211;her self-focused and at times ruthless sense of survival. I hope this stays the case (I’m already reading the next collection), as this is a journey I’m so here for.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I could go on at length about Dr. Aphra and these other characters but I’ll end here with my gratitude to recent Star Wars narratives across various media for giving me so many new women characters to love (so many characters to love, generally) and I am so hopeful and excited for things coming down the road&#8211;I mean hyperspace lanes in this galaxy far, far away.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tohru Honda’s Optimism is Important</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/tohru-hondas-optimism-is-important/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.E. Ash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 10:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In another time (and what felt like another world), a friend introduced me to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9854 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Fruits.Basket.full_.224172-207x300.jpg" alt="" width="207" height="300" />In another time (and what felt like another world), a friend introduced me to the anime<a href="https://www.funimation.com/shows/fruits-basket/"><em> Fruits Basket</em></a>. In this distant time, the anime and manga, penned by Natsuki Takaya (I always love reading her asides about life and gaming in the manga), were enjoying a crazy amount of success in the US. I have some theories about this—primarily, the strong bonds of the main character and her protective friends and of course, the Zodiac Curse characters—particularly, the Team Kyo vs. Team Yuki  aspects. But I digress.</p>
<p>Regarding <em>Fruits Basket</em>: like so many anime and manga I’ve loved, there are some pretty big and loud problematic moments, arcs, and relationships that weave their way through a narrative that in the end, stuck with me in ways more positive than not, despite the not insignificant issues I had (others have blogged about these problematic issues far better).  For this blog, I’m focusing on my biggest takeaway from both the manga and anime—Tohru’s optimism.</p>
<p>All these many years later and as a much Older, Wiser Me, I’m working through the manga in full. <a href="https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/encyclopedia/people.php?id=712">Natsuki Takaya</a>, the woman who created the manga, did not know her work was going to be the enormous success it turned out to be—at the time, she was something of a phenomenon even stateside. The manga unsurprisingly delves far deeper into the characters and their dynamics than I’d even hoped since like many, I saw the anime first and TV pacing is rarely the same as what you’ll find in the corresponding light novels or manga. Back in the day, I’d read volumes here and there (mostly from friends’ collections and libraries). I’d secured the entire series from E-bay, a generous and glee-inducing gift from the husband-person and I find myself only on volume 11 even after over a year, slowly savoring the series like the best kind of chocolates (the ones I hide from myself to keep from eating all at once). All these many years later, I’m seeing something that I did not see before—something that Younger, More Impatient Me didn’t seem to get . . .the importance of Tohru’s decisions and personality.</p>
<p>At first, Tohru’s character sometimes bothered me. I still sometimes have to empathize my way past her character’s propensity toward martyrdom (powerful tropes at work, and something I see in so many analogous series). It drove me nuts that she was far more willing to take hit after hit in life than to cause others trouble. What I overlooked, though, was Tohru’s soul-deep desire to see the best in people and situations in life.</p>
<p>It’s not a spoiler to say that the death of Tohru’s mother is the event (occurring prior to the series beginning) that shapes her situation and yes, her character and choices. We learn from moment one that Tohru is an only child mourning a terrible loss. So many anime and manga are filled with armies of parent-less children but what makes Tohru different for me (in a similar way Natsume of an earlier series I blogged about) is how she chooses to process the loss. Unlike a magical girl or a chosen one, Tohru is not outwardly remarkable to readers/viewers. She is an average to below average student, she is not great at sports or art or really anything besides seeing the world in a way that only she can.</p>
<p>I didn’t know what to think, at first. Tohru Honda: helpful always, a good cook, sparkles and rainbows levels of perky, hard-working, never thinking as much of herself as I’d like her to . . . sometimes I struggle with those characters. I want them to be happy, to have agency. To assert themselves and own their place in the world.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9855 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/2761136826_f163d1868e-300x219.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="219" />The thing is, Tohru does that . . . again and again. She does speak up for herself when it matters (New Year with her extended family, for instance). Tohru is an optimist, you see. And in her case, that means yes, more hard work. Working all the time to make her relationships authentic and rich and full. Working hard to see the goodness in the world even during the worst of times, and taking the time and making the effort to share this goodness with those around her. Optimism may be her default setting but as a girl who has lost so much, who daily faces challenges (financial, social, psychological) that could easily lead her towards cynicism, she again and again forces her gaze to the light, the beautiful, and the meaningful in life.</p>
<p>Optimism is not easy, not even for the Tohru Hondas of the world. It takes force of effort, practice (as much as any sport, hobby, or discipline). It takes force of will. It takes bravery in the face of being knocked down over and over again. Tohru’s friends sometimes talk among each other about her strength and how it shines in her decisions to be, unabashedly, who she is. The rough-and-tumble Uotani, the reserved and sometimes broody Hanajima, and the whole lot of the Sohmas who are forever wowed by her positive attitude and egalitarian kindness . . . if she is a magical girl, her ability to choose to see what is good in those around her is her biggest superpower.</p>
<p>Sometimes, I need to remember this. I get it now that I’ve been through years and stumbles and deep and jagged losses. I treasure when someone takes the time to see the good in me, even past the quills and barbs. And I thrive when I lift my face to the sunlight, when I bask in the goodness that exists all around me even while knowing it’s not the only game going, by far.  So here’s to the Tohru Hondas of the world—thank you for the light you bring.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Manga Reviews: Ooku: The Inner Chambers and A Drunken Dream and Other Stories</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/manga-reviews-ooku-the-inner-chambers-and-a-drunken-dream-and-other-stories/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.E. Ash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 12:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This year has been a rough year, I’m not gonna lie. So, of course, I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year has been a rough year, I’m not gonna lie. So, of course, I resort to reading things that absorb my attention and give me catharsis in the midst of the <em>icks</em>. And, oh, hi there&#8211;I’m so excited to be able to have time to blog with <em>Luna Station</em> again, whee!</p>
<p>I decided this summer that I was really going to dive into graphic fiction (I have the Comixology equivalent of a giant <em>Steam</em> backlog, ha) and wow, I launched myself into the deep end. I lost track of how <em>much</em> I read, to be honest&#8230;I would close my eyes and see line art etched in my mind’s vision. I was so fascinated by what made art a success in work I was reading that I even participated in Inktober as a hobbyist doodler just to immerse myself further in imagery when words were just too heavy. On this journey, I discovered quite a few awesome women content creators for both western and non-western comics, manga, and graphic narratives. In my upcoming posts I plan to talk about some of the highlights I’ve encountered on this journey. I’ll note I read all work in English as I do not speak Japanese and while I have a working understanding of a few manga genres, I do not consider myself an expert. I will also be using the American convention of first name/last name in providing author names since that is how the English language versions market the texts. I will say that even though I am no expert, I am developing quite specific tastes and overall, ‘slice of life’ stories will top my lists in pretty much any narrative genre&#8211;this is doubly so for manga.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Untitled1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8959 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Untitled1-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>For today’s post, I’ll start with <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6218001-oku">Ooku: The Inner Chambers</a>, an AU Edo period epic by Fumi Yoshinaga. I have only read the first four volumes of the series but I have to say, I hold out hope it will retain my interest.</p>
<p>In Yoshinaga’s Edo Japan, a mysterious illness that affects only men has altered the country’s landscape in every conceivable way, resulting in dramatic changes in even the power structure. We are introduced to a female shogun who possesses what no one woman in the country should: a full contingent of young, robust men entirely at her disposal. I don’t want to give too much away, but how she chooses to handle her situation and power are fascinating and go a long way in making me want to read the next books in the series (I’m starting on the second now) to see how else she changes her world.</p>
<p>With the idea that men are a rare commodity and women must scramble to find viable means of populating their country comes the possibility of some, IMHO, sticky and problematic gender dynamics. I have seen other reviewers note this series almost begs comparison with <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/156534.Y">Y: The Last Man</a>. I won’t go there since I wasn’t able to get very far into Y&#8230;I was too put off by the aesthetic and dynamic being set up. In Ooku, I feel that the difficulty of the situation is given enough gravity and dignity to handle the unpleasant aspects of the character dynamics. While there are plenty of instances of people being just awful (because that is sometimes what humans do), the art style, the narrative lens, and the tone of the first volume left me wanting to know more about the political and court intrigue being introduced. The focus on earnest and clever characters dodges some of the issues I thought I might encounter in such a narrative. I do wish, that said, that I had encountered more women characters with strong voice and agency in this first volume. For a world where men are scarce, the narrative is strongly male-centric and while that is not a problem in itself, I cannot help but wonder what the world looks like for the many women who must adapt to taking over formerly male-dominated leadership roles in efforts to preserve their society.</p>
<p>Where Ooku really shines is in its visual impact. For me, the art sells the world, the characters, and the story itself. Facial expressions, palace furnishings and backgrounds, patterns on cloth, shadows from lamplight&#8211;they all feel so <i>real </i>and evoke a lush and fully-actualized world that I don’t think I’ll forget anytime soon. Add to that the English translation writing style, and the entire experience is&#8211;how do I put this?&#8211;unique, and almost cinematic in scope. I will note, the style chosen for the English translation is something that takes getting used to, and which I understand was a roadblock for some readers. The story unfolds in a formal, maybe faux Elizabethan style which I understand was a way of echoing the archaic Japanese language used but I’m not sure the authenticity carries over. I was able to overlook it, though, and the wonderfully-developed characters and fascinating world carried me through the problems I had with the story as a whole. All in all, I’m excited to see where this series goes!</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Untitled2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8960 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Untitled2.jpg" alt="" width="214" height="288" /></a></p>
<p>Next up is a compendium of classics, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7840940-a-drunken-dream-and-other-stories">Moto Hagio’s A Drunken Dream and Other Stories</a>. Hagio has been writing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sh%C5%8Djo_manga">shoujo manga</a> since 1969 and one of the best aspects of this collection is the inclusion of interviews, historical observations, and biographical information that frame these remarkable stories.</p>
<p>I came away utterly haunted. I knew I was reading some of the classics penned by one of the foundational pillars of the shoujo genre. I knew that Hagio was a woman writing girls’ manga in a time when the market was dominated by male writers. I had an inkling that Hagio’s interest spanned many genres, too&#8211;sci-fi, fantasy, romances, fairy-tales&#8230;what I did NOT expect was how these stories unwound darkly and richly, with no fear of ambiguity and reader discomfort. So many of the pieces center on problematic and fierce familial relationships, love that doesn’t translate into any easy summation or simple trope, and characters who even when surrounded by others retain an isolation that I found intriguing. The art is, yes, a product of its time, but Hagio has a loud and clear artistic ‘voice’ pitting wide-eyed youth against the shadows in the world at large and it’s interesting to see this voice refine and solidify as her career progresses. Her lush worlds and yearning characters wind their ways through contemporary, sci-fi, or fairy-tale worlds, and the art for any of these diverse settings just somehow works, always in Hagio’s voice and tone despite disparate settings.</p>
<p>Every world in this collection is populated by tears, joy cut short by the realization of life’s difficulties, complex and at times alienating mothers, love-hate filled sisters and friends, love stories tangling through time and space only to reveal new ways a heart can be broken and reborn&#8230;these stories are cathartic, gripping, and unforgettable. Warning: if you want to read &#8220;The Willow Tree&#8221;, be prepared to cry. To UGLY cry. The last piece in this remarkable anthology, &#8220;The Willow Tree&#8221; encapsulates everything that will linger with me after reading these stories: a dreaminess that is still somehow moored in &#8220;the real world,&#8221; with unexpected narrative twists, gentle melancholy that permeates each panel, and art that requires few or no words to create a lasting narrative impact. These stories show that manga written with young girl readers in mind does not equate shallow or fluffy, by any means. I definitely recommend this to any shoujo fans who are interested in encountering classic examples of the genre and perhaps coming away with new perspective on how shoujo manga has evolved through the years.</p>
<p>I think I’ve gone on long enough&#8211;thank you for reading! If you have any recommendations for manga by female authors that you’ve loved, I would always love to see them in the comments and I’m sure other readers would as well. My read and to-be-read lists may be both growing but as far as I’m concerned, there’s always room for more! &lt;3</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sleepover/Creepover</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/sleepovercreepover/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.E. Ash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have always loved Halloween but not necessarily for the obvious reasons. I mean, yes,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have always loved Halloween but not necessarily for the obvious reasons. I mean, yes, I love it for those too &#8230; the time of year is truly magical with those first truly crisp nights (at least anywhere I’ve lived), fallen leaves dancing over the streets in autumn breezes scented with woodsmoke, and flickering candles in pumpkins and on windowsills. What I looked forward to the most, though, was the frisson of excitement that skittered through my friends and classmates when we talked about costumes and how late we’d be allowed to stay out. We made construction paper decorations, eagerly counted the days till class parties and more sweets than we were normally allowed. Most of all, we sat out in the playground in our jackets and took turns telling or making up spooky stories, a little more eager than normal to come back inside to the safe warmth of the classroom after recess was over. I loved Halloween because a good scare seemed to bring people closer together.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enter the girlhood sleepover, which proved my Halloween theory all year round. There were times I was bundled off to the homes of other girls in my class&#8211;sometimes girls I didn’t know very well, or didn’t always see eye to eye with. Once or twice, even girls who picked on me and my closer friends. We were encouraged to socialize, to branch out and give our moms a rare night off so we packed our PJ’s and pillows, our sleeping bags and off we went.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-7474 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Scary-Stories-to-Tell-in-the-Dark-300x169.jpg" alt="scary-stories-to-tell-in-the-dark" width="300" height="169" />Almost every one of these sleepovers seemed to start out the same way&#8211;dinner or snacks, a parent-approved movie, board games (and if we were lucky, the GOOD junk food&#8211;candy, ice cream, even &#8230; gasp &#8230; SODA). At some point we would be left to our own devices and almost inevitably, the scary stories would begin. Bloody Mary, light as a feather and stiff as a board, ghost stories about the creepy old houses around Charleston, the notorious Low Country Lizardman, stories girls made up about the mean neighbor or that strange clicking sound that came from another friend’s basement &#8230; sometimes, the lights would even go out, flashlights appear and gleeful screeches, shivers and the most wonderful storytelling one-up-(wom)manship would occur. If we were lucky, someone would have a good scary book&#8211;I don’t know how many people remember <em>Scary Stories To Tell In The Dark</em>&#8211;or, “that red, white and black book with the creepyass drawings,” as one of my friends so aptly put it. The book, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scary_Stories_to_Tell_in_the_Dark">part of a series of three by Alvin Schwartz, illustrated by Stephen Gammell</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, was full of wonderfully evocative, eerie stories and minimalist illustrations that were made even scarier by the light of a crappy K-Mart flashlight with ancient batteries which had seen better days.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’d take turns reading in dramatic voices, some girls even embellishing the stories with their own flourishes and anecdotes or others busting out tiny plastic boomboxes and rewinding their Thriller cassette over and over again while the reading spun on and we all held to our pillows, riveted in suspense. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We scared the <em>crap</em> out of ourselves. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Best of all, socially nervous girls like me forgot to be scared of present company&#8211;we had far creppier, spoopier things to be afraid of. Like, you know, women who undo the black ribbon around their necks only to have their heads fall off. Or wallpaper vines that come alive and wrap around and around you like a mummy. Or Critters. The sleepover became the creepover, and we forgot our differences in wake of the connection we felt in light of this spookiness. The lights would inevitably come back on, someone’s parent reminding us tiredly of what time it was, and by the time the morning rolled around and we packed into our mom&#8217;s cars or walked back home, we were (at least a little bit) better friends.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, do any of ya’ll have tales of bonding through scary narratives and shared fright-nights? Happy Halloween, and here&#8217;s wishing everybody a wonderful fall! </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lost Stars by Claudia Gray: A Review</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lost-stars-by-claudia-gray-a-review/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.E. Ash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 16:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ohai! So, today I’m continuing my delving into new Star Wars narratives surrounding the release&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-6358 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/3434-199x300.jpg" alt="3434" width="199" height="300" />Ohai! So, today I’m continuing my delving into new Star Wars narratives surrounding the release of <em>The Force Awakens</em> with a review of <a href="http://www.claudiagray.com/books/star-wars/"><em>Lost Stars</em></a> by <a href="http://www.claudiagray.com/">Claudia Gray</a>.</p>
<p>Ya’ll, it was freaking fantastic. I am not kidding you.</p>
<p>A novel in the <em>Journey to Star Wars</em> series, <em>Lost Stars</em> is billed as sci-fi and as young adult. Indeed, the book is a journey following the progress of two young protagonists, Thane Kyrell and Ciena Ree as they make their way from very different lives on the same tiny planet to more similar existences as students at the Imperial Academy. The events of <em>Lost Stars</em> begin eight years after the fall of the Old Republic, and we see some characters and events from familiar narratives (I will not say who or what because I do not want to spoil anything).</p>
<p>As with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-shattered-empire/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">my review of the comic <em>Shattered Empire</em></a>, I must note that <em>Lost Stars</em> does something I adore—it reframes familiar events in a narrative focusing on new characters in different circumstances, augmenting the existing canon and shedding light on the political situation that leads to what we find in <em>The Force Awakens</em>. And here, the characters are so very worth focusing on.</p>
<p><strong>I love them. </strong></p>
<p>Claudia Gray, thank you for this book. Thank you for a strong, believable female protagonist and an equally strong, believable male counterpart. Thank you for making Ciena a woman of color, a woman of agency, a woman of flaws and talent and hard work and some really awful decisions some times, and staggering bravery other times. Thank you for creating the most maddening, beautiful, natural and painful of slow-burn romantic entanglements and for letting me watch these two conflicted characters find their way in a world where very little is easy, and where what must be done to survive encompasses an enormous rainbow of shades of gray.</p>
<p>Ciena and Thane are complex in the best ways. The world-building of already-known <em>Star Wars</em> places and people woven in with new planets, new characters, and new details about this epic space opera is deft and compelling. Even the side characters are incredible in <em>Lost Stars</em>, and the book adds new dimension to an already beautiful body of lore.</p>
<p>My only complaint? Well, it’s not a <em>real</em> complaint—more, me whining. Simply put:  I want more. That last chapter…gah. It hurt, beautifully, and in the best possible way. It made sense, and it was perfect.</p>
<p>I recommend <em>Lost Stars</em> highly, and I cannot wait to read Gray’s new book <em>Bloodline</em> coming in May from Del Rey because OMG GUYS IT’S ABOUT LEIA!</p>
<p>So, what are ya’ll reading? &lt;3</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Shattered Empire</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-shattered-empire/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.E. Ash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 16:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Star Wars: The Force Awakens landed in 2015 in a huge way, as the entire&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Star Wars: The Force Awakens</em> landed in 2015 in a huge way, as the entire universe knows, and I won&#8217;t take space here geeking about why I loved it. Instead, I&#8217;ll geek out about why I am loving the new comics and narratives that bloomed in the wake of the new film. Most recently I gobbled up Marvel&#8217;s <em><a href="http://marvel.com/comics/series/19705/journey_to_star_wars_the_force_awakens_-_shattered_empire_2015_-_present" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Star Wars: Shattered Empire</a>,</em> a four-part comic book miniseries. Oh my goodness, people. It&#8217;s fantastic. I will not spoil anyone on content but timeline-wise, the series occurs well before the events of SW:TFA (after the Battle of Endor) and offers some insights into political/military events with repercussions carrying into the TFA world. Greg Rucka&#8217;s writing  is tight and fast-paced and yes, Marco Checchetto&#8217;s art is spectacular. The characters, well&#8211;seriously, if you like relateable and awesome lady leads in your Star Wars then you&#8217;ll be doing yourself a favor by buying this series. I&#8217;ll just put this <a href="http://www.starwars.com/news/a-new-warrior-stands-near-a-jedi-starfighter-in-star-wars-shattered-empire-2-exclusive-covers-reveal">cover for issue #2 featuring Shara Bey here</a> and let that sink in&#8230;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5861 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Unknown4-675x1024-198x300.jpeg" alt="Unknown4-675x1024" width="198" height="300" /></p>
<p>This comic does something I love&#8211;it combines familiar characters with new ones in ways that shine light on the old while letting the new dazzle in the spotlight. The new material enriches the existing canon and ties satisfyingly into The Force Awakens. What excited me most was how the diversity and richness of these new characters lends so much to the art and storytelling and creates a Star Wars in which I see myself logging some serious fandom time and dollars. I gave <em>Shattered Empire</em> an insta-five-stars on Comixology&#8211;I recommend it that much. I&#8217;ll be catching up on other comics in the comings days as well as Claudia Gray&#8217;s Star Wars novel <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25067046-star-wars" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Lost Stars</em> </a>(adore it so far but that&#8217;s another review for another day) and some of the other Journey to The Force Awakens narratives. I think there is reason to celebrate this new age of one of my favorite franchises, and I cannot wait to glory in all the new shinies coming down the line! May the Force be with you&#8230;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>IRL? It’s all real life.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/irl-real-life/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.E. Ash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 17:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This time of year I am almost always madly busy—holidays, holiday celebrations, end of year&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This time of year I am almost always madly busy—holidays, holiday celebrations, end of year deadlines, travel. I found myself posting on a group site I’m a part of that &#8220;IRL, stuff is busy, won’t be around as much.&#8221; I got to thinking, though—is this real life?</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/50479-felicia-day-is-this-real-life-84rr-300x168.gif"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-5622 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/50479-felicia-day-is-this-real-life-84rr-300x168-300x168.gif" alt="50479-felicia-day-is-this-real-life-84rr-300x168" width="300" height="168" /></a>What does that even mean? Why am I making these distinctions?</p>
<p>The reality of my reality is that the world is more connected than ever before. That is both amazing and sometimes problematic (a whole other blog post for somebody else to write) but it’s the truth—I live here, now, and in every moment. That includes my face to face interactions as well as my online/digital presence. Real life is all of this. Google Hangouts chatting with my bff across the country because we both hate talking on the phone is as real as any other interaction in my day to day existence. Emailing someone to tell them what’s on my mind, or help them problem-solve or cheer them up—it’s just as real as any other communication. It’s <em>different</em>, yes—we lack the nonverbal mode of communication in this format but it is a legitimate form of keeping in touch with friends and family and readers and anyone else I interact with each day. I have friendships I’ve developed with people I’ve never met or will never meet in person that are definitely real relationships with very real people. Just ask anyone who has ever been active on community forums, worked with creative/critique partners online, has had pen-pals over the years, or been active in a guild or other online gaming family. This <em>is</em> real life. It’s real because I spend “real” time (we all know time is just a construct, ya’ll) interacting meaningfully with them. My emails and chats with my in-town husband or faraway friends are still interactions that matter in a big way.</p>
<p>So when I say I&#8217;m wishing you well over the miles, through time and space, it&#8217;s legit. These wishes may be rocketed out to satellites and bounced back,  routed in ones and zeroes and  in the font of my choice on a screen of your choice but they come from a place of real hope for love and peace and good things for you all. &lt;3</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/fcdb78ce01964ebe8d7a13000c84b6c9.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="center-image aligncenter wp-image-5621 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/fcdb78ce01964ebe8d7a13000c84b6c9-300x240.jpg" alt="fcdb78ce01964ebe8d7a13000c84b6c9" width="300" height="240" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Giving of Thanks, Nerd Version</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/giving-thanks-nerd-version/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.E. Ash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 17:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello there! It&#8217;s that time of year here in the United States&#8211;Thanksgiving. A lot of friends&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello there! It&#8217;s that time of year here in the United States&#8211;Thanksgiving. A lot of friends and family are talking about gratitude this week and that is a Big Good Thing. In my own fashion, I have some geeky thanks to give. While nerdy hobbies, pop culture and TV and movies may not seem important, I have to argue, THEY ARE IMPORTANT. And here is why: they reflect our cultural values in so many ways. That&#8217;s why this Thanksgiving, I&#8217;m happy to give thanks for some awesome new trends, new franchises, and win that I&#8217;ve seen in the last couple of years for women.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/17beb6af09c5156fec050a269dd82b55.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5493 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/17beb6af09c5156fec050a269dd82b55-185x300.jpg" alt="17beb6af09c5156fec050a269dd82b55" width="185" height="300" /></a>I&#8217;m thankful for remarkable, problematic, beautiful, badass, interesting, complex women leads in movies and TV. Imperator Furiosa&#8211;an amputee, a suvivor, a goddess. <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1392190/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mad Max: Fury Road</a></em> was a gift to me&#8211;absurd and beautifully over the top, and so much YES. I mean, look at her!</p>
<p>And she wasn&#8217;t the only one. There were so many powerful women in that movie.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m thankful for the gift of Peggy Carter. I know I&#8217;ve blogged about her in the past, but it warrants saying again&#8211;she is amazing. Strong, yes. Flawed? Sure. But she is a <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/tumblr_nhsls8j8xd1qzuwh0o1_500-daniel-from-agent-carter-is-either-a-time-lord-or-a-time-lord.gif"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-5494 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/tumblr_nhsls8j8xd1qzuwh0o1_500-daniel-from-agent-carter-is-either-a-time-lord-or-a-time-lord-300x133.gif" alt="tumblr_nhsls8j8xd1qzuwh0o1_500-daniel-from-agent-carter-is-either-a-time-lord-or-a-time-lord" width="300" height="133" /></a>fighter in ways that are hard to easily quantify. She shapes the world The Avengers later inhabit, and is a huge reason Steve Rogers is the man he is. And she does it all with such impeccable style. Peggy, I love you. I&#8217;m not afraid to say it.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m thankful for a reason to read comics. Even better, for a reason to build a Comixology backlog that is rivalling my Steam backlog. Series that give me characters like the bawdy, badass, sarcastically delicious ladies of <a href="https://imagecomics.com/comics/releases/rat-queens-vol.-1-sass-and-sorcery-tp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Rat Queens</em></a>, the crazywack world of <a href="https://imagecomics.com/comics/series/bitch-planet" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Bitch Planet</em></a>, the delightful and odd <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22554204-lumberjanes-vol-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Lumberjanes</em></a>, and the many ladies of <em>Marvel</em>.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m looking at you, <a href="http://www.comicvine.com/kamala-khan/4005-94118/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kamala Khan</a>&#8211;a Muslim heroine nerdgirl/fangirl and all-around loveable and believable character, Ms. Marvel brings something to the world that I wish so hard I&#8217;d had when I was younger, but am glad to see out there now. I hear Captain Marvel&#8217;s recent stuff is to die for and I&#8217;m sad the movie was pushed back, but hopeful it will gain traction. I honestly think that <a href="http://kellysue.tumblr.com/">Kelly Sue DeConnick</a> is actually a story goddess sent to bring all of the denizens of earth fantastic, incomparable narratives about women who are both real and bigger than life.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Kamala-Khan.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5495 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Kamala-Khan-300x151.jpg" alt="Kamala-Khan" width="300" height="151" /></a>I&#8217;m thankful for a huge surge of interest in popular science and in astronomy thanks to the Mars Rover excitement, and movies like<em> The Martian</em>, which is a happy place for me. I&#8217;m thankful for a renewed sense of wonder in looking at our place in the cosmos as beautifully summed up in a <a href="http://www.erikwernquist.com/wanderers/film.html">2014 short film by Erik Wernquist.</a></p>
<p>I&#8217;m thankful to save the universe as a <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/im-commander-shepard/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">female Commander Shepard in the Mass Effect series </a>and though yes, that is old news, I&#8217;m SUPER excited-thankful to see the franchise continue, Fem-Shep&#8217;s voice narrating a message to explorers (a seed ship, maybe?) <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rn98FdSg-Fo">in a stunningly gorgeous trailer</a> for the upcoming<em> Mass Effect: Andromeda</em> game. I&#8217;m thankful that there are so many more games that feature wonderful women characters&#8211;heck, the female crusader avatar from <em>Diablo III</em> made it into Blizzard&#8217;s popular <em>Heroes of the Storm</em> (<a href="http://diablo.wikia.com/wiki/Johanna" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Johanna </a>is a badass). And have you seen the recent version of Lara Croft? She&#8217;s fantastic (watched hubby play through Tomb Raider, and Rise of the Tomb Raider looks to be a winner, too).</p>
<p>And finally, don&#8217;t even get me started on <em>Star Wars: The Force Awakens</em>, and how much hope and preemptive thankfulness I have for that movie. My feelings are best summed up <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DajJXToUKrs">by John Boyega&#8217;s reaction</a> to watching the trailer he was featured in&#8211;pure joy.</p>
<p>So yes, I am thankful&#8211;thankful to see such awesome things brewing in popular culture, thankful to hold hope that it will just get better and better in the coming days. &lt;3</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;m Commander Shepard</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/im-commander-shepard/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.E. Ash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 16:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If I start out rhapsodizing about how much I love the Mass Effect game franchise from Bioware you’ll not&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If I start out rhapsodizing about how much I love the <em>Mass Effect</em> game franchise from Bioware you’ll not want to continue reading this post. <em>Yes</em>, I lurves it. But that’s not why I’m here today. I’m here because I’m Commander Pax Shepard, and <em>Mass Effect</em> is my favorite game franchise in the galaxy. The internet loves Commander Shepard to this day and there is no shortage of squee out there for the female player character option. The #femshep tag gets a lot of use even now that the games are aging (though aging gloriously well, like Helen Mirren). Hell, I love Femshep as much as anyone. But I love Shepard beyond gender designation. This is important to me—and I’ll talk about why in just a bit.</p>
<p>Some background on my play style: I came to the <em>Mass Effect</em> party late as I have with gaming generally. I’m only now working my way through ME3 (mostly casual gamer). My playthroughs have been on normal difficulty, the 2<sup>nd</sup> two games as the Infiltrator class focusing on high damage and using my crew skills actively as I can. Every shot has to count in the bigger battles and it’s fun to hang back, scope, focus and watch my cooldowns so I can take stuff down hard and fast. While the 1<sup>st</sup> game is kind of clunky at times mechanics-wise (it is older, after all and those endless elevator rides are hilarious), the story kept me coming back and back and back.</p>
<figure id="attachment_4968" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4968" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/11057523_967937989907445_7126011268412196863_n.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-4968 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/11057523_967937989907445_7126011268412196863_n-300x169.jpg" alt="Actual in-game footage of me saving the galaxy." width="300" height="169" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-4968" class="wp-caption-text">Actual in-game footage of me saving the galaxy.</figcaption></figure>
<p>I say all of the above to note that there are many aspects of this franchise that have earned my loyalty, including the game mechanics. I don’t care how awesome a story is, if I cannot get past horribad gameplay, I’m not going to bother. Mass Effect wins for me on many levels—epic scope, memorable characters, amazing soundtrack music, beautiful and strange worlds. The biggest win, though, is being Commander Shepard for three glorious games. I’ll say here: yes, I love so hard that I can play through saving not just Earth, but the entire galaxy as a woman. Being Pax Shepard created an immersion factor that has won out over any other gaming experience I’ve had.</p>
<p>A couple of months ago, I was having a spirited conversation about Bioware Games and <em>Mass Effect</em> in particular. A friend noted that it really ticked her off how in the games, Femshep was just DudeShep with boobs. She was <em>too</em> patently badass. There was only one body type to choose from in character creation (but that was true for the male option), and the female Shepard’s base game model was the same exact one as the male avatar’s, just with different voice acting. It upset her that the motions/gestures for the female model were the same as for the male—that they even mostly had the same lines of dialogue. I get that, but in the end, I told my friend <em>THAT’S WHY I LOVE HER SO MUCH!!!!1!11</em></p>
<p>Sorry, ALLCAPS frenzy there but it’s so true. Pax Shepard (<em>my</em> Shepard) is much more believable to me because of the very reasons that bothered my friend. In this universe, it’s no big deal that Shepard is a woman. She is a soldier—like any other soldier. Like Ashley Williams, like Jacob and James.  Like anyone else in who has ever served in the Alliance Military.</p>
<p>And that is important to me. To experience a world where someone is N7 material not <em>in spite</em> of the fact she is a woman or <em>because of</em> the fact that he is a man is so awesome. Yes, Femshep avatars have only one body type—and normally that would tick me off too. But  N7 is the job code for the highest-ranking Alliance Military personnel. Shepard is spec-ops. I’d hope she’s in good shape if she’s out there protecting us from the Reapers. And while she still has boob-plate armor, it’s more believable to me than others—reasonable proportions, covering her in believable ways. She looks like a special forces soldier in a military sci-fi game. And I love it. As far as other cosmetic concerns go, players can customize Shepard’s features extensively. I’ve seen such a diverse array of galaxy-saviors in playing and reading about this game that it warms my heart.</p>
<p>The fact that the primary distinguishing factor between Femshep and Dudeshep is voice acting can’t be overlooked. The character models may shrug or swagger or shoot or lean in all the same ways, but at no point in the game did I ever doubt I was anything but Commander Pax Shepard, Alliance Military, and oh right, a woman.<a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0354937/?ref_=tt_cl_t5"> </a><a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0354937/?ref_=tt_cl_t5">Jennifer Hale</a>, the goddess of a voice actor who gives Commander Shepard her personality in the most believable and at times, heartbreaking way is the biggest draw for me. From what I can tell, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm1035752/?ref_=tt_cl_t9">Mark Meer</a> does a wonderful job with the male Shepard voice acting, but since I heard Hale’s voice (and she’s in SO many other games!), the deal was done. Femshep it was, and I have not regretted my choice once.</p>
<p>All of this is to say—I didn’t want it to be a big deal that my <em>female</em> Shepard is saving everyone’s butts time and time again. I didn’t want her gender to define her—and in my playthrough of the game, that held. The choices I made (lots and lots of Paragon points but Renegade when it counted), the romance options I chose (a whole other story of Bioware win for another post), and ultimately my gaming style were not “N7 For Her” choices—they were the choices of a soldier doing what she needed to keep her world safe. That is the future I am dreaming of and working towards. Where battles are won not because of or in spite of my gender or race, but because of the choices I make as a member of humanity. And<em> Mass Effect</em>, as a franchise, gives me a beautifully believable glimpse of this world.</p>
<p>In the immortal words of Commander Shepard, <a href="http://www.moviesoundclips.net/sound-clip.php?id=4132">“I should go.”</a></p>
<figure id="attachment_4969" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4969" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/1513318_705161412851772_265265484_n.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-4969" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/1513318_705161412851772_265265484_n-300x156.jpg" alt="&quot;I should go.&quot; -Pax Shepard" width="300" height="156" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-4969" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;I should go.&#8221; -Pax Shepard</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview With Charmingly Antiquated</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/interview-charmingly-antiquated/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A.E. Ash]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 15:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the many things I love about the intarwebz is the plethora of amazing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the many things I love about the intarwebz is the plethora of amazing webcomics I encounter. Having awesome art and stories in an always-available, digital format is a good and right thing. In my travels in Tumblr Land, I stumbled upon the one-of-a-kind artwork, humor, and edgy sweetness of <a href="http://charminglyantiquated.tumblr.com/">Charmingly Antiquated</a>. Sam, the mastermind behind this delightful Tumblr, is the creator of a barrage of unique, often funny, just as often pointedly moving (while sometimes STILL being funny) one-shots, and of the webcomic <em><a href="http://grantedcomic.tumblr.com/">Granted</a></em>. Her work focuses most often on remarkable, diverse female characters. I fell in love after reading <a href="http://charminglyantiquated.tumblr.com/post/79687899010/silly-silly-little-comic">this little ditty about a dragon, a princess, and a sacrifice.</a> When I went and read more of Sam&#8217;s work, I had no choice but <a href="http://charminglyantiquated.tumblr.com/post/115719727915/a-commission-for-mieulamieu-her-character-lian">to commission her to create art of Lian</a> from my Luna Station Quarterly story <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/daughter-of-the-sun/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&#8220;Daughter of the Sun&#8221;</a>. Needless to say, it’s good and perfect and she knocked it out of the park.</p>
<p>The artist’s take on diverse females (we’re talking, mermaids and banshees and cornerwitches diverse) is refreshing, her art clean, bright, and GORGEOUS.</p>
<p>I mean, how could you not fall in love with an <a href="http://charminglyantiquated.tumblr.com/post/99430229951/a-commission-for-thetimba-a-deep-sea-mermaid-it">anglerfish mermaid</a>? Or an <a href="http://charminglyantiquated.tumblr.com/post/112540295748/inspired-by-this-post-please-forgive-any">Afro-Caribbean Rapunzel</a> with 75-foot long dreads?</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/tumblr_nd2zy2pBOj1rt05s7o1_1280.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-5305 size-medium aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/tumblr_nd2zy2pBOj1rt05s7o1_1280-232x300.jpg" alt="tumblr_nd2zy2pBOj1rt05s7o1_1280" width="232" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/tumblr_nklruw7EuO1rt05s7o5_1280.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-5306 size-medium aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/tumblr_nklruw7EuO1rt05s7o5_1280-200x300.jpg" alt="tumblr_nklruw7EuO1rt05s7o5_1280" width="200" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>To celebrate an amazing artist and webcomic creator, I asked Sam if I could interview her for LSQ and SHE LET ME. *excited* So, let’s do this&#8211;</p>
<p><b>AE: I love your work. Like, </b><b><i>adore </i></b><b>it&#8211;and <a href="http://io9.com/a-charming-webcomic-love-story-about-a-mermaid-and-a-sa-1612785636" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">I&#8217;m not the only one</a>. Is there any one event, inspiration, or inciting idea that started you on the path of creating the kind of web comics that you do? And by &#8220;kind of web comics that you do,&#8221; I&#8217;m referring to the wry, often humorous, and just as often SQUEE!worthy lovely sorts of narratives you create. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></b></p>
<p>Sam: Oh wow, thank you! There was no particular point in time that I sat down and decided this is What I Do Now; I&#8217;ve always drawn a lot, and written these kinds of stories, so webcomics seemed like a pretty natural evolution. Granted, my longer webcomic began as a way to keep in touch with my youngest sister while I was abroad, and it doubles as a way for me to practice drawing expressions, backgrounds, poses, etc. The ideas for my shorter comics usually come out of nowhere &#8211; something I think is funny, or interesting, or simply fun to draw. With regard to inspiration, I get a lot of mileage out of fairy tales and classic fantasy! I grew up with literally every color of <a href="http://www.foliosociety.com/category/9319/andrew-lang-s-fairy-books">Andrew Lang&#8217;s Fairy Books</a>, which made a deep impression. In general, I&#8217;m very interested in the sidekicks, guards, post-adventure heroes, witches: the characters one step left of the spotlight.</p>
<p><b>AE: I notice that you do all of your sharing on <a href="http://charminglyantiquated.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">your Tumblr</a>&#8211;any reason you opt for this platform in particular? </b></p>
<p>Sam: Not much thought went into choosing Tumblr, because I never expected my art would become so popular. To be totally honest, I joined Tumblr in the first place because I wanted to read Homestuck theories and follow some artist. By the time I felt comfortable sharing any of my art, it was just the platform I was most familiar with.</p>
<p><b>AE: Any other artists or comics out there that you yourself can&#8217;t get enough of, or other inspirations in fandom or media that keep your creative-well filled?</b></p>
<p>Sam: Some favorite comics are <a href="http://www.paranatural.net/">Paranatural</a>, <a href="http://www.casualvillain.com/Unsounded/">Unsounded</a>, and <a href="http://lackadaisycats.com/">Lackadaisy</a>, but I follow <i>literally</i> over a hundred. I love Terry Pratchett&#8217;s books, and my favorite posts on Tumblr are the ones with new takes on fairy tales and mythology: what if this was modern, what if it was told from this perspective, what if we took this story to the logical conclusion. I think that&#8217;s fantastic, and it&#8217;s something that absolutely crops up in my own work. All these tropes and archetypes and mythological creatures are so much fun, and so ridiculous from certain angles, and so easy to play with. Outside of that, I&#8217;m pretty into weird history facts, and ruins, and old maps, and pirates. I know a lot of weird history facts about pirates.</p>
<p><b>AE: What are your plans for future projects? I know that your Tumblr webcomic <em>Granted</em> is ongoing, and that you do take commissions so you&#8217;re probably super busy. But are there any new platforms, narratives, or types of media in your creative future? <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></b></p>
<p>Sam: Besides <em>Granted</em>, and future short comics as they come to me, I&#8217;m actually in the process of publishing a novel! I&#8217;ll definitely be talking about this more on my blog once things become concrete (my lovely agent and I still need to agree on a name, for one). The story itself, like my comics, plays a lot with classic fantasy tropes, sometimes humorously, sometimes not. I&#8217;m pretty excited about it!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
