<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 046 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-046/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 14:15:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 046 Author Interview: Gillian Parrish and &#8220;City Light&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-gillian-parrish-and-city-light/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 046]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25746</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We have one last Issue 046 author interview for you, dear readers! Our next issue is on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We have one last <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-046/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://2f5.f93.mwp.accessdomain.com/issue/issue-046/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1630460603467000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEuuu0IJm93Hg3pS8FdRB0Pk88idA">Issue 046</a> author interview for you, dear readers! Our next issue is on its way, but you can come back and read these fantastic stories any time you like. To wrap things up on this quarterly, we have Gillian Parrish here discussing her thoughts on her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/city-light/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://2f5.f93.mwp.accessdomain.com/story/city-light/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1630460603467000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGoFqReEZRHo1LUZ_qqkQHjgoD4dA">City Light</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: What a pronouncement, for the boy to hear his name and that he had died in the park! Not only did it come as a shock to him, but it also confirmed to your readers that there was something different about his interaction with Chandra. How did you decide to wait until the halfway point to share this information with us? </em></strong></p>
<p>Gillian: I should say that I set out to write a ghost story as that was the task I set for my MFA students taking part in a Halloween flash fiction festival last year. In making my ghost, I found that what I was interested in was the experience of dying, particularly the denial of it. And so the timing of the reveal that the boy is dead was not about writing a story with a twist, but about getting close to the experience of the shock and denial of death. We are seeing denial play out at a vast scale right now with the pandemic and with the climate crisis. We fear change; we fear the unknown. And, thanks to the optical trick of aging in time—for at 25 or 85 we don’t appear as we did at five—death is our greatest unknown, and so tends to be our greatest fear. Chandra’s talent is helping ease the rough passage, to introduce death to the dead as less of an ending and more like a new dream.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Chandra really has the feel for how to reach the boy and for trying different things through the tone of her voice and the pace with which she approaches him. She has obviously been doing this a long time. How is this boy different from the others she has helped?</em></strong></p>
<p>Gillian: This boy is cut off from others. Hurt. Unheard. He’s not someone used to using his voice or being listened to—and this brings me back to your remark about how she approaches him, gains some trust, in part through her tone of voice.</p>
<p>To share something that writers may relate with: This story had a mind of its own in a few ways. For one, I tend to prefer to read and write fiction with lean dialogue, the kind of fiction that may even do away with quotation marks and embed the dialogue, winding dialogue in with the subtle actions or description of place such as the quiet of a room.</p>
<p>But stories are like wild horses, live, free-thinking things that wander off in surprising directions. This one decided it wanted to unfold through dialogue, which annoyed me greatly at times. I worried at points that it was too much of Chandra speaking, and that the boy is too passive. But, that passivity just really fit this addicted kid—he’s been shut out and shut down so long, on the nod, someone who has slid into a life of silent suffering. I think that his habitual silence worked with the loudness of the “ghost noise” that he was unconsciously unleashing on the neighborhood. Which is a question you ask me next….</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Tell us more about your fascinating concept of “ghost noise”. Beautifully descriptive examples from your story include, the “buzz of hunger up and down the street”, “maddening mosquito whine of his need”, and “metal scraping metal”.</em></strong></p>
<p><em> </em>Gillian: That ghost noise is about how what we feel ripples out, affects others. Interpersonal neurobiology is revealing the physical “how” of what has been known to many older cultures: we are woven together in an unseen web. Chandra and Andee are people tuned into the even more invisible parts of the web, where the living walk out of the frame of our sunlit world.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: </em></strong><em><strong>Chandra helped the boy ride the old spirit of the drug and let go into the wild of the afterlife before turning back to her grandmother in the orange chair.</strong> </em></p>
<p>Gillian: So to address the idea of riding a drug: I want to be very careful with this idea. I have wondered (more like worried and hoped) that this story does not anywhere seem to romanticize addiction. Opiates or any sticky addictive substance, is not a helpful spirit, though it may seem like it at first—such is the way of harmful spells. In my author’s note, I credit a mentor, the indigenous psychologist Eduardo Duran, for his way of talking about addictive substances as spirits. Andee’s remarks on the drug having “a mind of its own” echoes Duran’s words.</p>
<p>But Chandra needs to reach this kid, to meet him where he is, as teachers say. And where he is, or has been, is addicted to the stuff. So he’s been living in a particularly narrow tunnel, a single-minded blindness. And we have a clue that he’s holding a lot of pain in, as that “ghost noise” he is transmitting is so loud and chaotic, and so it feels that he might freak out and shatter and get even more stuck.</p>
<p>So she’s trying to ease him into death, and even better, as hospice writer Stephen Levine often notes, she’s trying to help him heal in the process. She’s trying to help the kid mourn and connect to love and then let go into death from there. But he’s far from all that. What he is close to is this drug, which has a momentary, sometimes sadly fatal, and false letting go in it. It also has a false bliss in it, a bliss with hooks and teeth, wrenching folks into the agony-anxiety of addiction. Again, bad spells.</p>
<p>Chandra works with what she can—first the false letting go, to give him some confidence. Then she has him think back to a moment of real bliss, a memory of deep connection, of love. I’m reminded here of a book that I have not read, but have heard the precis of and tend to agree with, Gabor Mate’s <em>In the Realm of the Hungry Ghosts</em>, about how disconnection is the ground of addiction and psychospiritual unrest in our world today. And from that restless, hungry psyche, well, we can see the collective mess we are in, what with the ocean on fire and all. And that brings us to grandmothers, wise children, witches…</p>
<p><strong><em> LSQ: </em><em>How does Andee’s presence weave through the story and what is her significance at the end?</em></strong></p>
<p>Gillian: Andee, Chandra’s grandmother and teacher in this ghost-whispering lineage, is part of a linked fiction collection that features wise children and witches. I&#8217;ve always loved such characters, and it feels like the world needs such stuff now more than ever, stories that put forth new-old ways of living more deeply together and in our home places. So Andee points to this kind of life with her garden and her laughter and her love. Chandra does too, growing up with a ghost-tending talent that might have led her to her work as a nurse, work we see glimpses a few times in the story.</p>
<p>As for Andee’s appearance in the chair at the end: Well, that’s another instance of the story having a mind of its own. This is one of those moments for us writing geeks to think about authorial choices. I had that ending two ways for a while and felt fine with either one. One version ended with Chandra going inside alone. In the other, Andee appeared in the chair. I chose the latter for its odd openness. It felt playful on my part or to put it more truthfully—it felt trickster’ish on <em>hers</em>—how she was suddenly sitting there so casually in that orange chair. I think the chair itself swayed me a bit in that direction too, as orange exudes suddenness and aliveness and warmth, all of which remind me of Andee.</p>
<p>To return for a moment to what I called the openness of that ending: Something that always interests me in fantastical fiction for the logic of the magic to feel real, to be true. And so that raises the question of how Andee’s ghost gets to be there in that chair, while other ghosts need to be helped to move on. I liked the idea of Andee as a conscious ghost, not the shocked, unconscious dead, but rather someone who has developed, over years of midwiving the dead, an understanding of the web of life enough to resist dissolution for a time until her tasks are done. (After all, she does have parts to play yet in the linked collection.)</p>
<p>In the end, I went with that ending because it disrupted neat closure, removed a wall we didn’t know was there. In that way, rather like the ghost boy moving out of sight, out of our frame, Andee&#8217;s appearance gave the story its own life, its own late-night conversation the two characters would keep living out, even as the story finished for the reader.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 046 Author Interview: Hesper Leveret and &#8220;We Who Are Left On This Dying Earth&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-hesper-leveret-and-we-who-are-left-on-this-dying-earth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 10:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 046]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you been loving the wealth of Issue 046 author interviews these past few months?&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div dir="auto">Have you been loving the wealth of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-046/">Issue 046</a> author interviews these past few months? We certainly have! Here&#8217;s another to add to the collection; today we&#8217;re talking with Hesper Leveret about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/we-who-are-left-on-this-dying-earth/">We Who Are Left On This Dying Earth</a>&#8220;.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: You mention that Cyrus and Jolene are unlikely flatmates for a different time, though the great equalizer is climate change and their inability to leave the earth. As soft spoken and introspective as they both are, do you think they would have been at least acquaintances under different circumstances?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25706 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greenhouse-691704_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greenhouse-691704_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greenhouse-691704_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greenhouse-691704_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greenhouse-691704_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greenhouse-691704_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div dir="auto">Hesper: No &#8211; they’re very much from different backgrounds and generations, so it’s unlikely they’d have ever met if circumstances were different. But that’s part of what I wanted to explore with this story- how two people with seemingly nothing in common can end up feeling like family.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: Your story includes chilling, but specific details of an age when the earth is past hope for habitation, including an Antarctic diaspora and the need to hand pollinate plants. Is there a specific detail that was more difficult to write about? Did you leave any thoughts out?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Hesper: The detail about hand-pollination of plants came from an article about human reliance on bees for pollinating food crops and how mass extinction of bees could lead to humans having to do all this very labor-intensive work by hand. That image really stuck with me &#8211; an example of how just growing the food to survive could become extremely difficult. I didn’t purposefully leave anything out &#8211; I wanted a few vivid details to tell the larger story.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: Jolene briefly mulls about the point of continuing, save for Cyrus. What does this say about your characters? Any thoughts on the tenacity of humanity as a whole?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Hesper: Humans have an astonishing capacity for continuing, even in the direst of circumstances, but we can also succumb to despair. Another thing I wanted to explore with this story was how that battle between tenacity and despair can play out not just at moments of obvious crisis but also during quieter times. Jolene is elderly and sees little left for her &#8211; but she has Cyrus, and she recognizes that they need each other.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: Regardless of their circumstances and the message Cyrus must deliver, Jolene breaks out the last bottle of champagne. The emotional impact of being left behind can’t be understated, but there remains a bittersweet celebration of being alive. How important was the idea of marking this event to the story?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25707 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/outlook-4011285_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/outlook-4011285_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/outlook-4011285_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/outlook-4011285_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/outlook-4011285_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/outlook-4011285_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div dir="auto">Hesper: I think a lot of events that humans mark ultimately boil down to a bittersweet celebration of being alive &#8211; most obviously funerals and somber anniversaries, but even things like weddings can be bittersweet occasions as we think of the people who should have been there. There’s also a sense that you shouldn’t hang onto things for too long &#8211; you have to drink that last bottle of champagne sometime. With this story, I wanted to show a snapshot of people whose lives are tough, who have been left behind, but haven’t entirely lost all hope, or the chance of happiness.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 046 Author Interview: Alice Paige and &#8220;The Mirror&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-alice-paige-and-the-mirror/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 13:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 046]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Issue 046 authors are so talented and clever, we just couldn&#8217;t wait to ask&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-046/">Issue 046</a> authors are so talented and clever, we just couldn&#8217;t wait to ask them our burning questions about their inspirations and writing processes! Today we talked with Alice Paige and  reflected on her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-mirror-2/">The Mirror</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story is a wildly creative mix of science and possibility. What influenced your idea behind the mirror?</strong></em></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25660 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/car-communication-3100981_1920-300x100.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="100" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/car-communication-3100981_1920-300x100.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/car-communication-3100981_1920-1024x341.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/car-communication-3100981_1920-768x256.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/car-communication-3100981_1920-1536x512.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/car-communication-3100981_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Alice: For this story, I was thinking about narratives that involve portals to other universes and how those portals act as transformative doorways for their central characters. Works of fiction like <em>Stranger Things</em>, <em>Alice in Wonderland</em>, and the <em>Divine Comedy</em> were definitely on my mind when writing this piece. The mirror, much like the doorways in those stories, provides a chance for transcendence. I also wanted to tell a story that challenged the use of the personal &#8220;I&#8221; in its narrative. How does that &#8220;I&#8221; expand when the main character comes face to face with her reflection? The best way to pull that off was to set Viv down in front of a literal mirror.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There are so many interesting images about the room: the smell of the sea, the uncomfortable chair, the sheet draped over the mirror. Put together, they not only intrigue the reader, but cause foreboding. How was the set-up of the room important to the story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Alice: The room&#8217;s set up had to be incredibly deliberate as it functionally serves as a tomb in the story. It needed to feel like something outside of our reality while also offering a handful of grounded elements for the reader to settle into, like the desk and chair, before its identity as death enters the story. Aside from that, the room needed to offer Viv opportunities to unveil the mystery and transform as a character from researcher to explorer. She needed the chance and the tools to step through the threshold and find what was waiting on the other side.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The moment we hear Viv and her mirror self are about to go off script, we understand that something bigger than herself (herselves) is about to happen. Tell us a little bit of the science or theory behind their decision.</strong></em></p>
<p>Alice: The main concept of this story is that the mirror provides a window between two identical universes. This is an extension of concepts like the multiverse, and the idea that for every new choice that is made, such as traveling down a road and deciding to go left or right, a new universe is created where the opposite choice is taken. Between the two universes in the story, that divergence has either not been discovered or has not occured yet, so the researchers in the Black Box are searching for that divergence. They want to learn the laws of the universe not through what is the same, but through what has changed or will change.</p>
<div></div>
<div>Viv figures that if everything has been exactly the same so far, she can hatch a plan and mirror her will create the exact same plan on her own. So, the two manage to plot together without ever talking. It&#8217;s a journey of the self that leads the two Vivians into the mirror. Their defining strength is introspection.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: In the end, Viv and Viv find the answer to the questions they are looking for, but sacrifice themselves to do it. It is both beautiful and terrible. How did you decide to end the story here? In your mind, did Anna make it in this strange world?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25662 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/chamber-5264172_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/chamber-5264172_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/chamber-5264172_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/chamber-5264172_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/chamber-5264172_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/chamber-5264172_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div>Alice: At its core, after all the fun Sci-Fi concepts, this story is about the endurance of queer love through death. Viv was able to make it through the mirror and find the possibility of a new world waiting on the other side. I wanted to end this story with the main character finding self love, the chance of something far more terrifying than death, and the hope that Anna is alive all perched on the other side of the mirror. In the end, there is no answer about Anna because the potential for Anna to be alive is what matters most for Vivian. Vivian believes that Anna is alive if she didn&#8217;t die in that box and by the end of the story, she receives that hope. All three of the women in this story transcend death in their own ways.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 046 Author Interview: Jennifer Shelby and &#8220;The Voiceless of Shalott&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-jennifer-shelby-and-the-voiceless-of-shalott/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-jennifer-shelby-and-the-voiceless-of-shalott/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 046]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We love getting to know our Issue 046 authors a little better, just as much&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We love getting to know our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-046/">Issue 046</a> authors a little better, just as much as we love reading their stories! Today we talked with Jennifer Shelby about her thoughts and inspirations behind &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-voiceless-of-shalott/">The Voiceless of Shalott</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your story starts with a powerful image of a girl’s voice literally being burned in her throat and taken away. How did this image come to you? Does it have a deeper meaning?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25583 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-641528_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-641528_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-641528_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-641528_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-641528_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-641528_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Jennifer: <span lang="EN-CA">In that scene I wanted to externalize the violence of being silenced. It is a cruel and devastating act that is often overlooked, ignored, and reasoned away because it happens in secret and the aftermath remains inside our private worlds. By pulling this outside of Tasilinn’s mind and placing it in the physical world, I hoped to break what may be the reader’s habit of seeing silencing in this way and to show it as the violence it truly is.</span></p>
<p><span lang="EN-CA">My own experience of being silenced was with weaponized religion and I wanted that to present in this scene. From there, the idea of Tasilinn’s parents stuffing her throat with pages of their scripture and lighting them on fire to burn out her voice spilled onto the page organically.</span></p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Not allowed off island without being able to speak, Tasilinn looks for other ways to show her voice. Do you believe many who are sent to the island end up testing their boundaries? Is the message she finds an indication of this?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: I think so. I was sixteen when I escaped the cult I based this story upon. When I had finally healed enough to look back, which took about a decade, I was surprised and delighted to discover that the majority of my peers from those years had broken free themselves. We all fought individual battles to gain freedom over our lives, very much alone, and with whatever tools we found at our disposal. The message that Tasilinn finds scratched under her desk acts as a catalyst for her, but I think that it was written as a tiny act of defiance on the part of the writer and without any great intention to influence another person. In hindsight, I’ve often wondered what messages my old peer group left for each other that we may have only seen as little rebellions when they happened.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tasilinn struggles with what has been done to her, though no one around her seems to give it a thought. What kind of</strong></em> <em><strong>world</strong><strong> allows someone to suffer while others blatantly disregard her struggles?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: The girls are sent to the Island of Shalott in this story because it’s a place where they can exist, but hidden. The cruelty is never public, it is always in a private space where the abusers are protected from scrutiny. The Faithful in this story have created an insular community where their motives are justified via their faith and their ideals. There is no one to point out the audacity of their actions and their acts have become deeply embedded into their identity as a religion. I think this happens often in society and I think it’s vital to our personal agency to be able to recognize it as the manifestation of a cult, whether it’s happening to you, someone you love, or if a kind of cult mentality begins to infect your own worldview.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: A lot of this story is about the intersection of undeserved Faith and the lies her parent believe. What other layers are present?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25582 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-5884203_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-5884203_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-5884203_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-5884203_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-5884203_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/woman-5884203_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Jennifer: There’s the fight for agency in a life that others presume to own and dictate. I think that’s also true of Tennyson’s Lady of Shalott. In the original poem, the Lady is locked away in a tower and told that if she looks down to the kingdom directly, rather than through a mirror, an unknown curse will fall upon her. We never learn her name, that Lady’s, and the only agency we see her perform in the original poem is when she defies fate and looks down at a knight (Lancelot) through her window. It’s beautiful but also meaningless and wasteful unless you realize that this glance is her choosing a moment of freedom over this rigid set of rules that would hold her captive all her life. Tasilinn doesn’t know what awaits if she manages to escape the tower, but there is a desperate creativity that comes to her in her worst hours that she clings to and follows because she can sense the choice inside of it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-jennifer-shelby-and-the-voiceless-of-shalott/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 046 Author Interview: Elizabeth McEntee and &#8220;Perihelia&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-elizabeth-mcentee-and-perihelia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 11:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 046]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Did you know Issue 046 is our biggest issue yet? That means more reading fun,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-046/">Issue 046</a> is our biggest issue yet? That means more reading fun, and more author interviews to go around! Today we&#8217;re visiting with Elizabeth McEntee about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/perihelia/">Perihelia</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: A combination of worlds, this story has elements of real and not real as well as science and metaphysics. In terms of allegory and science, where does your story lie?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25530 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/space-1486556_1280-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/space-1486556_1280-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/space-1486556_1280-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/space-1486556_1280-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/space-1486556_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Elizabeth: I was really into science fiction as a kid, but have been gravitating toward fantasy more as an adult. I think it&#8217;s because fantasy, to me, really captures a sense of wonder and also a sense of narrative malleability that doesn&#8217;t need a scientific explanation at every step. I love that freedom within total suspension of disbelief. And sometimes it&#8217;s there in sci-fi, too, the &#8220;soft&#8221; sort. I hadn&#8217;t written any science fiction in a while before I wrote this, so while writing &#8220;Perihelia&#8221; one of my goals was to create something that was as close to fantasy as possible while having some anchor onto the scientific. I opted for a comet as that anchor, as I find them fascinating and poetic. I think, perhaps, there is a lot of worth in &#8220;soft&#8221; science fiction, because it allows the reader to start to believe that things in fantasy may be one day possible, somehow. Including being able to be turned into an ice monster willingly. But that&#8217;s the next question.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: A love story at the core, Berene’s backstory is hinted at, but not explored. How much pain did she experience to make her leave humanity and become a self-isolated entity? </b></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: Berene is the character who received more of myself. I would rather not be human for various reasons. Berene felt the same, though I never really specified to myself exactly what her reasoning was, though it likely had something to do with the prospect of relative immortality and some degree of alienation from society, as well as personal fantasies that could be made true. It was definitely not because of Soleia, though. It was something that Berene had been struggling with much before becoming romantically involved with Soleia, and it ended up being a hard choice she decided she had to make. Self-fulfillment (and self-preservation) over love, even at great expense of quality of life.</p>
<p>A topic that interests me is the concept of what happens after a stable state is achieved. I suppose the classic form of this is &#8220;what happens after happily-ever-after,&#8221; but I think of it specifically from a transhumanist perspective, and perhaps Berene&#8217;s path is one that is similar to a rather isolated version of transhumanism. And a bit bleak, by some people&#8217;s standards, but I can&#8217;t say Berene made the wrong choice. It&#8217;s what she felt like she had to do, because everything was pointing toward it as the escape from her mortal human life. If you&#8217;re in a burning house and there&#8217;s a clear exit right in front of you to a snowy expanse, you&#8217;re going to want to make a run for it and deal with the snow later.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: Soleia is a little like her fiance, in that she doesn’t do anything halfway. She has come across space to find her love, with no way back. What does this say about her character and her story?</b> </em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I appreciate you saying that, they really are alike, in a bit of a mismatched way. She has a different set of values, but that same focus on those values. And the same shortsightedness. But with Soleia, her path ended up being a bit more tragic than I even intended. She was originally intended to be the warmth pushing back into Berene&#8217;s icy world, but while writing, I realized that her warmth, Berene, left her a long time ago. So it had to go the way it did. Soleia&#8217;s goal was to get her own life back, by being with Berene, with the vague assumption that Berene in her &#8220;ascended&#8221; form would be able to figure out what to do next&#8230;which, as it turned out, was not the case.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: At the end, Berene was able to find some of her humanity to be with her fiancé, even if it was in death. The scene of them forever entwined and preserved on a comet of dust and ice is a haunting one. What was the hardest moment of this story to write?</b> </em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: Well, first&#8230;it&#8217;s not death for Berene, at least. This perihelion was not about to be the last for the comet. And maybe it&#8217;s not death for Soleia, if the attempt at suspended animation was successful. My thought about this situation is this: Berene can&#8217;t take her attention away from Soleia or else she&#8217;ll likely start to thaw, and Soleia can&#8217;t be thawed without being able to breathe. So they&#8217;re both stuck there unless someone finds them, which is unlikely. But possible. But very unlikely. Anyway, this isn&#8217;t an answer to the actual question.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25531 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ice-crystal-2871068_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ice-crystal-2871068_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ice-crystal-2871068_1920-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ice-crystal-2871068_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ice-crystal-2871068_1920-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ice-crystal-2871068_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>I suppose this may not be the answer you were hoping for, but the hardest moments of this story to write were all in the first third or so. I had an entirely different draft for the first several pages&#8217; worth, as I was writing this to be a more lighthearted story at first. However, I feel like I naturally tend toward drama of the sort that &#8220;Perihelia&#8221; ended up becoming, so when I saw where it was going, I let it slide that way. And then, as a very helpful friend pointed out, I ended up with a story that had a massive shift in tone. So, it made a lot more sense to rework the beginning, and I&#8217;m glad I did, because I&#8217;m much happier with the final version. Writing my lovely couple to their probable doom was a lot more fluid for me, because, again, it just had to go the way it did, at least in my mind. That said, I did find myself becoming very emotionally invested, and emotionally depleted after I wrote the ending. But there&#8217;s catharsis in that, and I think that&#8217;s worth it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 046 Author Interview: Laurel Beckley and &#8220;Love and War Aboard the Peregrine Zircon&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-laurel-beckley-and-love-and-war-aboard-the-peregrine-zircon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 046]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25490</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We love stories about magic, and we love sci-fi stories with cool tech. What happens&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We love stories about magic, and we love sci-fi stories with cool tech. What happens when the two combine? Well, &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/love-and-war-aboard-the-peregrine-zircon/">Love and War Aboard the Peregrine Zircon</a>,&#8221; for example! Read on for <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-046/">Issue 046</a> author Laurel Beckley&#8217;s expert melding process.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story was exciting from the get-go, a blend of not only love and war (as your title states) but technology and magic. How did adding magic affect your dieselpunk fantasy, ramping up the stakes?</strong></em></p>
<div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-25496 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Final_countdown_1980-193x300.jpg" alt="" width="193" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Final_countdown_1980-193x300.jpg 193w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Final_countdown_1980.jpg 253w" sizes="(max-width: 193px) 100vw, 193px" />Laurel: I got the idea from this wild movie called <i>The Final Countdown </i>(1980)<i> </i>about a (then) modern-day aircraft carrier that somehow travels back in time to December 6, 1941. There are so many stories about magical sailing ships, why not a magical aircraft carrier?</div>
<div></div>
<div>There are no &#8220;big&#8221; magics in my world—much of it is small or made larger with collaboration, like a weather circle or operating the engine room—and because warfare is a never-ending game of one-upmanship, it made sense (at least, it does to me) that magical naval battles would end up marrying air- and sea-power like this as a form of power projection. I tried to work the magic in as organically as possible to fit with the technology, tactics and mindset, along with countermeasures to combat the advances in magical technology (for example, the shimmer blocking scrying capabilities).</div>
</div>
<div>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: You were able to cleverly incorporate tension and foreboding by using Reva’s intuition. I love how the other characters trusted her gut and believed her instincts, not having to prove this part of her (especially not at 97% accuracy). What gave you the idea for this kind of personal magic? Does intuition translate personally for you in the real world?</strong></em></p>
<div>Laurel: I wanted to write a naval battle story about someone who wasn&#8217;t in a stereotypically sexy military role (pilot, gunner, combat arms, etc), but who was instrumental nevertheless (and a little magical). There are fantasy books with seers and mystics, but I needed something a little more nebulous, because Reva wanted to become a pilot and they&#8217;re probably not going to let a seer pilot an aircraft (a mid-flight vision would be disastrous). The fact that Reva&#8217;s magic manifests as something like cramps was an homage (of sorts) to the woman&#8217;s intuition cliché, menstrual cramps and stress-based ulcers—and to the phrase &#8220;Make a decision, Lieutenant!&#8221; which features in many a young officer&#8217;s nightmares.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I&#8217;m a fairly gullible/non-intuitive person (even when taking into account the fact that intuition and common sense are subjective), so Reva is a bit of a wish-fulfillment, in that she has magical intuition that will lead her in the right direction—if she listens to it and interprets it correctly. She is already capable, but her magic gives her an edge that adds to her credibility.</div>
<p><span class="im"> </span></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The tactical details are very specific and interwoven seamlessly with your world. Do you have a military background or just know how to spin a good story?</strong></em></p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>Laurel: I was a captain in the Marine Corps and have no naval experience beyond one summer on a landing ship dock (or LSD, which is an amphibious warfare ship that launches amphibious boats from its well deck—super cool, by the way—and in my ship&#8217;s case, helicopters from the flight deck) when I was an NROTC midshipman. They had no idea what to do with a Marine Option and I had no idea what to do on a ship, so they stuck me on the bridge with the navigators and I bumbled my way around for a month.</div>
<div></div>
<div>That summer in no way prepared me to write a story about an aircraft carrier, nor am I well-versed in naval warfare. To prepare, I toured the <i>USS North Carolina</i> (a battleship, not a carrier); studied up on the <i>USS Enterprise </i>(of WWII fame, not the interstellar craft or the first nuclear carrier) and battle group composition; pulled inspiration from tactics used in the Battle of Midway and the Battle of Coral Sea; grilled a retired Navy friend who served quite a few tours on carriers; and conducted online searches that probably have me on several watchlists. Once I felt I had a decent-ish handle on the basics, I took all that information and tweaked it to be *magical*, with many liberties on condensing/rearranging things to work within the narrative (and probably quite a few errors, too).</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: If you were going to categorize your story into a specific genre, what would it be? What were the major influences to write it the way you did?</strong></em></div>
<div>
<p><span style="color: #1d1c1d; font-family: Arial;">Laurel: I&#8217;d call it dieselpunk fantasy with a dash of space (high seas?) opera. Although <i>aircraft carrier</i> might feel modern, the terminology, equipment, layout, etc., are all based on WWII-era craft.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #1d1c1d; font-family: Arial;">My major influences for this piece are <i>We Rule the Night</i> by Claire Eliza Bartlett (a YA fantasy re-<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-25497 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rule-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rule-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/rule.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" />imagining of the Soviet Night Witches that marries magic and tech and is super cool), <i>Once a Hero </i>by Elizabeth Moon (a Marine who writes military space opera and often features non-infantry/combat arms-centric main characters), and <i>Captain Vorpatril&#8217;s Alliance </i>by Lois McMaster Bujold (okay, really the entire Vorkosigan series, where the main message is that losing your heart&#8217;s desire isn&#8217;t the end of everything but is a redirection instead, but in this particularly book I finally found out what Ivan did for a living, which was sorting, compiling and ordering information according to priority). And, of course, <i>The Final Countdown.</i></span></p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 046 Author Interview: Mara Regan and &#8220;Lemon&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-mara-regan-and-lemon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 10:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 046]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 046 is a gift that keeps on giving&#8211;we still have plenty of author interviews&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-046/">Issue 046</a> is a gift that keeps on giving&#8211;we still have plenty of author interviews to share! Today&#8217;s shining star is Mara Regan as she shares her thoughts on her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/lemon/">Lemon</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story feels more than lovely, it feels genuinely affectionate and tender, and I just adored it. What inspired you to write this?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25487 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/sliced-lemon-667554_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/sliced-lemon-667554_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/sliced-lemon-667554_1920-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/sliced-lemon-667554_1920-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/sliced-lemon-667554_1920-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/sliced-lemon-667554_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Mara: Thank you, that means a lot! In the last few years my family has experienced loss, and I’ve been touched and inspired by the various ways I’ve witnessed my family members grieve, how they connect their loved ones to objects and feelings. Sometimes in fantasy when a character dies their story just ends with them, and what happens after they’re gone gets overlooked. I thought I’d focus on a character living on a little longer after they’re gone in a way that everyone who reads the story can understand, bringing the magic of real life into the fantasy.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I really appreciate how you indicate the shortness of a goblin’s life by comparison to a human’s; so often in fantasy literature we see things done the other way around, where everyone else lives longer. It particularly added a bit of melancholy when suddenly we’re reading about a human’s funeral. Did you know how far you wanted to go with Whisper’s life when you began writing this story?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Mara: I can see the appeal of working with long life spans for an epic fantasy, but when it comes to a short story, I’m glad I stuck to a sort of mayfly mentality—for my own sake! I’m glad the sudden jump to the funeral was noticed. I wanted the reader to feel like Whisper’s time was moving fast, but also feel the significance that she’d lived long enough to attend a human friend’s funeral. I knew from the beginning that I couldn’t write Whisper’s death if her view on grief was the point of the tale, so I had to find a point at which to end her story that supplied a bit of catharsis. And how better than to give her the one thing she wanted, a diploma?</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This feels like a fascinating beginning to a series of academy stories. Would you ever consider writing more in this world? </strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25488 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/book-1052014_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/book-1052014_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/book-1052014_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/book-1052014_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/book-1052014_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/book-1052014_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Mara: How did you know? I have a ton of little fantasies in the world of &#8220;Lemon&#8221; that I’m looking forward to presenting. I love work by writers like Terry Pratchett, where different stories in the same world are unexpectedly connected, and the world itself is filled with satirical institutions, fantasy versions of schools, restaurants, and libraries. At the same time, I am querying for my debut novel, a fantasy/science-fiction set in a lawless desert with an old western theme turned on its head.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 046 Author Interview: B. Zelkovich and &#8220;That Which Illuminates Heaven&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-b-zelkovich-and-that-which-illuminates-heaven/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-b-zelkovich-and-that-which-illuminates-heaven/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 12:25:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 046]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anyone want a triple helping of Issue 046 author interviews? We&#8217;re here with B. Zelkovich&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anyone want a triple helping of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-046/">Issue 046</a> author interviews? We&#8217;re here with B. Zelkovich to finish off the week with her thoughts on &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/that-which-illuminates-heaven/">That Which Illuminates Heaven</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This is so beautiful! What a delight, and I loved the little mystery in the beginning as I came to realize just who Amaterasu was. What gave you the inspiration for this fantastic story, and especially for Amaterasu?</strong></em></p>
<p>B.: Thank you! I really tried to make that particular mystery unravel in an organic way which was a fun challenge &#8212; I&#8217;m glad you enjoyed it! I don&#8217;t think I can pinpoint any one source of inspiration for the story. I knew I had these two women who were in love, but couldn&#8217;t be together, and wrote almost 4000 words of story shifting between their two perspectives, but it was coming out very &#8220;Ender&#8217;s Game&#8221; and it just really fizzled out until I had no interest in the piece. But I loved Ezra and Ashton and refused to give up, so I tried changing POV characters and tenses, but nothing stuck. And then, one early morning, I sat at the computer and my mind whispered, &#8220;tell it from the ship&#8217;s perspective.&#8221; I thought that was crazy and it would never work, but I had nothing else to try so I gave it a shot. I think the story came together in about two days after that.</p>
<p>With Amaterasu, I was really intentional about picking a name that wasn&#8217;t from the Western Canon. In Science Fiction so many spaceships are named for Greek and Roman mythology or <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-25429 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-towner-CakC6u4d95g-unsplash-300x238.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="238" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-towner-CakC6u4d95g-unsplash-300x238.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-towner-CakC6u4d95g-unsplash-1024x812.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-towner-CakC6u4d95g-unsplash-768x609.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-towner-CakC6u4d95g-unsplash-1536x1218.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-towner-CakC6u4d95g-unsplash-2048x1624.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />European or American historical figures. I wanted to avoid that, and had heard of &#8220;Amaterasu&#8221; from Kieron Gillen&#8217;s graphic novel series &#8220;The Wicked + the Divine&#8221;, so decided to do a little more research into the name. The literal translation is &#8220;That Which Illuminates Heaven&#8221; and I knew instantly that would be the title of the story. I was also playing a lot of <i>Mass Effect: Andromeda</i> at the time, so I had fully realized AI on the brain.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There’s so much goodness packed into this it’s hard to pick my favorite parts, but I love the idea of speaking to different people in languages only they can understand. If Amaterasu had to speak to you, what language would they use?</strong></em></p>
<p>B.: Oh my goodness, what a doozy of a question! I want to say something writerly &#8212; keyboard <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-25431 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-tecuceanu-4QxgkxNaGJ0-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-tecuceanu-4QxgkxNaGJ0-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-tecuceanu-4QxgkxNaGJ0-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-tecuceanu-4QxgkxNaGJ0-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-tecuceanu-4QxgkxNaGJ0-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/john-tecuceanu-4QxgkxNaGJ0-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />tapping, coffee dripping, the susurrus of pages flipping &#8212; but really it would probably be nature sounds. I&#8217;m really fond of hiking, especially anywhere near the ocean. The wind in Sitka Spruce trees and the sound of waves crashing on cliffs is probably the most direct route to my heart.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The revelations in this story still surprise me even though they’re not the jump-scare type. I got a real <i>Alien</i> vibe for a second, and was pleased you went a different way. Have you thought about revisiting Ezra and Ashton and their adventures?</strong></em></p>
<p>B.: I definitely wanted the tension of the story to hinge on the relationship between Ezra and Ashton, so I tried not to delve too much into what happens outside of the ship. For me, I haven&#8217;t really considered revisiting these characters. While I tried to make it clear that there&#8217;s still a lot of work for Ezra and Ashton to do to repair the hurt between them, to me theirs is a happy ending. Amaterasu accomplished her goal. Although, it could be fun to see more of their adventures, so I&#8217;ll never say never!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-b-zelkovich-and-that-which-illuminates-heaven/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 046 Author Interview: Maeghan Klinker and &#8220;Mother Haskell&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-maeghan-klinker-and-mother-haskell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 11:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 046]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25273</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You&#8217;re in for a treat, dear readers! Today&#8217;s Issue 046 author interview brings us Maeghan&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;re in for a treat, dear readers! Today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-046/">Issue 046</a> author interview brings us Maeghan Klinker&#8217;s thoughts and inspirations behind &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/mother-haskell/">Mother Haskell</a>,&#8221; and it comes with a sweet recipe, to boot!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This is such a beautiful little fairy tale, and even better, it left me wanting pie! I have to ask—do you have a favorite apple pie recipe? Would you consider sharing it with hungry readers?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25422 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-pie-5870542_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-pie-5870542_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-pie-5870542_1920-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-pie-5870542_1920-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-pie-5870542_1920-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apple-pie-5870542_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Maeghan: I can&#8217;t say that I have a favorite apple pie recipe, but I do have an apple crumble that I love to make and it was the inspiration for Mother Haskell&#8217;s baking scene! It&#8217;s a bit of a hodgepodge recipe, and like all the best recipes it&#8217;s missing some measurements&#8211;that&#8217;s the magic of it I suppose, you have to feel it in your bones.</p>
<div><u>Ingredients</u></div>
<div>4 large sweet potatoes</div>
<div>2 Tbs. butter, melted</div>
<div>1/2 cup maple syrup</div>
<div>2 large apples, peeled, cored, sliced</div>
<div>cinnamon</div>
<div>ground cloves</div>
<div>1/2 cup apple juice (the secret ingredient is spiced apple cider!)</div>
<div></div>
<div>For the crumble top:</div>
<div>flour, oats, brown sugar, butter, chopped pecans (if the urge strikes me, I&#8217;ll sprinkle in some dried cranberries as well)</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<ol>
<li>Preheat oven to 350 degrees Fahrenheit</li>
<li>Cook sweet potatoes until done but still firm and cut into 1/2 inch slices</li>
<li>Oil (butter) a deep casserole dish</li>
<li>Arrange 1/2 sweet potatoes on bottom</li>
<li>Drizzle with 1/2 of butter and maple syrup</li>
<li>Top with 1/2 of apple slices</li>
<li>Sprinkle with cinnamon and cloves</li>
<li>Repeat layers</li>
<li>Then pour the apple juice over the top</li>
<li>Cover and bake for 45 min, then remove from oven and top with crumble ingredients</li>
<li>Bake with crumble top for another 10-20 min or until golden brown</li>
<li>Enjoy!</li>
</ol>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: You’re clearly very deft at integrating a lot of worldbuilding over a short space. I’m left intrigued by the thought of which really <i>is</i> better for corpse roads, silver or iron horseshoes. Did you consider expanding this short story, maybe to include a Death point of view, or is it exactly how you always envisioned it now?</strong></em></p>
<p>Maeghan: &#8220;Mother Haskell&#8221; actually started out as a chapter in a short collection of interwoven tales that I wrote as part of a gift exchange my writing group did around the holidays. Each person in the group came up with three prompts for a story that they wanted to hear and then their secret writer wrote those stories for them. The prompt for &#8220;Mother Haskell&#8221; was to write a story featuring your favorite dessert, and so &#8220;Mother Haskell&#8221; was born!  In the original version, the three short stories were loosely connected by a narrative frame of someone telling stories to a child on a dark winter&#8217;s night, so in that respect this version of &#8220;Mother Haskell&#8221; is slightly different, but without the other tales around it, it doesn&#8217;t really need the same narrative frame.</p>
<div>I don&#8217;t think that I would expand this short story, but it is interwoven into a larger fictional universe in my head. I&#8217;m dreaming up two longer stories that are not directly connected to &#8220;Mother Haskell&#8221;, but one features Death as a main character and the other is centered on a descendant of Mother Haskell&#8217;s set in a town where everyone can see ghosts. The stories aren&#8217;t directly related, but the legend of Mother Haskell will probably end up making a cameo in one of those as part of the world building of that story.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What were your inspirations for this story? Any particular legends or myths?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25421 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apples-1873078_1920-300x192.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="192" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apples-1873078_1920-300x192.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apples-1873078_1920-1024x654.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apples-1873078_1920-768x490.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apples-1873078_1920-1536x981.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/apples-1873078_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div>Maeghan: I&#8217;ve always been very interested in fairy tales and folklore, so when I was writing this story I was really trying to channel the feeling and weight that those stories carry. They can be magical and whimsical, but they can also be very dark. They&#8217;re warnings and lessons, they share fears and they tell you how the world works. I didn&#8217;t consciously think of any one fairy tale or piece of folklore when I was writing this story, but looking back on it now, it does remind me a little of the the story about Godfather Death (or in some versions Godmother Death) in the way it humanizes Death as a character. I also like to write about trees, especially magical trees, so obviously I had to work those in. A lot of fairy tales tend to have magical tree elements, so I think that helped contribute to the folkloric feel of the story. A fairy tale I find fascinating with a semi-magical tree is The Almond Tree (also called The Juniper Tree, or The Rose Tree if the protagonist is a girl), and now that I&#8217;m thinking about it, there is some pie baking in that, although it is a very different sort of pie baking from Mother Haskell&#8217;s pies (yeah, you guessed it, it&#8217;s cannibalism). So while I wasn&#8217;t consciously channeling any fairy tales or folklore, I think they can&#8217;t help but slip in. They&#8217;re the kind of stories that plant themselves beneath your skin and keep flowering in unexpected ways in the stories that I write.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 046 Author Interview: Britt Foster and &#8220;Helix&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-046-author-interview-britt-foster-and-helix/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 11:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 046]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ready for a futuristic, sci-fi take on a classic monster? Go read &#8220;Helix&#8221; in Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ready for a futuristic, sci-fi take on a classic monster? Go read &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/helix/">Helix</a>&#8221; in <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-046/">Issue 046</a>, then come right back here to find out what inspired author Britt Foster to write such an epic tale.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story is so exciting! It ended just the way I hoped it would too. I found it so satisfying, so thanks for that <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I love the scope of this story, and how you blend classical monster imagery with a futuristic vision. What gave you the idea for &#8220;Helix&#8221;?</strong></em></p>
<p>Britt: I’m so happy to hear you enjoyed the story! The idea for &#8220;Helix&#8221; started with a vague desire to write about genetically engineered vampires. Genetic engineering has always fascinated me, especially when it comes to tweaking the DNA of humans, because it offers unlimited possibilities for humans to control of their own evolution. There’s a lot of controversy in the real world about <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-25379 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/national-cancer-institute-tV-RX0beDp8-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/national-cancer-institute-tV-RX0beDp8-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/national-cancer-institute-tV-RX0beDp8-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/national-cancer-institute-tV-RX0beDp8-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/national-cancer-institute-tV-RX0beDp8-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/national-cancer-institute-tV-RX0beDp8-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />whether we should go down that path, but can we stop ourselves?—we already have the technology to get started, after all. It makes me wonder what the mega-rich and/or powers-that-be are already doing in their secret laboratories.</p>
<div>This curiosity about what goes on in secret laboratories probably has a lot to do with my childhood. I grew up in a town based entirely around “The Lab”, and there were always whispers about secret experiments being conducted, especially in the canyons. My classmates had wild stories to evidence this, and when we would ask our parents about the rumors, we were warned not to chase after classified information (which was spooky and made us want to chase even more).</div>
<div></div>
<div>One popular story involved a boy noticing armored cars driving around in the canyons and deciding to follow them. He came across a garage door in the canyon wall, broke in, and found a second door inside with a sign that read, “proceeding further may result in death”. The boy got out of there as fast as he could and hid in the bushes, only to have several armored cars go flying past him minutes later. There were also stories about The Lab having captive extraterrestrials. I remember being shown a Youtube video about a man who claimed he was part of the alien project and, after speaking to the public about it, was mysteriously found dead.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“Helix” is the final result of several abandoned attempts to follow the genetically engineered vampire thread. I probably wrote about 50,000 words, with different characters and different plots, before I sketched out “Helix”. It was like molding clay—I played with the material a lot before I finally settled on a shape I liked.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The genetic engineering aspect of this was fascinating. How did you decide what traits you wanted Helix to have? What made you want to design in something like her darkened sclera? (Also, your description of her eyes was my favorite line in this fantastic story.)</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p>Britt: The chimeric adaptations came from my fantasy of what a perfect superhuman would be. They needed to be more in tune with nature to save the planet from human destruction. They needed to be smarter, stronger, more empathetic, and a little more animal/instinctual/intuitive. They needed to consume fewer resources.</p>
<div></div>
<div>The vampiric aspect of the chimeras comes from my lifelong fascination with vampires. I love that vampires have the ability to survive without killing anything, plant or animal or otherwise, and the way they’re often depicted as senseless killers frustrates me. They could easily just take a few sips of blood and let their victims go on living, so why don’t they? Self-control shouldn’t be so hard for a creature than can live for centuries.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I like the idea of vampires that are more evolved than humans. I like the idea of them being more in tune with their animal selves and /still/ being more evolved than humans. Part of this comes from my interest in shadow work, which involves looking at the parts of ourselves we usually hide from, and thereby recognizing ourselves as whole—good and bad—instead of pretending we’re 100% good all the time. Humans often pretend they’re better than animals, good and pure and right, when in reality, humans are just animals wearing clothes, turning a blind eye to their dark sides. I think vampires speak to unconscious processes within humanity; we survive on the life force of other beings, we chase immortality through various avenues, and we are predators—/the/ predators, preying on the entire planet—beneath our veneer of morality.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I wanted to create a human that sips on life force instead of guzzling it, a human that takes only what it needs instead of spilling blood all down its chin in the epitome of wastefulness and excess.</div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-25381 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/joshua-rodriguez-9OqkIhgYzO0-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/joshua-rodriguez-9OqkIhgYzO0-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/joshua-rodriguez-9OqkIhgYzO0-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/joshua-rodriguez-9OqkIhgYzO0-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/joshua-rodriguez-9OqkIhgYzO0-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/joshua-rodriguez-9OqkIhgYzO0-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />The darkened sclera is mainly an aesthetic choice. I think it looks cool. The imagery of something that appears demonic but is designed to save the planet satisfies me. It also plays into shadow work, especially in regard to our “demons”/flaws often serving some deeper purpose, such as protecting or teaching us. What looks demonic and scary is often just something that’s misunderstood, something we need to look at, accept, and work with. When we befriend our demons, they cease to have power over us. They don’t lash out unexpectedly and make us do things we regret, like they do when they’re invisible.</div>
<div></div>
<div>When we can /see/ the blood on our chins, we can make an effort to drink less of it.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: &#8220;Helix&#8221; reads almost like a prequel to a larger concept, a longer story. Do you have any plans to continue this adventure?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p>Britt: Yes, &#8220;Helix” is a prequel to a larger concept. I’ve been working on a novel about the chimeras for a couple years, but it’s been messy and unpredictable throughout. After changing the plot and timeline several times and still not knowing where to go, I decided to write a short story so I’d have something less huge to gather all my ideas into. It was very helpful in that regard!</p>
<div></div>
<div>I do plan to continue this adventure, and I have a much clearer idea now about what happens.</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
