<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 045 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-045/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 10:29:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 045 Author Interview: Sam Grieve and &#8220;The Garden of Extinction&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-045-author-interview-sam-grieve-and-the-garden-of-extinction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 20:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 045]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[And so we&#8217;ve reached our final Issue 045 author interview. We hope you&#8217;ve enjoyed these&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>And so we&#8217;ve reached our final <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-045/">Issue 045</a> author interview. We hope you&#8217;ve enjoyed these stories, and our authors&#8217; wise words about them, as much as we did! Now let&#8217;s have Sam Grieve wrap things up with some answers to our burning questions about &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-garden-of-extinction/">The Garden of Extinction</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The first indication of Kedu’s age is in reference to her mother’s scarf. How does Kedu’s extremely advanced years (and being the cause of it) frame her life?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24952 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/eden-1746757_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/eden-1746757_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/eden-1746757_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/eden-1746757_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/eden-1746757_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/eden-1746757_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Sam: The spark for this story came from a trip I took to Kirstenbosch Gardens in Cape Town, South Africa, where I found myself walking through a real Garden of Extinction. My mind began to wander, and before I knew it the premise for this story was conceived—a futuristic world, where genetically modified crops cover most of the earth, science has led to a significant increase in lifespan, and the lucky inhabitants live confident in the knowledge that earth’s lost biodiversity has apparently been backed up on a secret planet. Soon after this, Kedu made her appearance; long-lived, clear-minded, and cantankerous. We meet her on her last night on earth, as she finally faces the destiny she has spent decades and decades waiting for—her opportunity to travel to the Garden. The reader learns that Kedu has lived the dream of an extended lifespan, but what becomes apparent in the story is that this long life has not necessarily brought her happiness. Instead, she lost those she loved the most when she was still young, and her adult relationships did not achieve their potential, mostly because Kedu could never give enough of herself. Instead, she spent her years helping build a utopian society where hunger is unknown and lives extend far beyond their natural limits.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The book is a vehicle for Kedu’s memories and, in some ways, her regrets. Which do you think is the stronger pull of what wakes her in the night?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Sam: I believe it is a combination. I have witnessed in my own family the power that memory exerts on the very elderly and especially how identity is firmly rooted in early experience. It is this theme that interests me as writer and I do find myself returning to it again and again in different pieces. In terms of structure in this particular work, Kedu’s midnight exploration through the book allowed me to reveal the story of her life, as other than her walking from her bedroom to the study, there is no real action in the plot. The story arc hinges on her emotional journey as she confronts memory, regret, loss, and finally, a personal reckoning.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Kedu will not let those that come for her know she doesn&#8217;t believe in their Garden and even refuses her cane on principle. How is it that she figured out their lie?</strong></em></p>
<p>Sam: Subconsciously, Kedu has known for most her life that the Garden is, in all likelihood, a fiction. She first hears about it from her grandfather, but it is only after he leaves that she begins to doubt its existence. She is a clever woman, but this doubt is in direct conflict with her desperate desire to believe, and so she locks it away &#8220;in the carpentry of her heart.&#8221; In writing Kedu, I wanted to investigate, within the tight parameters of a short piece of fiction, the power of self-delusion. Like many people throughout history, Kedu commits herself to a particular viewpoint/interpretation/story and questioning its veracity would undermine all the choices she has made. The mere act of doubting, or disbelieving, would not only nullify all her work, but she would also have to face up to the fact that she, a genetic botanist, has been complicit in the destruction of the natural world. It is only on this last night that Kedu finally finds the courage to admit the truth.</p>
<p>And the walking without the cane&#8230;? Well, this is characteristic of her personality. Kedu is proud; even in this darkest moment of her life she would not wish to show weakness.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: It seems that everyone she knows has either died on Earth or “gone ahead”, while she worked tirelessly. Are these some of the factors as to why she “will surrender herself to the dream”?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Sam: No, I would not say that. At the end of the story, alone in the darkness, Kedu imagines the day ahead and gives herself a mental pep talk. She will be brave. She will walk without a cane. She will go out with style. For all of her adult life, Kedu’s belief system has been predicated on the existence of the Garden, but now, at the end, she acknowledges that her upcoming voyage is political theater, the shining pod is not a spaceship but a coffin, and that there is no paradise planet at the end of her journey. And yet, despite all the courage she plans to harness so she that she can face her death with dignity, Kedu still wishes to believe that this heaven exists. In fact, the only way she can be courageous, is to believe in it. This imperative, of course, is entirely human. It is hope.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you so much for letting me write about &#8220;The Garden of Extinction&#8221; in further detail. I wrote<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24951 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/book-5174879_1920-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/book-5174879_1920-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/book-5174879_1920-682x1024.jpg 682w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/book-5174879_1920-768x1154.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/book-5174879_1920-1022x1536.jpg 1022w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/book-5174879_1920.jpg 1278w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /> this story a number of years ago, so it has been an interesting experience to revisit Kedu’s world. I do think that both as a writer, and somebody who has been a literature student, this exercise has made me realize how instinctual a process writing is. I don’t believe that when I was working on the piece, and knee deep in Kedu’s point of view, I could have discussed it like this. I hope I have helped elucidate some of the themes, but I also believe that short stories are like a scant handful of a character’s life, so hopefully there are still some questions left unanswered!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 045 Author Interview: Hayli McClain and &#8220;Heaven-Bound&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-045-author-interview-hayli-mcclain-and-heaven-bound/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 11:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 045]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Would you like another double helping of Issue 045 author interviews? We&#8217;re happy to deliver!&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Would you like another double helping of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-045/">Issue 045</a> author interviews? We&#8217;re happy to deliver! Today we&#8217;re talking with Hayli McClain about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/heaven-bound/">Heaven-Bound</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ:  Percy and Ann are unlikely lovers, and yet what they accomplish together creates a bond and opens the door to a relationship. What else draws them together and what do you see for their future?</strong></em></p>
<p>Hayli: I think their unlikeliness is exactly what makes Percy and Ann perfect for each other. Ann might be the one looking up to the stars, but she&#8217;s also the more grounded and reasonable. Percy, even though she&#8217;s the &#8220;earth girl,&#8221; has the wild courage of old star-written legends. In each other&#8217;s eyes, they see proof of everything they ever dared to believe in. So I&#8217;m sure their future together will be one of constant discovery.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Drawing down the moon is an amazing and transcendent concept. What was it that sparked the idea?</strong></em></p>
<p>Hayli: Above all, &#8220;Heaven-Bound&#8221; is a story about love. Pulling the moon down from the night sky is impossible, but so is the idea that out of almost eight billion people, we could cross paths with the one person capable of knowing and loving us truly. I had the bare-bones concept for this story years ago, and I&#8217;m sure that, subconsciously, part of it came from George Bailey&#8217;s promise to &#8220;lasso the moon&#8221; in <em>It&#8217;s a Wonderful Life! </em>But the idea only found its heart through two of my close friends. Their love is pure and miraculous, like Ann and Percy&#8217;s, and it&#8217;s taught me to believe in the humble impossible.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Ann wondered what Cassiopeia would do if she were free and then encounters Percy trying to lasso the moon. How does this close encounter with the moon change or enforce her ideas about the stars?</strong></em></p>
<p>Hayli: Ann&#8217;s experience definitely reinforces her ideas about the stars. It affirms everything they made her feel over the years: passion, hope, and connection. Several stars and constellations are referenced in the story (my aunt worked in a planetarium, so I grew up on star lore myself) but Cassiopeia stood out as a natural favorite for Ann, representing both the feeling of imprisonment and the strained mother-daughter relationship she references in the story. The mythological queen initially tried to avoid punishment by sacrificing her daughter, Andromeda, from whom Ann gets her name. And who saved Andromeda? Perseus, of course!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: You have several references to singing and music in your story. What influence did the music in your life have on writing this piece?</strong></em></p>
<p>Hayli: I always listen to music when I write. I rely on it for focus and clarity. What are my characters feeling that I can&#8217;t see with words in the way? How can I get this complicated idea across as simply and clearly as possible? I believe the truth in what Victor Hugo once said: &#8220;Music expresses that which cannot be put into words and that which cannot remain silent.&#8221; In a story about love&#8211;especially LGBTQ+ love&#8211;this concept felt important to touch on directly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 045 Author Interview: J.V. Gachs and &#8220;Hubris&#8217; Nest&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-045-author-interview-j-v-gachs-and-hubris-nest/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 11:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 045]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to another Issue 045 author interview! Today&#8217;s star of the show is J.V.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back to another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-045">Issue 045</a> author interview! Today&#8217;s star of the show is J.V. Gachs, here to talk with us about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/hubris-nest/">Hubris&#8217; Nest</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your story begins with a person dying of sheer boredom. Could you explain where you got the idea for this plot point and what it means in the larger world (ours and the story’s)?</strong></em></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24870 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3340888_1920-300x170.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="170" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3340888_1920-300x170.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3340888_1920-1024x579.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3340888_1920-768x434.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3340888_1920-1536x869.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3340888_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />J.V.: Sudden death has been one of my obsessions ever since my grandmother and uncle died suddenly within six months of each other. Both deaths were completely unexpected. The idea that someone could be alive and well –eating a banana as my grandmother was doing– and be dead the next minute terrified me. In addition to this, last summer a good friend died the same way. He was only a couple of years older than me. It was the first time someone in my peer group died. It was really shocking. The untimely death of someone I considered an equal forced me to face my own mortality in a way I had never done before. Writing a humorous story about an expected death was my way of trying to make sense of those feelings. The fact that Hubris&#8217; death is caused by boredom came afterward as a logical result of the worldbuilding.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The worldbuilding in this story is done gradually, letting us know about customs and traditions over time, as it is encountered. It even hints at mythology and history, off the page. Like an iceberg, do you have more of the world mapped out in your mind?</strong></em></p>
<p>J.V.: Yes, I do. This is a fantasy story, set in a secondary world, so once the idea of an immortal tribe facing a death came up, the first thing I had to do was to imagine how their life would be, their world, which rites they would know and which ones they wouldn&#8217;t need, would they have gods, and so on. The worldbuilding process is always fun, and although it&#8217;s a shame you can only show the tip of the iceberg of that work you’ve done, I think it&#8217;s also interesting to leave readers the freedom to fill in the gaps with their own imagination.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There is a lot of contrast in this story that really brings out the differences between our culture and theirs. Their race is so “advanced” that they have forgotten about not only death, but the creation of life too. How else does their “advancement” affect their everyday lives?</strong></em></p>
<p>J.V.: It affects them above all in the way they deal with everyday situations, how they interact with each other, and with their environment. As I see it, it is impossible to live as long as they do without being extremely aware of the patterns in the cycle of life and nature and draw conclusions as to what impact they really have in their surroundings and also how dependent they are on nature for their own survival. They are the spectators of the “eternal recurrence” of nature, but not a part of it. Also, there’s one quotation by Terence I love that reads “Homo sum, humani nihil a me alienum puto” which translates roughly as “I am human, and I consider nothing human alien to me” and I think it’s relevant to this story because living for so long, they would have experienced all the spectrum of human feelings, allowing them to understand each other deeply. Moreover, the fact that they know there is no death coming for them, no afterlife in which they would be held accountable for their actions, has allowed them to naturally develop a Kantian morality based not on punishments and rewards, but on empathy. Doing what’s right just because it has to be done. Considering all this, they lead a quiet peaceful existence with not many surprises or strong emotions.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: A moment of significant pause occurs in this story when “the words anger and selfishness were born in our language”. When writing this part, were there any emotions you were trying to evoke in the readers? Did you consider this to be a regression?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24871 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woodpecker-5429886_1920-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woodpecker-5429886_1920-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woodpecker-5429886_1920-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woodpecker-5429886_1920-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woodpecker-5429886_1920-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woodpecker-5429886_1920-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woodpecker-5429886_1920-550x550.jpg 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/woodpecker-5429886_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>J.V.: When I wrote this part I wasn’t trying to evoke feelings in the reader, as much as I was trying to create a space for reflection. I had in mind, above all, the idea that such an immortal race would have developed a system based on group benefit over individual needs, and, at the same time, those needs would be met by the very work of the system. In fact, they have to face the inconvenience of a tie because everyone&#8217;s opinion is worth the same. No one has power over the others, nor their votes have more value. So, for them, the notion that one of their people could do something without regard for the others is totally alien. That’s why they have to create a word to name such behavior. Furthermore, in a system based on empathy, on understanding the feelings of others, there is no place for anger, but for dialogue. When they find themselves in a situation where they can no longer have a dialogue with Hubris to make him see their point of view or listen to his, they experience anger for the first time. So it’s not truly a regression for them, as much as a lesson on how to cope with silence and with someone that wouldn’t hear you or make the effort to try to understand you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 045 Author Interview: Elin Olausson and &#8220;The Moor&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-045-author-interview-elin-olausson-and-the-moor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 11:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 045]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s an Issue 045 author interview twofer this week! Today we&#8217;re treating you to this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s an <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-045/">Issue 045</a> author interview twofer this week! Today we&#8217;re treating you to this exclusive chat with Elin Olausson on her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-moor/">The Moor</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story is dense with so many layers: spirituality, family traditions, superstition, sequestered geography, and a rich vibrant voice. How would you describe the layers in your story? Which are the most important to your story as a whole?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Elin: To me, “The Moor” is about the dreams and imagination of childhood versus the harsh reality of adult life. The river that Mei longs for symbolizes life and beauty, and she’s upset when she’s told it doesn’t exist because she desperately wants to believe in something beautiful. Mei loves her family, she’ll do anything to protect their way of life, but she has seen and experienced bad things. She clings to the stories that Grandma told her, because she needs something to believe in.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Family is another important theme in the story. Mei is a child growing up in an isolated environment—she has been taught not to trust anyone except her own kin, and to revere her ancestors. When her sister invites a stranger into their home, Mei’s whole world is shattered.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em><strong>LSQ: Your story’s characters live in their own way, dedicated to their family. Their spirituality seems comparable to a wild magic. How much did you draw on folk and fairy tales to craft the basis of their beliefs?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elin: When I wrote about their spirituality, I imagined some sort of blend between Christianity and ancient Scandinavian beliefs and traditions. Mei hides in a cairn close to the cottage when she wants to escape her sisters, since she knows they won’t get too close to it for religious reasons—the cairn is the burial site of the men of the family. Burial cairns were common during the <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-24824 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jonny-gios-eMrunwZSxhQ-unsplash-300x212.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="212" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jonny-gios-eMrunwZSxhQ-unsplash-300x212.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jonny-gios-eMrunwZSxhQ-unsplash-1024x725.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jonny-gios-eMrunwZSxhQ-unsplash-768x543.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jonny-gios-eMrunwZSxhQ-unsplash-1536x1087.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/jonny-gios-eMrunwZSxhQ-unsplash-2048x1449.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Scandinavian Bronze Age, and the Church Rock that appears in the story was inspired by megalithic monuments. It’s called the Church Rock since they go there to worship instead of going to church—the name is older than the sisters, who have never been to a church and don’t really know what it is. In a way, the family has created its own religion, where the family itself is worshipped and mythologized.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em><strong>LSQ: When the stranger comes, a man, he brings with him a bit of the modern world, one where superstitions didn’t exist. Is it the disbelief that seals his fate, or more how he treats Mei?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elin: Mei sees the stranger as a threat to her entire life—his talk about the outside world worries her, and she hates him for getting close to her eldest sister. His disbelief and his lack of respect for the family traditions only make matters worse. Mei doesn’t know anything except her life on the Moor, and she wants it to stay that way.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Each sister has such a distinct personality. Mei seems to be the most tied to the land, in hearing the river, and in obeying the call at the end of the story. How does each sister compliment the other?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Elin: Dorte, the eldest, is the adult who keeps things together. She’s also the one with the most realistic worldview—she loves the Moor, but she might be dreaming about other things, too.</p>
<p>Tyra, Mei’s other sister, is violent and unruly. She idolizes Granddad and uses his old tools and weapons, even his boots. Compared to Dorte, Tyra is chaotic and weird, but she still fits within the family because she follows the rules.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Mei, the youngest, is just a child. She understands the world through stories and dreams, a view that clashes with that of her sisters.<strong> </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 045 Author Interview: Sophia Thimmes and &#8220;The Adopt a Zombie Program&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-045-author-interview-sophia-thimmes-and-the-adopt-a-zombie-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 10:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 045]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Zombie-lovers rejoice! In today&#8217;s Issue 045 author interview, we get up-close and personal with your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Zombie-lovers rejoice! In today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-045/">Issue 045</a> author interview, we get up-close and personal with your favorite monsters, Sophia Thimmes, and &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-adopt-a-zombie-program/">The Adopt a Zombie Program</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The motivations behind this story just beg to be asked. How and why did you create this world? If you could, would you adopt a zombie?</strong></em></p>
<div><span style="color: #000000; font-family: Arial;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24809 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3149240_1920-300x170.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="170" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3149240_1920-300x170.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3149240_1920-1024x579.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3149240_1920-768x434.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3149240_1920-1536x869.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/fantasy-3149240_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Sophia: No need to beg&#8211;I love to talk all things story and world-building! &#8220;The Adopt a Zombie Program&#8221; came from a long walk taken at the beginning of quarantine, at a time when my subconscious was processing discourse around vaccines, contagion, and <em>Tiger King</em>. I wanted to know&#8211;how would the modern world respond to domesticated zombies? What issues and controversies might arise as a result (for example, in the story, I mention the Zombie Justice Act that was introduced after people took offense to zombies being treated so poorly in society)? By the end of my walk, I had a basic understanding of the shape of my story, although I still made many discoveries throughout the process of writing. </span></div>
<div><span style="color: #000000; font-family: Arial;"> </span></div>
<div><span style="color: #000000; font-family: Arial;">And to answer the second question, I don&#8217;t quite see myself as ready to become a zom-mom.</span></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your story is a juxtaposition between the mundane and the bizarre, the blending creating a chilling atmosphere where morals are skewed. What moral area did you find to be the most challenging to write? Is there one you wanted to highlight?</strong></em></p>
<div></div>
<div>Sophia: While I was writing &#8220;The Adopt a Zombie Program,&#8221; one question of morality that felt a bit sticky was: if adequately sedated, would zombies actually be deserving of rights? Or would their nervous systems and self-concept be eroded to the point that them having rights would no longer be relevant (and if that was the case, would it be more ethical to just put them down rather than leave them in a vegetable-like state?)? Either way, the idea of killing what looks to be a human child would undoubtedly cause controversy, which is why in the story there are commercials with dramatic music in the background that beg the viewer to adopt a zombie so that they won&#8217;t have to be put down. Here, tension between aesthetics and ethics comes into play. There are hints that Abigail has a killing streak and will eventually harm more than just the occasional bird or rodent, but that issue is still somewhat ambiguous by the end of the story, and is ultimately up for the reader to decide.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The mother in your story seems to be obsessed more with image than with safety or reality: her social media account, the product placements, and captions. But there is something else underneath it. Why does she focus more on Abigail than her own daughter? Are there motivations that make her interested in zombies in particular?</strong></em></p>
<div>Sophia: I have so many thoughts on this! The mother was very tricky and interesting to write. There is room for other interpretations, but I see the mother as wanting an area of her life that she feels she has complete control over and something that stays the same. This is in contrast to her experience at the onset of the zombie outbreak when she had very little control, and in contrast to her relationship with her daughter. Her daughter does love her, but she&#8217;s an adolescent and isn&#8217;t particularly interested in spending time with her mom. In fact, she tries to avoid it. A zombie pet, however, is constantly around, unchanging, and easily controllable. The social media account is another way for the mother to cultivate her own world and gain validation for how good of a mom she is&#8211;something that I don&#8217;t think she gets from Rebecca. I&#8217;m also not convinced that she&#8217;s getting much validation in other areas of her life, which would make the social media account especially important to her. Another feature of why she&#8217;s obsessed with Abigail might be that she missed out on time with her daughter when she was younger, as she was preoccupied with worry and with keeping her daughter safe from the zombie outbreak. Maybe Abigail is a way for her to relive those years that she feels she lost with her biological daughter. One last thought that I have on the mother&#8217;s preoccupation with Abigail is that perhaps because she was so worried that she would lose her daughter to the zombie outbreak, Abigail functions as a way for her to believe that even if Rebecca<i> had</i> turned into a zombie, she would have been a good enough mom for everything to turn out alright.</p>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Rebecca’s distrust of Abigail drives her to an extreme action by the end of the story. Why did the story need to end this way? Is there anything else you would like to mention?</strong></em></p>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24810 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/child-2667485_1920-194x300.jpg" alt="" width="194" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/child-2667485_1920-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/child-2667485_1920-662x1024.jpg 662w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/child-2667485_1920-768x1187.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/child-2667485_1920-994x1536.jpg 994w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/child-2667485_1920.jpg 1242w" sizes="(max-width: 194px) 100vw, 194px" /></div>
<div><span style="color: #000000; font-family: Arial;">Sophia: Rebecca is caught between wanting to separate herself/her identity from her mother and feeling jealous of someone&#8211;or some<i>thing</i>&#8211;else coming into her home and playing the role of daughter. This tension is heightened by the fact that this paradaughter might be unsafe for her mother to be around. Throughout the story, it is clear that Abigail has <i>some </i>instinct to kill, as she brings the mother small dead creatures, such as birds and rodents, and Rebecca sees her eat a squirrel on a walk. At one point, the cat goes missing, and it is never quite clear if Abigail actually killed the cat or not, however, Rebecca comes to believe that this is the case and she remembers Abigail gnawing on her mother&#8217;s hair. Rebecca knows that her mother is too convinced that Abigail is harmless and loveable to take any precautions around her (the mother has stopped giving Abigail her zombie pills meant to keep killing impulses at bay due to online discourse that the pills are entirely unnecessary), so she takes things into her own hands and gets rid of the pet herself. Maybe Rebecca, at least on a subconscious level, sees killing off this zombie child as a symbolic act of moving on from a fraught childhood or from her child self. </span></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 045 Author Interview: K. A. Tutin and &#8220;Little, Little, Little&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-045-author-interview-k-a-tutin-and-little-little-little/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 19:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 045]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24368</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fret not, dear readers, we still have plenty of Issue 045 author interviews coming your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fret not, dear readers, we still have plenty of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-045/">Issue 045</a> author interviews coming your way! Today we&#8217;re sharing what K. A. Tutin had to say about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/little-little-little/">Little, Little, Little</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Ooh, this is a beautiful story and leaves me satisfied as a reader while also feeling incredibly curious, so great job on striking that balance! How did you decide where to start this story? Did you always know you wanted to begin with the mystery of a little girl lying in the snow?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24759 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fantasy-4300258_1920-203x300.jpg" alt="" width="203" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fantasy-4300258_1920-203x300.jpg 203w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fantasy-4300258_1920-691x1024.jpg 691w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fantasy-4300258_1920-768x1138.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fantasy-4300258_1920-1037x1536.jpg 1037w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fantasy-4300258_1920.jpg 1296w" sizes="(max-width: 203px) 100vw, 203px" />K. A.: Thank you for your kind words! My main focus going into “Little, Little, Little,” was the theme of accepting change expressed through transformative body horror, which was inspired by reading <i>The Metamorphosis </i>by Franz Kafka during my university degree. The opening scene of Little lying in the snow popped into my mind, and I ran with it. The sense of mystery attached to it was not something I’d planned from the start, but something I noticed later on in revisions and took advantage of.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The only ones with names in the story are Little and Paula, her host’s deceased daughter. Was that deliberate? Why not name the woman living in the cottage?</strong></em></p>
<p>K. A.: Not naming The Woman was a deliberate choice, yes. I wanted her and Little to share the feeling of being lost. In their lives and identities.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The woman in the cottage seems to know more than we initially think. She and the crows create two different paths for Little, yet also seem to have worked together to give her a sanctuary. Is the alliance I sense there a real one, or just expertly implied?</strong></em></p>
<p>K. A.: An alliance between the two of them was not something I planned on either – though it<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24760 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/feather-648481_1920-300x183.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="183" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/feather-648481_1920-300x183.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/feather-648481_1920-1024x624.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/feather-648481_1920-768x468.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/feather-648481_1920-1536x936.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/feather-648481_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> certainly sounds like a great way to describe it! On writing the story, I’d not established their relationship that way knowingly, so it would lean more toward implied, but it was definitely real in that there was a shared understanding and acknowledgment between them regarding Little’s choice on which path to take.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 045 Author Interview: Anastasiya Sukhenko and &#8220;The Graveyard Library&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-045-author-interview-anastasiya-sukhenko-and-the-graveyard-library/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 045]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to Tuesday, when we interview authors from our latest issue! Today we&#8217;re shining the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Tuesday, when we interview authors from our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-045/">latest issue</a>! Today we&#8217;re shining the spotlight on Anastasiya Sukhenko and &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-graveyard-library/">The Graveyard Library</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: What a heartbreaking and beautiful story! It read like such a delicate blend of hope and grief to me. How did you come up with this idea, and specifically, the magic of the books?</em></strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24718 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/library-425730_1920-300x216.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="216" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/library-425730_1920-300x216.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/library-425730_1920-1024x737.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/library-425730_1920-768x553.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/library-425730_1920-1536x1106.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/library-425730_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Anastasiya: Thank you so much! I initially came up with the idea of speaking with a version of yourself you aspire to be. I wasn&#8217;t in the best headspace when I wrote this story, and this was because I was anxious about achieving my goals. That&#8217;s when I thought of the story. It was my way of coping with my own anxiety.</p>
<p>As for the books, I just love libraries. To me, it&#8217;s one of the most comforting places to be, and I wanted to oppose the grim, eerie setting graveyards are often associated with.</p>
<p>The magic system came from the idea that characters from stories are somewhat immortalized because their stories live on for so long. Even when we read about &#8220;real&#8221; people from history or celebrate them, we&#8217;re really just memorializing a version of them. The actual person itself will never truly be remembered since that varies depending on who is recounting their story or their character. The color system of the books came to me as I was writing. I associate a lot of things with colors, especially feelings. It&#8217;s sort of like auras.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: You put a huge amount of world building into a story with a comparatively small word count, and balance it with genuine emotion so well. Was this a story that took a lot of drafts to get just right, or did it come out close to the final version?</strong></em></p>
<p>Anastasiya: This was the third draft. I mainly workshopped the beginning and tried to balance how much detail to include about the library and its magic without being info-dumpy. I kept going back and forth with omitting details and then adding them back in. The original version is very similar to the final version. Mainly the dialogue between Ella and &#8220;herself&#8221; is slightly different and the beginning.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Ella’s ending is so poignant and painful. Did you know when you planned this story out how things would end for her? Would you consider revisiting this world to write more in it, even if Ella isn’t the main character?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24720 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/woman-3435842_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/woman-3435842_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/woman-3435842_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/woman-3435842_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/woman-3435842_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/woman-3435842_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Anastasiya: I didn&#8217;t know how things would end until I finally sat down and wrote the first scene where Ella is waiting to enter. That was when I got a feeling for her character and what she was going through. It was no longer about my anxiety, rather Ella&#8217;s grief. It was then I knew she had an alternative motive.</p>
<p>I really love this concept and have written another, lighter story in the setting of this library. Ella was not the main character for that version. I definitely want to do more with this, I&#8217;m just waiting for the moment when I know what that is.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 045 Author Interview: Greta Hayer and &#8220;The Blinded God&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-045-author-interview-greta-hayer-and-the-blinded-god/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 01:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 045]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24502</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ready for another Issue 045 author interview? Today Greta Hayer&#8217;s in the hot seat, answering&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Ready for another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-045/">Issue 045</a> author interview? Today Greta Hayer&#8217;s in the hot seat, answering questions about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-blinded-god/">The Blinded God</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: What a lovely and mysterious story! There’s a great tension between Thea and Timon right from the beginning, and I really enjoyed the juxtaposition of their feelings of faith and doubt, the way they seemed to change places as the story went on. Which character did you come up with first? Was their relationship central to your initial plot, or did it come in later as you thought out the religion and backstories?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24636 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/floor-vase-2916012_1920-209x300.png" alt="" width="209" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/floor-vase-2916012_1920-209x300.png 209w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/floor-vase-2916012_1920-714x1024.png 714w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/floor-vase-2916012_1920-768x1102.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/floor-vase-2916012_1920-1070x1536.png 1070w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/floor-vase-2916012_1920.png 1338w" sizes="(max-width: 209px) 100vw, 209px" />Greta: Thank you! I’ve been thinking about the character that turned into Thea for a long time. Partly, it was a challenge&#8211;could I describe a world without relying on a character’s vision? But I also like magic that demands a price and gods who are mysterious and frustrating and rather unhelpful. Timon came later when this story was trying on its plot for the third or fourth time, and, with his help, the pieces started to fit together, from Thea’s questions of faith to the fire at the end.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Thea’s moments of doubt, especially near the end, are intriguing. She’s having holy visions at the same time that she’s convinced the amphora is nothing more than a jug. Is her perception of its simple nature accurate? Should that make us question the accuracy of all of her visions—could these pictures be her imagination, rather than divine inspiration?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Greta: I really love an ambiguous world where the magic can slip into hallucination, and so I’m glad you’re asking this kind of question. I don’t have a great answer, though. In my first draft, the True Sight was far more powerful and absolutely divine, but as this story changed around in revision, Thea’s doubts grew and her powers weakened.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I did think of the amphora a bit like Christian reliquaries, where bones or vials of blood or even clothes are preserved as something holy and special because it (might have) belonged to a saint long ago. I don’t think that the toe bone of Saint Someone actually has the power to heal a believer, but if the person has faith that they’re healed, maybe something clicks in their mind and they can start a healthier life. Placebo is a hell of a drug. So maybe the amphora will work exactly like people want it to, simply through the power of their belief. I don’t know though. I didn’t write that part yet.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: I’d love to see more of the world of the Blinded God (pun intended)! Would you ever<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24637 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/fantasy-2766616_1920-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/fantasy-2766616_1920-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/fantasy-2766616_1920-678x1024.jpg 678w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/fantasy-2766616_1920-768x1159.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/fantasy-2766616_1920-1018x1536.jpg 1018w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/fantasy-2766616_1920.jpg 1272w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /> revisit this story or setting?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Greta: Oh absolutely! This story started off as a chapter in a much longer, now-abandoned novel I wrote a couple of years ago. Thea has changed a lot (even her name), and there’s no amphora or Timon in the original story, but I love the world, which I affectionately call “Ancient-Rome-ish.” I think there’s definitely a hunger for non-medieval fantasy, and when I’m done with the two medieval fantasy novels I’m working on now, maybe I’ll travel back to Thea and Timon, fighting their way through a world of politics, gladiators, and capricious gods.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 045 Author Interview: Christi Krug and &#8220;Blood Feathers&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-045-author-interview-christi-krug-and-blood-feathers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 21:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 045]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s Tuesday, and you know what that means. Another interview with one of our Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s Tuesday, and you know what that means. Another interview with one of our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-045/">Issue 045</a> authors! Today&#8217;s contestant is Christi Krug as we talk about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/blood-feathers/">Blood Feathers</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: &#8220;Blood Feathers&#8221; is an absolutely gorgeous story. It gave me so much but also really made me think about how every piece of it fit together as I read. What was your inspiration for it?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24551 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/feather-886124_1920-150x300.png" alt="" width="150" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/feather-886124_1920-150x300.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/feather-886124_1920-512x1024.png 512w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/feather-886124_1920-768x1536.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/feather-886124_1920.png 960w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Christi: Thank you! The inspiration for this story began six years ago, but I didn’t have all of the pieces at first. I went through a personal crisis that culminated in finding feathers daily, everywhere, in all shapes and sizes. Each feather was a reminder of my true self and the freedom of being that self. It was a profound and painful experience and led to the loss of important relationships, but it was also deeply rewarding. When I wrote the story, I couldn’t figure out my ending. And then when I revised it this year, I saw that it was a circle, with the beginning and ending completing each other.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Ren is wonderfully complex. When I started the story I thought “Ah, I get what kind of person she is,” but then learning more about her history and the accident and Cousin Cornelia, my assumptions get completely turned around. When you first thought up Ren as a character, where did you start?</strong></em></p>
<p>Christi: Ren came to me as the person trying to be a good mom—or partner, or worker—doing her best but not tapping into who she really is. She goes so far as to misunderstand herself, telling herself she’s a linear person, when she’s really creative and flighty (which isn’t a bad thing!). I have been this person many times in my life (particularly in the life crisis mentioned above), and I meet people in my classes and work who have failed to recognize the need for their creativity and want to change that. To me, Ren’s accident, and her connection to her otherworldly cousin, are deep, hidden reminders of who she once was and is meant to be.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your descriptions are rich and vivid throughout the story, but the description of the feather ring is particularly fascinating to me. I also love your depictions of birds, and Ren’s own feathers coming to life. Are you a birdwatcher? Do you have a favorite bird?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24549 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/swift-5881445_1920-300x108.png" alt="" width="300" height="108" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/swift-5881445_1920-300x108.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/swift-5881445_1920-1024x369.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/swift-5881445_1920-768x276.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/swift-5881445_1920-1536x553.png 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/swift-5881445_1920.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Christi: I do love birds but I’m not an expert by any means. I admire feathers, and as I began noticing them, I started to draw and paint them as well, mesmerized by this small unit that provides warmth, strength, structure, and protection. By itself, one feather is stunning, and if you look closely, there’s mystery in the symmetry: a microstructure of tiny branches. A feather is flexible, resilient, and able to shed water. A bird’s feathers work in concert, providing warmth close to the body and enabling different skills for flight depending on shape or placement on tail, body, or wing. I love them as symbols of creativity, because our creative souls are all meant to fly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 045 Author Interview: Hannah Hulbert and &#8220;Cosmic Resolution&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-045-author-interview-hannah-hulbert-and-cosmic-resolution/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 18:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 045]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In this installment of Issue 045 author interviews, we&#8217;re spicing things up with a dash&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">In this installment of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-045/">Issue 045</a> author interviews, we&#8217;re spicing things up with a dash of eldritch horror, just to keep things interesting! Be sure to read Hannah Hulbert&#8217;s story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/cosmic-resolution/">Cosmic Resolution</a>,&#8221; then come back here for her illuminating interview.</p>
<p id="m_4922700760516347505docs-internal-guid-310ca6cb-7fff-129b-5767-0fde4b4c9e92" dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: What a fantastic and fun delve into the mythos of The Elder Gods! I love how Marina’s opening reaction to what is undeniably weird is fairly mild—I feel like her ability to take intrusive tentacles (almost) in stride is a neat bit of potential foreshadowing when it comes to her heritage. How did you decide to start the story here?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24515 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/photoshop-4782343_1920-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/photoshop-4782343_1920-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/photoshop-4782343_1920-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/photoshop-4782343_1920-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/photoshop-4782343_1920-1229x1536.jpg 1229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/photoshop-4782343_1920.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Hannah: My writing is always fueled by whatever is making me furious at the time, though I try not to make it too obvious. While I was writing &#8220;Cosmic Resolution&#8221;, I was thinking a lot about domestic violence. So, when we first meet Marina, she&#8217;s already been confronted by the tentacles a few times and tried dealing with the situation using denial and tentatively asking for help. The opening finds her settling into acceptance that the problem is real but also out of her control, and her Mum is either unwilling or unable to help. She&#8217;s reached a point where she just lets it happen &#8211; until things escalate and she&#8217;s forced to decide what to do next. As she discovers more about who she is, she finds that there are more options available to her than she could possibly have imagined!</p>
<p dir="ltr">I like to start my short stories just before the main dilemma presents itself, and that&#8217;s where we find Marina &#8211; dealing with an escalation of an already unpleasant situation, forced to decide how she&#8217;s going to react when so few options seem available.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: You do a great job laying out the relationship between Marina and her mum and by the end of the story, I had a much different impression of her mother than at the beginning. Who or what inspired Marina’s mother and her path skirting along the edges of darkness?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation">Hannah: I loved writing Marina&#8217;s Mum so much! She&#8217;s one of those characters you love to hate, but as the story progresses, you realize that there’s actually a real person inside that grimy exterior that you feel for. When I wrote her she just sort of sprang fully formed from my brain, like Athena. But when I read her now I can see I was subconsciously basing her on Marsha from &#8220;Spaced.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The end makes me wonder a bit about split timelines—whether Marina left the mother she grew up with in another world, while she hopped over to a happier timeline. Could Marina’s cosmic powers have unintended consequences, or should we take this happy ending at face value?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr" role="presentation"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24514 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fractal-art-3206739_1280-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fractal-art-3206739_1280-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fractal-art-3206739_1280-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fractal-art-3206739_1280-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fractal-art-3206739_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Hannah: This is such a great question! All of my main characters are really explorations of facets of myself, and Marina is no exception. When she blasted her way through reality and created a better world, she was only thinking about herself and escaping the immediate threat of the tentacle monster in her hallway. She wasn&#8217;t thinking about the consequences of her actions or possible repercussions in other timelines. I don&#8217;t think we should expect her to &#8211; she&#8217;s just a kid dealing with a bad situation (which she did nothing to deserve) the best way she knows how. By extension, that&#8217;s what I was doing when I wrote her &#8211; myopically trying to fix the dilemma she was in. I think if there are unpleasant side effects we need to blame them on the Elder God who brought this entire situation into being. Unfortunately, I think that Prime Mover was me. Sorry, Marina!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
