<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Broadcasts from the Far Side &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/broadcasts-from-the-far-side/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 03:00:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Woman of Many Voices: Robin Miles narrates Redemption in Indigo</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/woman-of-many-voices-robin-miles-narrates-redemption-in-indigo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carrie Naughton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 16:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Broadcasts from the Far Side]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4412</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As readers and writers orbiting and inhabiting Luna Station, it&#8217;s a safe bet that most&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As readers and writers orbiting and inhabiting <i>Luna Station</i>, it&#8217;s a safe bet that most of us seek out not only fiction and poetry, but editorials, articles, and tweets about <a href="http://www.newstatesman.com/culture/2013/08/i-hate-strong-female-characters" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&#8220;strong female characters.&#8221;</a> We apply the Bechdel Test to everything. We demand an answer: where are the women?</p>
<p>I submit to you <a href="http://whatever.scalzi.com/2010/07/08/the-big-idea-karen-lord/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Karen Lord&#8217;s <i>Redemption in Indigo</i></a>. Here is a gem of a book, a genuine <i>story</i>, which interweaves character and tale so seamlessly that I began to believe it was real.  There are plenty of synopses on Goodreads and various SFF sites (all of which seem to reiterate that the book is a quasi-retelling of a Senegalese folktale, so I will reiterate that here for you as well), but I avoided these reviews before diving into the book, and I&#8217;m glad I did. Just in case you like a little preamble: <i>Redemption in Indigo</i> is a morality tale wrapped up in an adventure; also it&#8217;s a dramedy and a love story. I&#8217;ll tell you a bit more: there&#8217;s djombis and a chaos stick and a gluttonous husband and wise women and talking animal-gods. Yes! Oh &#8211; wait &#8211; didn&#8217;t I just prattle on in <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-author-who-narrates-her-own-books-catherynne-m-valente/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a previous review</a> about how I&#8217;m not much for fantastical whimsy? Oops. Well, this is just the right touch &#8211; I appreciated the wisdom here and the story&#8217;s multi-faceted female lead. And hmmm…I think it all resonates with me because Robin Miles narrates <i>Redemption in Indigo</i>.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/redemption-in-indigo.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-4997 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/redemption-in-indigo-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>I&#8217;m going to state right now that this is one of the best audiobooks I&#8217;ve ever listened to.</p>
<p>There are great readers.  There are skilled narrators and talented voice artists. And then someone comes along who has all of that, and MAGIC. Miles is magic, I&#8217;m telling you. I completely forgot that she was a separate being &#8211; I heard only each individual character. I <i>lived</i> in this book as Robin Miles&#8217; vocal chords gave life to Karen Lord&#8217;s characters. From a sly spider to a stick bug to our heroine Paama and the indigo-skinned djombi.</p>
<p>Miles brings a palette of so many unique characteristics for each persona. As soon as a new someone came to be introduced in the novel, my eagerness to hear how this person (or bug, or animal!) might speak was as great as my anticipation to hear the rest of the story.</p>
<p>I had the great fortune to interview Robin Miles via Skype &#8211; what a blast! She&#8217;s an actress, a voice artist, and she owns her own recording and training company, <a href="http://www.voxpertise.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VOXpertise</a>. As a well-known director of audio recordings, she is especially esteemed for her ability to manage large cast recordings, like <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/midnight-in-garden-good-evil/id968247307?mt=8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">her production of <i>Midnight in the Garden of Good and Evil</i></a>. She has an innate gift for accents &#8211; she can go from a manly Scottish brogue to a lilting Jamaican patois in a heartbeat, and has a keen ear for the subtle intricacies of regional dialects.</p>
<p>Her background as an actress serves her well; I asked her how she related to the character of Paama, and she responded with a deeper comment on the embodiment of all characters, for example, a spider. &#8220;Imagine being really thin and leggy &#8211; does that do anything to your voice?&#8221; Miles definitely knows how to combine years of experience and training with what she dubs &#8220;the emotional reality&#8221; that must propel a scene. &#8220;I tend to let my first impressions land,&#8221; she says. &#8220;Because instincts are to be heeded. I want to tell that to all women.&#8221;</p>
<p>You can <a href="http://www.audiofilemagazine.com/narrators/robin-miles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">read more about Robin Miles</a>, and owe it to yourself to seek out her <a href="http://www.audible.com/search/ref=a_search_c4_1_1_1_srNarr?searchNarrator=Robin+Miles&amp;qid=1431905866&amp;sr=1-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">catalogue</a>. Miles also narrates Karen Lord&#8217;s latest novel, <em><a href="http://www.audible.com/pd/Sci-Fi-Fantasy/The-Galaxy-Game-Audiobook/B00WIU6F36/ref=a_search_c4_1_2_srTtl?qid=1431905902&amp;sr=1-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Galaxy Game</a>. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Through a Door Darkly: Kate Wilhelm</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/through-a-door-darkly-kate-wilhelm/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carrie Naughton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 15:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Broadcasts from the Far Side]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I haven&#8217;t reviewed a straight-up science fiction novel for Luna Station Quarterly since my first&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1348845487l/2078650.jpg" alt="" width="248" height="353" />I haven&#8217;t reviewed a straight-up science fiction novel for <i>Luna Station Quarterly</i> since <a title="Voice of a Star Pilot: Listening to Five-Twelfths of Heaven" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/voice-of-a-star-pilot-listening-to-five-twelfths-of-heaven/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">my first blog post</a>, so this month I chose <i>The Dark Door</i>, by <a href="http://katewilhelm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kate Wilhelm</a>, as read by the great <a href="http://www.audiofilemagazine.com/reviews/listing/?Narrator=Anna%20Fields" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Anna Fields</a>. Wilhelm, you might know, is the author of <a href="http://katewilhelm.com/bibliography/barbara-holloway-mysteries/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the Barbara Holloway mystery series</a> and the Hugo Award-winning novel <i>Where Late the Sweet Birds Sang</i>. She&#8217;s a multi-genre master, with a gift for genuine dialogue, humor, and suspense. Her books are that sweet-spot combination of character and story, and she&#8217;s definitely got an affinity for the speculative, even in her mystery fiction (see, for starters, <i>Death Qualified</i>). Whether she&#8217;s writing about clones or chaos theory, I appreciate her commitment to science and rationality &#8211; no hand-waving for Wilhelm. And no boring info-dumps! I&#8217;ve noticed too that even when her novels are from, say, 1988 (like <i>The Dark Door</i>), they never feel dated.</p>
<p><i>The Dark Door</i> is a tense, smart sci-fi thriller along the lines of Dean Koontz or Daniel Hecht&#8217;s Cree Black novels (which Anna Fields also narrates). This is the second book of the Constance and Charlie Mystery series, but I fell right into it without having read the first book. The premise is this: an alien portal of neurological evil (yes, that&#8217;s what I said) keeps appearing in abandoned wooden buildings in isolated American towns &#8211; and seems to drive good citizens to madness and rage. A tormented survivor of the dark door teams up with Charlie and Constance Meiklejohn to investigate and destroy the alien probe.</p>
<p>Charlie and Constance are the best part of the book, no surprise. This is a novel that&#8217;s definitely for fans of <i>The X-Files</i> and <i>Fringe</i>, because the plot revolves around the investigation into an artifact not of this earth, and its disastrous affect on humans. But like the story arc of Mulder and Scully or Olivia and Peter (or hey, Astrid and Walter!), <em>The Dark Door</em> is a portrait of a happy partnership between two equals &#8211; two people who love and respect each other and work wonders as a team. And when our beloved heroes are in danger, we feel it all the more.</p>
<p>The narration by Anna Fields was flawless. She also reads the audiobook <i>Death Qualified</i>, which I listened to years ago and enjoyed, so I can attest to her consistency. Her strong, authoritative voice is both rock solid reliable and comforting. Her delivery and pacing are perfect &#8211; especially with a book that&#8217;s heavy on back-and-forth dialogue laden with all degrees of intellectual discourse, emotion and humor. I love the way Fields distinguishes the many male characters (and I have to note here that in a book with mostly male characters, it&#8217;s pretty sweet that Constance is the ultimate hero).</p>
<p>Anna Fields is the stage name for <a href="http://www.audiofilemagazine.com/narrators/anna-fields-kate-fleming/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kate Fleming</a>, chosen by Fleming in honor of her great-grandmother. Whenever I write these reviews, I do everything possible to contact the audiobook readers for an interview. I love hearing about their work and their thoughts on women&#8217;s speculative fiction. I was heartbroken to find out that Kate Fleming passed away in 2006 at the age of 41. Tragically, she drowned in her basement recording studio during flash flooding in the Pacific Northwest.</p>
<p>I recommend listening to everything from her back catalogue, which you can find <a href="http://www.audiofilemagazine.com/reviews/listing/?Narrator=Anna%20Fields" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>. She was a rock star. I believe future generations of vocal talents should study the audiobook recordings of Anna Fields, to learn how it&#8217;s done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Author Who Narrates Her Own Books: Catherynne M. Valente</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-author-who-narrates-her-own-books-catherynne-m-valente/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carrie Naughton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Broadcasts from the Far Side]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s not often that an author records the narration for their own audiobook. Sure, you can&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1388179691l/9591398.jpg" alt="" width="219" height="329" />It&#8217;s not often that an author records the narration for their own audiobook. Sure, you can go to public readings or listen to podcasts, but a recording of the whole dang book? Not likely, unless you&#8217;re Stephen King. Sometimes there&#8217;s good reasons for that &#8211; after all, a professional writer is not usually a professional voice artist as well (but oh I do love King&#8217;s Maine accent). That said, there&#8217;s of course something to be gained from hearing an author read her own work. You&#8217;re listening to the creator re-enact her creation in its most perfect form.</p>
<p>As I listened to <a href="http://www.catherynnemvalente.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Catherynne M. Valente</a> narrate her 2011 novel <i>The Girl Who Circumnavigated Fairyland in a Ship of Her Own Making</i> (hereafter, I&#8217;m sorry, but I&#8217;m going to refer to it as <i>The Girl Who…</i>), I found myself not thinking about the story at all. Maybe because this is a book about a teenage girl, magical creatures, and whimsical adventures in the fairy realm. I didn&#8217;t enjoy it. That&#8217;s because I&#8217;m dead inside. Also I typically shun anything remotely resembling YA. I have been a YA, and I don&#8217;t want to go back. I admit, I didn&#8217;t realize this book would foist its YA-ness upon me &#8211; my bad. Not that September&#8217;s (that&#8217;s the girl&#8217;s name, September) adventures weren&#8217;t somewhat….dark and harrowing and grotesque at times (waaaiit…so is young adulthood). Hmm&#8230;maybe this book is more of a bedtime story for grownups (and almost-adults). It lulled me.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright" src="http://www.slate.com/content/dam/slate/articles/arts/books/2013/10/SBR/AUTHOR/1310_SBR_Valente_AUTHOR.jpg.CROP.promovar-mediumlarge.jpg" alt="" width="297" height="212" /></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t let me put you off <i>The Girl Who…</i> It&#8217;s quite exquisite, the language is gorgeous, the worldbuilding is utterly wild, and it has a heroine possessed of courage and emotion. I just couldn&#8217;t fall into it, though the tale reached out its bony fairy arms and offered me strange delicacies and tried to embrace me for many a chapter. I found myself daydreaming instead about rereading Pamela Dean&#8217;s <a href="http://www.publishersweekly.com/978-0-312-86004-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i>Juniper, Gentian and Rosemary</i></a>. That&#8217;s just me.</p>
<p>So, but &#8211; the narration. Wow. So much to say. I want to thank <i>The Girl Who… </i>for allowing me the opportunity to evaluate a narrator based on several important qualifications that I am now definitely going to apply to all audiobooks.</p>
<p><b>I. Voice </b> Valente&#8217;s voice is absolutely unique. She sounds like a velvet cushion with a kitten curled up on it. Like a gooey box of caramels. Like she just gargled Candyland&#8217;s Molasses Swamp. She does not sound like a professional voice actor. I was okay with that &#8211; in fact I really like her voice…but. You cannot polish a sugary cushion.</p>
<p><b>II. Delivery</b>  Valente clearly feels the story. Duh, she wrote it. The listener can feel it, too &#8211; the tension between the characters, September&#8217;s fear and wonder. However, there were also times when I felt like the narration was too subdued. The story, to me, required an actress to make it truly come alive. Wait &#8211; required isn&#8217;t the right word. The story deserved an actress. A voice actor would&#8217;ve had a <i>blast</i>. Valente delivers, especially when she&#8217;s breaking the fourth wall and reading her lines as the often sly, wicked Narrator, but she doesn&#8217;t quite sound like she&#8217;s over the moon. I regretted on numerous occasions during my long listen that someone like Juliet Stevenson or Emma Thompson or even Anna Paquin didn&#8217;t get a chance to record the narration.</p>
<p><b>III. Technical Stuff  </b>Valente does not enunciate. She does not create terribly individual accents for the many, many fantastical creatures and characters (from the Green Wind to a dragon-library to a trio of witches)…I mean, hoooo….the opportunity for performance here! see above). Her pacing is great though &#8211; just fast enough to keep things moving, and slow enough to digest all the quirkiness of the tale. This lulling…inner child&#8217;s…storytime tale.</p>
<p>I have no regrets about listening to <i>The Girl Who… </i>(wait &#8211; does it sound like I do?). This experience definitely reminded me of how incredibly vast is the universe of speculative fiction. There is literally something for everyone &#8211; at least, one can hope, and when there&#8217;s a lack (see <a href="WeNeedDiverseBooks.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WeNeedDiverseBooks.org</a>) then spec fic offers opportunity for expansion, indeed a rallying cry for more, more, more. I love that. So if you liked <i>The Wizard of Oz</i> (hate me….I never loved it like most people), The Brothers Grimm or <i>The Wind in the Willows</i> (I really should read that some day), then seek out <i>The Girl Who…</i> posthaste. You will adore it.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure you know, but this isn&#8217;t a standalone novel &#8211; there&#8217;s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/59347-fairyland" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">four more in the series</a>, all narrated by Valente. I haven&#8217;t listened to them, but I am wondering if she&#8217;s done anything differently from her recording of <i>The Girl Who…</i> I would love to find out, but I&#8217;ve got to go reread <a href="http://www.tor.com/blogs/2011/11/stories-and-secrets-pamela-deans-the-secret-country" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pamela Dean</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quality of Mercy: Moon Called by Patricia Briggs</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/quality-of-mercy-moon-called-by-patricia-briggs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carrie Naughton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 16:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Broadcasts from the Far Side]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Once upon the late 1990&#8217;s, I worked at a library in Wyoming, and I had&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1272070347l/71811.jpg" alt="" width="241" height="388" />Once upon the late 1990&#8217;s, I worked at a library in Wyoming, and I had the privilege of developing the sci fi and fantasy book collection (talk about a dream come true). My friend was in charge of the romance books, a collection development post I never, ever could have championed, but I so admired her tenacity and gusto, especially in the face of those patrons who might disparage the romance genre. Luna Station&#8217;s own A.E. Ash has something to say about the romance genre, too &#8211; <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/romantical/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">check out this post</a>.  And if you haven&#8217;t discovered the <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/VaginalFantasy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vaginal Fantasy goodreads bookclub</a>, well&#8230;</p>
<p>Right, I&#8217;m digressing here. Obviously <i>Moon Called</i> isn&#8217;t traditional romance &#8211; it&#8217;s urban fantasy with a tinge of romance. It&#8217;s in that category of speculative fiction that might otherwise be overlooked by readers deadheading for cerebral space opera and epic fantasy, kind of the way all speculative fiction is often shunned by readers who only like literary fiction. Am I right? Patricia Briggs&#8217; <i>Moon Called</i> is the <a href="http://www.patriciabriggs.com/books/timeline.shtml" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">first book of her Mercy Thompson series</a>, and it reminds me of a lot of other urban fantasy series with strong female protagonists &#8211; like Sookie Stackhouse, Anita Blake, or Kitty Norville.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright" src="http://www.patriciabriggs.com/images/misc/bioPhoto.png" alt="" width="244" height="292" />I&#8217;m not complaining &#8211; write me a strong female lead, yes please. Give her some flaws, a little vulnerability, mad skills, and don&#8217;t make her too pretty. Make her like a real woman &#8211; in an unreal world. Mercy Thompson will do just fine, thanks &#8211; although with her Native American heritage and her toned arms she&#8217;s probably too gorgeous to behold. I would&#8217;ve liked her a smidge less perfect, but <i>Moon Called</i> is, after all, her debut, and there&#8217;s plenty more Mercy to follow.  Maybe I believe Mercy as a coyote shapeshifter more than I believe her as a Volkswagen mechanic. No &#8211; not because I don&#8217;t think women can be mechanics. To me, the way she was written, the &#8216;shifter side of Mercy felt more natural. There were moments when the mechanic side of Mercy felt like a ploy &#8211; setting and props to make her seem more tough. Not always &#8211; I really enjoyed the scenes where she worked on cars, and her resourceful use of WD-40, but I want to believe in her badassness whatever her career path. Maybe it&#8217;s too risky to be a shapeshifter while working 9 to 5 in an office cube farm.</p>
<p>So, what kind of voice might one expect from a young woman who was raised by werewolves in Montana, runs her own auto garage, and morphs into a coyote whenever she wants? Mature yet playful. Breathy delivery and steel-edged consonants. Guess what? <a href="http://www.loreleiking.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lorelei King</a> is on the mike. I loved King&#8217;s vocal embodiment of Mercedes Thompson &#8211; confident and tough, yet sensitive, with that titch of insouciance to let the listener know that, oh yes, Mercy can handle danger, she&#8217;s running with the wolves and rescuing her special manimals. It&#8217;s evident that King absolutely loves reading the Mercy books. She&#8217;s already recorded eight titles in the series, plus the recent short story collection, <i>Shifting Shadows</i>. King feels that</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;one of the especially nice things about recording a series is that you really get to know the characters and their world, and after awhile they start to feel like your own family.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The Mercy Thompson series explores issues like honesty, family and loyalty in the context of supernatural suspense, and King identifies with Mercy&#8217;s &#8220;love for and loyalty to her mate and her pack. In my view, that&#8217;s what life is about &#8211; love and loyalty.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-3822 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/studio-action-shot-2-300x237.jpg" alt="Lorelei King" width="300" height="237" />Moon Called</em> isn&#8217;t all emotion and danger, though &#8211; and King has a great time with the myriad of accents and fantastical character origins. She notes, &#8220;this series, like other paranormal series, does have its challenges – supernatural creatures, for example. How <i>does </i>a tree fae sound? The writer will often give clues or hints and it’s great fun figuring all of that out. It gives the narrator freedom to maybe try something a little bit quirky.&#8221;</p>
<p>There&#8217;s humor too, much welcomed by King &#8211; who has &#8220;a particular affinity for the darkly comic&#8221; (which is sometimes evident in her fun <a href="https://twitter.com/LoreleiKing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tweets</a>). The comedy &#8211; mainly Mercy&#8217;s inner monologue and one-liners &#8211; provides a welcome balance to the novel&#8217;s more intense storylines. King admits wittily that Mercy &#8220;is obviously very mechanically-inclined, whereas it once took me ten hours to put up a curtain rod.&#8221;</p>
<p>There really is only one thing I didn&#8217;t like about the audiobook, and it&#8217;s a pet peeve of mine. <em>Moon Called</em> has intro and outro music at the beginning and end, and it sounds like a limp synthesizer theme from an 80&#8217;s cop show. I just don&#8217;t see the point &#8211; do audiobooks need this? I can understand music bookending the audio edition of a Kitty Norville novel &#8211; Kitty does work at a radio station &#8211; but it seemed silly for <em>Moon Called</em>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-3821 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/studio-action-shot-1-300x189.jpg" alt="Lorelei King in the studio." width="300" height="189" />On a final note, I&#8217;m always analyzing the way narrators handle reading different genders, especially in a novel that &#8211; if lightly &#8211; explores male and female roles in werewolf pack dynamics and features a woman as rescuer and hero. There are a lot of male &#8211; <i>alpha</i> male &#8211; characters in <em>Moon Called</em>. King portrays each uniquely, through accents, inflections, pitch, and tempo &#8211; without resorting to the easy out of &#8220;low voice = man.&#8221; Mercy&#8217;s two love interests &#8211; Samuel and Adam &#8211; are both intriguing, dominant characters, but Mercy is the protagonist, and she&#8217;s often solo in a world of male power.  I liked the way <a href="http://www.patriciabriggs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Patricia Briggs</a> didn&#8217;t let this define her heroine. Mercy is her own woman, with her own power. So, on second thought, I&#8217;m glad she&#8217;s a mechanic, because when I think about it, she&#8217;s not in that line of work because she &#8211; or Briggs &#8211; has something to prove. Mercy&#8217;s just good at it. I&#8217;m really happy I found this series, because as far as novels go in this subgenre, Briggs is good at it too. And I agree with Lorelei King:  &#8220;I am very grateful that there are so many wonderful women writers of speculative fiction, because – generally speaking – a book written by a woman will have a female narrator – so more jobs for the girls, which is a good thing.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memoirs of Yeine: N.K. Jemisin&#8217;s The Hundred Thousand Kingdoms</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/memoirs-of-yeine-n-k-jemisins-the-hundred-thousand-kingdoms/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carrie Naughton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 16:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Broadcasts from the Far Side]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3594</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At first I could not help but think of N.K. Jemisin&#8216;s The Hundred Thousand Kingdoms&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="http://d.gr-assets.com/books/1303143211l/6437061.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="304" />At first I could not help but think of <a href="https://twitter.com/nkjemisin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">N.K. Jemisin</a>&#8216;s <a href="http://www.audible.com/pd/Sci-Fi-Fantasy/The-Hundred-Thousand-Kingdoms-Audiobook/B003ZZRW3A/ref=a_search_c4_1_1_srTtl?qid=1421108760&amp;sr=1-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i>The Hundred Thousand Kingdoms</i></a> as a fantasy prime time soap opera &#8211; addictive and dangerous like <i>Revenge</i> meets…well….uh…there you go. I can&#8217;t invite any mashups or comparisons, because there aren&#8217;t any. Jemisin&#8217;s Inheritance Trilogy (of which <i>The Hundred Thousand Kingdoms, </i>published in 2009, is Book One) takes place in a thoroughly developed and unique world.  So on second thought &#8211; maybe this isn&#8217;t soap opera but autobiography: a heady, twisty-turny memoir from another realm. This is a story of political and magical intrigue told in first person, after all. But is our heroine Yeine a reliable primary source? She is intrepid, candid and determined, but she also exhibits memory lapses and bouts of disorientation.</p>
<p>Yeine was born of a mixed marriage: her mother was Kinneth Arameri, of the unofficial ruling elite, and her father hailed from the Northern lands. As the novel opens, Yeine, who is in her own words, &#8220;short and flat and brown as forestwood,&#8221; travels from her homeland to the magical palace above the city of Sky. She comes to Sky ostensibly because she has been summoned by her grandfather Dekarta Arameri to take part in an inheritance game. The reader knows that Yeine, who is looked upon as &#8220;a barbarian warrior from the north,&#8221; has also come to solve the mystery of her mother&#8217;s death.</p>
<p>I found Yeine&#8217;s story to be a thriller in the way that a fascinating biography is suspenseful.   There is so much detail to be absorbed, so many layers and nuances of the kingdom Yeine inhabits, with its gods and magic, with all the characters&#8217; lies, manipulations and contradictions. Even Yeine fights to remember all that has happened to her &#8211; on the page, those holes in her memory often appear midchapter, and she tends to digress, to interrupt her own narrative, and to converse with herself rather cryptically.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/casaundravox" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Casaundra Freeman</a> reads the audiobook version, and her interpretation of Yeine is a marvel.  It&#8217;s a rare audiobook experience where I can finish the last chapter and know that I will forever hear that narrator&#8217;s voice so clearly as the voice of a character &#8211; or even more remarkably, as <i>all</i> the characters distinctly. There are other key players in the Kingdom of Sky &#8211; the haughty throne contender Scimina, the mysterious and lusty god Nahadoth, the child trickster god Sieh. Freeman inhabits each of them &#8211; and many others &#8211; with effortless fluidity. I didn&#8217;t hear a voice actor &#8220;reading&#8221; these parts &#8211; I heard individuals, period. So very well done.</p>
<p>In a novel of complex worldbuilding and political machinations, it&#8217;s easy to become bogged down in endless infodumps. <a href="http://nkjemisin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jemisin</a> keeps things rolling with Yeine&#8217;s canny awareness of her volatile and vulnerable position at court, and her willingness to take risks and act on instinct. Yeine seems doomed from the start, set up to lose not only the throne but her life, yet that doesn&#8217;t stop her from jumping into the game, and although she has much to learn, she is no fool. The reader &#8211; or the listener &#8211; has much to learn as well, about the history and the people of this kingdom. It&#8217;s such a gift that Freeman is able to clearly articulate Jemisin&#8217;s rich details without sacrificing the pace of the story &#8211; and without turning an intricate backstory into a long monotonous lecture. Her voicework is as captivating as the tale.</p>
<p>Freeman&#8217;s voice &#8211; with its astonishing emotional range &#8211; conveys so much about Yeine: her calm, her fears, her anger. Hearing her embody Yeine&#8217;s pain and fury with a trembling voice, there were definitely moments that gave me chills. I appreciated the way she interpreted Yeine&#8217;s interjections of memories outside the narrative stream, with subtle modulations in her voice to convey Yeine&#8217;s different states of mind. Only once or twice did I feel tripped up by the recording &#8211; the occasional emphasis on a word or phrase that seemed awkward, but to me those instances are due to misguidance from the director. It&#8217;s good to know that the next book in the series &#8211; <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7904453-the-broken-kingdoms?from_search=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i>The Broken Kingdoms</i></a> &#8211; is also narrated by Casaundra Freeman. There&#8217;s simply no one else so perfect for the job.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voice of a Star Pilot: Listening to Five-Twelfths of Heaven</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/voice-of-a-star-pilot-listening-to-five-twelfths-of-heaven/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Carrie Naughton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 18:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Broadcasts from the Far Side]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My biggest regret about reading Five-Twelfths of Heaven recently is that it took me so&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1329770711l/175026.jpg" alt="" width="233" height="383" />My biggest regret about reading <i>Five-Twelfths of Heaven</i> recently is that it took me so long to get around to it.  <a href="http://mescott.livejournal.com/">Melissa Scott</a>&#8216;s novel was originally published in 1985, and it&#8217;s still relevant thirty years later, not to mention it&#8217;s a captivating story. The first book of Scott&#8217;s <i>Roads of Heaven</i> trilogy, <i>Five-Twelfths of Heaven</i> begins when the star pilot Silence Leigh arrives at a Secasian probate court to negotiate for her share of her grandfather&#8217;s estate after his sudden death. When we first meet Silence, she is veiled, as women are required to be on Secasia, and she lacks a male guardian&#8217;s representation, as women are required to have. Neither of these rules suit her, but Silence knows how to navigate not only space, but the laws of the Hegemon empire. By the end of the first chapter, she&#8217;s lost her grandfather&#8217;s ship<i> Black Dolphin</i>, but secured a position as a pilot on <i>Sun-Treader</i> and formed an alliance with <i>Sun-Treader</i>&#8216;s captain Denis Balthasar and engineer Julian Chase Mago.</p>
<p>The story might be considered space opera, but Scott&#8217;s detailed world-building is fresh and fantastical, involving starships with harmonium drives powered by the music of the spheres, pilots leapfrogging their ships from sun to sun using metaphysical starbooks as interstellar space guides, powerful magi wielding mind control tactics, and a ruthless empire expanding throughout the galaxy.   Silence&#8217;s partnership with her new husbands Balthasar and Chase Mago is a three-way marriage &#8211; practically, to gain citizenship and greater freedom of travel; and ultimately, based on mutual respect and growing friendship. But there is much more to Silence than even she knows, and only after she survives multiple ordeals at the hands of pirates, the magi, and the empire&#8217;s minions will she discover her true talent and her purpose.</p>
<p>This is a major simplification of the complexities and delights of this novel, but to impart any more of the plot would be an injustice &#8211; the book deserves to be read &#8211; or better yet, heard.</p>
<p>A great reader can transform a mediocre book into entertainment. A great book read by a gifted professional can be a riveting experience not easily forgotten.  The audiobook recording of <i>Five-Twelfths of Heaven</i> is narrated by <a href="http://www.arielleaudio.com/">Arielle DeLisle</a>, an accomplished voice talent, producer, and entrepreneur with her own recording studio in Arizona.  She read and produced the <i>Five Twelfths of Heaven</i> audiobook in her first home studio, a converted master closet with excellent sound quality due not only to acoustic paneling but DeLisle&#8217;s unneeded winter coats (that&#8217;s one way to use winter wear in the desert!).</p>
<p>Arielle DeLisle&#8217;s voice is perfectly suited to portray the young, determined Silence. Silence is both vulnerable and strong-willed, qualities that arise in DeLisle&#8217;s softspoken delivery and deliberate cadences.  DeLisle accomplishes something that very few audiobook readers are capable of: she imbues the character of Silence with vibrant personality. Silence Leigh comes to life through DeLisle&#8217;s voice: sweet-natured but not without nerve, young but mature, straightforward and sarcastic, too.</p>
<p>Of course, there are other characters who speak &#8211; the book&#8217;s dialogue is spot-on and flows wonderfully, conveying much knowledge of this spacefaring world without resorting to numbing info-dumps &#8211; and DeLisle succeeds at making each, male or female, unique and recognizable. Only occasionally did her interpretations of Balthasar and Chase Mago overlap for me, but I think that may be due more to Scott&#8217;s lesser focus on the character development of the two men. In contrast, DeLisle&#8217;s low, sinister personification of the magi perfectly captures their diabolical nature. Her reading moves seamlessly from dialogue to narration without any distracting jumps, and her delivery is crisp and clear. She&#8217;s also quite adept at conveying physicality in the novel. A magus&#8217; mind control manifests in one way through negative reinforcement &#8211; each time the victims think subversively or plan escape, they are stricken with stomach pain and nausea. Listening to DeLisle interpret the characters&#8217; suffering is a visceral experience.</p>
<p>With so many exotic names and concepts, I can imagine it must be difficult for a scifi/fantasy narrator to translate a story&#8217;s believability and legitimacy. In this case, Melissa Scott actually provided DeLisle with a pronunciation guide to the vocabulary, names and places in her universe, a true gift to both narrator and reader.</p>
<p>Arielle DeLisle records in her fancy new VocalBooth these days, no more winter coats, and better ventilation for those scorching Phoenix summers. She&#8217;s not only passionate about great books, but female entrepreneurship. She emphasizes women&#8217;s peer groups and mentoring as beneficial to her in her field. &#8220;Being in the trenches with others who want to see you succeed has been extremely helpful to my professional growth. Ultimately, we&#8217;re only competing against our best selves and trying to reach our full potential, and it&#8217;s not about competing with each other.&#8221;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Arielle_headshot.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-3275 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Arielle_headshot-200x300.jpg" alt="Arielle_headshot" width="200" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>DeLisle&#8217;s catalogue is <a href="http://www.audible.com/search/ref=a_search_c4_1_1_1_srNarr?searchNarrator=Arielle+DeLisle&amp;qid=1416502239&amp;sr=1-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">available on Audible</a>. Find her on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ArielleAudio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a> and Twitter at @arielleaudio.</p>
<p>Sadly, Books 2 and 3 of the <i>Roads of Heaven</i> trilogy have not been recorded (by anyone) &#8211; but according to Scott&#8217;s editor at Crossroad, something may be in the works soon. In the meantime, you can read the e-books: <i>Silence in Solitude</i>, followed by <i>The Empress of Earth</i>.  Beware, however, that <a href="http://mescott.livejournal.com/31798.html?thread=280630">Scott has apparently rewritten parts of Book 3</a> for the ebook edition, so feel free also to pick up a used paperback copy of <i>The Empress of Earth.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
