<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>A Woman Was Here &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/a-woman-was-here/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 03:16:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>“I have changed England”: Reading Susanna Clarke’s Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/i-have-changed-england-reading-susanna-clarkes-jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin K. Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 11:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Woman Was Here]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to our re-read of Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. For the month of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-19763 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Jonathan_strange_and_mr_norrell_cover-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="126" height="189" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Jonathan_strange_and_mr_norrell_cover-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Jonathan_strange_and_mr_norrell_cover.jpg 257w" sizes="(max-width: 126px) 100vw, 126px" />Welcome back to our re-read of <a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell-9781408891469/"><em>Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. </em></a>For the month of September, we reach the end of the novel (chs. 65-69) and say farewell to the magicians Strange and Norrell—but eagerly look forward to the release of Clarke’s second novel, <a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/piranesi-9781526622426/"><em>Piranesi</em></a>.</p>
<p><u>Recap</u></p>
<p><u> </u>The gentleman with the thistledown hair is panicked by the return of Strange to England and, accompanied by Black, demands to be magically escorted to the man who poses him the greatest danger. He is faced with Vinculus, whom he finds an unlikely foe and promptly hangs by means of magic.</p>
<p>Strange reveals to Norrell that he seeks his old teacher’s aid, not vengeance. Together, they determine how to call John Uskglass back to England, so that they might use his magic to free <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19761 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/valentin-petkov-FK5uXiCp9-Q-unsplash-169x300.jpg" alt="" width="169" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/valentin-petkov-FK5uXiCp9-Q-unsplash-169x300.jpg 169w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/valentin-petkov-FK5uXiCp9-Q-unsplash-576x1024.jpg 576w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/valentin-petkov-FK5uXiCp9-Q-unsplash-768x1365.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/valentin-petkov-FK5uXiCp9-Q-unsplash-864x1536.jpg 864w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/valentin-petkov-FK5uXiCp9-Q-unsplash-1152x2048.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/valentin-petkov-FK5uXiCp9-Q-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px" />Arabella and Lady Pole. Uskglass does return, but in an unexpected manner—and not to them. Childermass, who has just discovered Vinculus’s body—and the strange writing that covers him (comprising the book of John Uskglass)—unknowingly encounters the Raven King. Uskglass brings Vinculus back to life.</p>
<p>Strange and Norrell unwittingly grant the powers of England—stone, sky, tree, and water—to Black. As the gentleman in the thistledown hair attempts to kill Lady Pole (now freed from her enchantment), Black wreaks vengeance upon him, washing him away in a stream and burying him under stone and rock. Shortly thereafter, Black finds himself in a reinvented Lost-hope, where he becomes a new and better king.</p>
<p>Arabella finds herself freed of Lost-hope upon the gentleman’s death and emerges from the mirror in Flora Graysteel’s care.</p>
<p>And Strange and Norrell realize—however fleetingly—how insignificant they are in the scope of John Uskglass’s concerns and turn with renewed energy to their study of magic, entrapped still in the darkness. Stealing themselves away from the mortal world and its concerns, the magicians leave England unencumbered and Childermass conveys to the magicians of the York society, and anyone else who desires to practice magic, that they may do so once again. Magic has truly returned to England.</p>
<p><u>Response</u></p>
<p>The <em>carnival</em>, Mikhail Bakhtin writes, is “the true feast of time, the feast of becoming, change, and renewal. It [is] hostile to all that [is] immortalized and completed.”</p>
<p>As a grad student in medieval studies, I was required to know something of Bakhtin and his theory of the <a href="https://www.oxfordreference.com/view/10.1093/oi/authority.20110803095550811"><em>carnivalesque</em></a> which, in simple terms, theorizes that the non-dominant classes and members of society are given limited and controlled times in which to upturn the status quo (thus, carnivals which often included the lampooning of religious and secular officials) so that they do not upturn it in a more enduring fashion.</p>
<p>As I complete my read-through of <em>Jonathan Strange &amp; Mr. Norrell</em>, I find that I still love it. But it also puts me in a reflective mood (not just because the last page is the best sort of melancholy). With the completion of this series, I am putting my column on hiatus so I can finish up some other pressing writing and job obligations. And I find that I want to end my treatment of the novel with something that probably departs from any authorial intent on Clarke’s part. This is truly a response, rather than an analysis.</p>
<p>In these last chapters, Strange declares that “I have changed England to save my wife.” After all of the professional squabbles and clash of egos, it is love and family and humanity that drive Strange and Norrell to do something truly great. However, it is not ultimately they who save Arabella. It is Stephen Black who, mistaken for John Uskglass and temporarily granted all the magical powers of England, kills the gentleman with the thistledown hair. A gentleman who he has watched commit horrible atrocities. Who has dulled Black’s very existence. Who has justified his manipulation of Black by promises of future glory.</p>
<p>Who has, however, also paid attention to Black in a way that no one else in the novel has, despite his constant forced and unforced self-sacrifice on their behalf.</p>
<p>When invested with England’s essence, Black realizes that he finally has power: “Now all of England lay cupped in his black palm. All Englishmen were at his mercy.” The structures of power have been turned topsy-turvy, and his thoughts of vengeance are justified. Instead, Black saves Lady Pole. And England realizes that Black is not Uskglass and its magic leaves him.</p>
<p>And this is where the carnivalesque fails us. Temporary inversions do not make permanent change. Though Black finds another place to rule, in fairy, it is not England: “Stephen had done with England and England had done with him.”</p>
<p>Clarke’s depiction of Stephen Black is not perfect. But the end of <em>Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell </em>reminded me that I, with whatever privilege I have, need to work to disrupt the status quo—constantly and continually. Not temporarily, not for a couple of months. Even if there is no magic to make it easier.</p>
<p>And this is the work of literature, to make us more empathetic. To make us pause. To make us the examine the structures in which we live.</p>
<p>Check out ways to support the Black Lives Matter movement <a href="https://blacklivesmatter.com/">here</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">#</p>
<p>Since this will be my last piece for a while, I just want to say thank you to the whole blog crew at <em>Luna Station Quarterly. </em>This blog produces a lot of content and they deserve recognition for all of their hard work!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“UnChristian and UnEnglish”: Reading Susanna Clarke’s Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/unchristian-and-unenglish-reading-susanna-clarkes-jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin K. Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 11:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Woman Was Here]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to our re-read of Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. For the month of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back to our re-read of <a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell-9781408891469/"><em>Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. </em></a>For the month of August, we’re looking at chapters 57-64, wherein magic returns to England.</p>
<p><u>Recap</u></p>
<p>Stuck within the darkness in Venice, Strange reaches out to his brother-in-law, Henry Woodhope. Woodhope, upset by letters that say Arabella is still alive, goes to Norrell for advice. Norrell uses <img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19345 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/leonardo-yip-rVcuY3LfH_Q-unsplash1-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/leonardo-yip-rVcuY3LfH_Q-unsplash1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/leonardo-yip-rVcuY3LfH_Q-unsplash1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/leonardo-yip-rVcuY3LfH_Q-unsplash1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/leonardo-yip-rVcuY3LfH_Q-unsplash1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/leonardo-yip-rVcuY3LfH_Q-unsplash1-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />these letters to discredit his former student.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Lascelles sends the impoverished Drawlight to Italy to collect information. While there, Drawlight is confronted by Strange and given three messages to deliver. To Childermass, the truth of Arabella and Lady Pole’s captivity (with Lady Pole’s finger). To all the magicians of England, the alliances with tree, stone, sky, and water that Uskglass established are still active. To Norrell, that he is coming back to England.</p>
<p>Flora Graysteel encounters Strange one last time and is given guardianship over a mysterious mirror. Norrell is called to account by Lord Liverpool for magic spontaneously performed by untrained personages all over England, who claim that the stones and sky tell them what to do. Lascelles intercepts Drawlight and kills him, fearing the security of his position with Norrell. Consequently, Lascelles, Norrell, and Childermass retreat to Hurtfew Abbey, Norrell’s country home. There, Childermass and Lascelles quarrel, and Childermass leaves Norrell’s service. Childermass, having recovered Lady Pole’s finger from Lascelles, returns it to her and she finds herself finally and fully back in England.</p>
<p>And Norrell finds himself visited by Strange at last.</p>
<p><u>Response</u></p>
<p>These chapters drive home the examination of English nationalism in the text and ask us to question how nationalism gets tied up with other identities—religious, for one.</p>
<p>When Strange needs Drawlight to understand his message about Uskglass’s old alliances with <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19346 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/lachlan-gowen-MVa-JxwzQlQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/lachlan-gowen-MVa-JxwzQlQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/lachlan-gowen-MVa-JxwzQlQ-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/lachlan-gowen-MVa-JxwzQlQ-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/lachlan-gowen-MVa-JxwzQlQ-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/lachlan-gowen-MVa-JxwzQlQ-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />the land, he inundates him with a vision of sorts, one in which “he became England” by embodying the rain, the stones, the waterways of the nation’s landscape. What has been continually repeated throughout the novel becomes explicit and pointed near the end: Strange is trying to resurrect not just any magic, but a particularly English magic.</p>
<p>This nationalism, though, that Strange and other characters exhibit, is inherently flawed. Though scholars <a href="https://www.oxfordhandbooks.com/view/10.1093/oxfordhb/9780199935338.001.0001/oxfordhb-9780199935338-e-70?rskey=56HVRm&amp;result=5">debate</a> when British or English nationalism took hold, we can certainly trace its rocky, problematic trajectory to the <a href="http://www.uscannenbergmedia.com/2019/04/04/how-modern-nationalism-led-to-brexit/">present day</a>. And Clarke does not flinch away from examining both twenty-first-century and nineteenth-century nationalism simultaneously. Commentary from Stephen Black, for example, on how tired he is of “English arrogance and English malice” should make us pause before celebrating a distinctly English magic. After all, the Graysteels dismiss the Italian language of their hired servants as “dialect words” and Lascelles’s dedication to a toxic masculine idea of honor leads to his own foolhardy attempt to defend “England’s honor” (and his entrapment as the Champion of a fairy castle).</p>
<p>When we find out, then, that John Uskglass himself is regarded as “unChristian” and “unEnglish” by Lascelles, we are faced with a contradiction. Uskglass’s magic both represents England but is also labeled un-English by others who highly value their nationalistic identity. How can we reconcile this? Perhaps by recognizing the link between nationalism and religious identities. Christianity is not English, but certainly English nationalism has incorporated Christianity into itself. And, this portion of the novel reminds us, Christianity has often been wary of folk magics and fairy lore. Uskglass is reputed to have had Lucifer as an ally and we see clergy members suddenly wary of association with Mr. Norrell. This uneasy alliance between England and Fairy is grounded in real conflict of the Middle Ages (see Dr. Richard Firth Green’s <a href="https://muse.jhu.edu/article/685802">research</a> on how ideas of fairy get neutralized by or co-opted into Christian theology). The idea of what England is, then, is constantly shifting. There is no one true <em>England </em>to return to, no matter how much the characters may depend on it.</p>
<p>Uskglass is a walking contradiction, one that threatens our characters’ national allegiances even while they suppose him to be the representation thereof. After all, the fairy roads (the King’s Roads) that appear as magic floods through England are “not like Christian roads” and they “lead everywhere,” part of and yet outside of England. And approaching fairy as a defender of England’s honor does not save you, as Lascelles finds out to his detriment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“You Must be Arrogance”: Reading Susanna Clarke’s Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/you-must-be-arrogance-reading-susanna-clarkes-jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin K. Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 11:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Woman Was Here]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to our re-read of Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. For the month of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back to our re-read of <a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell-9781408891469/"><em>Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. </em></a>For the month of July, we’re looking at chapters 49-56, wherein Strange finally meets the gentleman with the thistledown hair.</p>
<p><u>Recap</u></p>
<p>Strange’s book, <em>The History and Practice of English Magic,</em> is released to the reading public, and Mr. Norrell promptly employs magic to steal copies of it from the hands of readers and the shelves of booksellers alike. In consequence, public opinion turns against Norrell.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Strange is eager to meet with a fairy because he is convinced that doing so is the only true way to progress in English magic—yet he has promised Arabella, his late wife, that he would not walk on the King’s Roads again. His new method, which he cultivates while abroad in Europe, is to engender madness in himself, since fairies are said to be attracted to those so afflicted. In dabbling with such magic, though, Strange unwittingly puts his new friends, the Greysteels, in danger and realizes—perhaps too late—the real fate of his wife, stolen away to dance eternally in the court of the gentleman with the thistledown hair. By visiting the court of the gentleman, who is already surprised at Strange’s power, Strange incurs his wrath and finds himself wrapped in eternal night.</p>
<p><u>Response</u></p>
<p>When Strange visits the court of the gentleman with the thistledown hair, he engages in an unsettling conversation with a fairy lady there. She implies that Strange is out of his depth and unaware of the full ramifications of the prophecy about him—as “one of the two magicians who is destined to return magic to England.” These two magicians she labels Fearfulness and Arrogance and quickly determines that Strange is Arrogance. The label made me pause.</p>
<p>These chapters, in general, focus on the arrogance of men swanning about Europe and <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19112 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/photo-of-british-shorthair-cat-sitting-on-grass-field-1521306-236x300.jpg" alt="" width="236" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/photo-of-british-shorthair-cat-sitting-on-grass-field-1521306-236x300.jpg 236w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/photo-of-british-shorthair-cat-sitting-on-grass-field-1521306-804x1024.jpg 804w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/photo-of-british-shorthair-cat-sitting-on-grass-field-1521306-768x978.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/photo-of-british-shorthair-cat-sitting-on-grass-field-1521306-1206x1536.jpg 1206w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/photo-of-british-shorthair-cat-sitting-on-grass-field-1521306-1608x2048.jpg 1608w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/photo-of-british-shorthair-cat-sitting-on-grass-field-1521306.jpg 2010w" sizes="(max-width: 236px) 100vw, 236px" />squabbling over books. Strange, for example, meets <a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/lord-byron">Byron</a> in the course of his travels and they take “an immediate dislike to each other.” One cannot help but realize this is the result of two self-important men wrestling for dominance. More dangerously, perhaps, Strange becomes so obsessed with his magic and skill that he does not stop and consider the ramifications of the Jekyll-and-Hyde-esque tincture he makes to bring on madness (and thus access to fairy). In the course of this magic, he turns an old lady into a cat (something he assumes she wants), hurts the woman he is courting, and ends up cursing the part of the city where he lives to darkness. Thus it is no wonder that when he finally arrives at the fairy court, Lady Pole is dismissive of his ability or desire to help either herself or Arabella. When Strange insists that he wants to talk to his wife, she confronts him with a question: “Did you come here to help us?” And he is forced to say no. Lady Pole thus writes off all men: “I put no faith in them at all.”</p>
<p>In sum, these chapters deal with the privilege and obliviousness of white men. If nothing else tunes us into this, Strange’s echoing of Jane Austen’s <a href="https://janeausten.fandom.com/wiki/William_Collins">Mr. Collins</a> in <em>Pride and Prejudice</em>—one of her greatest buffoons—should do so. Strange assumes the fairy lady who insults him is like women in Europe who “pretended to scold the men they meant to attract.” An earlier reference to <em>Emma</em>, another of Austen’s works, prepares us for this allusion.</p>
<p>However, I became particularly aware of the voice of yet another in this chapter, one that underlines and supports the actors and reminds our readers of how deeply ingrained patriarchy and racism are in the society under investigation. This voice is that of the narrator, clearly a character unto himself. Clarke uses the narrator to show how ubiquitous are the problematic views of her characters, particularly of her men.</p>
<p>For example, we meet Strange’s pupils in these chapters, three young men, two of which are “well-born English gentlemen” and the other a Jewish “ex-dancing-master”: William Hadley-Bright, Henry Purfois, and Tom Levy. We learn that the two gentlemen are prejudiced against the dancing master. The narrator describes this in his usual sardonic manner: “Knowing Tom to be the most talented amongst them, they generally deferred to him in all matters of magical scholarship, and, apart from calling him by his given name…and expecting him to pick up books they left behind them, they were very much inclined to treat him as an equal.” England, much like most of Europe, has a particularly <a href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/anti-Semitism/Nazi-anti-Semitism-and-the-Holocaust">terrifying past with antisemitism</a>, something we see echoes of in later chapters where the Greysteels visits an old Jewish friend of the family. So it is disturbing, then, when we see the narrator follow the model of his characters. Whereas the narrator references the gentlemen by their full or last names throughout this paragraph, he references Tom by first name. You see this even in the quote above.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-19114 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/John_Martin_-_Manfred_on_the_Jungfrau_1837-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/John_Martin_-_Manfred_on_the_Jungfrau_1837-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/John_Martin_-_Manfred_on_the_Jungfrau_1837.jpg 700w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />The narrator thus becomes a character, one that often adopts the self-obsessed and problematic perspective of the white men in the narrative. This perspective is hammered home by Byron’s narcissistic response to Strange’s predicament; he uses it as inspiration for his poem “Manfred.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, it is Stephen Black who finds himself perpetually forced into the role of helping those around him, and Strange cannot even remember his name when they meet at the fairy ball, “though he had heard Sir Walter speak it a hundred times.” We can only hope that the curse laid on Strange helps him wake up to his responsibilities and the harm he has done.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Madhouse Keeper: Reading Susanna Clarke’s Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-madhouse-keeper-reading-susanna-clarkes-jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin K. Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 11:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Woman Was Here]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18723</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to our re-read of Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. For the month of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-18895 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Jonathan_strange_and_mr_norrell_cover-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Jonathan_strange_and_mr_norrell_cover-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Jonathan_strange_and_mr_norrell_cover.jpg 257w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Welcome back to our re-read of <a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell-9781408891469/"><em>Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. </em></a>For the month of June, we’re looking at chapters 41-48, wherein more than one wife is separated from her husband.</p>
<p><u>Recap</u></p>
<p>With the patronage of the wealthy Mrs. Lennox, Segundus tries to start a school of magic and is consequently harassed and shut down by Norrell. Meanwhile Strange begins his oft-footnoted book, <em>The History and Practice of English Magic</em>—which is excerpted for us in chapter 45. This book forces its readers to acknowledge the fay influence of the Raven King on English magic.</p>
<p>The gentleman with the thistledown hair makes all too clear his impact on the English world. Arabella Strange starts wandering the moors and dies suddenly, i.e. is stolen away to the realm of fairy. And Lady Pole, stricken with grief at the fate of her friend, attempts to kill Norrell. As a consequence, she is sent away to Segundus’s school, now changed through Norrell’s harassment into a genteel madhouse. After escorting her there, Black encounters the street-magician Vinculus, whose entire skin is covered in tattoos.</p>
<p><u>Response</u></p>
<p>It is almost passé now to reference Charlotte Perkins Gilman’s “<a href="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/exhibition/theliteratureofprescription/exhibitionAssets/digitalDocs/The-Yellow-Wall-Paper.pdf">The Yellow Wallpaper</a>” in a <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-18896 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/wallpaper-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/wallpaper-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/wallpaper.jpg 317w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />feminist argument about the control and repression of women, but allow me to mention it once more. The story was published in 1892 and in America, some 76 years after the events in Clarke’s English novel. But it narrates the gradual insanity of a woman trapped for “her own good,” for a rest cure after giving birth. Gilman based this on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Yellow_Wallpaper">her own exposure</a> to such a cure.</p>
<p>The woman in the story becomes obsessed with the pattern of the wallpaper in the room she is constrained to, convinced that there is a woman trapped in it, “trying to climb through” and escape. Eventually, she identifies as the woman in the wallpaper, who frees herself in an attempt to control her own fate. The story is meant to exemplify the mistreatment of women’s physical and mental health.</p>
<p>The history of women and asylums is very similar in Britain to that in America. In the 1800s, women “<a href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/arts/history/chm/outreach/trade_in_lunacy/research/womenandmadness/">were deemed likely to fall prey to disorders of the mind related to their biological vulnerability and the female life cycle</a>” and consequently committed. Women were considered frail by reason of their very identity and often asylums were used merely to control or discipline women who defied typical gender roles.</p>
<p>Though, in <em>JSMN</em>, Lady Pole does indeed commit a terrible crime, attempting to murder Norrell, her sequestering at Segundus’s facility raises some important questions about how women are possessed, controlled, and manipulated by the men in these chapters and the book more broadly. Even Lady Pole, it must be remembered, suffers daily the tortures of living half in fairy and half in England due to Norrell’s ill-thought-out cure. She attempts to kill Norrell because she realizes her friend Arabella has been condemned to a similar fate, stolen away by the gentleman with the thistledown hair.</p>
<p>Lady Pole’s agony comes down to Norrell who, out of fear of revealing his own missteps, refuses to acknowledge or revisit her condition. We are reminded of how much he ultimately controls her fate when Black urges Segundus to hide his own profession from Lady Pole: “There is nothing in this world—in this world or any other—that would give her ladyship greater pain than to find herself <em>in thrall</em> to another magician.”</p>
<p>Ultimately, even more so than Norrell, the gentleman with the thistledown hair blithely manipulates and controls whoever he hopes to possess. This includes, of course, Black himself who is forced to help the gentleman procure the very moss-oak that will “obtain” Arabella. Though, the gentlemen still praises Lady Pole as an “addition” to his collection, he expresses that he likes Arabella more, but views himself in a constant struggle with Strange for her attention. This, in and of itself, points out the ownership model underlying much of the problematic marriage politics of the era.</p>
<p>And in Arabella’s abduction/death, we see an additional criticism of Strange. When Arabella finally returns to her home, wet and cold, after a mysterious disappearance, the neighbors are disturbed by the harsh tone of Strange’s questions: “the ladies began to think that it was her husband’s harshness that made her so quiet.” Though we know, as readers, that Strange is not typically harsh to Arabella (if anything, he is neglectful), the neighbors’ perceptions cue us into the position of power that Strange holds in his own marriage. Though his tone ultimately stems from fear, Strange’s authoritative questions, without accompanying care for Arabella’s distress, reveal his assumed dominance.</p>
<p>These chapters of the novel highlight the marginalized members of society that are ultimately hurt and controlled by white men in positions of power, whether due to obliviousness, maliciousness, or pettiness. It reminds us that magic, just like education or healthcare, can be used to reinforce damaging social hierarchies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Fairy Roads Lead Nowhere At All”: Reading Susanna Clarke’s Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fairy-roads-lead-nowhere-at-all-reading-susanna-clarkes-jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin K. Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Woman Was Here]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to our re-read of Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. For the month of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back to our re-read of <a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell-9781408891469/"><em>Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. </em></a>For the month of May, we’re looking at chapters 33-40, wherein the magicians part ways.</p>
<p><u>Recap</u></p>
<p>Jonathan Strange, while aiding the king of England, finds himself locked in magical conflict with the gentleman of the thistledown hair (who he does not yet know) for the well-being of the king. The gentleman wishes to clear the way for Stephen Black to rule England, and though Strange successfully resists him, he finds himself more attuned than ever to otherworldly influences. We <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18204 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mirror-4078601_1280-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mirror-4078601_1280-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mirror-4078601_1280-1024x1024.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mirror-4078601_1280-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mirror-4078601_1280-768x768.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mirror-4078601_1280-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mirror-4078601_1280.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />find out that Arabella Strange has also come to know the gentleman, though she assumes he is a displaced king who lives at the Poles’ house.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Mr. Lascelles is abusing the name of the magicians for his own profit, promising long-distance lessons and personal commission without their knowledge. When Strange encounters two of these supposed students, he is pushed to demonstrate his own magic in unprecedented ways. He travels through a mirror—and thus through a strange land—to interrupt one of Mr. Lascelles’s meetings, throwing all of the man’s shady plans into disarray. But the fervor for the fairy world and the Raven King’s magic that this inspires in Strange creates a rift between himself and Mr. Norrell. The two of them break their arrangement and Strange finds himself shortly thereafter called to help fight Napoleon upon his escape from Elba.</p>
<p><u>Response</u></p>
<p>Jonathan Strange’s increasing conviction that the key to truly understanding and performing English magic lies in embracing the lore surrounding the Raven King means that these chapters focus a lot on fairy roads and paths, as well as fairies themselves. As such, we find these chapters engaging with medieval folklore. And this recalls one of the incidents I find most fascinating in medieval chronicles.</p>
<p>Norrell describes fairy roads as “wide green roads between high green hedges or stone walls” and he explains that these roads have fallen into disuse. He also dismisses superstition and fear concerning them, insisting that “[f]airy roads lead nowhere at all.” When Strange becomes obsessed with otherworldly roads and the possibility that mirrors might provide an entry point onto them, Norrell is forced to admit that there is “a path which joins all the mirrors of the world,” one which was “well-known to the Great Mediaevals.” This novel, after all, repeatedly asserts that there was a “thriving community of magicians and fairies” in the Middle Ages. Indeed, Strange’s jokes about how to acquire a fairy patron (to wander in “out-of-the-way copses and mossy glades”) reflects medieval romances, where fairies were most often met alone in liminal spaces—by running water and under trees (particularly <a href="https://d.lib.rochester.edu/teams/text/laskaya-and-salisbury-middle-english-breton-lays-sir-orfeo">grafted ones</a>). Modern fantasy classics, like<a href="https://narnia.fandom.com/wiki/The_Silver_Chair"> C. S. Lewis’s <em>The Silver Chair</em></a> also play with these conventions.</p>
<p>But medieval fiction was not the only genre fascinated with the otherworld. Here and there, we see references pop up in contemporary historical records as well. One such example is the account of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Green_children_of_Woolpit">green children</a> who wandered into the English village of Woolpit in the 12<sup>th</sup> century. You can find one version of it in William of Newburgh’s <em>Historia rerum Anglicarum</em>, translated into English <a href="https://sourcebooks.fordham.edu/basis/williamofnewburgh-one.asp#27">here</a>. The chronicle recounts a heavily-witnessed account of two children with green skin wandering into the village, unable to speak English and unable to eat anything but beans. Their skin color seems directly related to their diet, as the text indicates they “changed their original color, through the natural effect of our food” after a while. The children have very little knowledge of their past, but know they lived in a land without sun and can assure the anxious villagers that it was Christian, an indication to readers that there is concern about the otherworldly origins of these children. The chronicle presents the incident as odd and follows it <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18210 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/forest-1967253_1280-281x300.jpg" alt="" width="281" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/forest-1967253_1280-281x300.jpg 281w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/forest-1967253_1280-958x1024.jpg 958w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/forest-1967253_1280-768x821.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/forest-1967253_1280.jpg 1197w" sizes="(max-width: 281px) 100vw, 281px" />up with a list of other strange incidents—including one wherein a drunken man finds a group of men and women feasting in a house set into a hill and steals away a cup of “unknown material, unusual color, and strange form.”</p>
<p>And the concept of roads that might run between fairy and human worlds, is not without its medieval origins as well—perhaps, most famously, in the legends of <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Thomas-the-Rhymer">Thomas Erceldoune</a> (or Thomas the Rhymer), a thirteenth-century Scottish seer who was later reputed to have visited fairyland. In the <a href="https://archive.org/details/romanceprophecie00thomuoft/page/12/mode/2up">late medieval romance</a> about him, Thomas takes up with a fairy mistress and she shows him roads to heaven, hell, and her own country. This is retold in one of Child’s later <a href="https://www.sacred-texts.com/neu/eng/child/ch037.htm">ballads</a><u>,</u> where Thomas is shown three paths:</p>
<p>O see ye not yon narrow road,</p>
<p>So thick beset with thorns and briers?</p>
<p>That is the path of righteousness,</p>
<p>Tho after it but few enquires.</p>
<p>‘And see not ye that braid braid road,</p>
<p>That lies across that lily leven?<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18213 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/landscape-1949474_1280-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/landscape-1949474_1280-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/landscape-1949474_1280-1024x1024.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/landscape-1949474_1280-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/landscape-1949474_1280-768x768.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/landscape-1949474_1280-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/landscape-1949474_1280.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>That is the path of wickedness,</p>
<p>Tho some call it the road to heaven.</p>
<p>‘And see not ye that bonny road,</p>
<p>That winds about the fernie brae?</p>
<p>That is the road to fair Elfland,</p>
<p>Where thou and I this night maun gae.</p>
<p>It is his journey to fairy land that grants Thomas his prophetic ability. How will Strange’s journeys on otherworldly roads change him? We’ll have to read and find out!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“One Need Not So Much As Look Upon Another of One’s Fellow Creatures”: Reading Susanna Clarke’s Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/one-need-not-so-much-as-look-upon-another-of-ones-fellow-creatures-reading-susanna-clarkes-jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin K. Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Woman Was Here]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to our re-read of Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. For the month of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back to our re-read of <a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell-9781408891469/"><em>Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. </em></a>For the month of April, we’re looking at chapters 25-32, wherein the magicians go to battle!</p>
<p><u>Recap</u></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17630 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/library-980732_1280-300x144.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="144" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/library-980732_1280-300x144.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/library-980732_1280-1024x493.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/library-980732_1280-768x370.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/library-980732_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell settle into their roles as student and teacher. Together, they are able to renew efforts to use magic to aid the English in the war with Napoleon. Arabella Strange is introduced to Lady Pole, who seems curiously unable to say what she wants about her mysterious illness. Instead, she tells long winding stories about magical folks and events unrelated to her own present circumstances. Stephen Black is afflicted with a similar problem, though the gentleman with the thistledown hair has promised him an earthly kingdom.</p>
<p>Strange is recruited to go to Portugal himself and help with the war firsthand. Norrell is convinced to let him go out of his own desire to possess the library of the Duke of Roxburghe (which he fears Strange will also want). While in Portugal, Strange works hard to gain the respect of Lord Wellington, marching and eating alongside the English soldiers. He becomes indispensable to the war efforts, though is forced to engage in questionable necromantic magic. When Strange finally returns to England, he is a hero, called upon to attend the “mad” king, where he finds magic afoot cast neither by himself nor Norrell.</p>
<p><u>Response</u></p>
<p>There are moments to analyze in these chapters that build on the themes and concerns we’ve already identified in our read-through.</p>
<p>Stephen Black is literally and magically silenced (as is Lady Pole) in his attempt to express his suffering under the attentions of the gentleman with the thistledown hair. We also hear more about his origins—“My mother was a slave on an estate in Jamaica that Sir Walter’s grandfather owned”—and are reminded that the English, though they may not allow slaves on the British isle, “own slaves in other countries.” This hypocrisy is highlighted again and again in the text.</p>
<p>These chapters also remind us, right and left, of Europe’s medieval, Gothic, and Romantic literary heritage, as it namedrops <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chr%C3%A9tien_de_Troyes">Chrétien de Troyes</a>, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ann_Radcliffe">Ann Radcliffe</a>, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Scott">Walter Scott</a>, each an author influential in their time for determining taste and style. These are appropriate references for a novel so steeped in its literary influences that it not only evokes the history and culture of Regency-era England, but imitates its writing. We are reminded strongly of this when the text censors Strange’s cursing: “D—!” The strikethrough is familiar to any reader of Austen or her contemporaries who used the dash to mark out place names (<a href="http://www2.iath.virginia.edu/elab/hfl0256.html">for the sake of generalizing the text</a><u>)</u> or swear words (<a href="https://dianeclement.wordpress.com/2013/12/02/swearing-and-taboo-in-jane-austens-works/">for common decency</a>!).</p>
<p>But what I would like to focus on, for a moment, is how the text dwells on Mr. Norrell’s introversion and desire for solitude. Studies have been done on how the act of reading can stimulate <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2011/sep/07/reading-fiction-empathy-study">empathy.</a> But it must also be acknowledged that we approach reading egocentrically sometimes. And as I started these chapters, I was immediately struck by Mr. Norrell’s description of a career in magic: “best of all, one need not so much as look upon another of one’s fellow creatures from one month’s end to the next if one does not wish it!” The line struck an odd chord, contextualized as it was by reading it during the 2020 pandemic. As an introverted extrovert myself (or an extroverted introvert?), the concept of social isolation is daunting.</p>
<p>Because even Norrell needs a friend. And though Strange finds Norrell annoying, Norrell himself becomes very attached to his pupil over these chapters: “His feelings of attachment seemed all the stronger for being entirely new; he had never felt truly comfortable in any one’s society before.” It is only Norrell’s obsession with books that ultimately reconciles him to Strange’s <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17782 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/janko-ferlic-sfL_QOnmy00-unsplash-300x277.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="277" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/janko-ferlic-sfL_QOnmy00-unsplash-300x277.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/janko-ferlic-sfL_QOnmy00-unsplash-1024x947.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/janko-ferlic-sfL_QOnmy00-unsplash-768x710.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/janko-ferlic-sfL_QOnmy00-unsplash-1536x1420.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/janko-ferlic-sfL_QOnmy00-unsplash-2048x1893.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />departure for the war. And I find myself more sympathetic with Norrell on this re-reading of the text. He is selfish, yes, but he is also discovering friendship for the first time. And one might imagine what the loss of that would lead someone to do. I am wondering myself how I will change over the next weeks or months.</p>
<p>Sir Walter’s reprimand of Norrell’s reluctance to part with Strange—“But every man must be prepared to make sacrifices for the sake of his country during a war”—might be a rallying cry for us all right now. Obviously, we should decry the nationalistic and jingoistic tendencies of Sir Walter Pole and the English. We should not fall prey to racism and xenophobia.</p>
<p>But we can turn to magic for comfort and embrace solitude by reading books and watching movies and chatting online with friends And, from a distance, <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2020/03/21/how-you-can-help-during-coronavirus/?arc404=true">help those in need</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Like a Person Sleepwalking: Reading Susanna Clarke’s &#8220;Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/like-a-person-sleepwalking-reading-susanna-clarkes-jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin K. Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 11:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Woman Was Here]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17298</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to our re-read of Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. For the month of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back to our re-read of <a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell-9781408891469/"><em>Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. </em></a>For the month of March, we’re looking at chapters 17–24 wherein the fey world impinges ever more on our own!</p>
<p><u>Recap</u></p>
<p>Mysterious happenings are afoot in the house of Sir Walter Pole and wherever Lady Pole and Stephen Black venture. Mrs. Brandy, a widowed grocer infatuated with Mr. Black, finds twenty-five glowing guineas in her shop. The streets of London lead to fairyland when Black ventures out at night. And Lady Pole has grown cold and still and quiet. When Mr. Norrell confronts the man with the thistledown hair about her condition, he is scared off by the fairy’s anger. But the man with the thistledown hair thinks very highly of Black and plans to make him a noble of fairyland, despite all of Black’s protestations to the contrary.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Mr. Norrell is intent on ridding London (and all of England) of anyone who assumes the title of magician. To this end, he sends Childermass to run Vinculus out of town, but Childermass finds that Vinculus has some tricks up his sleeve, and the prophecy of the Raven King feels ever more real.</p>
<p>Jonathan Strange, intent on finding a profession so as to please his fiancée (and later wife), Arabella Woodhope, finally settles on magic as one to his liking. He has a natural knack for it. The last remnants of the Learned Society of York Magicians stumble upon Mr. Strange in the <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17522 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/mario-klassen-pfkSmvryyzk-unsplash-300x186.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="186" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/mario-klassen-pfkSmvryyzk-unsplash-300x186.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/mario-klassen-pfkSmvryyzk-unsplash-1024x636.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/mario-klassen-pfkSmvryyzk-unsplash-768x477.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/mario-klassen-pfkSmvryyzk-unsplash-1536x954.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/mario-klassen-pfkSmvryyzk-unsplash-2048x1272.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />ruins of Shadow House, a gloomy abode once owned by the Tudor magician, Gregory Absalom. At their suggestion, Strange introduces himself to Mr. Norrell. Initially, the two disagree over the nature of English magic and the respect to be accorded the Raven King, but their shared passion for magic overcomes initial dislike. Mr. Norrell takes Strange on as an apprentice.</p>
<p><u>Response</u></p>
<p>The living dream in which Mr. Black finds himself disassociates him from the real world: he “felt like a person sleepwalking.” And yet chapters 17 and 19 remind us that Black’s <em>real </em>world has nightmarish qualities as well.</p>
<p>Upon returning from Mrs. Brandy’s shop, Black accidentally bumps into another gentleman. Despite the innocence of the encounter, the gentleman is immediately suspicious: “Instantly he was all alarm; he saw a black face close to his own face and black hands near his pockets and valuables . . . immediately concluding that he was about to be robbed or knocked down, he raised his umbrella to strike a blow in his own defence.” The moment is horrifying, yet it is not one that surprises Black. In fact, it “was the moment that Stephen had dreaded all his life.” He has very real concerns about the likelihood of an English jury acquitting him if he were to be arrested. It is only the transformation of Piccadilly into fairy that saves Black from discovering whether his fears are founded. The narrative, though brief, is incredibly poignant in light of ongoing conversations regarding racial prejudice and law enforcement.</p>
<p>But it is not only strangers who are implicated in nineteenth-century racism. Chapter 19 reminds us that slavery is still alive and well—and that ultimately Walter Pole, no matter how beneficent to Black, is complicit in the institution. When discussing his position with the man with the thistledown hair, Black lists for himself the many ways in which Pole has helped him, but cannot help but be struck by the fey gentleman’s description of the lord: “Because in the fulsomeness of his wickedness he has captured you and girded you with chains and now he triumphs over you, dancing about and howling with wicked laughter to see you in such straits.” Black cannot accept this entire description and is still set against the plan of the man with the thistledown hair to elevate him, but he is forced to take stock:  “the word ‘chains’ seemed to send a sort of silent thunderbolt through him.” Black has a sudden vision of the hold of a slave ship: “a hot, rank, closed-in place.” Black does not recognize the image for what it is but is nonetheless horrified. The man with the thistledown hair and the accompanying conflation of the worlds of fairy and human have revealed the nightmares that already exist in Black’s world, ones that Pole is safe from and one that he implicitly (if not explicitly) endorses. Britain did not <a href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/Slavery-Abolition-Act">abolish slavery until 1834</a>.</p>
<p>Despite the natural aversion its characters hold to the encroachment of fairyland, the novel seems to ask us to consider which world is really worse: nineteenth-century Britain or the eternal realm of fairy.</p>
<p>For a larger discussion of marginalized identities in <em>Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell, </em>I recommend you check out Elizabeth Hoiem’s <a href="http://strangehorizons.com/non-fiction/articles/the-fantasy-of-talking-back-susanna-clarkes-historical-present-in-jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell/">2008 essay</a> in <em>Strange Horizons. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lost-hope House and Heart-break Farm: Reading Susanna Clarke’s &#8220;Jonathan Strange &#038; Mr. Norrell&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lost-hope-house-and-heart-break-farm-reading-susanna-clarkes-jonathan-strange-mr-norrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin K. Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Woman Was Here]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to our re-read of Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell. For the month of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17195 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/kate-krivanec-moW-dSe5CiU-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/kate-krivanec-moW-dSe5CiU-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/kate-krivanec-moW-dSe5CiU-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/kate-krivanec-moW-dSe5CiU-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/kate-krivanec-moW-dSe5CiU-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/kate-krivanec-moW-dSe5CiU-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Welcome back to our re-read of <em><a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell-9781408891469/">Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell</a>. </em>For the month of February, we’re looking at chapters 9 through 16, and we finally get a glimpse of our second magician, Strange.</p>
<p><u>Recap</u></p>
<p>Miss Wintertowne, soon-to-be Lady Pole, is almost frighteningly healthy after Mr. Norrell resurrects her and she accepts her new role in society as Sir Pole’s wife with vigor. But there’s a fey influence on her house and the servants are haunted by the sounds of ghostly music, ringing bells, and trees tapping at the windows. Stephen Black, Sir Pole’s butler, finds himself serving a man with thistledown hair in a room he has never seen before and is swept into a ball at the Lost-hope House, a fairy castle, where he finds Lady Pole on the strange gentleman’s arm.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Mr. Norrell uses his magic to aid the war against Napoleon. He crafts ships from rain to barricade the French ports and allow the English ships to move untroubled. His fame skyrockets, and he is convinced by Mr. Drawlight and Mr. Lascelles to edit a new journal on magic. In the midst of this popularity, he is confronted by the street-magician Vinculus (generally considered a fraud), who delivers a prophecy of kingdoms, thrones, and mysterious doorways that is reminiscent of the Raven King. Mr. Norrell is affronted and upset.</p>
<p>And on the Welsh border, a young boy—Jonathan Strange—grows up with his cruel and neglectful father. We see his father die as a consequence of his own petty vendetta against a stubborn manservant. But Strange himself, a young man now, seems mysteriously and often absent from the house.</p>
<p><u>Response</u></p>
<p>These chapters deal with a number of important social issues—all filtered again through a narrator trapped within the society being critiqued and consequently sometimes complicit in the criticized behavior. For one, the marriage of Miss Wintertowne to Sir Pole reveals the inequity of men&#8217;s and women’s status within marriage. Lady Pole does not expect her husband to be engaged in their relationship: “Oh! I know that you will be pretty constantly engaged with business affairs. I know I must not expect anything else.” He cannot protest that and we are told that his own dreams of the marriage were, in fact, based partially on his desire to pontificate: “And being a man—and a clever one—and forty-two years old, he naturally had a great deal of information and a great many opinions upon almost every subject you care to mention, which he was eager to communicate to a lovely woman of nineteen—all of which, he thought, she could not fail but to find quite enthralling.” Though Pole is not an unsympathetic character in the novel, this description of his expectations is a not-so-subtle dig at the gender relations of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regency_era">Regency era</a>, one that anticipates the twenty-first-century term <em>mansplaining.</em> The narrator, omniscient as they are, does not hesitate to reveal these mockable interiorities.</p>
<p>The narrator also turns their critical eye to the treatment of racialized others and people of color within the text, sometimes in more subtle ways. Whereas Mr. Lascelles&#8217; and Mr. Drawlight’s hesitation towards the Scotch (grounded in a very thorny history of intra-island racism) is shortly undercut by the reader’s realization that Jonathan Strange’s own heritage is Scottish, it is the unremarked-upon contrast that must serve as its own commentary. And the novel’s presentation of Perroquet and Stephen Black must be unpacked in the context of a British textual history that exoticizes, when not villainizing, non-white figures.</p>
<p>Perroquet, whose name means parrot, is the servant of a French admiral and is described to be “as dark as a European can be.” Here, already, we have a complicated and troublesome statement about the relationship between nationality and race. But this accords with how thoroughly the omniscient narrator is a part of the world they describe, sometimes reinforcing and sometimes criticizing what they observe. The Admiral is especially proud of the color of his servant’s skin: “Admiral Desmoulins often boasted that he had seen blacks who would appear fair next to Perroquet.” It is clear that Perroquet’s appearance is exoticized; he is treated as a prize and object. It should not be surprising, then, that Sir Pole’s household has a problematic relationship with Stephen Black.</p>
<p>Black’s name draws direct attention to the fact that he is a person of color, a fact of no small <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17196 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/claudio-testa-iqeG5xA96M4-unsplash-300x188.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="188" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/claudio-testa-iqeG5xA96M4-unsplash-300x188.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/claudio-testa-iqeG5xA96M4-unsplash-1024x640.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/claudio-testa-iqeG5xA96M4-unsplash-768x480.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/claudio-testa-iqeG5xA96M4-unsplash-1536x960.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/claudio-testa-iqeG5xA96M4-unsplash-2048x1280.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />importance to the other servants. They are initially “inclined to be indignant” that he is their superior and threaten to be rude if he were ever to give them an order. However, they find themselves incapable of carrying out these threats: “But whatever their intentions, they discovered that when they were actually in Black’s presence they did nothing of the sort. His grave looks, air of authority and reasonable instructions made it very natural to do whatever he told them.” Rather than attributing this authority and reason to Black’s skill and hard work, though, the servants help to circulate (and believe themselves) that he must be a secret African prince. After all, they would never “have submitted to the authority of a <em>black man, </em>had they not instinctively felt that respect and reverence which a commoner feels for a king!” The narrator, of course, presents this as a mockery of the servants’ racism, but the rumor is reminiscent of other British texts that similarly argued for the humanity or status of a black man based on his hidden royalty rather than his innate claim to equality. See, for example, <a href="https://wmich.edu/dialogues/texts/oroonoko.html">the novel <em>Oroonoko, </em>written by Aphra Behn in 1688</a>. Though the text praises the titular character, an African prince stolen into slavery, it does so due to a belief in the &#8220;<a href="https://www.britannica.com/art/noble-savage">noble savage</a>,&#8221; an intensely disturbing perspective.</p>
<p>And though Pole may not know of the rumor about Black’s heritage, the text pokes holes in his attitudes as well: he is “a politician who was pleased to advertise his liberal principles to the world by entrusting the management of his house and business to a black servant.” Pole values Black as an indicator of his own supposed virtue, and the text questions a liberality that is based primarily on public perception rather than a genuine desire to disrupt systemic inequalities.</p>
<p>How will Strange upset or reinforce this system? If you’re reading along, we’ll be looking at chapters 17 through 24 in March. See you then!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gentleman-Magicians: Reading Susanna Clarke’s Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrell</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/gentleman-magicians-reading-susanna-clarkes-jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin K. Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Woman Was Here]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I love Jonathan Strange &#38; Mr. Norrell. It is one of my favorite books of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17014 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/tom-parkes-xuPiZa2TvuQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/tom-parkes-xuPiZa2TvuQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/tom-parkes-xuPiZa2TvuQ-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/tom-parkes-xuPiZa2TvuQ-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/tom-parkes-xuPiZa2TvuQ-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/tom-parkes-xuPiZa2TvuQ-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I love <em><a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/jonathan-strange-and-mr-norrell-9781408891469/">Jonathan Strange &amp; Mr. Norrell</a>. </em>It is one of my favorite books of all time. So imagine my joy when I saw that Susanna Clarke was releasing a novel in 2020—and another one after that! <a href="https://io9.gizmodo.com/susanna-clarke-announces-piranesi-her-first-book-since-1838625083"><em>Piranesi </em></a>is certainly on my must-preorder list.</p>
<p>But <em>Jonathan Strange &amp; Mr. Norrell </em>is also a divisive book. I have friends who similarly loved it and ones who just couldn’t get through it. Perhaps I was drawn to it because I grew up on a steady diet of Austen and Dickens—and Clarke’s work was such a perfect 21st century version of 19th century prose with a complex magical lore that drew from the medieval (I was soon to be a medievalist myself). For whatever reason, the book was a satisfying read. And I want to celebrate Clarke’s work and her impact on me in my column <em>A Woman Was Here </em>for the bulk of 2020.</p>
<p>From January through September, when <em>Piranesi </em>will be released, I will be doing a read-through of <em>Jonathan Strange &amp; Mr. Norrell</em>, one that provides a loose summary, dwells on some of the historical and cultural details, and analyzes the literary devices. I will be covering approximately eight chapters a month (about 100 pages), so I welcome you to follow along. Maybe you’ll discover a new favorite or rediscover an old friend!</p>
<p><em><strong>In January, I’m looking at chapters 1-8, pp. 3-98.</strong></em></p>
<p>In these chapters, we are informed that, in 1806, the magicians of England are theoretical, rather than practical. They are, in essence, scholars—they study what magic was and how it was used, rather than practicing it themselves. This is in contrast to the Golden Age of magic during the Middle Ages (the age in which the Raven King lived). However, due to the efforts of one John Segundus, the only known practical magician is brought out of his solitude. Mr. Norrell, a dry little man, performs a wondrous feat, bringing the statues and stonework of York Cathedral to life. After this affair is publicized, Mr. Norrell’s aide or waiting-man, Mr. Childermass, encourages Mr. Norrell to go to London. There, he is swept into a life of party and petty fame by the hangers-on Mr. Drawlight and Mr. Lascelles. However, Mr. Norrell has grander ambitions. He wants to help England in the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Kingdom_in_the_Napoleonic_Wars">Napoleonic Wars</a>. In order to do so, he approaches Sir Walter Pole, a member of Parliament. Sir Walter thinks magic is cheap trickery until Mr. Norrell brings his fiancée, Miss Wintertowne, back to life. This last event concludes our reading for the month and introduces us to the man with the thistledown hair, the fairy who makes a deal with Norrell in exchange for Miss Wintertowne’s resuscitation: half of her newfound life.</p>
<p>Of course, footnotes throughout the text deepen the alternate history of <em>Jonathan Strange</em>, many of the tidbits drawn from a fictional library of books, some written by characters we meet. This focus on scholarship and textual history is part of what makes Clarke’s novel so fascinating. It is a book built on books, those mentioned within its pages, and those it imitates. The novel replicates the mocked gentlemen’s society of Dicken’s <em>Pickwick Papers </em>(see the York society of magicians) and the social maneuverings of Austen (see the mentions of Brighton and watering places).</p>
<p>But the novel is also one that questions whether books can provide the full picture. Mr. Norrell, for example, dismisses many of the very books he studies, and male characters frequently <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17015 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/sergiu-valena-_Drvb_c_72Y-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/sergiu-valena-_Drvb_c_72Y-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/sergiu-valena-_Drvb_c_72Y-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/sergiu-valena-_Drvb_c_72Y-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/sergiu-valena-_Drvb_c_72Y-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/sergiu-valena-_Drvb_c_72Y-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />deride the reading of novels as feminine or frivolous—an opinion charmingly undermined by its inclusion in a novel. In this respect, Clarke is poking fun at nineteenth-century sexist mores. More importantly, however, it is made clear that many of the greatest magicians did not or could not write in Latin or otherwise to record their lives and practices. A footnote informs us that “[t]he great masters of magic, those we term the Golden Age or <em>Aureate</em> magicians…wrote little, or little has survived. It is probable that Thomas Godbless could not write.” Literacy does not necessarily equate to intelligence or skill. (And lack of textual evidence can be a very real problem for scholars who want to accurately represent all experiences—not just literate ones—of the past.) This is a subtle point that highlights the extreme classism of England’s elite. The characters’ responses (sometimes conflated with or echoed by the narrator’s descriptions) to figures like Childermass (“one of that uncomfortable class of men whose birth is lowly…”) exist to be questioned and undermined in much the same way as does their casual anti-semitism and sexism.</p>
<p>Though these characters’ views serve as our perspective, we are not meant to embrace them. In fact, the novel awaits the disruption of the preening London society by older magic and fairy influence. This, in and of itself, is not an unproblematic view of the Middle Ages, but one very much similar to the actual attempts of eighteenth and nineteenth century readers and writers to rediscover what they perceived to be a purer (alarm bells!) Britain. See, for example, the consternation and fascination with the con-games of poets <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ossian">Macpherson</a> or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Chatterton">Chatterton,</a> who passed off their own work as that of rediscovered medieval poets.</p>
<p>In essence, in imitating so closely the prose and ideology of nineteenth-century England, Clarke turns the culture back on itself in a scathing and entertaining criticism of values that still underlie much of western society.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Passing Extraordinary”: Beatrix Potter</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/passing-extraordinary-beatrix-potter/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/passing-extraordinary-beatrix-potter/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Erin K. Wagner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Woman Was Here]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“On the Germination of the Spores of Agaricineae.” That was the title of the scientific&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16846 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ramamoorthy-kumar-SwuvcKXp3eg-unsplash-1024x685.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="488" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ramamoorthy-kumar-SwuvcKXp3eg-unsplash-1024x685.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ramamoorthy-kumar-SwuvcKXp3eg-unsplash-300x201.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ramamoorthy-kumar-SwuvcKXp3eg-unsplash-768x514.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ramamoorthy-kumar-SwuvcKXp3eg-unsplash-1536x1028.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ramamoorthy-kumar-SwuvcKXp3eg-unsplash-2048x1371.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />“On the Germination of the Spores of Agaricineae.”</p>
<p>That was the title of the scientific paper that Beatrix Potter submitted to the <a href="https://www.linnean.org/the-society/history-of-science/beatrix-potter-the-tale-of-the-linnean-society">Linnean Society</a> in 1897. The society is the “world’s oldest active biological society” and, at the time that Potter was working in mycology (the study of fungi), not open to women members. Nowadays, we don’t think first of Potter’s scientific work or the way that her beautiful watercolor illustrations were useful for scientific record. We usually think instead of her vast accomplishments in the world of children’s literature. But she was a <a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Beatrix-Potter">multifaceted woman</a>: a mycologist, a writer and illustrator, and a farmer and sheep-breeder. She was deeply invested in <a href="http://www.bpotter.com/">preserving</a> and recording nature.</p>
<p>So, too, were her stories nuanced and complex. The narratives are straightforward (Peter Rabbit must escape Mr. McGregor; mice feud with cats; Mrs. Tiggy-Winkle helps a girl with laundry), but the illustrations and themes comment on the struggles to survive, both as animal and as farmer, and address the question of whether these two occupations can be reconciled. And, interestingly enough, Potter does not prioritize the human experience over the animal. In imbuing mice and bunnies and squirrels with personalities and motivation (however anthropomorphic), she asks her readers to decentralize humans for just a few moments.</p>
<p>I find <em>The Tailor of Gloucester </em>one of the most charming examples of this. Though the narrative ultimately stems from the struggle of a tailor to finish a coat for the Mayor of Gloucester in time for the latter’s wedding, the story on the page is primarily concerned with the tailor’s cat, Simpkin, and his struggle to care for the poor, sick tailor and yet also revenge himself upon the mice who taunt him. As much as Potter’s work always feels speculative, just on the edge of our reality, <em>Tailor</em> explicitly engages with a world of magic and legend. The story takes place on Christmas Eve, when—as<a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/72843/how-talking-animals-became-christmas-legend"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> legend</span></a> has it—“all the beasts can talk.” And Potter here notes that humans rarely have access to this world: “there are very few folk that can hear them, or know what it is that they say.” And ultimately the world of the animals is always just out of reach of human comprehension. The mice, for example, have a whole community in secret: “For behind the wooden wainscots of all the old houses in Gloucester, there are little mouse staircases and secret trap-doors.”</p>
<p>In many ways the world of the humans is far more prosaic. While McGregor might be obsessed with his vegetables, the tailor is obsessed with the coat that will ensure his escape from poverty, for, “although he sewed fine silk for his neighbors, he himself was very, very poor.” The commissioned coat is stunningly beautiful, fitting as the promise of prosperity: “a coat of cherry-coloured corded silk embroidered with pansies and roses, and a cream-coloured satin waistcoat—trimmed with gauze and green worsted chenille.” But the tailor is sick and his time to complete the coat is running short. True to many Christmas stories, a miracle occurs. As he lies ill in bed, the mice whom he has released from Simpkin’s traps and “who run in and out without any keys through all the old houses of Gloucester” finish the coat. Simpkin observes them, even though <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16847 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/glen-hooper-TOHHuI7cot8-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/glen-hooper-TOHHuI7cot8-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/glen-hooper-TOHHuI7cot8-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/glen-hooper-TOHHuI7cot8-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/glen-hooper-TOHHuI7cot8-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/glen-hooper-TOHHuI7cot8-unsplash-2048x1367.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />his master does not, and he is struck by his own selfishness (he has hidden away the last bit of twist that the tailor needs to finish the coat): “he felt quite ashamed of his badness compared with those good little mice!” Much like Scrooge of <em>Christmas Carol, </em>the repentant Simpkin is by his master’s side when he wakes on Christmas morning, a cup of tea in hand.</p>
<p>The coat crafted by the mice ensures the tailor’s success and he becomes especially popular for his button-holes which the narrator wryly wonders at: “I wonder how they could be stitched by an old man in spectacles, with crooked old fingers, and a tailor’s thimble.” This contrast—between the charity and agon of the animals and the understated tragedy of the tailor’s struggle—highlights part of the appeal of Potter’s work. She gives us a glimpse into a world not human and too often invisible or unacknowledged. Even the tailor, when he releases fully dressed mice from Simpkin’s teacup traps, though he remarks that it is “passing extraordinary,” cannot be long distracted from his economic woes. Potter encourages us to do differently. She displaces human concerns with animal and, in doing so, reminds us of the kinship between the two. We must simply find those liminal and magical moments when we might truly recognize them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/passing-extraordinary-beatrix-potter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
