<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 035 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-035/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 03:50:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 035 Author Interview: Beth Goder and &#8220;Pulling Secrets from Stones&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-author-interview-beth-goder-and-pulling-secrets-from-stones/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 11:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 035]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You&#8217;ve read Issue 035, right? If not, go&#8211;nay, run&#8211;and check it out. There are 16&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/scott-webb-258760-unsplash.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11979 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/scott-webb-258760-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>You&#8217;ve read <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-035/">Issue 035</a>, right? If not, go&#8211;nay, <em>run</em>&#8211;and check it out. There are 16 fabulous spec fic stories in there! One of them, &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/pulling-secrets-from-stones/">Pulling Secrets from Stones</a>&#8221; is by Beth Goder. We&#8217;re excited to post our recent interview with her today!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Putting unwanted memories into stones&#8211;dangerous, but an appealing concept. Is this something you’d ever consider if it were possible? What drew you to this idea?</strong></em></p>
<p>Beth: As an archivist, I work with historical documents, so I think a lot about how the historical record influences our collective memory. (In other words, how the documents we save change how we understand our history.) I work with all sorts of documents&#8211;correspondence, diaries, business records, photographs. It occurs to me that a document is a little like a memory stone, storing information about the past that would otherwise be forgotten. Those gray manuscript boxes where we house our documents are certainly stone-like, and you never know what you are going to find when you open one up.</p>
<p>As for giving up memories, the archivist in me wants to hold on to everything. I will often tell people that history is full of terrible people doing terrible things, but it&#8217;s important for us to remember what has gone on before. It&#8217;s important for us to understand how historical choices affect the world today.</p>
<p>I wrote another story, <em><a href="https://zeteticrecord.org/2016/11/the-forgetting-place/">The Forgetting Place</a></em>, which touches on what we lose when we give up our memories, even the ones that are most difficult for us.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging thing about writing this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Beth: I originally wrote this story using a prompt from <a href="https://www.thefirstline.com/"><em>The First Line</em></a>, which is a neat little magazine that, as you might guess from the name, asks authors to write stories using the same first line. The sentence that inspired this story was: &#8220;By the fifteenth month of the drought, the lake no longer held her secrets.&#8221; To meet the deadline, I wrote the first couple drafts of &#8220;Pulling Secrets From Stones&#8221; <span data-term="goog_1054921013">in one week</span>, a furious pace for me.</p>
<p>After some critiques, I realized that the story had some structural issues. I rewrote the first section (and the first line), and reworked some of the imagery at the end. After that, the story came together a little better.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What advice would you give to someone who’s afraid of change?<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/alexander-andrews-464024-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11980 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/alexander-andrews-464024-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></strong></em></p>
<p>Beth: I myself am someone who dislikes change. I think a fear of change is really fear of the unknown. But if you refuse to change, you can get stuck with a bad status quo. How can you know if something better is out there if you never explore?</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Beth: I recently finished up final edits on two short stories, so I&#8217;m deciding what to tackle next. I&#8217;ve got a folder full of ideas, outlines, and stalled story drafts. Next, I might work on the story with the woman employed as a lexicographer at a dictionary and who of course has a little magic in her voice, or a story looking at the ethical implications of the trolley problem as it relates to self-driving cars, or the one with the college student who gets stuck in a parallel universe where everything is made out of bananas. I also have a file here called, &#8220;Death and the Magical Kazoos,&#8221; which my notes tell me is supposed to be a literary story of great seriousness. We&#8217;ll see about that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 035 Author Interview: Alessia Galatini and &#8220;Winter Flowers&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-author-interview-alessia-galatini-and-winter-flowers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 035]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re excited to share a chance we recently had chatting with Issue 035 author Alessia&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cristina-gottardi-617328-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11975 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cristina-gottardi-617328-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>We&#8217;re excited to share a chance we recently had chatting with Issue 035 author Alessia Galatini about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/winter-flowers/">Winter Flowers</a>.&#8221; Go read her story then continue here to see what she has to say about it.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: There are countless re-tellings of the story of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-dark-queen/">Persephone</a>, as if people just can’t resist her. What is it that drew you to her?</b></em></p>
<p>Alessia: First of all, I’m a huge Greek mythology nerd. An entire section of my high school education was dedicated to learning the language of ancient Greece and its culture, which included countless legends with the most diverse themes. Much like other figures such as Troy’s Elena or Medea, stories about Persephone vary immensely according to who’s telling them. There is a big debate as to whether Hades kidnapped her or she fell in love with him willingly and how much choice did she actually have when it came to staying in the Underworld. Most re-tellings tend to favor the kidnapping or Zeus and Demeter making choices for her. But I’ve always liked to think of Persephone as a character with her own agency, both from a feminist standpoint and from a writer&#8217;s. She’s the daughter of Demeter, goddess of life and prosperity, and yet she falls in love with the God of Death. This gives her enormous complexity and internal conflict &#8211; it was very challenging but rewarding to explore this in writing. I think every young woman who’s coming of age and has to try and reconcile society’s expectations of what it means to be a ‘daughter’ or a ‘figure of fertility’ can, at some level, identify with Persephone’s refusal of her role and her struggle to create her own identity.</p>
<p>Philosophically as well, exploring how much life and death only have meaning because of each other ought to be intriguing for any writer. It’s a story from over a thousand years ago and yet it proved itself to be perfectly adaptable to events from not even half a century ago. That’s the beauty of ancient myth.</p>
<p><b><em>LSQ: The world changes immensely between the years in this story, but gods tend to stay the same. What was the most challenging aspect of writing about ageless beings?</em></b></p>
<p>Alessia: Making sure readers don’t get bored by the lack of change. Just kidding (maybe). Luckily short stories are a great medium for investigating characters who tend to remain the same &#8211; you have space to get inside their mind and know what makes them tick, but it’s short enough that as a writer I don’t grow tired of them and as a reader the story cuts away exactly when I think I’ve figured out what happens next.</p>
<p>In this case particularly, the characters’ lack of change was helpful thematically. Like you said, yes, the world changes <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/j-w-675134-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11976 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/j-w-675134-unsplash-217x300.jpg" alt="" width="217" height="300" /></a>immensely, and I purposefully chose world-changing events from a relatively recent past, but if you look at them through a god’s perspective, then humanity is ageless too. It doesn’t change. It goes from stages of thinking they can do better, to ages of destruction, some more devastating than others. A tricky part was the historical research and crafting the setting in a way that could significantly parallel the relationship between Persephone and Demeter at that stage as well as writing ancient characters in a way that could be both modern but also evoke the aura of respect goddesses like them should have.</p>
<p><b><em>LSQ: Unlike other stories about Persephone, “Winter Flowers” focuses heavily on Demeter. Why did you choose to use her as one of your narrators instead of, say, Hades?</em></b></p>
<p>Alessia: When I wrote the story, I was coincidentally learning about a lot of artists who had a mother-daughter relationship at the core of their work. The first was <a href="https://www.moma.org/artists/710">Louise Bourgeois</a>, and particularly her most famous sculpture: a giant horrifying spider called ‘<a href="https://womensartblog.wordpress.com/2018/01/29/louise-bourgeois-maman-the-mother/">Maman</a>’, about which she said:</p>
<blockquote><p>“<i>The Spider is an ode to my mother. (&#8230;) Like spiders, my mother was very clever. Spiders are friendly presences that eat mosquitoes. We know that mosquitoes spread diseases and are therefore unwanted. So, spiders are helpful and protective, just like my mother.&#8221;</i></p></blockquote>
<p>Bourgeois was always very open about how the death of her mother scarred her. She never would have gone into art if not to get over the trauma. So her choice to create something so apparently scary and terrifying and yet choose to give it a positive meaning left me baffled and curious to explore the subject more. At the same time I was reading Angela Carter’s <em>Bloody Chamber</em>, where she retells many famous fairy tales in a way that often involves the heroine having to get rid of the mother/grandmother before accomplishing her task. In her youth, Angela ran away to Japan to escape her controlling mother and that complicated relationship influenced her writing.</p>
<p>Finally, I was also obsessed with <a href="https://www.fridakahlo.org/my-birth.jsp">Frida Kahlo’s painting “My Birth”</a>, which explores the roles of mother, daughter, and woman through a horrifying depiction of a monstrous child being born in a pool of blood as the mother’s face is covered and a painting of an older woman hangs above them, staring at the scene. All of this made me crave to find a story that would allow me to explore an equally complex mother-daughter relationship and the theme of legacy. From there, I fell back on my love for Greek myth to find the perfect metaphor for it. From a writer’s standpoint as well, my best shot at developing Persephone’s character and her conflict would be to make her face her worst antagonist, hence her mother. Hades, in &#8220;Winter Flowers&#8221;, is more of a catalyst to push Persephone to explore another side of life, so he wouldn’t have been as helpful as Demeter.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: Are you working on other projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</b></em></p>
<p>Alessia: I have a fantasy novel that’s been sitting on my desk for a good two years and is craving a re-write. The Greek influence is clear there as well &#8211; the main character’s name is Antigone and she lives in a world where humans are only characters in books. I’m focusing on screenwriting at the moment and developing an LGBT short called “Say Grace” &#8211; you can find out more about it at @saygracefilm on IG and FB. I’m also working on two TV pilots and a feature film script.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 035 Author Interview: K. Bannerman and &#8220;The Mothership&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-author-interview-k-bannerman-and-the-mothership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 11:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 035]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What? Another Issue 035 interview? YES! Today we had the pleasure of chatting with K.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/bill-jelen-555154-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11923 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/bill-jelen-555154-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>What? Another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-035/">Issue 035</a> interview? YES! Today we had the pleasure of chatting with K. Bannerman about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-mothership/">The Mothership</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div><em><b>LSQ: There are quite a few tales of humans being sent into space to recolonize, but yours is unique in that only women are sent into space. What made you to decide to leave the men on Earth?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>K.B. It came down to a matter of resources. An all-female crew who were committed to being the mothers of the next generation would give a new population the greatest chance at genetic diversity. Why invest vital resources in space travel on a man when you could just as easily reduce his genetic contribution to a vial? In this case, every member of the crew has the ability to create children for the colony from a number of different donors and this ensures the best opportunity for a healthy population in the long term.</div>
<div><span style="font-family: Calibri;"> </span></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: Our ladies are left with quite an open ended fate. Do you plan on continuing their story? What kind of future do you envision for them?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>K.B. It&#8217;s an open ended fate, but it&#8217;s a hopeful one, too. The birth of a single son provides a chance for the human species to continue; I don&#8217;t foresee an easy future for them, of course, but humans are very good at struggling on in bad situations.</div>
<div><span style="font-family: Calibri;"> </span></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: What was the most difficult part about writing this story?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>K.B.: The story came together quite quickly and I suppose the most difficult part was digging back into my own experiences <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/richard-gatley-533872-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11924 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/richard-gatley-533872-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>of labor and childbirth, postpartum depression, and new motherhood to describe Kyana&#8217;s labor. It&#8217;s difficult enough to go through childbirth on Earth &#8212; the whole process would take on a new set of challenges if it&#8217;s happening while entering the upper atmosphere of a distant moon.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div class="gmail_extra">
<div class="gmail_quote">
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div class="m_-5910129364753865372h5">
<div>
<div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Can you name a few authors who inspire you? Are there any who particularly inspired you for this story?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div>K.B.: Inspiration for this story came from a number of different places. Before writing it, I&#8217;d been reading Mary Roach&#8217;s book <a href="http://maryroach.net/packing-for-mars.html"><em>Packing for Mars</em></a>, in which she discusses NASA&#8217;s early space program and their reasons against sending up women as astronauts in the 1960s. Plus, I&#8217;d been following <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/astronauts/biographies/peggy-a-whitson/biography">Peggy Whitson&#8217;s mission aboard the ISS</a>, so it was interesting to explore how social attitudes have changed in regard to women in STEM. For another project, I&#8217;d been researching population migration and what would be required for a healthy gene pool, especially for isolated island communities. All of those elements came together in &#8220;Mothership.&#8221;</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 035 Author Interview: Rose Strickman and &#8220;The Ghol&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-author-interview-rose-strickman-and-the-ghol/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 11:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 035]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Did you know Issue 035 is still available? With 16 fantastic speculative fiction short stories&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/thomas-shellberg-31280-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11918 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/thomas-shellberg-31280-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Did you know <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-035/">Issue 035</a> is still available? With 16 fantastic speculative fiction short stories by women authors? It is! Go take a peek, especially at Rose Strickman&#8217;s &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-ghol/">The Ghol</a>&#8220;, the topic of today&#8217;s author interview.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: In my admittedly quick Google search, I could not find a definition of &#8220;ghol&#8221;. Could you tell us a bit about this ghoulish creation? Is it a creature found in other tales or something of your imagination?</strong></em></p>
<p>Rose: The idea of a &#8220;ghol&#8221; is taken from the general idea of a ghoul: a monster that comes back from the grave. I used this slightly different spelling for two reasons. One, I wanted to emphasize that this is another world, similar to ours, but not quite the same. (They have different monsters in this world&#8211;also, I imagine people&#8217;s attitude toward them would be a bit different if those monsters were actually real!) Second, I wanted to create the ghol myself: to build its character, behavior and motivations, free of any previously established fantasy or folklore traditions.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ:</em> <em>The twist of a loving husband coming back as a thing of evil is an interesting spin &#8212; can you tell us a bit about how and why this story went in that direction?</em></strong></p>
<p>Rose: The identity of the ghol revealed itself to me slowly: at first I wasn&#8217;t sure who or what this thing was or why it was tormenting Miranda and her family. That it was the husband&#8211;the idea of love twisted into a murderous force&#8211;dawned gradually. It seemed like the perfect metaphor for the human cost of war, and a pointless death. Also, it threw another twist into Miranda&#8217;s dilemma: the ghol isn&#8217;t just a faceless monster out to get her and her children, but the last remnant of the man she loved. Does she stay true to a dead husband or does she protect her living children? The story came down to that choice.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ:</em> <em>The strength of a mother&#8217;s love and her desire to protect her children &#8212; this is really felt in the character of Miranda. What was it like to write her character? Where did you find inspiration for Miranda?</em></strong></p>
<p>Rose: It was wonderful to write about Miranda. I really like her as a character: her strength, her vulnerability, her determination, her grief, her fierce love, and her desire to survive. Mothers and maternal figures are often portrayed in fantasy in one of three ways: dead, abusive, or useless. While there are reasons for this (imagine the Harry Potter series if Aunt Petunia had been a loving, protective surrogate mother who refused to expose Harry to the dangers of Hogwarts and fought to keep him safely away from the wizarding world), it does get old after a while. I don&#8217;t have children myself, but I&#8217;ve been fortunate enough to know many wonderful women in my life. I drew inspiration from them, and imagining how they would act in such a situation. Also, my favorite stories have always been those in which a woman saves herself or others, instead of waiting around to be rescued.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The stress on the children is almost an unspoken character in the story, seen most via its effects on Violet. This is something many stories involving kids doesn&#8217;t adequately reach but you&#8217;ve captured it starkly in this piece. Can you comment on this?</strong></em></p>
<p>Rose: Portraying the effect of the ghol on the children was both fun and harrowing. I was a pretty anxious kid growing up, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/kelly-sikkema-196851-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11919 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/kelly-sikkema-196851-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a>checking for monsters in the closet and afraid of the dark, so it was easy to imagine how I would have felt at their age in such a situation. And with a monster creeping closer and closer over a long period of time and cutting the family off from the outside world, it would have been pretty unrealistic if the children hadn&#8217;t suffered extreme stress and fear. Kids are smart enough to know when their lives are in danger. Violet and Lily aren&#8217;t just props to the action; they&#8217;re full characters, and I wanted to portray that. Also, this is a major factor in Miranda&#8217;s final decision: her daughters are suffering terribly, and will die if she doesn&#8217;t take action.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the hardest part of this story to write and why? What was the easiest? Where did the overall idea come from?</strong></em></p>
<p>Rose: The hardest part to write might have been the setting: I wanted to demonstrate that this is an alternate, steampunk world experiencing the equivalent of the American Civil War without overdoing it. Also, the specific setting&#8211;an isolated farmhouse&#8211;didn&#8217;t make that easy! It was surprisingly difficult to portray the steampunk technology and the war when the household is both poverty-stricken and cut off from outside communication. I&#8217;m not sure if any part of writing is easy, but the story flowed organically. I could easily enter my characters&#8217; psyches, and greatly enjoyed writing about Miranda&#8217;s final plan of attack and its effect on the ghol. Also, I enjoyed exploring the idea of ghols, and the reasons why they manifest and behave the way they do. There may be other stories to write in this universe . . .</p>
<p>As for where the idea came from, I originally wrote this story as a submission to a fantasy anthology, <em>Sword and Sonnet</em>. I got hooked on the idea of poetry as a weapon&#8211;specifically, written poems as opposed to spoken or sung. In what situation would written poetry be a useful defense? The rest of the story flowed from there. As it turned out, however, &#8220;The Ghol&#8221; wasn&#8217;t what the editors were looking for, so I&#8217;m glad it&#8217;s found a good home!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Can you name a few other authors you draw inspiration from and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Rose: Whoa, so many choices! There are so many authors I admire and draw inspiration from, but if I have to pick a few, I’d say that Diana Wynne Jones has always been a major influence on my writing, with her fabulous fantasy settings inhabited by very human, fallible, sympathetic characters (young wizards who get lines for losing one of their nine lives, magical cats who steal the steak meant for dinner, dark lords hired as attractions in theme parks . . .). I also love what might be termed anthropological science fiction, as found in the works of Ursula K. Le Guin or Marie Brennan’s <em>Lady Trent</em> books: what if dragons were real, natural creatures? What if women outnumbered men sixteen to one? How would that change things? It’s amazing to see how altering just one thing can change an imagined society or ecology so completely, if the author applies both imagination and logic. I love the juxtaposition of fantasy and realism.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other projects at the moment? If so, could you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Rose: I’m working on several projects at the moment, writing short stories for submission to various anthologies and magazines. Also, I’m working (very intermittently) on a novel set in a world I’ve visited before, where humans are born female and turn male around age forty (see my short story “Changeover” in the 2015 anthology <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Rejected-Jo-Anne-Russell-ebook/dp/B00UARXUUU"><em>Rejected</em></a> if you want a foretaste). I’ve only just gotten back to this novel after six months’ hiatus, though, so we’ll have to see.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 035 Author Interview: Erin Wagner and &#8220;To Walk for the First Time&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-author-interview-erin-wagner-and-to-walk-for-the-first-time/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 11:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 035]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Get your Issue 035 author interviews right here! Today we chatted with Erin Wagner about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cristian-newman-63291-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11826 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cristian-newman-63291-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a>Get your <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-035/">Issue 035</a> author interviews right here! Today we chatted with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/e-k-wagner/">Erin Wagner</a> about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/to-walk-for-the-first-time/">To Walk for the First Time</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your story starts with an attention-grabbing first sentence. Do you have a secret for thinking up good first sentences?</strong></em></p>
<p>Erin: There is, of course the age-old writing advice: start <em>in medias res. </em>My first sentence is a gesture towards that. Though it is reflective and nostalgic in tone, the sentence cuts to the core of the story: the juxtaposition of age with experiences often associated with youth or beginnings. The contrast is deliberately provocative. So, start in the middle and start with formal or plot tension (easier said than done in most of my drafts!).</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Erin: It is a story that dwells in detail to evoke the slow and constant wait of the protagonist&#8211;to wake up, to take the throne, to escape into freedom. I enjoy writing in this reflective, weighty style of prose.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: It’s rare to see stories about an old woman liberating herself. What inspired you to write this kind of story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Erin: It was initially inspired by a call for stories very similar to that of your next issue (Crones). So the story was a deliberate attempt to centralize an unlikely (unlikely, because underused) protagonist. It was a rewarding experiment and allowed me to centralize a population usually marginalized.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have any plans to continue our narrator’s journey? What do you foresee in her future?</strong></em></p>
<p>Erin: I wouldn&#8217;t be opposed to the idea of returning to her story. I can imagine a quest of sorts, as our narrator experiences life in a way she has never had the chance to do before. She would meet new friends and enemies, eat new food, observe new landscapes. And, of course, face new challenges from her unique perspective. Who knows what lies outside the castle?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 035 Author Interview: Richaundra Thursday and &#8220;Space Witch&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-author-interview-richaundra-thursday-and-space-witch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 10:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 035]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello again, faithful readers! We&#8217;re here with another Issue 035 author interview, this time taking&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/andy-holmes-734162-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11819 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/andy-holmes-734162-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>Hello again, faithful readers! We&#8217;re here with another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-035/">Issue 035</a> author interview, this time taking a moment to visit with author <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/richaundra-thursday/">Richaundra Thursday</a> about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/space-witch/">Space Witch</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: One of the most apparent elements in “Space Witch” is voice. Did the narrator’s voice just come to you or was it something you had to develop over time?</strong></em></p>
<p>Richaundra: When I first wrote the story, it was formatted as a long narrative poem, which lent itself well to a conversational tone, a line break where a pause or emphasis might go. In that way, the voice just came to me; once I&#8217;d written that first line I knew the overall tone it would take. However, many of the idiosyncrasies, lingo/slang, terms and whatnot I spent a great deal of time thinking about and trying to balance &#8216;This is obviously the future&#8217; and &#8216;This is a working class individual that is both excitable and 100% over everything.&#8217; It&#8217;s always those single words or small phrases that take the longest to edit!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Richaundra: Translating relatable, even mundane experiences to a new setting, and thinking about some of the practicalities of long-distance space travel and how that would affect cultures and mutate archetypes. The Witch is always the &#8216;Necessary Outsider.&#8217; She solves problems society doesn&#8217;t want to admit having. In space, some of those problems may be new, some will be frustratingly evergreen. I wanted it to feel fantastic, yet grimy and real. Smell the stardust <em>AND</em> the engine oil.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What kinds of things do you envision a space witch doing?</strong></em></p>
<p>Richaundra: I did actually write a follow up poem/story to this one that focuses more on the Witch&#8217;s daily activities. I like <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/alexander-andrews-520156-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11820 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/alexander-andrews-520156-unsplash-300x192.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="192" /></a>the idea that she pops into the hydroponic gardens because, while all the scientists can design environments physically perfect for them, she knows they also need songs and smiles to grow right. She fights the monsters only children can see and helps the people who fall between the cracks, all the while staying out of the way of the system that simultaneously needs and fears her.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Richaundra: I wrote a poetic biography of Mary Shelley and the writing of <em>Frankenstein</em> that I really wanted to get published this year (the 200th anniversary of <em>Frankenstein</em>&#8216;s publication), but looks like I will be tweaking and resubmitting it for a bit still. (There is, perhaps unsurprisingly, not a wide center in the Venn Diagram of &#8216;People that like to read poetry&#8217; and &#8216;People that like to read end notes.&#8217;) I have a similar project starting regarding Ada Lovelace and the transition from the Romantic to the Victorian era. This experience has also strongly encouraged me to write more short fiction and trust that maybe someone out there is interested in the stories I want to tell, which I am forever grateful for.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 035 Author Interview: K.G. Anderson and &#8220;Escape&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-author-interview-k-g-anderson-and-escape/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 10:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 035]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Three! Days! In! A! Row! Are you ready for another Issue 035 author interview?! Today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>Three! Days! In! A! Row! Are you ready for another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-035/">Issue 035</a> author interview?! Today we chat with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/k-g-anderson/">K.G. Anderson</a> about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/escape/">Escape</a>.&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cayetano-gil-532119-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11763 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/cayetano-gil-532119-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="327" /></a>LSQ: A golem in a western &#8212; please tell us how you decided to put such a twist on a well-known Wild West &#8220;villian.&#8221; Are you a fan of Billy the Kid or westerns in general?</strong></em></div>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>K.G.: An anthology editor remarked that she was getting too many Weird West stories focused on men &#8212; fairly mainstream cowboys and outlaws. I took that remark as a challenge to set a story in the Weird West and to take it in a new direction by telling the story of a woman from my own culture. I’m Jewish and there were many Jewish dry goods merchants in the early West. I’d always wondered how these men found wives, so I did some research and found out about mail-order brides. Women (usually older spinsters or widows) answered marriage ads placed in Jewish community newspapers in New York. So, my character was going to be a Jewish mail-order bride. (The story uses an actual ad from an 1880s paper.)</div>
<div></div>
<div>Golems are well-known magical creatures in Jewish lore, so I decided the bride would have a golem and that it would be the magical (weird) element in my Weird West tale. While researching the Wild West and Jewish New York of the 1880s, I discovered that Billy the Kid (born Henry McCarty) had grown up on the Lower East Side of Manhattan. There is a historical mystery about Billy the Kid and his final days in New Mexico, so I decided to involve my protagonist, Shulamit, and her golem, in that mystery.</div>
<div></div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Can you tell us a bit about what golems are and their history?</strong></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>K.G.: A <a href="https://www.jewishvirtuallibrary.org/the-golem">golem</a> is man-shaped creature made of clay that can be brought to life, usually by a rabbi who uses specific Hebrew letters to animate or deactivate the creature. In traditional tales, a golem is brought to life to protect the Jewish community. The most famous story is about a golem created by a late 16th century rabbi in Prague. But often the use of a golem results in tragedy because the creature misinterprets, or takes too literally, human commands.</div>
<div></div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: This story feels like it was a lot of fun to write. Where did you get the idea? What was the most challenging aspect about this piece to write and why?</strong></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>K.G.: The idea came from the editor looking for non-traditional Weird West tales. The biggest challenge for me was getting <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/eniko-polgar-81606-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11764 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/eniko-polgar-81606-unsplash-1024x576.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="360" /></a>inside Shulamit’s character. I had to know all the factors — her love for her grandfather, her fear of her step-mother, her shyness about her looks, and her spirit of adventure — that made it possible for her to leave the sheltered community in which she had grown up to move all the way to the New Mexico territory. I had to figure out how someone with her sheltered background (but quick wits) would deal with tough frontier types like Billy the Kid and Kate Flaherty, the New Mexico innkeeper who befriends Shulamit.</div>
<div></div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Can you name a few authors that inspire you? Are there any that particularly inspired you for this story?</strong></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<p>K.G.: I&#8217;m generally inspired by stories powered by well-drawn, intriguing settings. These include Georges Simenon&#8217;s mysteries set in Paris; Arthur Upfield’s mysteries set in the Australian outback; Ray Bradbury’s Mars stories; and Charlaine Harris’ contemporary fantasies set in small Southern towns. For “Escape,” I drew inspiration from Isaac Bashevis Singer (who wrote many stories about supernatural elements in Jewish culture) and David Milch, who wrote the TV series <i>Deadwood</i>.</p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other writing projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>K.G.: I write short stories in a wide range of fantasy and science fiction subgenres, including alternate history and horror. Recently I’ve been writing near-future dystopian stories for a series of anthologies issued by B Cubed Press. But I’m also writing stories set in modern secondary worlds, including one where master gardeners and master chefs wield magical powers.</div>
<div></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 035 Author Interview: Alyssa Striplin and &#8220;Necromance&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-author-interview-alyssa-striplin-and-necromance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 035]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re back again to continue a week full of Issue 035 author interviews. Today we&#8217;re&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re back again to continue a week full of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-035/">Issue 035</a> author interviews. Today we&#8217;re sharing a chat with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/alyssa-striplin/">Alyssa Striplin</a> about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/necromance/">Necromance</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Second person narrative is a tricky one. Why did you choose it?</strong></em></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/mathew-macquarrie-149083-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11759 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/mathew-macquarrie-149083-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Alyssa: I’m not usually a fan of second person narrative, so I can’t say it was my first choice for this story. Originally, it was in third person and Max was the only named character (the naïve necromancer was just referred to as “she”). When I started revising, though, I was teaching second person narration to my creative writing students and I was struggling to find examples they could connect with. Somehow, that led to me revising my story into second person, since my students liked horror. I ended up using a different, already published example in class because the story wasn’t ready yet, but I had already fallen down the rabbit hole with second person, so I kept going until it became what it is today.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The horror in this story is palpable, from the macabre notion of Max’s heart being transplanted into her best friend, to Max’s horrific undead appearance. What is your favorite part about writing horror?</strong></em></p>
<p>Alyssa: You get to make dead things look pretty. I love writing about blood, bone, and broken teeth in a way that makes them beautiful. I blame <a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm0868219/">Guillermo del Toro</a> because he always makes terrifying things look so aesthetically pleasing. Like the blood red ghosts in <a href="https://www.legendary.com/film/crimsonpeak/"><em>Crimson Peak</em></a>—they’re absolutely grotesque, but you can’t look away even if you want to. I guess writing horror is kind of like being a mortician—you take something dead and you bring it alive with vivid description.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging thing about writing this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Alyssa: Editing it down to the necessary parts, mostly because I have a tendency to get carried away with details and <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/eddie-howell-606929-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11760 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/eddie-howell-606929-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>descriptions. I have a tendency to keep adding and adding to a story. I’ve got a whole backstory to go along with the protagonist—what happened to her mother, how she came across necromancy in the first place, her first interactions with Max, and so on. Not to mention all the gory details I had to cut out because my description of a freshly risen corpse was turning into an epic. It’s the same problem I have with everything I write, really. I’ll paint you a picture, sure, but I’ll keep adding layers and layers of acrylic paint until it’s practically touching your nose standing ten feet away and you can’t see the whole portrait.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Alyssa: Right now, I’m just planning two Halloween parties for October and drafting up my 31 days of Halloween movies list. As soon as that’s done, though, I’d love to finish the novel I’ve been working on, <em>Cryptid</em>, and at least get some spooky story ideas I have down on paper (so far, I’ve got a mermaid in the Ozarks, a girl who wants to grow into a monster, and a story from the perspective of the gorgeous forest monster/goddess in the Netflix movie, <em>The Ritual</em>).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 035 Author Interview: Victoria Sandbrook and &#8220;Phalium arium ssp anam&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-author-interview-victoria-sandbrook-and-phalium-arium-ssp-anam/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 035]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whoa, friends, do we have a week of Issue 035 author interviews for you! The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Whoa, friends, do we have a week of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-035/">Issue 035</a> author interviews for <em>you</em>! The current issue of <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> has 16 (if you can believe it &#8212; we hardly can) speculative fiction short stories by women authors and we&#8217;re so excited to share not only the issue with you (it came out <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-is-here-meet-our-cover-artist-shreya-shetty/">September 5</a>) but also share the excellent and enlightening conversations we&#8217;ve had with the authors. To start the week, we chatted with author <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/victoria-sandbrook/">Victoria Sandbrook</a> about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/phalium-arium-ssp-anam/">Phalium arium ssp anam</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div>
<div><em><b><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/martin-vysoudil-701005-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11755 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/martin-vysoudil-701005-unsplash-300x202.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="202" /></a>LSQ: Is Phalium the genus of some large sea snails the same Phalium in the title of your story? Can you tell us more about this title and its link to your story?</b> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Victoria: When I started writing the story, I did some very light snail research and picked a sea snail genus with a size and shape I thought translated well to the kind of snail-cryptid I&#8217;d been seeing in my head. The rest is an attempt to play with a potential species name, suggesting flight and some sort of bonded mating habit. It&#8217;s what <i>should </i>be on the display and not just &#8220;sea snails.&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: There&#8217;s far more to the character of Nora than what meets the eye. Can you tell us a bit about her background, her powers, her ambitions?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Victoria: Oh I have ideas for Nora that have not hit the page. While I hesitate to say too much, for fear it will hem me in if I come back to her later, I will say that she&#8217;s the kind of person who has found a chink in the veil and is determined to tear it away entirely. She obviously doesn&#8217;t fit into the expectations of her Irish-American family or community, and she&#8217;s already prioritizing knowledge over many things. For all that rebellion, I think she&#8217;s relieved not to be entirely alone, either.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: What made you choose sea creatures like the jellyfish and snails as the animals on display? Can you tell more about these cryptids?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Victoria: This answer goes right along with the next question; I&#8217;ll be getting ahead of myself a touch. This story came out of a friendly contest among <a href="https://viableparadise.com/">Viable Paradise</a> alumni in which we were tasked to write flash stories around the prompt &#8220;snail rodeo.&#8221; So I started with that picture in my head&#8211;the corral, the snails&#8211;and zoomed out. The jellyfish are a nice homage to the <a href="http://www.ucmp.berkeley.edu/cnidaria/ctenophora.html">ctenophores</a> Viable Paradise students go hunting for on Martha&#8217;s Vineyard. I knew I wanted them to be a little unexpected, to be marvelous things actually held back by the sideshow, and making them flying creatures and not water-dwellers just made sense.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: Where did the idea for this story come from? What was the most enjoyable part about writing it?</b> <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ashleigh-robertson-768568-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11756 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ashleigh-robertson-768568-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Victoria: So after the struggle of the rather open prompt (see the question above) and the fight to figure out what story would work, I think I most enjoyed the moment I realized who I wanted John to really be. Nora and I were both quite pleased, to be honest. And since that moment, I think the only thing that has surpassed that fun turn has been sharing it, seeing it float off into the world beyond my reach. It&#8217;s been a good ride!</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: Are you working on other writing projects right now? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</b> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Victoria: I&#8217;m very happy to see my story &#8220;El Cantar de la Reina Bruja&#8221; hit the real world as <i>Sword &amp; Sonnet</i>, a battle poet anthology, as released in ebook and paperback (still forthcoming). &#8220;El Cantar&#8221; and another, yet unsold story are two of several &#8220;attic wife&#8221; stories that are rolling around in my head, and I&#8217;m looking forward to putting pen to paper for a third one later this week as my daughter heads back to school.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>[<em>Editor&#8217;s note: as told in late August</em>]</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 035 Author Interview: Natalia Yanchak and &#8220;Better You Than Me&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-035-author-interview-natalia-yanchak-and-better-you-than-me/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 035]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11146</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 035 author alert! Meet Natalia Yanchak and of course go read her short story&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-035/">Issue 035</a> author alert! Meet Natalia Yanchak and of course go read her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/better-you-than-me/">Better You Than Me</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: How would you classify your protagonist? Is she an android or other type of synthetic humanoid? What made you want to explore the &#8220;emotional&#8221; side of AI (if you call her that)? Also, I&#8217;m making an assumption the gender is &#8220;she&#8221; but please correct me if that wasn&#8217;t your intent. </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<figure id="attachment_11147" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-11147" style="width: 240px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/N_Yanchak_lo-res_2018_by_Richmond_Lam.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-11147 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/N_Yanchak_lo-res_2018_by_Richmond_Lam-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-11147" class="wp-caption-text">Author Natalia Yanchak Photo by Richmond Lam</figcaption></figure>
<p>Natalia: The protagonist here is definitely a human-shaped robot. They switched from he to she in various drafts, and in the end I left it ambiguous, or to be reader-defined, though the name is feminine. I wanted Gal to express, and process, memory and feeling through the context of her mechanical body. There&#8217;s a certain dysphoria in her experience, but I think that often comes to humans with figuring out what it means to be in love, reconciling the physical and emotional. The hard tech aspect is intentionally even more ambiguous &#8212; there&#8217;s something a little steampunk about grinding gears being at the core of this complex, emotionally-burdened entity.</p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: This story explores not only robotic characters with emotions but also how those emotions come into conflict with prime directives. What was it like to &#8220;think&#8221; like your main character given the construct you put her in?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Natalia: The initial spark for this story stemmed from some very personal memories from my younger days. As the story evolved, my catharsis turned the lens outward. I wanted to challenge the reader with how they defined their own prime directives in a relationship. A third-party never specifies that for us; we have to assert it for ourselves, learning from our previous failed attempts. What makes a good relationship? Or a real friend? What makes us robotic about staying with someone? There&#8217;s so much in a relationship, and in life, that we want to control, but can&#8217;t. That&#8217;s partly what drives my character&#8217;s instinct, whereby some of her life is dictated by programming, but not all of it.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Can you describe the world you&#8217;ve created? A world where not only AI is used for dirty business but where there are other human-like creatures like gynoids and bivalve-mixes. There seems to be a lot more going on here than meets the eye.</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Natalia: I feel like the most reasonable vision of &#8220;the future&#8221; will be, on one hand, totally pragmatic and quite similar to how <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/franck-v-795965-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11626 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/franck-v-795965-unsplash-300x219.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="219" /></a>we live today, and on the other hand, require extreme inter-species cross-breeding for survival. How else will humans adapt to, say, extreme flooding due to climate change? By becoming half-fish, duh.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect of this story to write and why?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Natalia: Because some of these scenes are memoir-inspired, I was very shy about sharing drafts with any other readers and in fact didn&#8217;t have any readers on this piece. I just straight up started a somewhat manic cycle of submitting it, then re-writing it. Fortunately, all that re-drafting naturally drew out the non-fiction aspects completely. In the end, save for some elements of place like the geography of Montreal, it&#8217;s a work of fiction.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you currently working on any other writing projects? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>Natalia: I&#8217;m presently writing a second novel, a post-climate change spy-fi thriller that may contain dragons and a main character based on the current Canadian Prime Minister, Justin Trudeau. I have a handful of stories on the go, and am having a lot of fun writing a slightly bizarre story about surviving being eaten by a dinosaur, but that also satirizes music festival culture.</div>
<div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
