<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Everybody and Their Motherboard &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/everybody-and-their-motherboard/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 17:15:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Eureka Moment</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-eureka-moment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anne Elise Brinich]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 13:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Everybody and Their Motherboard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22897</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In science fiction, the Eureka Moment often happens at the climax of a story. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-22953" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dominic-swain-HxDrZ3rHiac-unsplash-276x300.jpg" alt="" width="276" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dominic-swain-HxDrZ3rHiac-unsplash-276x300.jpg 276w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dominic-swain-HxDrZ3rHiac-unsplash-943x1024.jpg 943w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dominic-swain-HxDrZ3rHiac-unsplash-768x834.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dominic-swain-HxDrZ3rHiac-unsplash-1415x1536.jpg 1415w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dominic-swain-HxDrZ3rHiac-unsplash-1886x2048.jpg 1886w" sizes="(max-width: 276px) 100vw, 276px" /></p>
<p>In science fiction, the Eureka Moment often happens at the climax of a story. The audience has been waiting for the entire film/book/episode to see how the characters are going to get out of the technological jam they&#8217;ve found themselves in: their formula for interstellar travel doesn&#8217;t work, their ship&#8217;s engines have failed, they&#8217;ve been unable to communicate with an alien species. Take your pick. There is a scientific problem, and the crew or character needs a scientific solution, which one or more of them has been working on for days, weeks, months, and/or years, only to find themselves up against seemingly unyielding technological barrier.</p>
<p>Just when the stakes could not be higher (they&#8217;re heading straight into the black hole, nooooo!), the protagonist has a seemingly mundane conversation with someone, or sees and everyday scene from a new angle, or is reminded of a childhood memory. This thematically relevant realization leads them to the one piece of the puzzle they had not yet understood: the key to getting out of their current predicament.</p>
<p>&#8220;Of course!&#8221; they say, more to themselves than anyone else, and break off the conversation that led them to their realization to race down the hallway and begin scratching frantically at a blackboard. Moments later, they have their solution, and the day is saved.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m writing all this to, yes, point out that the Eureka Moment in science fiction is a little bit of a cliche. Obviously, scientific breakthroughs in reality are most often the result of years of research and team work, and rarely involve someone tossing all their papers in the air and yelling &#8220;Eureka!&#8221;, then kissing the person they&#8217;ve had quite a bit of sexual tension with but to whom they&#8217;ve never verbally expressed interest.</p>
<p>But also. Sometimes, this is how breakthroughs work. I have to point out that there is a large helping of truth to the fictionalized eureka: realizations are often teased to the surface of consciousness because of seemingly everyday sights, old memories, and mundane conversations. These are, after all the narrative approximations of the most powerful tools we <img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-22954 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/karla-hernandez-LrlyZzX6Sws-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/karla-hernandez-LrlyZzX6Sws-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/karla-hernandez-LrlyZzX6Sws-unsplash-818x1024.jpg 818w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/karla-hernandez-LrlyZzX6Sws-unsplash-768x961.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/karla-hernandez-LrlyZzX6Sws-unsplash-1227x1536.jpg 1227w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/karla-hernandez-LrlyZzX6Sws-unsplash-1636x2048.jpg 1636w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/karla-hernandez-LrlyZzX6Sws-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2046w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />have, as people: observation, education, and each other. The Euerka Moment in fiction and real life is often also made possible by getting some new eyes on the problem: often, a puzzle&#8217;s impossibility has become a fact for a long-time solver&#8211; for someone else, a solution is well within reach.</p>
<p>In fact, the most objectionable part of the Eureka Moment in fiction is probably actually the part the comes right after, when the solution the protagonist has come to is easily implemented and the rest of the story resolves quickly. That, I think we can all agree, is truly the stuff of imagination.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smoke &#8216;Em if You Quantum</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/smoke-em-if-you-quantum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anne Elise Brinich]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 11:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Everybody and Their Motherboard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a blog about technology in science fiction, but I think it&#8217;s worth noting&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22708 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/earth-2254769_1920-300x184.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="184" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/earth-2254769_1920-300x184.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/earth-2254769_1920-1024x629.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/earth-2254769_1920-768x472.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/earth-2254769_1920-1536x944.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/earth-2254769_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />This is a blog about technology in science fiction, but I think it&#8217;s worth noting that this year heralded some incredible technological feats that <em>sound </em>like they&#8217;re straight out of a work of fiction, but which are, for better or worse, very real. Some of these technologies seem like a natural part of this dimension&#8217;s timeline; others are so straight-up bonkers that I feel like anyone with a passing interest in speculative fiction should know about them, for fodder for future stories (or panic attacks). For the purposes of this post, I will focus on the one from this year with the best name: the Quantum Internet.</p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t know it, but the information I was exchanging while using the internet is what&#8217;s referred to as &#8220;classical&#8221; information, which makes it sounds quaint. This &#8220;classical&#8221; information is shared and stored in 1&#8217;s and 0&#8217;s, bits that are parsed by machines. At its most basic, classical information is either a 1 or a 0.</p>
<p>Quantum information uses quantum bits, where 1s and 0s can be superpositions and expressed simultaneously. Quantum bits can be encoded in the certain states of certain particles (no I&#8217;m not a physicist, why do you ask?). When these particles become entangled, the information they express cannot be accessed by unintentional recipients without being destroyed, which makes it <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22710 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/light-1834289_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/light-1834289_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/light-1834289_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/light-1834289_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/light-1834289_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/light-1834289_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />pretty much the most secure way to share information humans have ever conceived.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s what I&#8217;ve gathered as a total layperson, at least. You can read more about the quantum internet and other technological breakthroughs from 2020 in <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/10-breakthrough-technologies/2020/">MIT&#8217;s Technological Review. </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quick—Research Montage!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/quick-research-montage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 14:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Everybody and Their Motherboard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While writing my thesis in grad school, I repeatedly wished that research was a lot&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While writing <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-22400 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/dan-dimmock-3mt71MKGjQ0-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/dan-dimmock-3mt71MKGjQ0-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/dan-dimmock-3mt71MKGjQ0-unsplash-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/dan-dimmock-3mt71MKGjQ0-unsplash-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/dan-dimmock-3mt71MKGjQ0-unsplash-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/dan-dimmock-3mt71MKGjQ0-unsplash-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />my thesis in grad school, I repeatedly wished that research was a lot more like it seems in movies and books about scientists and engineers. That way, it would just be a short compilation of scenes where people ask intelligent questions, poke around in the library, remove glasses and rub their eyes wearily, and scratch out calculations while shaking their head, all before finally presenting their findings to a wildly enthusiastic lecture hall.</p>
<p>I don’t think I have to tell you that’s not how my thesis research or presentation went down. But watching or reading about a grown woman cry in the shower between coffee- and pizza-fueled 8-hour JSTOR visits probably wouldn’t make for a compelling montage sequence.</p>
<p>I’d chalk the research montage (and the montage in general) up to another unrealistic standard set by Hollywood if it weren’t so often a useful narrative device, especially when you have a lot of relatively uninteresting explaining to do. Anyone who has the time to intimately describe the process it takes for their protagonist to get out of, or into, whatever trouble technology has led them into in their speculative fiction story is a much better writer than me. The research montage is a way of showing the reader that the payoff for the resolution of a story is earned: the protagonist didn’t just conveniently have a PhD in particle physics—she had to spend six years trapped in an intergalactic prison, reading in all of her spare time and befriending the former quantum mechanic in the next cell block over before she could even start to sketch out her plans for the time-traveling, empire-destroying starship.</p>
<p>Though it depends on the length of the whole story, I’d argue that a research montag<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-22401 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/martian-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/martian-198x300.jpg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/martian.jpg 313w" sizes="(max-width: 198px) 100vw, 198px" />e (or whatever you would call the literary equivalent) never needs to be more than a few pages, if that much. That said, I’ve read well-paced researching scenes that are considerably shorter, and some that are a lot longer, though I’ve mentioned before that my enthusiasm for infodumps is maybe greater than other people’s. I’d say that about 75% of Andy Weir’s <em>The Martian</em> is a research montage, as the main character attempting to figure out how exactly to engineer the biological conditions that perpetuate his existence and logging his attempts in the journal comprises most of the novel.</p>
<p>And though the research montage is just the justification for the resolution of the story, or perhaps the response to some unforeseen complication, I really, really enjoy them when they’re done well. I just watched the surprisingly excellent movie <em>Palm Springs</em>, and was delighted by a silly but narratively effective research montage near the end of the film, every moment of which was ridiculous, entertaining, and necessary for the story.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interior, Spaceship</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/interior-spaceship/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anne Elise Brinich]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 11:13:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Everybody and Their Motherboard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=21960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For reasons totally unrelated to a massively popular online indie multiplayer game that takes place&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For reasons totally unrelated to a massively popular online indie multiplayer game that takes place in space and requires players to have an intimate knowledge of a spacecraft’s different rooms in order to report and solve (or commit) murder most foul, the interior design of spaceships has become a fascination of mine in the past month or so. It’s interesting that despite having no knowledge of what a spaceship would actually need in terms of square footage and technical components, I have a very clear idea in my mind of what the interior of a spaceship looks like.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22086 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/outer-space-2177944_1920-300x240.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="240" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/outer-space-2177944_1920-300x240.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/outer-space-2177944_1920-1024x819.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/outer-space-2177944_1920-768x614.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/outer-space-2177944_1920-1536x1229.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/outer-space-2177944_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />In fact, there are two main versions of what the interior of a spaceship looks like, in my mind. First, there’s the 2001: A Space Odyssey / Star Trek / Apple Store version, which favors luminous ceiling panels, glossy surfaces, and enormous opaque wall, floor, and ceiling panels. It’s pretty and clean, but also a little… too clean.</p>
<p>The other version is what I’d categorize as the Alien franchise / Millennium Falcon / electronics warehouse style, which is not only poorly lit, but which has flickering lights for dramatic effect, interior <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greeble">greeble</a>, and buttons. Lots of multi-colored, flashing buttons. It looks like the kind of ship where duct tape is still a viable repair method for most problems.</p>
<p>Interestingly, these two styles aren’t wildly different, when you look at them side-by-side. The most obvious factor influencing the moods of both interiors is the lighting and the designer’s attempts to either cover up or showcase the “guts” of the ships using exposed tubes, wires, and compartments. Other than that, both styles favor drab neutral tones, narrow corridors flanked by automatic sliding doors, panel or tube lighting, and uniform floors, walls, and ceilings.</p>
<p>It’s taken me until writing this to realize that they are both very boring-looking, brutalist-modern interior styles. They are the airport waiting areas of spaceship interiors. Obviously, a spaceship not only doesn’t need wall hangings or rugs or track lighting—those accoutrements very much belong to interiors that don’t do barrel-rolls. And it also makes sense that more organic interiors don’t exist in sci-fi movies or TV shows—what visual media has the time to explain to an audience why a spaceship has hardwood floors?</p>
<p>But books and graphic novels do have that kind of time, and it’s always a pleasure to read or look at a new take on the spaceship that isn’t so obviously affected by the functional, militaristic style favored in film and TV (and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=llbIzbOStt4">real life</a>). A great example is the treeship in Brian K. Vaughan &amp; Fiona Staples’ Saga graphic novels—a space vessel with an incredible natural interior that <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22084 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/space-358237_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/space-358237_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/space-358237_1920-1024x769.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/space-358237_1920-768x577.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/space-358237_1920-1536x1154.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/space-358237_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />seems to be lit by bioluminescent fungi. Does it &#8220;make sense&#8221; that this ship moves through the vacuum of space as a living entity, full of other living entities? Sure! In the world of Saga, magic is as fundamental a rule of the universe as science. In fact, the series centers itself on the concept of inorganic, machine beings and organic, magic-using beings warring. A spaceship that introduces non-machine technology is a great concept. After all, even in the real world, technology can be grown as well as built. Also, this is speculative fiction—why limit a spaceship to what is ultimately a trope based on interior design trends from last millennium?</p>
<p>In some senses, having an interior that looks a bit more natural, or a bit less uniform, does make sense when speculating about what interstellar travelers might need. If passengers are undertaking a voyage that takes years, or making their living traveling on spacecrafts, doesn’t it make sense that they’d spruce the place up a bit? Even the ISS makes use of <a href="https://youtu.be/06-Xm3_Ze1o?t=1374">stickers</a> and <a href="https://www.space.com/29233-space-station-viewscreen-astronaut-tech.html">projectors</a>&#8211;truly the wall-hangings of a zero-G future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ode to the Infodump</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ode-to-the-infodump/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anne Elise Brinich]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 10:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Everybody and Their Motherboard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I think of infodumping, the practice of including far too much backstory or explanation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I think of infodumping, the practice of including far too much backstory or explanation in fiction (or nonfiction!) writing, there is one man who stands above the rest: the science fiction author Neal Stephenson.</p>
<p>Stephenson is famous for his infodumps, including his long, long lists, which transcend <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19888 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/The_Diamond_Age-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/The_Diamond_Age-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/The_Diamond_Age.jpg 260w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />the winking comedic effect most writers use them for to become something more like a middle schooler trying to consume the required word count for an English class essay. I first encountered Stephenson&#8217;s practice of heaping paragraph after paragraph of tangentially relevant, but somewhat unnecessary information, in his novel, <em>The Diamond Age</em>, a book that goes out of its way to educate readers about technology and architecture in a delightfully meta way<em>.</em> Consider, from <em>The Diamond Age</em>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Therapies administered included but were not limited to: turning things off, then on again; picking them up a couple of inches and then dropping them; turning off nonessential appliances in this and other rooms; removing lids and wiggling circuit boards; extracting small contaminants, such as insects and their egg cases, with nonconducting chopsticks; cable-wiggling; incense-burning; putting folded-up pieces of paper beneath table legs; drinking tea and sulking; invoking unseen powers; sending runners to other rooms, buildings, or precincts with exquisitely calligraphed notes and waiting for them to come back carrying spare parts in dusty, yellowed cardboard boxes; and a similarly diverse suite of troubleshooting techniques in the realm of software.</p></blockquote>
<p>Somewhere, Hemingway is weeping. Stephenson&#8217;s infodumping truly stands out in the novel <em>Reamde, </em>which might as well be used as a textbook explaining the economic systems of MMORPGs. I want to put an excerpt from that book here, but the level of detail he goes into about virtual currencies, game design, and global politics is so dense that in order to put a coherent passage here I&#8217;m pretty sure I would have to use several pages of text, and that would actually be breaking copyright law.</p>
<p>This is not an indictment of Stephenson&#8217;s style. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/introducing-the-ominous-sounding-tech-generator/">Like dumb tech jargon</a>, I love the pseudo-crunchiness of infodumps, and I especially love them when they are well-done. Here are the four elements I think an infodump needs to have in order to be relevant to a story:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>An omniscient narrator. </strong>A first-person narrator infodumping is a hard no for me, unless they are intentionally insufferable, or knowledgeable about a few, recurring subjects that are near and dear to their character.</li>
<li><strong>Relevance. </strong>Otherwise, it&#8217;s just a flex on how much you know about cryptocurrency, marine biology, the lore of the world you&#8217;re created, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Humor. </strong>Alternatively, just a sense of fun. I refer to <a href="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/ten_thousand_2x.png">this Randall Munroe comic</a>. It&#8217;s so fun to share new information with people&#8211;what if they get excited about it too?</li>
<li><strong>An ending.</strong> When you&#8217;ve said the information that needs to be said in a fun way, it&#8217;s over. Back to the action.</li>
</ol>
<p>To be completely honest with you, these are rules I&#8217;ve made for myself more than anyone else, and it should go without saying that a good writer can break any of these rules to great effect. In my case, there&#8217;s a fifth rule: that rules 1 through 4 don&#8217;t have to apply on first draft, but <em>must </em>apply during editing. Not everyone wants to hear how amazing the the ancient Mesopotamian barley standard economic exchange was.</p>
<figure id="attachment_19890" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19890" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-19890 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/barley-300x198.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="198" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/barley-300x198.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/barley-1024x675.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/barley-768x506.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/barley-1536x1013.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/barley-2048x1350.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19890" class="wp-caption-text">Ooooh, barley tablet! Tell me more!</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing: The Ominous Sounding Tech Generator</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/introducing-the-ominous-sounding-tech-generator/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anne Elise Brinich]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 10:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Everybody and Their Motherboard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19578</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have enough exposure to the real-life commercial tech world to know that, for the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have enough exposure to the real-life commercial tech world to know that, for the most part, <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19718 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/franki-chamaki-1K6IQsQbizI-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/franki-chamaki-1K6IQsQbizI-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/franki-chamaki-1K6IQsQbizI-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/franki-chamaki-1K6IQsQbizI-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/franki-chamaki-1K6IQsQbizI-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/franki-chamaki-1K6IQsQbizI-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />new technology sounds much more interesting than it really is. The hype around emerging tech is often thanks in no small part to the names assigned to it by tech journalists (“big data,” “artificial intelligence,” “hyperautomation”) who, being giant nerds, have sometimes lifted terminology straight out of science fiction stories that have been around decades longer than the technology itself.</p>
<p>I love this jargon. I love that it often references science fiction, creating a recursive cycle where new technology is both influenced by, and influences, how and why science fiction stories are written. I even love that it’s a bit hyperbolic, as if it’s aspiring to be as cinematic and exciting as we want our technology to be, even if it’s technically just a program that makes work easier, and which has been assigned a cool name to hype people up.</p>
<p>I especially love that when I read a new jargon-y word, what it actually does is not at all connected to what I initially imagined its application to be (looking at you, “computer vision”). <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19719 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/markus-spiske-iar-afB0QQw-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/markus-spiske-iar-afB0QQw-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/markus-spiske-iar-afB0QQw-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/markus-spiske-iar-afB0QQw-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/markus-spiske-iar-afB0QQw-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/markus-spiske-iar-afB0QQw-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Given that the purposes of new jargon-y programs are often much cooler in my imagination, I find these misdirects to be ripe for brainstorming stories—what if an “Internet of Things” was what I thought it was, when I first heard the term? So, I created an <a href="https://codepen.io/aeb685/full/abNyqaB">Ominous Sounding Tech Generator</a> to get those creative juices going. I hope you’ll use it too, for brainstorming or for thinking of a name for an absolutely wild technology that exists in the world of your story.</p>
<p>For the record, my favorite output from this program so far has been “Dark Optimization,” which sounds like the name of a Transformer. A few of my other favorites:</p>
<ul>
<li>“Quantum Multiexperience&#8221; (Absolute word salad. Love it.)</li>
<li>“Growth Disruption” (Unfortunately, I think I have actually heard this uttered at a tech event.)</li>
<li>“Crypto-Neutrality” (&#8220;Crypto&#8221; just makes everything sound cooler.)</li>
<li>“Computer Fix” (They can’t all be good.)</li>
<li>“Growth Things” (Yuck?)</li>
</ul>
<p>Try the <a href="https://codepen.io/aeb685/full/abNyqaB">Ominous Sounding Tech Generator</a> for yourself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Manmade Woman</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-manmade-woman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anne Elise Brinich]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Everybody and Their Motherboard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve been looking for over a month now, and I have to say: as far&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19446 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/h-heyerlein-BsWgMBfb208-unsplash-300x198.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="198" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/h-heyerlein-BsWgMBfb208-unsplash-300x198.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/h-heyerlein-BsWgMBfb208-unsplash-1024x675.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/h-heyerlein-BsWgMBfb208-unsplash-768x506.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/h-heyerlein-BsWgMBfb208-unsplash-1536x1012.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/h-heyerlein-BsWgMBfb208-unsplash-2048x1349.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I’ve been looking for over a month now, and I have to say: as far as well-known creation stories go, it is not easy to find one written by a woman, about women creating someone woman-identifying in science fiction<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1">[1]</a>. I didn’t realize just how rare it is to read a woman-centric creation story ticking those three boxes until I started researching this very column, searching through science fiction narratives about female androids, by female authors, for one—just one, please, for the love of god— story where the android’s creator was a woman.</p>
<p>Why did those become the criteria I became obsessed with? Your guess is as good as mine. And if your guess is “because you knew such a story doesn’t exist, and you wanted to make a point by ripping off Alison Bechdel”, you’re probably on the right track. It should be noted that I am not the arbiter of what makes android-related fiction good, nor do I think that including female-identified androids will automatically make a story good, or important.</p>
<p>Still, it does seem like a story that should exist. So, I looked for it. And I looked. And I looked.</p>
<p>I even stretched the definition of android a bit in my search, as well as my criteria for female authorship. I reached way back to Pygmalion, which may very well have been told by a woman originally, but which features a man bringing to life the statue of a woman that he has sculpted and fallen in love with. I ran into the same problem with Genesis—even assuming the unknown originator of the story was female, Eve comes from Adam’s rib, and the whole creation process is thanks to a god with he/him pronouns.</p>
<p>From these two stories of creating a human form come a long tradition in western literature of male characters creating women. The narrative echoes of Pygmalion and Genesis are apparent, scanning science fiction from the 1800s forward, as the notion of humans creating human-like beings using non-biological reproductive means start becoming popular. And despite these many riffs, I couldn&#8217;t find what I wanted.  At a certain point, it occurred to me that there may not be very much woman-authored female creator/createe literature by virtue of women not having written science fiction for very long, but then I remembered that a woman originated the genre, and that she did so <em>with a novel about a man creating a male being. </em></p>
<p>Women are no strangers to writing about the creation of androids; Mary Shelley may have been the first woman to write a science fiction story about creating a human-like being, but she was not the last. Some of the greatest and oldest riffs on the mortal creator story are by women. Marge Piercy’s <em>He, She, and It </em>is a masterpiece, and a nuanced discussion of gender, sex, and creation. But it is a story that centers on a male android created by a woman. And it misses my desired trifecta by one criterion.</p>
<p>My difficultly finding the female android story may also be a problem of pronouns, or of vague origins. Isaac Asimov, the go-to guy for android fiction, mentioned in his introduction to <em>The Bicentennial Man and Other Stories</em> that his robots are meant to be read as sexually neutral, though he follows this up with the confusing admission that they almost all have male names, <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19447 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/eric-krull-Ejcuhcdfwrs-unsplash-300x175.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="175" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/eric-krull-Ejcuhcdfwrs-unsplash-300x175.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/eric-krull-Ejcuhcdfwrs-unsplash-1024x599.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/eric-krull-Ejcuhcdfwrs-unsplash-768x449.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/eric-krull-Ejcuhcdfwrs-unsplash-1536x898.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/eric-krull-Ejcuhcdfwrs-unsplash-2048x1198.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />and he treats them “all as male”.  It might be inferred that Asimov, along with other authors who use the pronouns he, him, and his for their androids, are using these pronouns in a now-defunct gender-neutral sense, where “he” is the filler pronoun for a person whose gender is unknown. Female androids are not present in their stories because gender and sex don’t really make sense to robots, or have no obvious bearing on the stories about androids that they’re trying to tell: “he” is a placeholder more than an identity.</p>
<p>And in plenty of stories, the creator of the android is a faceless, genderless corporation. The gender-free protagonist of Martha Wells’s <em>The Murderbot Diaries</em> series has no one creator: the androids of the series are corporate creations, and the person or teams of people who created them are not the subject of much discussion.</p>
<p>There are countless other stories (good stories! Great stories!) combining aspects of my desired android narrative. There are so many that the fact that my female-centric android story has never been widely popularized is a bit of a statistical anomaly. I think there are also dozens of novels and short stories that <em>do</em> match my criteria, but that I simply haven’t read because I haven’t heard of them yet because the folks in charge of marketing such material may not know that a demand for it exists. If you are one of those people, here is the evidence you needed. Show this column to your boss.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1">[1]</a> That is, excluding strictly biological mother-daughter stories by women</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
