<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Darkest Part of the Forest &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-darkest-part-of-the-forest/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 03:57:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Honesty</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/honesty/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melody Wolfe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 16:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Darkest Part of the Forest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a writer, a friend, a person, a student, and an employee, I tend to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a writer, a friend, a person, a student, and an employee, I tend to give a lot of thought to honesty; what it means, whether it’s a good idea or a bad idea, and how I feel about it.</p>
<p>To get started, let’s define “honesty.” Honesty is generally accepted as the antithesis of lying, hiding, or covering something up. It is bald-faced. It is The Truth. The problem here is a lot of life’s truths are subjective.</p>
<p>I once spent a week in first grade with my best friend and I ignoring each other, because SHE was WRONG about how to write the letter “e” and she was convinced that it was ME who was wrong. It turns out we were both technically right, but because we were sitting opposite each other, we were really just handicapped by our lack of spatial awareness. The teacher intervened.</p>
<p>And this happens all the time, with values and culture and religion and politics. Which is why, for the sake of this writing, I’m going to clarify. When I say “honesty,” I mean intentional honesty – not the Indisputable Facts of the Universe – but the kind of honesty where you’re trying hard to communicate how things look or feel from where you’re at.</p>
<p>With definitions down, we move on to the <em>ha-ha-should-I-really-be-saying-this-out-loud</em> conundrum. And this one is personal, folks. I’m not going to tell you when to tell the truth, or to whom, or on what subject. I will, however, explain how I approach it.</p>
<p>I tell the truth until I think telling the truth is a stupid idea.</p>
<figure id="attachment_4683" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4683" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/honesty-card..jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-4683 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/honesty-card.-300x210.jpg" alt="Courtesy of thefunniestpictures.com" width="300" height="210" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-4683" class="wp-caption-text">Courtesy of thefunniestpictures.com</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Why I tell the truth most of the time:</strong> I believe that honesty is the truest form of activism. People are complex and confusing, and when that gets brought to light, stereotypes crash and fall. When I’m honest about my life, it becomes really obvious that I don’t actually fit any particular stereotype. I’m female, and I like getting hatchets and geeky action figures for Christmas. I also really, <em>really</em> love cute underwear, and tiny utensils. And this goes for everything – gender, sexuality, hobbies, political leaning, religion/spirituality, age, mannerisms, etc. People are incredible varied creatures.</p>
<p>I consider breaking stereotypes activism, because I view ignorant assumptions as the cause for most conflict. When strangers go from being “them weirdos” to “real people”, the conversation is open and blanket justification is no longer an option.</p>
<p><strong>When I stop telling the truth:</strong> I stop telling the truth when it becomes impractical. When it hurts people I love (without that hurt being necessary in a larger conversation or situation). When it gets in the way (like telling a customer that I think they’re fucking stupid and creepy and I just really want their money). When it has legal ramifications (like when it’s summer and I’m too hot walking around town and wearing clothes feels like a lie, but going full naked gets me arrested). And when I’m too vulnerable to face the scrutiny of the public (I have scars that are healing, but aren’t quite ready to be displayed and poked yet).</p>
<p>That pretty much covers it. And while I recognize that I’ve got a pretty reasonable philosophy worked out, the lying part can still sometimes suck. As I see it, there are two reasons for this, and both of them are culturally perpetuated.</p>
<p><em>If you have to lie, it’s because what you’re doing is wrong. Shame on you.</em> You don’t tell people about embarrassing things, because it’s awkward and makes you blush, right? Yeah, sometimes that’s the case for me. It may line up that I’m lying about a mistake I’ve made, or something I, or someone else, considers wrong. It may line up that I’m completely honest about it, even if it’s hard. And that’s because my honesty (or lack of it) isn’t based on shame and the avoidance of shame. But the stigma attached to telling tall tales is pervasive enough that I catch myself feeling sad every once in a while, buying into it on reflex.</p>
<figure id="attachment_4684" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4684" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/liar.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-4684 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/liar-300x162.jpg" alt="Courtesy of Quickmeme" width="300" height="162" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-4684" class="wp-caption-text">Courtesy of Quickmeme</figcaption></figure>
<p><em>Why can’t you just suck it up for the cause? You’re lying because you’re a coward!</em> Sometimes I don’t tell the full truth because I’m scared of people’s reactions. But being worried about real consequences (getting fired, getting kicked out while still underage, not being ready to deal with insults on a certain topic, etc.) is not cowardice. I’m choosing to weigh the risks and protect myself and the ones I love. Could I just “suck it up for the cause”? Yes, and it would be a one-shot waste of effort that I could have been using elsewhere – in areas that won’t take rejection like an arrow to the knee, and will have a much stronger impact.</p>
<p>Honesty and lying, much like anything else, cannot be cut into black and white. To simplify truth/perspective, fact/subjectivity, open/shameful, or good/bad is to take away the nuances of being human; the richness of expression, or the details that make us individuals. So no, I may not be honest or dishonest all the time, but I’m fairly honest about being dishonest, and that suits me fine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>TW: Trigger Warnings.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/tw-trigger-warnings/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melody Wolfe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 15:22:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Darkest Part of the Forest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4999</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Quick start, what is a trigger warning? It’s a little post at the beginning of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Quick start, what is a trigger warning? It’s a little post at the beginning of a piece, warning readers about possibly emotionally charged content (rape, violence, abduction, abuse, incest, you-name-it), much like the “Viewer discretion advised” warnings on TV. The idea of an emotional “trigger” started in psychology and psychiatry, mostly in dealing with PTSD, and is now broadly used to describe anything that puts a reader/viewer in an emotional or unstable state of mind.</p>
<p>The subject of trigger warnings is a messy one. There are people who think it’s all censorship or plot-ruining, those who think it’s enabling or infantilizing, and those who will defend the idea of trigger warnings to the death and will insist that anyone who won’t is a terribly insensitive privileged dick.</p>
<p>The first is obviously the easiest to debunk. Censorship is the request/demand is to edit the writing and take out the offending (scary, triggering, anything disliked/disapproved of) bits, or to tone it down, or to remove the piece completely (politics and legality notwithstanding). Posting a trigger warning is adding onto the piece, not erasing something that’s already there. As for the idea that trigger warnings ruin the plot? Book jackets. Synopses. Blurbs. I’m pretty sure this has been done before. Most people find a way to get the idea across without baring it all.</p>
<p>The idea that trigger warnings, and the culture that adores them, are promoting ignorance and a perpetual state of victimhood is a little harder to dismiss. There are a lot of people who go to great pains to avoid things that make them feel honestly uncomfortable, which means that some traumas never get addressed and some people never learn to deal with their shit. They hobble themselves by avoiding the pain of growth or realization, and, at worst, end up negatively impacting the world with their self-protective stupidity – i.e.: All the bigots who refuse to acknowledge any counter argument as valid BECAUSE REASONS. (“Because I’m avoiding looking at this with an open-mind and facing whatever trauma has me believing this horrible shit, and the consequences of healing that.”) The thing is, if they’re already that determined to stay ignorant, they’re probably avoiding things just fine even without the handy trigger warning labels.</p>
<p>On the flipside, for those already working through their hurts, moving too quickly (by stumbling into something without having a heads up about the content) can actually be damaging. It’s like being ready to learn to swim, and then getting thrown in the deep end and told to “just cope.” If that were me, I’d be pissed – <em>fuck you, and fuck swimming; I’m never trying this again</em>. And even if I decided to give it another go, it would take loads more time and loads more effort. Being given a choice about how much a person is willing to face can be really beneficial in terms of moving forward without tripping over the feels. Trigger warnings let people who are struggling with recovery face things when they’re ready to face them.</p>
<p>Because of this, there are those who fervently advocate the use of trigger warnings on everything, explicitly. The problem encountered here is two-fold. First, it’s highly unrealistic to try to cover everything that anyone fears or isn’t ready to face. People are varied, diverse, individual creatures with equally varied traumas and hurts. A person who tried to list everything would probably fail.</p>
<figure id="attachment_5001" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-5001" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/triggerunpredictable.gif"><img decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-5001 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/triggerunpredictable-300x225.gif" alt="http://worldbuilderblog.me/2015/06/25/trigger-warning/." width="300" height="225" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-5001" class="wp-caption-text">http://worldbuilderblog.me/2015/06/25/trigger-warning/.</figcaption></figure>
<p>The second part is tied to the idea that triggers absolve everyone, and anyone, from any sort of personal responsibility. The group of people who most strongly argue for trigger warnings as mandatory are, as I’ve noticed, also those who buy into certain other aspects of victim culture – namely, the idea that triggers are absolutely terrible and impossible to deal with. Triggers become an excuse to act out, not something to work around and overcome. The idea being that trigger warnings must be posted everywhere because there is no way to deal with a trigger other than avoidance.</p>
<p>And so where have I settled in this mish-mash of arguments?</p>
<p>I think some description, whether that’s a trigger warning or a blurb or a foreboding color scheme on your blog or whatever else, is a really good idea. It’s packaging, or basic marketing, and lets the consumer know what they’re getting (and lets them decide if they want it or not). I wouldn’t want trigger warnings, specifically, to be compulsory. That’s limiting and limited. Use them if you’d like (sometimes I do!), but it’d be hell to regulate and impossible to account for.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>For Glory! For Loot! For&#8230;Sexism?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/for-glory-for-loot-for-sexism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melody Wolfe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 16:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Darkest Part of the Forest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I play World of Warcraft. And I love it. As a female player. And when&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I play World of Warcraft. And I love it. As a female player. And when I decided to write something about the game, I figured I’d answer the question I get asked most commonly – “How’s the sexism?” My usual answer is a mashed-up, tangential, meandering reply about how it’s not that bad. When I decided to write something a little more formal, I had to pick that to pieces to organize it into something coherent, and I wasn’t thrilled with what I found.</p>
<p>World of Warcraft (abbreviated to WoW) is a mass-multiplayer, online, role-playing game (or an MMORPG, for short). As such, it falls into a lot of the sad trappings of online gaming culture. Female computer-programmed characters have skimpier, sexier armor. There are many more strong male leads than female leads in the over-arching storyline. Online, players use insults like “faggot,” “slut,” and “retard” on a not infrequent basis. “Go make me a sandwich” is as common a retort as “UR MOM,” and often texted with the same casual douchery.</p>
<figure id="attachment_4110" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4110" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-4110" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/wrynn-sexy-300x278.jpg" alt="King Varian Wrynn, leader of the humans, dressed in about as much clothing as Alexstrasza, queen of the dragons." width="300" height="278" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-4110" class="wp-caption-text">King Varian Wrynn, leader of the humans, dressed in about as much clothing as Alexstrasza, queen of the dragons.</figcaption></figure>
<p><em>Awww, that’s just gaming culture! Yeah, it’s bad, but at least the insults are aimed at everyone, equally?</em></p>
<p>Not quite. Female toons get stalked, courted, grinded on, flirted with, tea-bagged, and humped more than male characters. In starting areas, new female characters are almost always approached by at least one Creepy Jim who wants to “help them out” while naked and emoting kisses (the problem, for anyone who’s wondering, is solved by logging out for a few minutes and then logging back in – saying “no” just opens a conversation of “marry meeeeee, ur cute, i love youuuu”). At higher levels, Creepy Jim expresses his discomfort with respectful social contact by grinding up against female characters waiting for the boat, or via humping unsuspecting female strangers (the virtual art of sitting and standing in rapid succession while facing another player to make it look like intercourse). While these occurrences are not necessarily tied to being female in real life, it is a pretty blatant display of sexism.</p>
<p>As for being female in real life, there’s a different problem that pops up. On a male character, almost no one will believe the player behind the mask is female (the same is not true of dudes playing female characters – that’s totally normal). On a female character, if played really fucking well, another brand of special enters the ring, the Self-Proclaimed-Well-Educated-Atheist. The SPWEA will argue that, because of evolution, women cannot play aggressive characters as well as men can. Women might receive leeway if they play a healer class, because, y’know, they nurture babies and stuff. But only if they remain modest, without bragging. Bragging is a man’s game. Any counter-argument is, obviously, invalid because the SPWEA has seen the truth of the universe and is apparently omniscient. The freakiest part is that SPWEA is famed at large for his quick logic and brilliant insights. In the forums online, the SPWEA rules as celebrity-king.</p>
<p><em>If that’s the case, why the fuck are you still playing?! That sounds terrible!</em></p>
<p>Honestly? Because I like the game, and side-step most of the bullshit. I choose minimal contact with most players. I join guilds run by reasonable people, with reasonable people in them – or often guilds that just don’t talk much. I stay away from the online forums, which are separate from the game anyways. I recruit real-life friends to play online with me, and I hit the “ignore” button on those assholes who verbal-vomit into my playtime. Those who are cool, and funny, and sweet, get my attention and we end up chatting and joking around. Out of my control, sometimes the storyline takes a turn for the worse, in terms of great heroines crumbling into stereotypes, and I speak my piece to Blizzard (the company who runs the game), and hope the next expansion will be better. The most recent expansion, Warlords of Draenor, introduced a new strong female character, and I was mollified enough to keep playing.</p>
<figure id="attachment_4111" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4111" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-4111 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/epiccloak-300x300.jpg" alt="My character with the Epic Questline Cloak reward from the last expansion." width="300" height="300" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-4111" class="wp-caption-text">My character with the Epic Questline Cloak reward from the last expansion.</figcaption></figure>
<p>It can be infuriating and disheartening, but I still just really like the game! I love the graphics, and the world, and running through epic battles killing shit. I played the original strategy game and fell in love with it, before I had even heard of the online role-playing version. I grew up with crushes on elves and orcs and mages, dying to be a part of that world. And with World of Warcraft, I can run through it, to an extent. So is WoW sexist? Yes, it is. Sometimes really uncomfortably and disgustingly so, but I find ways to work around that because I love the game.</p>
<p>WoW is the exception for me. I cannot watch movies with heroic men and weak women. I just can’t. And the same is true of the books I read, versus the books I throw across the room, revolted. Warcraft is different, for me. Like some of the slightly dudebro-ish friends in my life, World of Warcraft has enough charm and wonder and fun and possibility for it to be worth the slow frustration the sexism often inspires. As the world changes, and especially as sexism in games is under the spotlight, I’m hoping that Blizzard takes note and hires some better writers and better moderators.</p>
<p>So CHEERS! Here’s to suffering through the asinine, because I really, really like playing kick-ass night elves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“If you go out in the woods today…”</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/if-you-go-out-in-the-woods-today/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Melody Wolfe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 21:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Darkest Part of the Forest]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Why “The Darkest Part of the Forest”? Because that’s where I come from. It’s where&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Why “The Darkest Part of the Forest”?</p>
<p>Because that’s where I come from. It’s where I write from. It’s where I prefer to live.</p>
<p>The “Forest” part is probably pretty obvious – I like the woods. I love wild places, and I’ve grown up in forests my entire life, clambering cliffs and valleys, climbing trees, and curling up in the nooks of roots to nap or read my book.</p>
<p>The “Darkest” part is probably a little more ambiguous. See, most people think of the Deep Dark Woods, and they think of Little Red Riding Hood’s grandma getting eaten. It’s a scene of horror and fear and terrible, terrible things. Bad people hang out in dark places, and if there are no people, then it’s the killer animals. Or the shadows that lurk on the edge of the soul, waiting for a chance to bring nightmares to life. Whatever it is, most people don’t like it. Don’t want it. And those who do, often seem to chase it with an elated, pee-your-pants, morbid fascination.</p>
<p>I admit it; I was in the morbid fascination group, and that’s how I first ended up in the forest at night. It was a heady combination of anger, recklessness, and desperation. I needed something a little more raw, a little more dangerous. I needed the adrenaline to feel alive, and what provided more blood-pumping fear than going unaided and unlit to the place that everyone unanimously avoided? And so I went from wandering the streets at night, to sitting in starlit parks, to wandering my favorite shadowed woodsy trails.</p>
<p>What I found was something I hadn’t expected. Sure, the first time, I jumped at crickets, I was so nervous. The second time, I decided to stay longer. I picked a nice piece of shade, and sat down.</p>
<p>There’s a quote by Henry David Thoreau, “A howling wilderness does not howl: it is the imagination of the traveler that does the howling.” I found it to be so incredibly, beautifully true. I sat, and listened, and watched, and was still. There were animals, minding their own business. There were trees, minding their own business. There was the wind, minding everyone’s business, as it blew through. I didn’t get attacked, or eaten, or abducted by <em>things in the night</em>. Those ravenous man-eating wolves? No shows. The serial killer with the blood-stained cleaver? Didn’t even bother to say “hello.” The terrifying goblin-demons with glowing red eyes? Pretty sure they all stayed home.</p>
<p>Which is not to say that dangerous things haven’t happened, and that’s why I vastly prefer walking with a friend. I’ve cut trips short because I heard a bear in the area, or canceled going outside because there was a cougar hunting in the backyard. Things happen. It’s not all terrifying, and it’s not all serene. Peaceful, exhilarating, wondrous, simple, nerve-wracking, dull, busy, quiet, calming, breath-taking – it’s this vibrant reality that makes the woods a wonderful place to be.</p>
<p>In that all, though, there is a certain sameness to the woods, especially when one is alone. While animals may amble through, or flit from branch to branch, there is no man-made entertainment. No television, no computer games, no advertisements or car crashes – no people. And this lends itself to a sort of quiet introspection. Without massive amounts of external stimulation or distractions, there is time and time enough to think. To wonder.</p>
<p>I love the honesty in it, the open eyes that see the danger and also the beauty. There’s a joy in deciding that the risk is worth it, and enjoying the moonlight. There’s a joy in being happily flexible, bending to accommodate paradox and possibility, and having a place to think. In modern Western society, “The Darkest Part of the Forest” is a fearful place, where all those paradoxes and possibilities meet in a torrential river of paranoia. How I see it, paradoxes and possibilities are the truest realities, and that’s why I love them.</p>
<p>I choose to live in “The Darkest Part of the Forest.” And in living there, that’s where my words come from.</p>
<figure id="attachment_4217" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4217" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/lynnvalley.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-4217" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/lynnvalley-300x200.jpg" alt="Lynn Valley, North Vancouver, B.C." width="600" height="400" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-4217" class="wp-caption-text">Lynn Valley, North Vancouver, B.C. &#8211; courtesy of http://www.stefanf.com/.</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
