<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Daughters of the Last Frontier &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/daughters-of-the-last-frontier/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 23:28:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Magical Realism of María Luisa Bombal</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-magical-realism-of-maria-luisa-bombal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Bannerman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 11:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Daughters of the Last Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Magical realism blends the mystical with the mundane, a task that pioneering voice María Luisa&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/enfqmcttsjo.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28683 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/enfqmcttsjo-300x200.jpg" alt="body of water and mountain" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/enfqmcttsjo-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/enfqmcttsjo-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/enfqmcttsjo-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/enfqmcttsjo-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/enfqmcttsjo.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Magical realism blends the mystical with the mundane, a task that pioneering voice María Luisa Bombal used with passion and poetic flare in the 1930s and 1940s. She explored irrational and subconscious themes in a highly personal, poetic style, and by doing so, became one of the first Spanish American novelists to examine the secret inner worlds of women’s imaginations.</p>
<p>Born in the Chilean resort town of Viña del Mar in 1910, <a href="https://www.themodernnovel.org/americas/latin-america/chile/bombal/">María Luisa Bombal</a> moved to Paris with her family and attended the Lycée La Bruyère and the Sorbonne at the University of Paris. She returned to Chile in 1931 and, due to political unrest, moved to Buenos Aires in 1933 where she lived with Chilean writer Pablo Neruda and his wife. The famous poet, seeing her talent, encouraged her to write. Her first short stories were quickly published by the influential <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sur_(magazine)">literary magazine <em>Sur</em></a>. In 1934, she married the Argentinian painter, Jorge Larcos.</p>
<p>After he died in 1940, she moved to the United States and married Count Raphael de Saint-Phalle, with whom she had a daughter. However, when he died thirty years later, she returned to Chile, where she lived until her death in 1980. While she never achieved fame for her work, the Chilean government recognized her contributions to art and literature by providing her a small stipend in her final years.</p>
<p>While she wrote many short stories, she translated two of her novellas into English for American audiences. In<em> The House of Mist</em>, published in Spanish in 1935, the heroine uses her vibrant creativity as a sanctuary from a boring and unfulfilling marriage. When she takes a mysterious lover to add passion and excitement to her life, she begins to question if the man really exists, or if he is a figment of her desperate imagination. In The Shrouded Woman, published in 1938, the dead protagonist watches from her coffin as funerary mourners file by – family members, old lovers, friends – and she regales the reader with the stories of their relationships. While the main character is honest about her own shortcomings in life, she has grown more forgiving and tender in death, and reflects upon her mourners with compassion.</p>
<p>The struggles of Bombal&#8217;s female protagonists are rooted in sad reality – often trapped in unhappy relationships or pushing against the confines of a male-dominated society – but wonderful and strange fantasies provide them with an avenue of escape and a source of strength. Their dreamscapes are sometimes accessed through music, or through nature, or through a desire for intimate connection. Again and again, Bombal blurs the lines between memory, passions, and reality. Perhaps her work holds too much of the real world to be considered fantasy, but steeped in the creativity of her own vibrant imagination, her stories fit neatly into the genre of magical realism, and her work predates Gabriel Garcia Marquez’s <em>One Hundred Years of Solitude</em>, which is often considered the quintessential example of <a href="https://www.vox.com/2014/4/20/5628812/11-questions-youre-too-embarrassed-to-ask-about-magical-realism">magical realism</a>.</p>
<p>The work of María Luisa Bombal is full of vibrant imagery, passionate and emotional characters, and fantastical elements that juxtapose the challenges of real life with the rich hallucinations of those trapped in it. Her stories are infused with strange and unbelievable moments, leaving her characters to navigate a magical universe that may, or may not, exist only in their fertile imaginations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gertrude Barrows Bennett: Lady of Shadows</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/gertrude-barrows-bennett-lady-of-shadows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Bannerman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 10:59:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Daughters of the Last Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The invention of modern American dark fiction is often attributed to HP Lovecraft, but in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28591 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Argosy_19180914-209x300.jpg" alt="" width="209" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Argosy_19180914-209x300.jpg 209w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Argosy_19180914.jpg 400w" sizes="(max-width: 209px) 100vw, 209px" /></p>
<p>The invention of modern American dark fiction is often attributed to HP Lovecraft, but in the early 20<sup>th</sup>-century, another author traversed those shadowy, eldritch paths.  Some even claim that this author came first, trailblazing a new genre with a more elegant and graceful style.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Writing under the pseudonym ‘Francis Stevens’, Gertrude Barrows Bennett was a pioneering voice in fantasy and science fiction. She crafted a number of <a href="https://sf-encyclopedia.com/entry/stevens_francis">short stories and books</a> between 1917 and 1920, exploring themes and ideas that continue to intrigue modern readers. Her story <a href="https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/author/37650">‘Friend Island’</a> (published in 1918) is set in a 22nd-century society where gender roles have been abandoned, while her dystopian novel ‘The Heads of Cerberus’ (published in 1919) features an early – and perhaps the earliest – example of parallel universes. In addition to these works, her most famous books include the novel ‘Claimed’ and the lost world novel ‘The Citadel of Fear’.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Gertrude Barrows was born in Minneapolis in 1884. Her parents, Charles and Caroline, nurtured her love of reading but she left school during eighth grade to study art at night school, as she aspired to become an illustrator. Eventually, however, she quit school and took a job as a stenographer, which could provide a steady income. Her <a href="https://www.thefandomentals.com/gertrude-barrows-bennett-1/">early years</a> were marked by a parade of tragedy: her father died in 1892, her brother Reginald died in 1896, and her brother Clark died in 1898. She married British journalist and explorer Stewart Bennett in 1909, moved to Philadelphia, and quickly became pregnant, but tragically he died only a year later: while on a treasure hunting expedition off the coast of Florida, he drowned during a tropical storm. His death left a devastated Gertrude with a new-born daughter, Josephine, and an ailing mother to support.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>By the end of World War I, she began to write stories to supplement her income as a stenographer. This was not her first foray into writing: in 1904, at the age of seventeen, her short story ‘The Curious Experience of Thomas Dunbar’ had been accepted for publication in the magazine <i>Argosy</i>. In it, the character of Dunbar survives a harrowing car crash and wakes up in the laboratory of a scientist, where a mishap during an experiment gives Dunbar super-strength. Here in the 21<sup>st</sup>-century, we can immediately recognize the classic superhero origin story, but in 1904, this was a ground-breaking plot device, and contributed to the foundation of future hero stories.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>In 1917, she threw herself into her work with verve, crafting vibrant worlds and harrowing situations that showed off her remarkable imagination. Her first novella, &#8220;The Nightmare&#8221;, is set on an island cut off from the rest of the world, where evolution has taken a different course. It was published in All-Story Weekly Magazine, and while she originally asked to use the pseudonym <i>Jean Vail</i>, the editor instead credited the story to Francis Stevens – why he chose this name, we may never know. When eager readers reacted positively to her story, Bennett chose to continue writing under the pseudonym.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>In 1918 she published her first novel, ‘The Citadel of Fear’, in which a forgotten Aztec city is rediscovered during World War I. Many readers felt the style and images were similar to the work of Abraham Merritt, and rumors soon swirled that ‘Frances Stevens’ was actually his pseudonym – but Merritt quickly squashed these ideas. He claimed to enjoy the work of Frances Stevens, admitted to being influenced by it, and openly praised the talent it displayed.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>‘The Citadel of Fear’ received many glowing reviews, including one letter from Mr. Augustus T. Swift, who wrote,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<div>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;If written by Sir Walter Scott or Ibanez, that wonderful and tragic allegory, would have been praised to the sky… Stevens, to my mind, is the highest grade of your writers.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
</div>
<div>
<p>In her novel ‘Claimed’, a magical artifact summons an ancient god to early 20th-century New Jersey. Of this book, Swift wrote, “One of the strangest and most compelling science fantasy novels you will ever read.”</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Now, I will not wade into the debate that this letter was itself written under a pseudonym, with the actual author being HP Lovecraft. Some researchers insist that Lovecraft <a href="https://books.google.ca/books?id=n1aBDwAAQBAJ&amp;pg=PA139&amp;lpg=PA139&amp;redir_esc=y#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false">enjoyed and supported</a> her work, while others <a href="https://tellersofweirdtales.blogspot.com/2018/03/augustus-t-swift-1867-1939.html">debunk this claim</a>, citing evidence that Mr. Swift was a humble teacher living in Providence, Rhode Island. Still, the letter speaks highly of Bennett’s work and shows, she had many devoted fans.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Far from being obscure, her stories continued to be highly celebrated during the post-war years. From vials of magical dust, to unseen evils lurking in working-class neighbourhoods, to volcanic eruptions belching up boxes full of nightmares, her tales often veers into the weird, the unsettling, and the bizarre. Bennett liked to explore the vast, uncaring nature of the universe, but instead of feeling insignificant, she used this subjectivism as a reason for humans to care about each other. Her characters, instead of despairing, support one another as a way of defying an uncaring cosmos.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Almost all of Bennett&#8217;s literary work dates from 1917 to 1923. When her mother died in 1920, she seems to have ceased writing completely, with any work published after this date having been written years before. By the mid-1920s, Bennett placed her daughter in the care of friends and moved west to California. In 1939, her daughter sent her a letter but it was returned as undeliverable, and with no further communication between them, researchers assumed that Gertrude Barrows Bennett was dead. Only recently was her death certificate discovered, to reveal that she died in February 1948.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Critic Sam Moskowitz calls her &#8220;the greatest woman writer of science fiction in the period between Mary Wollstonecraft Shelley and C.L. Moore&#8221;, and author Gary C. Hoppenstand credits her with having &#8220;the best claim at creating the new genre of dark fantasy’. When asked about herself, Barrett said,</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I had just one merit, as I remember it, and that was a rather grotesque originality.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
</div>
<div>
<p>It would be a shame if the works of Gertrude Barrow Bennett were eclipsed by other Lovecraftian authors. Bennett’s work continues to lurk and linger in the shadows, waiting for a new generation of fans to discover her vibrant imagination &#8212; perhaps this time, under her own name.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Blazing Meteor of Norma Hemming</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-blazing-meteor-of-norma-hemming/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Bannerman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Daughters of the Last Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In September 2010, the 68th World Science Fiction Convention was held in Melbourne, Australia, affectionately&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="font-weight: 400;">In September 2010, the 68<sup>th</sup> World Science Fiction Convention was held in Melbourne, Australia, affectionately dubbed ‘Aussiecon 4’. The convention marked the inauguration of a new award: the <a href="https://normakhemmingaward.org/about-the-award/">Norma K. Hemming award</a>, which would mark excellence in the exploration of themes of race, gender, sexuality, class, or disability in speculative fiction.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">To celebrate this new award, a small cast performed a staged reading of Norma Hemming’s play, <a href="https://openpublishing.psu.edu/utopia/content/“-matriarchy-renok”">‘The Matriarchy of Renok’</a>. The play was originally written in 1958 and staged at a fan convention, but no one had performed it in 50 years so anticipation ran high. The abridged version, scripted and directed by author Sean McMullen, included readers in costumes and retro-1950s audiovisual effects, and from all accounts, seems to have been a rousing success.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">An annotation for the play provided by <a href="https://openpublishing.psu.edu/utopia/content/“-matriarchy-renok”">Utopian Literature</a> sums up its humor and light-heartedness:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">A matriarchy that keeps men in their “proper” role as slaves is visited by a man from Earth, which leads the all-powerful Galactic Empire. The man is crass in the extreme and assumes that the women will fall for him. They don’t.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/zzdqkwdsxwg.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-28375" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/zzdqkwdsxwg-300x200.jpg" alt="blue and white water droplets" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/zzdqkwdsxwg-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/zzdqkwdsxwg-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/zzdqkwdsxwg-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/zzdqkwdsxwg-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/zzdqkwdsxwg.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The tales of Norma Hemming are difficult to track down. She wrote only 20 short stories, published between 1951 and 1959, a couple of plays for science fiction conventions, and a few romance novels under a pseudonym. Most of her short stories are impish satires on relations between the sexes, pitting men and women against each other in unconventional situations. In light-hearted tones and with humor, she explores matriarchs and cosmic Amazons, inter-galactic love affairs, and children with super-human powers, bringing a sense of romance and playfulness to science fiction.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Norma Hemming was born in England in 1928 and trained as a secretary, but before beginning her career, she emigrated to Sydney, Australia, with her parents and younger brother in October 1948. Three years after arriving in Australia, her short story ‘Loser Takes All’ was published in the British magazine Science Fantasy. This seemed to open a flood-gate of creativity for Hemming: in 1951, she had three stories published, then another seven published in 1952.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">She became active in the Sydney science fiction scene, attending conventions and events, but the casual sexism of the time only allowed men to join the Sydney Futurian Society; women could participate as guests, but not members. The January 1942 issue of the <a href="https://verticalhorizons.wordpress.com/the-original-vertical-horizons/">Futurian Observer</a> noted that “…most of our friends in the Futurian Society have not a high opinion of the intelligence of females.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">For a forward-thinking genre, this would not do! During a lively campaign to include women, she revealed that she was a professional science fiction writer, and this caused a bit of a stir amongst the men. As one fellow in his <a href="https://verticalhorizons.wordpress.com/the-original-vertical-horizons/">convention report</a> stated, “… it came as a surprise that the N.K. Hemming” of Thrills (Incorporated) is the N.K. Hemming of New Worlds, and an actual person, Norma K. Hemming. Why doesn’t someone tell us these things?” As a result, Hemming became one of the first female members of the society in 1952, and was <a href="https://efanzines.com/MFM/MFM-26.pdf">introduced to the society</a> as “…the only pro-author at present in Sydney fandom”.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The fight to be included in the Futurian Society had galvanized the new women members. Their victory inspired them. Norma Hemming, Rosemary Simmons, and Laura Molesworth wanted to provide more opportunities for women in science fiction. Banding together, they launched a fanzine for female fans entitled <a href="https://efanzines.com/MFM/MFM-26.pdf">Vertical Horizons</a>. It contained news and reviews, as well as passionate essays. The zine challenged boundaries and concepts that a male-dominated industry had never before broached &#8212; the new forum gave women a venue to explore their own ever-expanding cosmos.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Hemming was a great champion for women’s involvement in Australian Science Fiction, and she used her clout to raise up others through new opportunities. However, despite her blazing journey over the landscape of science fiction, her life would soon to come to an abrupt end. In the late 1950s, Hemming was diagnosed with breast cancer, which then spread to her bones and lymph nodes. She died in Melbourne on July 4, 1960, at the age of 31. One can only wonder at the many ways that Hemming would have continued to shape and influence science fiction, if she’d lived just a little longer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Improbable Worlds of Zenna Henderson</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-improbable-worlds-of-zenna-henderson/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-improbable-worlds-of-zenna-henderson/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Bannerman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 11:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Daughters of the Last Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28166</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the 1950s and 60s, when most science fiction tales revolved around swashbuckling adventure and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p>In the 1950s and 60s, when most science fiction tales revolved around swashbuckling adventure and intergalactic monsters, Zenna Henderson’s work offered a fresh perspective as she explored what it means to be human.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Zena Chlarson, the oldest of five children, was born in 1917 in<span class="apple-converted-space"> </span>Tucson, Arizona. As a young woman, she pursued a bachelor of arts in education from Arizona State College, and taught mostly in the Tucson area. During World War II, she taught at Gila River Relocation Center, a Japanese internment camp in Sacaton, AZ. In 1944, she married a miner named Richard H. Henderson, but their marriage did not last and ended in 1951. After this, she changed her first name to ‘Zenna’, completed her master’s degree at Arizona State and, in the late-1950s, worked on a US Military base in France. After returning the United States, she taught at The Seaside, a tuberculosis sanatorium for children located in Connecticut.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Henderson’s love of science fiction had begun at the age of 12, and continued with her as she pursued her teaching career. Her first science fiction story, <i>“Come On, Wagon!,”</i> appeared in the December 1951 issue of Magazine of Fantasy and Science Fiction and, in 1959, her story <i>“Captivity”</i> received a Hugo nomination.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Henderson’s experiences as a teacher would influence <a href="https://jamesdavisnicoll.com/review/different-is-dead">her writing throughout her career</a>. In her 1952 short story &#8220;Ararat&#8221;, aliens marooned on Earth are searching for a new teacher to guide their children; all the other teachers have been scared away by the children’s telekinetic powers. This story was the first in a series that featured ‘The People’, a community of gentle humanoids trying to survive on Earth.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>The People are isolated, lonely individuals seeking safety and community, and they must suppress their inherent gifts in order to be accepted by human society. Instead of focusing on conquest and war, Henderson’s stories examine the quiet, personal lives of The People. She explores the relationships between the alien women and human women, who use discussion and co-operation to solve conflicts. For example, in “Subcommittee”, the wife of a human general befriends an alien mother and child. As they share skills like knitting and cooking, the human woman discovers that the aliens require salt to survive: this has been the root of human-alien strife. Using discussion and empathy, they’re able to find resolution and avert a potential crisis.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Henderson’s work has been labelled as pre-feminist, and while many of her female characters fall into stereotypical 1950s roles, she portrays a wide range of ages and personalities without falling into overused tropes and 2-dimensional roles. Her experience of working with children heavily influenced her ideas of belonging and camaraderie, and how difficult it can be to feel like one is outside the group. Raised as a Mormon, Henderson left the Church of Latter Day Saints to marry a Methodist, and this may have influenced her ideas on ostracism, too. Many of her stories explore the dangers of being different in an uncaring world, and she often highlights the importance of community and of patient communication.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>A common theme in her work is a child with extraordinary powers, discovered by a caring teacher through observation. A fine example of this is Henderson’s short story, <a href="https://www.kirkusreviews.com/book-reviews/a/zenna-henderson/the-anything-box/">“The Anything Box”</a>. An elementary school teacher notices that one of her students, a quiet and withdrawn girl named Sue-Lynn, is captivated by an item in her hands. The girl is holding the Anything Box, a container in which the viewer can see that which is most beautiful to them. When the teacher stares into the seemingly-harmless box, she realizes its power is dangerous: the viewer is distracted by what they can see but never have. The desire to leave reality and stare forever at the imaginary is too seductive.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>When she wrote ‘The Anything Box’ in the early 1960s, Zenna Henderson was an elementary school-teacher living in a small Arizona town, and one wonders if her own hopes, dreams, and fortitude were reflected in the short story. Henderson’s tales are haunting and poignant, sometimes frightening, but always thought-provoking with a deep sense of longing.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>In an era when most science fiction was action-packed, male-dominated, and often devoid of women, Henderson’s stories provided a remarkable departure. Her tales are not set on far-away planets full of thrills and conflict. Instead, through her imagination, Zenna Henderson explores an equally improbably landscape where diverse people are caring, compassionate and co-operative, and put aside all differences to work towards peace.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/uffqnkuj-hc-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28209 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/uffqnkuj-hc-2-300x231.jpg" alt="brown rock formation" width="300" height="231" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/uffqnkuj-hc-2-300x231.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/uffqnkuj-hc-2-1024x789.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/uffqnkuj-hc-2-768x592.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/uffqnkuj-hc-2-1536x1184.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/uffqnkuj-hc-2.jpg 1557w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-improbable-worlds-of-zenna-henderson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
