<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Story Mystic &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/story-mystic/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 11:34:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>A powerful spread to end the year</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-powerful-spread-to-end-the-year/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 11:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Story Mystic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=29000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I will draw five cards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><i>Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I will draw five cards focused on the art of writing. What do the cards have in store for us? What writing challenges will the next month bring? Let’s find out!</i></p>
<p class="p1">Wow, writers, what a spread! This month the cards are bombastic and powerful. They are bursting with energy and creative inspiration, and they will guide you toward great things as we wrap up this month and move toward the new year.</p>
<p> <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-29002 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/nic-y-c-WzazSaQF1F8-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="399" height="599" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/nic-y-c-WzazSaQF1F8-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/nic-y-c-WzazSaQF1F8-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/nic-y-c-WzazSaQF1F8-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/nic-y-c-WzazSaQF1F8-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/nic-y-c-WzazSaQF1F8-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/nic-y-c-WzazSaQF1F8-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 399px) 100vw, 399px" /></p>
<p class="p1">A general card for writers right now &#8211; <i>The Sun</i></p>
<p class="p1">The card for general circumstances this is the Sun. This is a card has powerful energy—mostly optimistic and positive. The card itself shows a large, bright sun in the sky, representing the source of life. Around the sun is life, growing bright and fertile from the earth. Nothing on the card itself is as big as the sun, which is the most powerful element of all.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This card shows the life-giving power of the sun, and the way that the sun itself holds power. When this card comes into our spread, it represents pure creation and power. This card may be connected to a person or situation in your life, or it may even be you! No matter what, when the Sun comes into the spread, you know that there is a powerful force that is influential in your life.</p>
<p class="p1">It is also interesting to note that the Sun comes into this reading in the darkest month of the year, with the longest nights. The days have begun to feel very short, and I have found that my energy and passion has been waning in general. In this moment of darkness, the Sun is here. This suggests that no matter what stage of writing you are currently at, no matter how you feel about the world and your writing process right now, there is bright hope and creativity as well. You have the creative power to envision new worlds, and your writing has the power to change the world. Do not forget that, or let your dreams lapse in this time.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for your plot &#8211; <i>Judgement</i></p>
<p class="p1">When it comes to your plot, the card this month is Judgement. This is a card of balance. It shows the end of the world and images from the Biblical book of Revelation—the dead rising from their graves, the messengers of God coming down to uplift the faithful, and the heavens opening. Whether this imagery aligns with your own beliefs or not, it is a sure symbol of a bold moment of reckoning. The time has come to pass judgement, and your plot is on trial.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Judgement card has weight when it comes to plot. Often, the stories we tell revolve around the actions of characters and how they are judged by the world they live in. It may be that the structure of your story is about to pass judgement upon your characters. If so, know that this is the right time. It may also be that it is time for you to pass judgement upon your story. You may be called to look more closely at the plot that you have been shaping and judge whether it is successful or not. You may need to be critical in this moment, cutting off plot threads that are not working, and adding in new plot threads as necessary.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Judgement card has powerful meaning, but it means that you need to weigh all the elements against one another. When it comes to your story, you at the ultimate and powerful creator. Do not be afraid to act like one.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for your characters &#8211; <i>The World</i></p>
<p class="p1">The World is the card that has been drawn for your characters. This is another card of balance, but it is less strict than the previous card in this reading. Traditionally, the World shows a nude woman who carries symbols of power and creation. She is dancing, moving from one thing to the next. The World is a card of completion, of the cycle of life, of beginnings and endings. It is a card that reminds us that every part of life is necessary and meant to be, from the most beautiful to the most terrible.</p>
<p class="p1">With this card in the place of your characters, the World shows us that our characters are moving through their own kind of cycle throughout the story. They have their beginnings and endings, their high points and their lows. They are not perfect, but they are complete. They have to be, in order to progress through our stories as we wish them to.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This month, you must make sure that your characters have balance. They cannot be only one thing, but must be many things at once. They should have strengths, balanced by weaknesses; moments of happiness as well as tragedy. Do not let any of your characters fall flat or into the trap of tropes. Those forms are common for characters with reason, but they cannot be all that a character is. Even a secondary character should have a rich inner life. And if they do, they will be complete. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for unforeseen circumstances &#8211; <i>The Star</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Star is the card of unforeseen circumstances this month, and that it a wonderful thing. The card itself shows a nude woman kneeling at the edge of a pool of water. She holds a container of water in each hand and pours them out—one onto dry land, and the other into the water. This water nourishes the earth and the fills the pool before her. On this card, the woman represents purity of thought and dreaming. She is situated between the land and the water, showing her connection with both parts of the world. She is intuitive and beautiful, and she is a bridge between things.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">When it comes to unforeseen circumstances, the Star is a card that represents dreaming and the unknown. The world right now is at the beginning of winter, and we are coming to the end of the year. This is a time to dream big and set goals. The Star in this placement suggests that circumstances may shift in surprising ways. Opportunities may come along that are beyond what you might have expected and seem like they are beyond your reach. Do not be afraid to dream big this month. Allow yourself to go with your intuition and be a little impulsive. Take a step toward the unexpected things that move your way, and know that taking a risk is sometimes the best thing to open new opportunities for you.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for the wider world &#8211; <i>King of Cups</i></p>
<p class="p1">The King of Cups is the last card in this spread. This is another card of power, like all the kings in the deck. The King of Cups is the king of the emotional world. He sits strong and tall upon a throne, and carries the symbols of the emotional world. He is strong and serious, in master of his emotions. Around him are chaotic waves and animals, symbolizing that no matter how strange and turbulent the world may be, he is in control of himself through it all.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This card comes into the spread to remind us that we are in control of ourselves and what we create. Even when the world seems out of control, we have the ability to master our own emotions and inner lives. We can allow ourselves to feel strongly, and we can restrain our feelings when necessary. We do not have to let the turbulent nature of the world derail us.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This card also reminds us that we have the mastery needed to write powerful works. As writers, we are always imbuing our inner and emotional selves on the page. If we do not have mastery of ourselves and our emotions, then we may struggle to write. But the King of Cups is here to remind us that we do have enough control, and we do know ourselves well enough. All that remains is for us to sit down and put it on the page.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-29001 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/mario-caruso-qtiemd1ofMc-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="547" height="308" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/mario-caruso-qtiemd1ofMc-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/mario-caruso-qtiemd1ofMc-unsplash-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/mario-caruso-qtiemd1ofMc-unsplash-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/mario-caruso-qtiemd1ofMc-unsplash-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/mario-caruso-qtiemd1ofMc-unsplash-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 547px) 100vw, 547px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Ann Langley writes speculative fiction and wild poetry, and can be found on twitter @ann_elangley for general chatting and hanging out purposes. She used the Pagan Otherworlds Tarot Deck for this reading, which can be found <a href="https://uusi.us/collections/uusi-tarot/products/pagan-otherworlds-tarot">here</a></i><i>.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trust yourself, love yourself, and start a conversation.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/trust-yourself-love-yourself-and-start-a-conversation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 12:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Story Mystic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is already November, writers! As always, it seems that the years has both flown&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">It is already November, writers! As always, it seems that the years has both flown by and crept along. Perhaps you are working on the challenge of NaNoWriMo this month and are pushing yourself to write great and wonderful things. Or perhaps you, like me, are looking for creativity in other ways—by taking a pause from your writing, revising, and enjoying the long evenings and rapidly cooling skies.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Whatever you are doing, writers, know that this will be a month to flourish and learn new things, especially when it comes to your relationships with other writers.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A general card for writers right now</strong> &#8211; <i>Three of Pentacles</i></p>
<p class="p1">To start with, we have the Three of Pentacles. This card is for general advice, and it shows that collaboration and teamwork is the way to go right now. The Three of Pentacles shows a young craftsperson at work with tools on a great project. Plans are laid out in from of them, plans that are bold and ambitious and beautiful. The architects of those plans stand nearby, and all the figures are in dialogue.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This card is here to remind us that great things can be accomplished when we work together. The Three of Pentacles is a card for planning and cooperation. It is for working with others and joining forces to defeat evil… or at least to write a great story. The Three of Pentacles is a positive card. This card says that as a writer, you are not alone.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This card may represent the community surrounding you. There are many other powerful writers out there, as well as those who have come before you. There is so much advice and learning to be done. You may find yourself looking for guidance this month—if that is the case, do not hesitate to reach out to those around you who are a few steps ahead. Read craft books to learn new techniques and ways to use them. Share your journey with others, because just as you may need to the help and support of others, so too may someone turn to you.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Three of Pentacles says that you are still learning, no matter where in your journey you are. This month, seek out opportunities to learn and grow. Do not just rely on yourself and your intuition. Reach out to others or do research. Get a support system in place. If you work together, you will do amazing things.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28784 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/ian-schneider-TamMbr4okv4-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="494" height="329" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/ian-schneider-TamMbr4okv4-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/ian-schneider-TamMbr4okv4-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/ian-schneider-TamMbr4okv4-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/ian-schneider-TamMbr4okv4-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/ian-schneider-TamMbr4okv4-unsplash-2048x1367.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 494px) 100vw, 494px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for your plot</strong> &#8211; <i>Queen of Cups</i></p>
<p class="p1">When it comes to your plot, we have the Queen of Cups. This is a beautiful and resplendent card. Queens are always figures of power and mastery, and this card is no different. The Queen of Cups shows a beautiful figure seated on a throne. She is introspective, and she sits at the edge of a sea, holding symbols of richness and intuition. She is thoughtful and calm, and she has all the hallmarks of the dreaming world in front of her.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This month, the Queen of Cups is here to show that when it comes to your plot, you are in a position of power. You have everything you need at your fingertips at long as you trust yourself and your intuition. This is a figure who is in control and trusts herself. As you write this month, allow yourself to follow your intuition. If you have a feeling about a character, follow it. This may take you to some strange places, but they will be powerful ones.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Queen of Cups is a very interior figure as well. She is powerful, but her wisdom is focused inward. Her strongest power is over the realm of interior thoughts, dreams, and the soul. She represents mastery of interior thought and emotions. When it comes to your plot this month, do not forget that sometimes subtle changes are just as important as the big ones. Do not let your plot carry you away so that it is one explosive moment after the next. Allow your characters some time to rest. Consider the emotional journey they are on as well. You are in control of that, and by developing this kind of journey, you will not be overwhelmed.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for your characters</strong> &#8211; <i>Six of Swords (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Six of Swords has come up with regard to your characters. This is a card that has appeared in these readings before. The card shows a pair of characters in a small boat, traveling across a body of water. Behind them, the water is dark and turbulent, and ahead it is tranquil. The six swords that figure in this image are weighty, suggesting the fact that the past, and memories of past experiences, may still bother us.</p>
<p class="p1">This month, the Six of Swords reminds you to trust in the journey that your characters are on. It may seem difficult and unclear at times. As a writer, you may not know exactly where your characters are going or how they will get there. The Six of Swords shows us that the journey is hard. Sometimes this journey may feel hopeless. As the card is reversed, it shows that the difficulties that you may be facing with regard to plot are internal, and that you need to face them. Your own doubts and insecurities may be making things difficult for you right now. Perhaps you doubt that you have made the right choices with your characters, or even that you are not able to create the types of characters and story that you dream of.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Until the journey is done, it may be difficult to see hope in the situation that you are in, but you must hope. The Six of Swords is a reminder that all journeys mean leave difficult situations behind and moving toward the light. Brighter days are coming, as long as you keep going.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for unforeseen circumstances</strong> &#8211; <i>Eight of Wands</i></p>
<p class="p1">When it comes to unforeseen circumstances, we have the Eight of Wands. This is a powerful card, though more abstract than others in its symbolism. It shows eight wands flying through the air, accompanied by bright-winged birds and swift winds. This card has a connection to travel, movement, and change.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This month, you should expect that things will change, and change fast. There may be travel in your future, or changes so swift and complete that they feel like you have entered a whole new world. Your story may change swiftly, and become something you never expected, or you may have the opportunity to go somewhere new.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Change can feel scary at times. Shaking up the usual and ordinary can be a terrifying thing. But no matter what, the Eight of Wands also signifies brighter days to come. Around the flying wands is a bright sky and beautiful landscape. You are traveling through a wonderful place this month, writer, and you will land well. Don’t fear the change—it will bring good things your way.</p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for the wider world</strong> &#8211; <i>The Lovers (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">Finally, we have a card for the wider world. This is the Lovers, a classic card symbolizing coming together, creation and fertility, the union of two creatures who can make something beautiful together. The Lovers is a card of desire and connection, and it shows us that there is power in coming together and creating something new.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">But this month the card is reversed. This means that there may be a sense of disconnection in your life, or that your realizations and unions are internal, quiet things. You may be feeling alone or set apart from others this month. You may feel that your work as a writer is unrecognized and unloved, or that something is not quite good enough. Just as the Lovers can symbolize love and desire and connection, so can they symbolize the opposite—distance, anger, and loneliness.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Do not let this negativity bring you down. It is natural to have times in our lives when we feel out of step with the world, or even our own desires. Try to restrain your urge to judge others and take a step back. Use the disconnection in your life to help you discover the edges of yourself and center yourself against any oncoming storms. The wider world may be trying to separate us and tear us apart, but as long as we hold true to the truth of ourselves, we will always find connections once again. Love yourself, and your will find a community along the way.</p>
<p> <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28785 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jiroe-matia-rengel-b9kh72kOcdM-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="543" height="407" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jiroe-matia-rengel-b9kh72kOcdM-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jiroe-matia-rengel-b9kh72kOcdM-unsplash-1024x769.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jiroe-matia-rengel-b9kh72kOcdM-unsplash-768x577.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jiroe-matia-rengel-b9kh72kOcdM-unsplash-1536x1153.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jiroe-matia-rengel-b9kh72kOcdM-unsplash-2048x1538.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 543px) 100vw, 543px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Ann Langley writes speculative fiction and wild poetry, and can be found on ig @<a href="https://www.instagram.com/aelangley/">aelangley</a>. She used the Pagan Otherworlds Tarot Deck for this reading, which can be found <a href="https://uusi.us/collections/uusi-tarot/products/pagan-otherworlds-tarot">here</a></i><i>.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Be strict with your routines&#8230; but don&#8217;t forget to schedule something fun!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/be-strict-with-your-routines-but-dont-forget-to-schedule-something-fun/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 11:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Story Mystic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I draw five cards focused&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><i>Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I draw five cards focused on the art of writing. What do the cards have in store for us? What writing challenges will the next month bring? Let’s find out!</i></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28704 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/joel-fulgencio-VSrHD079L78-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="440" height="660" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/joel-fulgencio-VSrHD079L78-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/joel-fulgencio-VSrHD079L78-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/joel-fulgencio-VSrHD079L78-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/joel-fulgencio-VSrHD079L78-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/joel-fulgencio-VSrHD079L78-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/joel-fulgencio-VSrHD079L78-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 440px) 100vw, 440px" /></p>
<p class="p1">A general card for writers right now &#8211; <i>The Emperor</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Emperor is a powerful card, and it symbolizes structure and control. In the hand of the Emperor lies the world itself, and this card signifies no less.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The emperor himself sits upon a throne, and wears red for passion and armor to show his invulnerability. The emperor is an older figure, wise with years and experience. This card shows that tradition and stricture can be powerful tools to help you as a writer. Think about your writing life right now. Is the Emperor your draft at the moment? This may mean that in order to sort it out, you need to go back to the basics in order to make your story the best it can be. Are <i>you</i> the Emperor right now? If so, you have all the power and ability in the world, and years of experience to back up your craft. But you will need a steady routine to bring out the best of yourself as a writer, and you will need to adhere to it every day.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">As a card for writers, the Emperor represents the fact that keeping control is essential right now. Traditional narratives and structures are also aligned with the Emperor, and may prove to be useful to you. The Emperor comes into this spread to remind us that as writers we have the ability and the talent to control entire worlds, if only we stick to the structures and routines that will keep us strong.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for your plot &#8211; <i>Ten of Swords</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Ten of Swords is a powerful card. It shows a latticework of swords, all criss-crossed across the sky above a figure lying on the ground, apparently dead. This is a card of betrayal and deep wounds, but also of the peaceful stillness that comes when the worst has come to pass.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Consider how this card may connect to you this month, writers. If this is a card represents your plot, perhaps the worst has come to pass for your characters. They may be in a bad position with no apparent way out. They are struggling, and you are not sure where to take them next. If that is the case, do not be afraid of this moment in the story. Allow your characters time to grieve, or to be angry. Explore their darker emotions and their wants and needs in this moment. Let your plot run its course, and look for the glimmer of hope of the horizon.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">If this card represents you as a writer right now, you are likely struggling with your abilities as a writer and storyteller. You may have come to a difficult part of your story, and you are looking at all that you have written and plotted (or left un-plotted), and you find that it is not right. The plot of your story has betrayed you, and has not turned out like you imagined. Your work has fallen short, and you are struggling.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">If this is the case, do not despair. This is natural to all writers. We all struggle with what we have created and fear that it is worthless somewhere along the way. The Ten of Swords is here to say that no matter how dark things may seem in your story right now, there is always hope. You have not plotted yourself into a corner. Give it time, and the solution will dawn upon you.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for your characters &#8211; <i>Judgement (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">Judgement is a biblical card, with the weight of not just the judgement of others, but the judgement of the gods. When this card arrives, there is a moment of reckoning and an ending on the rise, and this applies no less to your characters than it applies to you.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">If the Judgement card is here for your characters, it is likely that they are being held to account by your story. This might something that you have planned and orchestrated within the story structure, or it may be that your characters are being judged by readers. In either case, since the card is reversed, your characters are being found wanting. When reversed, Judgement means that there is doubt in the air, that the understanding of what is right and wrong is no longer clear to you.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">As a writer, you need to believe in yourself in this moment. Do not allow yourself to doubt yourself or your portrayal of your characters. Do not allow yourself to doubt the work that you have done with them, or their quality as pieces of your story. In this moment, you must be careful not to let your characters lapse into flatness because you are afraid to make them a little strange. Trust your instincts and trust the advice of others. Go for it with your characters, so that no matter how others judge them, you can be proud.</p>
<p class="p1">A card for unforeseen circumstances &#8211; <i>Six of Pentacles</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Six of Pentacles is a card for giving, and for receiving. Traditionally, it shows a wealthy person is rich robes, handing out coins to beggars to kneel and beg. This card uses symbols for equality and fairness, and it is a cyclical card, because there are times in life when we are wealthy enough to give, and other times when we receive what others have shared with us.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Since this card has come as a part of “unforeseen circumstances”, it is likely that you will received an unexpected opportunity with regard to your writing soon. You may receive unexpected free time that you can use to writer, or a scholarship to a writing course that you have been pursuing. Maybe you will receive a moment of inspiration that carries you through the end of your latest story in a flash, leaving you awed that you could do it all so quickly.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Whatever kind of bounty comes to you, writer, don’t forget that to receive is just a part of the cycle of things, and that you should consider ways to give back to others as well. You will be in a position to be generous, soon. Do not forget that your largesse comes from others, and that you have the ability to share your wealth. Give back. Share your ideas. Host a writing party. Spread the joy.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for the wider world &#8211; <i>Six of Cups (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Six of Cups is a card of nostalgia and looking back. It shows a young child offering flowers to another, and that second child reaching up happily to receive them. The children work together, and they are in their own, joyful world, heedless of the adult world around them. They are not burdened by worries or fear. They are content with each other.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In the context of the “wider world”, the Six of Cards is here to remind us that though the world will always been challenging and often scary, this is a season for reveling in the joys of childhood once again. But since this card is reversed, it also reminds us not to get lost in those memories. This is the time of year that reminds many of us of being young and playful, without a care in the world, but we cannot idealize that time and forget all else. We want to reflect on the past in order to find paths to joy, and we need to find new ways to be joyful and playful in the present. The Six of Cards reminds us that we are adults, and though our joys may be different from what they were when we were children, they are not less meaningful and important. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28705 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-1-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="557" height="371" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-1-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 557px) 100vw, 557px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Ann Langley writes speculative fiction and wild poetry, and can be found on twitter @<a href="https://twitter.com/ann_elangley">ann_elangley</a> for general chatting and hanging out purposes. She used the Pagan Otherworlds Tarot Deck for this reading, which can be found <a href="https://uusi.us/collections/uusi-tarot/products/pagan-otherworlds-tarot">here</a></i><i>.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hold yourself to a high standard&#8230; and be ready to face up to your story.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hold-yourself-to-a-high-standard-and-be-ready-to-face-up-to-your-story/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 16:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Story Mystic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I draw five cards focused&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><i>Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I draw five cards focused on the art of writing. What do the cards have in store for us? What writing challenges will the next month bring? Let’s find out!</i></p>
<p class="p1">A general card for writers right now &#8211; <i>Judgement</i></p>
<p class="p1">The time has come, writers. The Judgement card has come, and while this card may appear strict and forbidding, it is really a reminder of the rules and strictures that govern our lives each day. When Judgement comes, it is a sign that something (whether a higher power or our own inner moral compasses) is looking critically at our work and weighing it meaningfully. What will Judgement find wanting?</p>
<p class="p1">Seen through the lens of our writing, the Judgement card calls for us to look more closely at the work we are creating and our ethos for writing. What is the purpose of the story we are working on telling? Are we telling stories that have deep meaning to ourselves, and possibly to others? Or are we working on a story that has lost all meaning and begun to fall flat? What are the ways in which we have become lazy and rushed in our work? How can we push ourselves to be our best? Look at your work and think about the ultimate meaning that it holds for you. Is this a story about family? Love? Fate? Whatever your story is really about, it is important and good. Be a critical writer this month. Check in with your story and weigh whether it tells the story that you really want it to tell, or whether it has gone off course. Make sure you are holding yourself to a high standard, and push yourself to do your best.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-28570 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/elena-mozhvilo-j06gLuKK0GM-unsplash-244x300.jpg" alt="" width="398" height="489" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/elena-mozhvilo-j06gLuKK0GM-unsplash-244x300.jpg 244w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/elena-mozhvilo-j06gLuKK0GM-unsplash-831x1024.jpg 831w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/elena-mozhvilo-j06gLuKK0GM-unsplash-768x946.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/elena-mozhvilo-j06gLuKK0GM-unsplash-1247x1536.jpg 1247w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/elena-mozhvilo-j06gLuKK0GM-unsplash-1662x2048.jpg 1662w" sizes="(max-width: 398px) 100vw, 398px" /></p>
<p class="p1">A card for your plot &#8211; <i>Six of Swords (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Six of Swords is a card for journeys, and a card of change. How appropriate when it comes to the idea of plot! When the Six of Swords comes, it symbolizes that change is in progress—and change is not always the easiest of processes. In this case, as the card is reversed, it may show that there is resistance to change, and a certain stubbornness clinging to the situation. You may be making the best of a bad situation, and working hard to salvage something that is not going the way you want.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In terms of plot, there is always change going on. Plot itself is the act of change, after all. But this month, you may find yourself (or your characters), resisting the change that the story has planned for them. They may not want to change, and are stubbornly trying to remain as they were, fighting you as you try to write. You may even be resisting the change yourself. Maybe you had an idea for your plot that is no longer working, and yet you are loathe to change course. Whatever the change is in your story, know that it is a good thing. Change signals progress. The Six of Swords shows us that change can bring good things. Do not be afraid of shifting the course of your story and changing up the plot. Let your intuition guide you, and let go of that which might be holding you back.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for your characters &#8211; <i>The Devil (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">Wow, what an amazing card to draw! The Devil might seem terrifying, but it is not. This is not a devil of torment, but a creature of boundaries and limitations. The Devil shows us that there are things we hide within ourselves, things that are taboo and forbidden. These are the things we bind up, wrapping in layers of shame and condemnation; indulging our darker urges can bring great pain to ourselves and others, but it can also bring us great pleasure.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In this spread, The Devil is reversed for your characters. This is fantastic! This shows that we should be releasing the beliefs that limit us, allowing ourselves to explore the darker desires that lurk beneath the surface, and allowing our characters to do so, too. This also shows that we should be wary of deception in our characters — the lies they tell themselves, and the lies we tell ourselves about them. As you work on your story this month, let your characters indulge in some dark thoughts. Let them be selfish, and foolish, and sexual. Let them be all the things that make a person human. Do not try to censor your characters or restrain them. Let them act out and be terrible, and see where that takes you. It will be liberating for both them and for you, dear writer. Have fun.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for unforeseen circumstances &#8211; <i>Five of Pentacles</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Five of Pentacles is a card of challenges, writer. Challenges that will make you feel isolated and alone. It is a card for winter, and for being so wrapped up in the things that are happening to you that you cannot see the goodness that is around you.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This month, it seems that there will be some real challenges coming your way. Unexpected challenges that will set you back and make you doubt yourself. You may feel alone in your writing process, as if you are struggling against the very forces of nature itself. But even in that moment, the Five of Pentacles also tells us that there is hope ahead. All is not lost. So when you feel that you are alone, take a moment to breath and refocus. Do not wallow in self-pity or condemnation. Look up and take a step away from the problem. Breathe, and look around yourself for solutions. If it is social media that is causing the problem, get away from the internet for a bit. Take in the beauty of nature and the sound of the wind through the leaves, and breathe. If it is family troubles or financial troubles that plague you, do not forget the community of writers that is all around you. Reach out to your friends. Read a book that stirs your soul. The Five of Pentacles tells us that trouble will come, and it will be hard, but we are not alone.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for the wider world &#8211; <i>Death (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">Ah, the card we all dread. The Death card is here, carrying the weight of endings upon its bony back and grinning at us meaningfully. The Death card may sometimes feel terrible, and it is indeed inevitable, but it is not a negative card.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Death signifies change—the kind of change that comes to everything in its time. In the reversed position, Death tells us that we are entering a time of personal change and transition. There is an ending here, which may be difficult for us to accept, and it is an internal ending. You may find this month that something in your worldview is changing in a way that you never expected. The things you once valued may no longer hold as much importance to you. This may feel startling and frightening at first, but it is not a terrible thing. Because just as Death comes to us all, so does Rebirth. After Death comes a renewal.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Death card tells us not to be afraid of change, but to value it. It brings beautiful things in its wake, even if it seems frightening at the time.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-28571 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/matt-howard-A4iL43vunlY-unsplash-300x168.jpg" alt="" width="561" height="314" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/matt-howard-A4iL43vunlY-unsplash-300x168.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/matt-howard-A4iL43vunlY-unsplash-1024x575.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/matt-howard-A4iL43vunlY-unsplash-768x431.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/matt-howard-A4iL43vunlY-unsplash-1536x863.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/matt-howard-A4iL43vunlY-unsplash-2048x1150.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 561px) 100vw, 561px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Ann Langley writes speculative fiction and wild poetry, and can be found on twitter @<a href="https://twitter.com/ann_elangley">ann_elangley</a> for general chatting and hanging out purposes. She used the Pagan Otherworlds Tarot Deck for this reading, which can be found <a href="https://uusi.us/collections/uusi-tarot/products/pagan-otherworlds-tarot">here</a></i><i>.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Take a step back and check in&#8230; you are doing fine.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/take-a-step-back-and-check-in-you-are-doing-fine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Story Mystic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28368</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I draw five cards focused&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><i>Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I draw five cards focused on the art of writing. What do the cards have in store for us? What writing challenges will the next month bring? Let’s find out!</i></p>
<p> <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-28370 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/kristian-egelund-uaQvRXa8izg-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="536" height="804" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/kristian-egelund-uaQvRXa8izg-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/kristian-egelund-uaQvRXa8izg-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/kristian-egelund-uaQvRXa8izg-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/kristian-egelund-uaQvRXa8izg-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/kristian-egelund-uaQvRXa8izg-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/kristian-egelund-uaQvRXa8izg-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 536px) 100vw, 536px" /></p>
<p class="p1">A general card for writers right now &#8211; <i>Seven of Swords</i></p>
<p class="p1">As we move into the dog days of summer, when the heat of August starts to sink into our bones, the Seven of Swords is here for us as writers. This is a card of deception and strategic thinking. Secrets and lies are on the agenda. This may seem like a bad sign, but it does not have to be.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This card shows us that not all is as it seems. You must be thoughtful and methodical right now, writers. This may mean that an idea you thought was wonderful turns out to be false and flat. Or maybe you are entering into contract negotiations and need to be very clear and careful about what you say. You may have to lie about something right now—and that’s okay. There are times in life when we cannot be wholly honest with others. That is natural, and sometimes it is even a good thing. But if you are feeling anxious or fearful right now, and you think that lying is the only path forward, question that impulse. Why do you feel that way? What is driving you toward lying as the only option? Sometimes in life we lie (both to ourselves and others) because it is the easy path forward. Don’t give into that impulse without thinking. As writers, our jobs are to tell stories that are <i>true</i>, no matter how fantastical they seem.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Wherever you are in your process right now, the Seven of Swords tells us not to rush ahead. Don’t dive in without thinking and act on your first impulse. Slow down and consider your options carefully, so that you do not make a decision that will hurt yourself or others.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for your plot &#8211; <i>Three of Swords (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Three of Swords is a difficult card, symbolizing painful events in life, things that may damage you emotionally and physically. This card often comes to us when the world is a dangerous place, and our hearts are in danger of breaking. But the good thing is that this month the Three of Swords is reversed. This can turn its meaning inward, toward our inner lives, and it can shift the meaning away from damaging situations, and toward healing and forgiveness.</p>
<p class="p1">The Three of Swords in a reversed position refers to the ways we think about ourselves and our stories. We may feel tempted to give in to negative self-talk this month, telling ourselves that all our work has been for nothing, and our stories are terrible. This is not the time for that. We must have forgiveness for ourselves and our mistakes. We must be optimistic about what is to come.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In the context of plot, do not become bogged down in the details. Do not look back at what you have already written and critique it. Look ahead and keep going. You may also want to consider providing ways for your characters to reach a point of forgiveness and release as well. Consider what big events your plot may have in store for your characters—where is the opportunity for catharsis in the plotline? How will your character react when they reach that moment?<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for your characters &#8211; <i>Death</i></p>
<p class="p1">Okay, writers, don’t panic.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Death card has come for your characters, and it’s going to be okay. This does not mean that your characters have to die (unless you’re into that, and then you have the card’s blessing). No, the Death card shows us that all things must end. Death is a natural part of our experience of life, and this goes for the stories we tell as well as the people that surround us. It is a card of grief and mourning, of finishing things and letting them go. It is an ending, but it is not The End.</p>
<p class="p1">With regard to your characters, think carefully about their endings this month. Will they live, or will they die? How will their stories end? Do you need to excise a character from your draft because they are not working in this story? Does your character go through a change so profound that it is <i>as if</i> they have died? Consider not just a character’s journey, but how they are going to end up. Make sure that you are clear on your characters’ ends, and how those ends will resonate with the readers.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This card reminds us that we cannot just consider our characters in the moment. We have to think about those characters as on a journey of change, from beginning to end. Check in with your characters this month. Consider their endings. Make sure you understand them and why they are important.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">A card for unforeseen circumstances &#8211;<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span><i>The Star</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Star has come, and we are grateful for it. This is such an amazing, optimistic card! The Star connects us to ideas of faith and spirituality. It is a card of water, which flows with powerful inspiration and connection. In the card, a beautiful woman holds two chalices, collecting and pouring water out—both onto the earth and into a pond. By doing so, she represents replenishment and inspiration.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Things may have been hard and challenging in the last few months. The world has not been easy or hospitable lately, and this may have influenced your writing lately as well. The Star tells us that this is a time for us to replenish ourselves and our reserves. We have the strength and potential of water, able to change our shape and move through difficulty smoothly. Like water, we writers can reshape ourselves at will, and we can also reshape the world around us with just a little patience and time.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This month, tap into your beliefs in order to help you manage any unforeseen circumstances or surprises. Why do you write? What is the foundation for your writing practice? You will want to return to that in order to steady yourself. The Star is also a card for renewal, so know that this month may bring something positive your way, a circumstance that is unforeseen, but also reinvigorating.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28369 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/alfred-schrock-wfNm2fIgapI-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="575" height="383" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/alfred-schrock-wfNm2fIgapI-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/alfred-schrock-wfNm2fIgapI-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/alfred-schrock-wfNm2fIgapI-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/alfred-schrock-wfNm2fIgapI-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/alfred-schrock-wfNm2fIgapI-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 575px) 100vw, 575px" /></p>
<p class="p1">A card for the wider world &#8211; <i>Ten of Wands</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Ten of Wands tells us that you are full up this month. There is a lot going on in your world, and you are fighting to manage it all. This may be writing-related responsibilities, work responsibilities, or other kinds. Your plate is full, and you cannot take on more at the moment. The weight of the world is on your shoulders, and you are nearly overwhelmed. Your physical and emotional muscles are aching, and the thought of taking one more step forward is nearly too much for you. At least, that is how you feel.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Allow yourself to feel that way. Your writing is progressing and you are coming to important moments in your work. There is fulfillment in the process, no matter where you are as a writer—just dreaming up a story, to finishing a draft, to preparing to publish. You are balancing a lot right now, and you are on the edge of taking on too much. Do not push yourself to try anything huge, or put a new responsibility onto your plate right now.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Ten of Wands also tells us writers that we need to be critical of ourselves right now. Take a closer look at the responsibilities on your plate and the way the wider world influences you. Have you taken on too much? Are you trying to run a blog in addition to writing a novel, because it seems like that’s what everyone else is doing? Are you trying to write a story that includes seven different plotlines because your favorite author did so? Are other responsibilities piling up on your plate right now? Think critically about what you have to deal with right now, and what is essential. Can you put anything aside, even just temporarily? Can you scale back your big projects to allow yourself time and space to breathe? The Ten of Wands tells us that you are not quite overwhelmed yet, but you are very close, and you need to slow down.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Allow yourself to be satisfied with what you have already done. Keep going, and keep dreaming.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Ann Langley writes speculative fiction and wild poetry, and can be found on twitter @<a href="https://twitter.com/alangleyyy">alangleyyy</a> for general chatting and hanging out purposes. She used the Pagan Otherworlds Tarot Deck for this reading, which can be found <a href="https://uusi.us/collections/uusi-tarot/products/pagan-otherworlds-tarot">here</a></i><i>.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keep writing&#8230; you are creating something magical.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/keep-writing-you-are-creating-something-magical/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 12:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Story Mystic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I will draw five cards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28155 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/steven-kamenar-MMJx78V7xS8-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="556" height="417" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/steven-kamenar-MMJx78V7xS8-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/steven-kamenar-MMJx78V7xS8-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/steven-kamenar-MMJx78V7xS8-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/steven-kamenar-MMJx78V7xS8-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/steven-kamenar-MMJx78V7xS8-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 556px) 100vw, 556px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I will draw five cards focused on the art of writing. What do the cards have in store for us? What writing challenges will the next month bring? Let’s find out!</i></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A general card for writers right now</strong> &#8211; <i>Five of Cups (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Five of Cups is a hard card. And the world is hard right now, especially for us, women writers. Things may seem hopeless and grim. There has been great loss in the world, and the news has been grim. It is natural that we mourn for all that we dreamed up, and the things that have been taken from us.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">But the writing goes on, and this card is reversed. In this case, that is a very good thing! That means that while things have been hard, you are moving forward. We have lost much, and been very sad, but now it is time to build upon the foundation that has been laid. Our writing is a way to do that. Reversed, the Five of Cups is a card of slow and steady healing. As writers, we can use our stories to change the world. We must write what is important to us. Write to conjure power. And share your writing. Go ahead and burn all the bridges. Tell the story you need to tell. That is how you will empower yourself and all who stand with you.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for your plot</strong> &#8211; <i>Five of Wands</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Five of Wands is another challenging card. The card itself shows five wands all tangled together, getting in each other’s way and generally causing a mess. While the suit of wands aligns itself with inspiration and creativity, sometimes your creative impulses get in the way of each other. It may feel like nothing is going right for you right now, especially with regard to plotting.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The only good part of the Five of Wands is that the difficulties and “stuck” feeling you may have right now is not serious. These problems are all small things, and though the aggravation they may be causing is very real, they are not causing problems that will destroy your plot or your story. If you can stay the course through this moment, everything will sort itself out.</p>
<p class="p1">Right now, the solution for your plot is to play around. Take all those little ideas that seem to be getting in each other’s way and play around. Try one plotline, then another. Skip ahead and write a scene that brings you joy. Or go backward and rewrite that crucial scene that started it all. Play around with your ideas. They will work themselves out eventually, and all the problems will vanish.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for your characters</strong> &#8211; <i>Two of Pentacles (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Two of Pentacles is back! And this time, in the reversed position. As perviously discussed, this is a card of balance. When the Two of Pentacles comes, there is a lot going on in a particular aspect of your story and you need to work hard to get everything to balance itself out. You may feel that things are on the edge of spinning out of control, but this is just where the hard work comes in.</p>
<p class="p1">This month, the card shows up for your characters, and in the reversed position. This likely means that something is feeling out of balance for your characters. Maybe they are too much of one thing—your hero is too strong and without flaws, or your villain is too negative without any justification. You might also have the problem your character does not have a balancing element in the story. This could be another character that acts of a foil to your main, or a setting or plot problem that challenges them appropriately. You might not even realize it at first, but an imbalance in character can lead to problems with your story down the line. So take a moment to step back and examine your character. What are their strengths and flaws? Are they being challenged as they need to be? Take actions now, and early, to restore balance.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for unforeseen circumstances</strong> &#8211; <i>Eight of Pentacles (reversed)</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Eight of Pentacles is a card for minutiae, and a whole lot of it. This is the card for opening your inbox and finding three hundred new emails, for realizing that your short story has grown legs and turned into a novel, for the moment when you realize that you committed to teaching a writing seminar that you are completely unexcited about. This card symbolizes hard work, grueling work, and the kind of work that you are not enthusiastic about.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The goods news is that this is the kind of word that leads to mastery of a skill. It is not wasted work! But the bad news is that this card is reversed, meaning that your effort might feel like it is misdirected and leading to no good end.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Be wary of misdirections these days, writers. Do not let the world and its problems lead you astray. You are working are—<i>so hard</i>—and you are doing the kind of work that we need in the world. But you may find yourself getting off track. Maybe other work piles on and takes you away from your writing. Maybe you write a plotline that is thirty-thousand words long and suddenly realize that it led you nowhere. Keep checking in with your goals. Where do you want <i>yourself</i>, and <i>your story</i> to be in the end? Keep your eye on that goal so that you do not stray from the path.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for the wider world</strong> &#8211; <i>The Magician</i></p>
<p class="p1">This card is amazing. The Magician is the card of inspiration, of making the mystical and dreamy part of your like real. This means that you are in the right place at the right time. You are creating, and doing what the world needs. The world <i>needs</i> your story. You are making it happen.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">When this card shows up for you, be comforted. Know that you are doing the good work. You are creating something beautiful, which will enlighten the world and change it for the better. You are creating magic with your story, creating worlds for the readers to explore, and characters for them to fall in love with.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">You are also creating a story for yourself. Do not forget that you are the first and most important reader of your story, and you must love it more than anything else in the world in order to write it to the end.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Magician says: go forth and create. It’s going to be something magical.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28154 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/rhett-wesley-NQexDDK9P9w-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="489" height="326" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/rhett-wesley-NQexDDK9P9w-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/rhett-wesley-NQexDDK9P9w-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/rhett-wesley-NQexDDK9P9w-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/rhett-wesley-NQexDDK9P9w-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/rhett-wesley-NQexDDK9P9w-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 489px) 100vw, 489px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Ann Langley writes speculative fiction and wild poetry, and can be found on twitter @<a href="https://twitter.com/alangleyyy">alangleyyy</a> for general chatting and hanging out purposes. She used the Pagan Otherworlds Tarot Deck for this reading, which can be found <a href="https://uusi.us/collections/uusi-tarot/products/pagan-otherworlds-tarot">here</a></i><i>.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Look ahead, writers, and make a plan.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/look-ahead-writers-and-make-a-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Story Mystic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I will draw five cards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-27737 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ugne-vasyliute-Dag9cv89jb4-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="386" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ugne-vasyliute-Dag9cv89jb4-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ugne-vasyliute-Dag9cv89jb4-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ugne-vasyliute-Dag9cv89jb4-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ugne-vasyliute-Dag9cv89jb4-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ugne-vasyliute-Dag9cv89jb4-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I will draw five cards focused on the art of writing. What do the cards have in store for us? What writing challenges will the next month bring? Let’s find out!</i></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A general card for writers right now</strong> &#8211; <i>Two of Swords</i></p>
<p class="p1">Ah, crossed swords and a blindfold. You are at an impasse, and you need to do some soul-searching to figure out why and what the next steps may be to resolve this problem. The swords in this card are balanced, suggesting that you have many viable options in front of you right now. Each option seems correct, so you are stuck and don’t know which path to take.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This month, you might be struggling with your writing a bit. Swords represent logic, and this can often come into contrast with your emotional needs and desires. It may be that your writing is not flowing, and this is leaving you frustrated. The blindfold in this card shows that you may not be sure that you have all the information that you need.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Two of Swords signals that action is needed. You must take stock of your writing, your routines and the stories you are crafting, and be self-critical. What is working, and what isn’t? Have you been hesitating for any reason? Get in touch with your emotions and look inward. Flip a coin to help yourself decide between two options (your immediate relief or disappointment will help you uncover your <i>true</i> emotions). Meditate on the problem.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The right path forward is in front of you. You just need to trust your instincts.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for your plot</strong> &#8211; <i>King of Wands, reversed</i></p>
<p class="p1">The King of Wands holds power is his hands—a staff of power, a lion held captive, salamanders at his feet. This is all fire, new life, and boldness personified. He signifies being in command of your creativity and being filled with inspiration.</p>
<p class="p1">But the King of Wands has shown up reversed, which signals a shift in meaning. With regard to your plot, do not charge ahead blindly, doing whatever creative thing you dream up. You may be able to think of a thousand plot twists and convoluted structures to make your story feel more exciting, but those things will not always been the right choice. Do not reorder all the chapters of your story impulsively. Do not start adding dream sequences or time travel on a whim. If a writing partner or editor says that something is confusing, don’t ignore them. When you read a new book that inspires you, don’t throw aside everything else you have been creating to rewrite your own story.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">My biggest recommendation is to make a list. Keep a notepad on your desk, and fill it with your new, bold ideas as they come. Keep writing what you had planned, and don’t shake things up right now. As you move through the month, look back to your list and consider your big, new ideas. Do they still inspire you? If so, innovate away! But you will likely find that a lot of the ideas that seemed so great in the moment have since paled, and your original path through the story was the best one after all.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for your characters</strong> &#8211; <i>The Moon, reversed</i></p>
<p class="p1">This card has the moon high in the sky, full and shining. It is balanced above large towers of rock. Beneath, a dog and a wolf turn their faces up and howl. This is a card of mystery and dreaming, and not always the pleasant kind. This is the card of false illusions and fever dreams, and nightmares, too.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This card has taken the reversed position, signaling that you may not be entirely clear about your character’s intentions and motivations. Something about them is clouded to you, and still needs working out. This may be hindering your process through the story and making it feel like the characters are fighting you.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Look your characters right in the eye. Get some distance from them and examine them closely. Track the patterns of their behavior in the story. Consult with a writing partner to work out their motivations. Write down everything you know about them, or make a timeline. Dust off your plotting and planning, and look at your characters squarely. The solution is there, if only you can clear away the illusions cloud your mind’s eye.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for unforeseen circumstances</strong> &#8211; <i>Ace of Pentacles, reversed</i></p>
<p class="p1">This card shows a beautiful coin marked with a pentacle, being held up high. Surrounding this is a bounty of lush flowers blooming. This is the card of new opportunities and the first seeds of abundance. This card says that new and surprising things happen often, and one of those things may be coming for you!</p>
<p class="p1">This card has come in a reversed position, so these new opportunities may be hidden at first. Unforeseen circumstances may seem like setbacks at first. You may be unpleasantly surprised, or pulled away from your writing. Reversed, this card shows us that something is coming that you have not planned for. You will have to be patient with yourself and wait it out. With determination, the bountiful reward will come. Just give it time.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><strong>A card for the wider world</strong> &#8211; <i>Knight of Pentacles</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Knight of Pentacles has come! They carry a coin in their hand, seated upon a tall and powerful horse. They do not look ahead to what lies ahead, but down at the coin instead. They are thinking and considering what comes next. They take stock of their plans and what they know of the road ahead. When they spur their horse forward, they will be ready for anything.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Knight of Pentacles here suggests that you will need to have a clear plan of your path forward to make the progress you dream of. You might be able to do things impulsively, of course, but a plan of action will serve you well. This may mean that you should make a list of your priorities, including steps to get them done. You are being called upon to sit down and commit to the hard work that goes into crafting your story—every single chapter, sentence, and word of it. Commit, make a plan, and then go for it.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-27738" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/20220601_185055-300x170.jpg" alt="" width="462" height="262" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/20220601_185055-300x170.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/20220601_185055-1024x582.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/20220601_185055-768x436.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/20220601_185055-1536x873.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/20220601_185055-2048x1163.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 462px) 100vw, 462px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Ann Langley writes speculative fiction and wild poetry, and can be found on twitter @alangleyyy for general chatting and hanging out purposes. She used the Pagan Otherworlds Tarot Deck for this reading, which can be found <a href="https://uusi.us/collections/uusi-tarot/products/pagan-otherworlds-tarot">here</a></i><i>.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The cards say&#8230; go for it!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-cards-say-go-for-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Story Mystic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27410</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I will draw five cards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-27411 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/austin-chan-ukzHlkoz1IE-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="621" height="415" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/austin-chan-ukzHlkoz1IE-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/austin-chan-ukzHlkoz1IE-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/austin-chan-ukzHlkoz1IE-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/austin-chan-ukzHlkoz1IE-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/austin-chan-ukzHlkoz1IE-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 621px) 100vw, 621px" /></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Story Mystic is a new column for writers. Each month I will draw five cards focused on the art of writing. What do the cards have in store for us? What writing challenges will the next month bring? Let’s find out!</i></p>
<p class="p1"><b>A general card for writers right now — </b><i>Ace of Wands</i></p>
<p class="p1">Oh, writers, get ready! The Ace of Wands symbolizes new ideas and inspiration. You may just be starting a new project and are packed full of ideas, or maybe you have not yet developed that new story yet, but it’s coming! No matter what, know that newness is coming. This card does not just mean that inspiration is coming to you, but that the universe is giving you a big, positive green light for your ideas. Don’t be afraid to try something new. Have you been working on a novel but feel inspiration for a short story? Put the big story on hold and allow yourself a day or two to experiment. Have an idea for a plot twist? Give it a try! Introduce that new character! Add that dream sequence! Want to take up painting landscapes for a while? Sure! Go buy those canvases and paints! All of your ideas have promise and meaning right now. Nothing is a waste of time.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Crucially, the Ace of Wands does <i>not</i> mean that all your new ideas will work out. You may start something and fail badly. You may begin that new idea and find that it begins to feel dull to you after a week. That’s okay! The Ace of Wands just points you toward newness, knowing that trying new things is the best way to grow. Whether your new ideas lead you to success or not, know that it is not the end result that matters here—the most important thing is that you have the courage to begin, to take a step down that path of inspiration, and allow yourself that chance to grow.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">You may be feeling a lack of inspiration right now, however. This just means that the Ace of Wands is reversed for you. You may feel stagnant, stuck, or dull. You might be doubting your path as a writer. But don’t worry! Inspiration will return! Allow yourself this time to reflect on the old ideas you have had. Go back into your archives, or your story drawer, or trunk, or whatever you call it, and look at all the amazing things you have already crafted. Inspiration will return to you soon, when you least expect it. Just like a new card turning over.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><b><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-27412 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092124-191x300.jpg" alt="" width="281" height="441" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092124-191x300.jpg 191w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092124-768x1209.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092124-976x1536.jpg 976w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092124-1301x2048.jpg 1301w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092124-scaled.jpg 1626w" sizes="(max-width: 281px) 100vw, 281px" />A card for your plot — </b><i>Two of Pentacles</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Two of Pentacles is a card that connects with the idea of balance in all its forms. Balance is a beautiful and tenuous thing. It may often feel unsteady, like you are barely holding on. You need to constantly shift and change to keep everything working together.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">When this card is seen through the lens of plot, it means that you have a lot of plot threads going on. There is a lot of action, scheming characters, and twists and complications. This is a beautiful thing, as long as all remains in balance. But it may also feel that your plot is too much, and threatening to spin out of control. In that case, the Two of Pentacles emphasizes flexibility. You need to be creative and use all your skills and resources to keep this plot in balance. Trust yourself, reach out to friends, and know that you can do this. Eventually, all the pieces will come together in the way you wish, and it will be a wonderful thing.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><b>A card for your characters — </b><i>The Hierophant</i></p>
<p class="p1">The Hierophant is a powerful card, symbolizing both the power of teaching and learning. This card can sometimes be associated with academia and spirituality, particularly the powerful side of those realms. It connects to systems and structures of power in the world, and how those systems are built upon historical and (we hope) intellectual foundations.</p>
<p class="p1">In the context of character, this card means that you don’t always want to eschew the tried and true, the traditional path for your character and their path through the story. You may be trying to break the mold and try something new, which is very exciting! But don’t forget to consider the traditional path; there may be value in using a more usual character arc or plot device to get your character where they need to go.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">And also—don’t forget about your character’s past! Their background has shaped them and their choices, and your character’s past will be especially important to your character in the month to come!</p>
<p class="p1"><b>A card for unforeseen circumstances — </b><i>Eight of Wands</i></p>
<p class="p1">A card of energy, forward movement, and power. This is a card of fearlessness, the <i>let’s do this </i>card, the card of the moment when you just decide to give up your reservations and dive in, <i>fuck it all.</i></p>
<p class="p1">In the next month, it is likely that an unforeseen opportunity will come to you, or a wild idea about your story. This card is telling you to go for it. Don’t be frightened. Take that leap, try the new thing. Go ahead and kill off your main character suddenly; or if you’ve already done that, maybe resurrect them. Submit an application for the writer’s retreat or MFA program. Go for it! This is a gambling card, a card of chances. Don’t be afraid to take a risk. Fuck your hesitations and your worries, they don’t truly know you. The Eight of Wands knows: <i>you’ve got this.</i></p>
<p class="p1"><b>A card for the wider world </b>—<b> </b><i>Nine of Cups</i></p>
<p class="p1">Lucky you! The Nine of Cups is the card of wishes and dreaming. A card for fulfillment<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-27414 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092033-193x300.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="417" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092033-193x300.jpg 193w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092033-660x1024.jpg 660w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092033-768x1192.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092033-990x1536.jpg 990w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092033-1320x2048.jpg 1320w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/20220416_092033-scaled.jpg 1650w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /> and joy. You may have achieved something that you have been working toward materially—finishing a draft, completing your degree, finally sending out the draft that has been languishing. Or you may have reached a moment of internal achievement, and have finally figured out the answer to that character/plot problem that has been languishing.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">No matter what, the world is allowing you a moment to breathe. This is your signal to look back on all the amazing things that you have already accomplished and throw yourself a party. The wider world itself believes in you. You have worked hard and achieved so much. You can give yourself a pat on the back, celebrate with a writers&#8217; group, or share your draft with someone else at last. Look at the way you have balanced your passion for writing with the rigors of life in their world. Take a breath and indulge a bit. The Nine of Cups says that the world wants you to throw yourself a party, knowing that you have worked hard to get to this moment.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><i>Ann Langley writes speculative fiction and wild poetry, and can be found on twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/alangleyyy">@alangleyyy</a> for general chatting and hanging out purposes. She used the Pagan Otherworlds Tarot Deck for this reading, which can be found <a href="https://uusi.us/collections/uusi-tarot/products/pagan-otherworlds-tarot">here</a>.</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
