<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Favorite Female Characters &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/favorite-female-characters/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:03:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Favorite Female Characters: Pippi Longstocking</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/favorite-female-characters-pippi-longstocking/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8272</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I dressed up as Pippi Longstocking for Purim as a junior in high school,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/index-5.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8273 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/index-5.jpg" alt="" width="136" height="236" /></a>When I dressed up as Pippi Longstocking for Purim as a junior in high school, I knew I had discovered something special. And it wasn&#8217;t just in the thrill of wearing mismatched knee-high socks.</p>
<p>Pippi Longstocking, created by Swedish author Astrid Lindgren, provided a new definition of female strength. A sea-captain&#8217;s daughter, Pippi and her father get caught in a storm and her father goes overboard. Pippi waits for her father&#8217;s return at her home: Villa Villekulla (pronounced Villa Villa Coola). She lives with her monkey and her horse, but without adults.</p>
<p>I grew up fascinated by the animated movie (1997) where this red haired child knew no social constraints, lived life shouting with joy, had the strength to <em>pick up her horse </em>(literally. She has unexplained super strength.) and all the while remained at heart a vulnerable child. As a junior in high school, my heroes were the muscled men of Dragon Ball Z. I desired the gritty, physical strength of beating an opponent. But rekindling my childhood love of Pippi reminded me that strength does not lie in conquering others. When I stumbled upon my childhood favorite film, I rediscovered that women could be both physically and mentally strong without having to prove it through physical violence.</p>
<p>Pippi lives each day as an adventure she doesn&#8217;t plan to miss. In the opening to the film, she sings, &#8220;I am the sea and nobody owns me.&#8221; Before I would even begin to call myself a feminist, I was writing this phrase again and again as a mantra into my journal: <em>nobody owns me. </em>What could be more feminist than claiming ownership over your actions and desires? What better lesson can we teach young girls?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a7m4vPcfeOE">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a7m4vPcfeOE</a></p>
<p>Pippi is magic. She has no love interest. She is not a child version of a manic-pixie-dream-girl. Her joy and her exuberance is for her. But what further strikes me is that the film knows Pippi cannot be joyous one-hundred percent of the time. Particularly in the quiet moments at night, waiting for her father&#8217;s return, I love her all the more. She has hope that her father survived. She has hope that all loneliness can be conquered. At her core, Pippi holds strength and vulnerability.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Favorite Female Character: Adelaide Stratton (Houdini and Doyle)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/favorite-female-character-adelaide-stratton-houdini-and-doyle/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 17:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m trying desperately to enjoy last year&#8217;s television series Houdini &#38; Doyle (2016). Houdini &#38;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="left-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/index.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-8215 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/index.jpg" width="225" height="225" /></a>I&#8217;m trying desperately to enjoy last year&#8217;s television series Houdini<em> &amp; Doyle </em>(2016). <em>Houdini &amp; Doyle </em>crosses Victorian mystery with the X-Files, when Houdini (a skeptic) and Doyle (a spiritualist) set out to solve seemingly supernatural crimes. Adelaide Stratton, the first female constable of Scotland Yard, accompanies the duo on their adventures.</p>
<p>The show has some historical truth: Harry Houdini and Sir Arthur Conan Doyle were, in fact <a href="http://www.wildabouthoudini.com/2016/04/the-real-story-of-houdini-doyle.html">friends and contemporaries</a>. The two were fans of each other&#8217;s work and met in London in 1920 during one of Houdini&#8217;s European tours. Houdini <em>was</em> a skeptic (but with far more nuance than the show portrays&#8211;he had a collection of books on spiritualism and later in life attended seances in disguise and gave lectures disproving mystics and mediums, eventually waging a war against the spiritualist community) and Doyle <em>was</em> a spiritualist.</p>
<p>Adelaide Stratton (Rebecca Liddiard) did not exist. Or at least, not in 1901, when the show takes place (the first female constable did not appear on the scene until 1915). Adelaide has been hailed even by critics of the show as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mzi8CNtfv0w">&#8220;the best part of the series.&#8221; </a>I agree.</p>
<p>Even when I find myself shaking my head and proclaiming &#8220;Houdini wouldn&#8217;t do/say that!&#8221; and find myself cringing at all the missed opportunities in creating a dynamic character for Doyle, Adelaide holds my attention to the last. And here&#8217;s why:</p>
<p><strong>She has the most to lose. </strong>Until assigned to assist Houdini and Doyle, Adelaide had been stuck in the basement filing and making coffee. Solving these cases, no matter whether the outcome proves scientific or supernatural, is not about proving either side of the equation correct, but about <em>proving herself. </em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe title="One of the many wonders of the new century" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l3wP4N4jlj0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><strong>She&#8217;s practical and professional. </strong>While Houdini and Doyle polarize themselves, Adelaide understands that the police work comes first. <em>All</em> egos aside. And she deals with a lot of egos, while traveling with these two celebrities. The earlier episodes ship Adelaide and Houdini, with Houdini as the big flirt (<em>Houdini &amp; Doyle </em>wrote out Bess Houdini&#8211;Harry&#8217;s wife&#8211;a mistake I will never be ready to forgive). Adelaide will have none of Houdini&#8217;s flirting. She does her job with professionalism and an eye for the practical that keeps the story moving forwards.</p>
<p><strong>She reveals her past as she deems fit.</strong> Despite Houdini&#8217;s pestering her with questions, she reveals her past on her terms. She does not cave under pressure and is just as firm in her beliefs as both Houdini and Doyle. One of my favorite pieces of Liddiard&#8217;s portrayal of Adelaide is the way she consistently makes eye contact.</p>
<p>Even if you are not a Houdini or Doyle fan, Adelaide is well worth watching this 10 episode series.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Favorite Female Characters: Blake Belladonna (RWBY)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/favorite-female-characters-blake-belladonna-rwby/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 17:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8170</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It didn&#8217;t take much time watching RWBY, for Blake Belladonna to win my heart. Though&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It didn&#8217;t take much time watching <a href="http://roosterteeth.com/show/rwby">RWBY</a>, for <a href="http://rwby.wikia.com/wiki/Blake_Belladonna">Blake Belladonna</a> to win my heart. Though every female character in the Rooster Teeth web-series RWBY will land a spot on my Favorite Female Characters list, Blake had to be the first I explore more in depth.</p>
<p>Her character arc in season 1 was the first hint for me that this would be a series which brought the fun of fantasy and adventure stories, but did not ignore that fantasy is a perfect genre for tackling real world issues.</p>
<p>Blake is a Faunus. In the World of Remnant, the Faunus are half-human half-animal. Full-humans treat them no better than animals, and created a hierarchy with the Faunus at the bottom. Blake comes from this under-class and like many people from minority backgrounds in the real world, hides her identity in order to fit in. She can <em>pass </em>as Full-Human with the help of black bow to cover her cat ears.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/index-5.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8171" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/index-5.jpg" width="400" height="223" /></a>But that&#8217;s not the only thing Blake is hiding. She had been a member of the radical Faunus group The White Fang. The White Fang morphed from an organization intent on gaining equal rights for the Faunus, into a militant terrorist group. Through Blake&#8217;s character development, RWBY addresses contemporary issues of racial discrimination, militant tactics and terrorism.</p>
<p>As an undergraduate student I studied contemporary Turkish political history (roughly 1960s to the present) and grew fascinated by radical politics and eventually <a href="http://thekurdishproject.org/history-and-culture/kurdish-nationalism/">the Kurdish movement</a> within Kurdistan (southeast Turkey). Blake&#8217;s involvement in the White Fang became a direct correlation to my research interests. But her struggle to find a balance between fighting for equality and fighting through violence alone, could just as easily be compared to the struggles of the Black Lives Matter Movement, the fight for Palestinian rights, the fight against Islamophobia and many other social and political movements going on today.</p>
<p>To fight prejudice, do you put on a bow, try to become respectable and forget your past? Do you pick up a gun and take to the streets? Do you pick up a sign and take to the streets? RWBY does not advocate violence and terrorism, but reminds viewers why someone would be tempted toward those methods in the first place.</p>
<p>I love how Blake never becomes a political statement for the show&#8217;s writers and creators, but that politics is interwoven into her character.</p>
<p>Easily, Blake became my favorite of the main heroines (Ruby, Weiss, Blake, Yang). Yes, I could relate her struggle to my academic interests, but I could also just relate to her.</p>
<p>Team RWBY begins a hunt for Roman Torchwick, a criminal working with the White Fang. Blake pushes herself and pushes herself, losing sleep, letting her grades drop, abandoning her friends, because <strong>all that matters is the End Goal</strong>. As a writer I understand that drive. The feeling that nothing else matters other than your work, and the pressure and intensity that comes with taking yourself too seriously. She is a woman who refuses to stop. Yet, through her friends (and *cough* her female romantic interest Yang) learns to slow down.</p>
<p>Through Blake, we too can learn to slow down and take time for the ones we love.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Favorite Female Character: Celia Bowen (The Night Circus)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/favorite-female-character-celia-bowen-the-night-circus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 17:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a first for me: a favorite female character out of a book I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a first for me: a favorite female character out of a book I did not enjoy. <em>The Night Circus</em> (2011) by Erin Morgenstern, is a fantasy romance. Two magicians pit their students against each other in a game of competing schools of magic. The Circus becomes the arena as the two students&#8211;Celia and Marco&#8211;struggle to understand the game they&#8217;re forced to play and the rules which will determine who wins and survives. But as they compete, the two fall in love and must determine how to stop the game, at all costs.</p>
<p>I would rather have skipped <em>The Night Circus </em>to be honest (review to come), but I will at least have Celia Bowen as a bright spot from an otherwise dull reading experience.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/index-1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8004 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/index-1.jpg" width="181" height="279" /></a>Celia is an illusionist, with the power to manipulate matter around her. She can change the color of her dress, but also heal her broken bones and stitch up cuts in her skin. Her father and teacher, Hector Bowen, taught her magic through experience: when she was a child, he would cut her fingers open only for her to pull herself back together as a test of her skill. But even in an abusive, loveless relationship with her father, she pulls through as a character willing to love others.</p>
<p>She develops friendships with Isobel (set up as her romantic rival with Marco&#8211;but don&#8217;t worry, it&#8217;s not a love triangle), showing that women can be friends with other women. Her friendship with Herr Theissen, a clock maker, shows that women can be friends with men without the relationship turning romantic or sexual. Finally, she takes on the role of mentor and teacher to young twins who are born into the circus. Celia does not let her past trauma with her father, stop her from reaching out to the next generation of magicians to be the teacher her father was not.</p>
<p>Yet, it took me most of the book to appreciate Celia. Partly because I was frustrated with Morgenstern&#8217;s continuous use of passive voice to create mystery, but also because we always learn information at the last minute in this novel. Only when I knew that (SPOILER) Celia was controlling the Circus&#8211;using her mind to keep every tent and magical feat real and tangible&#8211;did I understand her. She&#8217;s a character who can&#8217;t relax or take a breath because she <em>is </em>the circus. Her control over her mind is immense and it is also her greatest weakness.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8216;I&#8217;m tired of trying to hold things together that cannot be held. Trying to control what cannot be controlled. I am tired of denying myself what I want for fear of breaking things I cannot fix. They will break no matter what I do.&#8217; &#8211; Celia Bowen, <em>The Night Circus </em></p></blockquote>
<p>I&#8217;m thrilled to see a female character with such complexities to her strengths and flaws. While I do not recommend <em>The Night Circus, </em>maybe there&#8217;s some good Celia Bowen fanfic out there to try. If you know of any good Celia stories, let me know! I&#8217;d love to read more about this illusionist.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Favorite Female Characters: RWBY</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/favorite-female-characters-rwby/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 17:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; The web series RWBY&#8211;produced by Rooster Teeth Animation in Austin, TX&#8211;has become my new&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_7925" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7925" style="width: 1280px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2013912-1444945741002-RWBY-Vol3-OpeningAnimation.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-7925 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/2013912-1444945741002-RWBY-Vol3-OpeningAnimation.png" width="1280" height="720" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7925" class="wp-caption-text">Team RWBY (from Left to Right) Ruby, Weiss, Blake, Yang.</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The web series RWBY&#8211;produced by <a href="https://roosterteeth.com/show/rt-animated-adventures">Rooster Teeth Animation</a> in Austin, TX&#8211;has become my new favorite feminist cartoon. <a href="http://rwby.wikia.com/wiki/Thread:10517">Vaguely based on fairy tales</a>, the show takes place in the world of Remnant where young people aspire to be Huntresses and Huntsmen to protect their world from the creatures of Grimm. The series beings when Ruby Rose&#8211;an energetic, optimistic weapons enthusiast&#8211;skips a few grades and gets accepted to Beacon Academy, one of the premier schools for Huntresses. She joins her older sister Yang and together with Weiss and Blake, form Team RWBY (Ruby, Weiss, Blake, Yang).</p>
<p>So many female characters! The entire main team is women and that&#8217;s unheard of, especially in a genre that deals heavily with ridiculous battle sequences and futuristic weapons&#8211;Ruby designed her own sniper-scythe.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dsy7VJheMBI">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dsy7VJheMBI</a></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been describing this show to my friends as the fun of <em>Teen Titans</em> with the action of <em>Dragon Ball Z</em>. I know I&#8217;ll get flack for this, but it&#8217;s <em>a better Harry Potter. </em>Seriously. It&#8217;s a feel-good show, and while the episodes definitely take a darker turn in Seasons 3 and 4 (season 4 is currently in the being released via <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/RoosterTeeth">Rooster Teeth&#8217;s youtube channel</a>, as well as on their <a href="http://roosterteeth.com/show/rwby">website</a>), you root for these female characters because they are loveable and energized in a way only cartoons can be.</p>
<p>A few key highlights:</p>
<p><strong>Women are fighters no questions asked. </strong>Monty Oum, the creator of the show, drops you into the world where women are just as capable as men to fight the creatures of Grimm. In this way, it&#8217;s a bit of a utopia&#8211;if only in that women are not banging their heads against the wall to be seen as equals. The show later provides world building background about women fighters, but even without that additional information, women fight and that&#8217;s part of the world.</p>
<p><strong>There is no toxic masculinity*. </strong>This is an action show, but no matter how the characters give and take hits , it&#8217;s good guys v. bad guys, not about conquering your opponent to prove you&#8217;re top dog. Also, the main male characters don&#8217;t talk down to, insult or sexually harass women. It&#8217;s great. Oh, and, occasional cross-dressing and it&#8217;s not played off strictly as a joke.</p>
<p>*caveat, Cardin and his team that bullies Jaune is toxic masculinity, but viewers are meant to see Cardin et al as bad guys who deserve to be put in their place</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="RWBY Volume 2 Dance Scene" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/99dVb6Wu_aI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><strong>So much queer fodder! </strong>Out of the main young characters, 6 out of 8 are female (Ruby, Weiss, Blake, Yang, Pyrrha, Nora). All 4 main heroes are female! So, Blake x Yang and Ruby x Weiss (though nothing confirmed yet).</p>
<p>My main critique: <strong>we need more people of color. </strong>While the show highlights people of color in nearly every crowd scene, as well as featuring people of color in supporting roles, we need more heroes of color. Blake is potentially coded as a woman of color, but that is not enough.</p>
<p>RWBY is not a paragon for diversity or intersectional feminism, but it brings fun back to fantasy. The world is dangerous and unfair, but there are heroes who will defend it nonetheless.</p>
<p>You can watch the first two seasons of RWBY on Netflix, or seasons 1-4 on youtube.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women Who Say No</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/women-who-say-no/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 17:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7530</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Remember remember the fifth of November, the gun powder treason and plot. I know of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>&#8220;Remember remember the fifth of November, the gun powder treason and plot. I know of no reason why the gun powder treason should ever be forgot.&#8221; <em>V for Vendetta </em></p></blockquote>
<p>The film <em>V for Vendetta </em>(2005), based off Alan Moore&#8217;s graphic novel, opens with Evey Hammond&#8217;s voice-over. When she explains how Guy Fawkes attempted to blow up the British Parliament in 1605, she ends, &#8220;it is not an idea that I miss, it is a man&#8230; A man that made me remember the Fifth of November. A man that I will never forget.&#8221;</p>
<p>But Evey is the character I will never forget. She was one of my first fictional heroines who stood her ground and said <em>no.  </em>More importantly, she was not killed, raped or otherwise abused for her defiance. Because unfortunately, that is the reality for many women who say, no&#8211;especially to unwanted sexual advances. The tumblr <a href="http://whenwomenrefuse.tumblr.com/">When Women Refuse</a> documents these real stories of violence against women. Seeing fiction where women say <em>no, </em>stand up for their beliefs and defy oppressors of any gender, is necessary for women to stand up in real life, even when the consequences can be terrifying. We need female heroes who say no and live to tell about it.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a list of 3 Defiant Fictional Women.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7535" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7535" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Natalie-Portman-as-Evey-Hammond.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-7535 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Natalie-Portman-as-Evey-Hammond-300x241.jpg" alt="Natalie Portman as Evey Hammond" width="300" height="241" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7535" class="wp-caption-text">Natalie Portman as Evey Hammond</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Evey Hammond </strong>(V for Vendetta) *Though I have read the graphic novel, I&#8217;ll discuss the film version in this post</p>
<p>The defining moment of Evey&#8217;s character is when she&#8217;s imprisoned, tortured and still refuses to cooperate and provide the government with information on V. Her values are more important than her life.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Defining quote:</strong></p>
<p><i>Guard</i>: Look, all they want is one little piece of information. Just give them something&#8230; anything.<br />
<i>Evey Hammond</i>: Thank you &#8230; but I&#8217;d rather die behind the chemical sheds.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Esmeralda </strong>(Hunchback of Notre Dame) *Disney movie</p>
<p>Almost immediately after we are introduced to Esmeralda as the sexy, feisty dancer on stage, she proves herself to be so much more than her sexuality. She openly defies Judge Claude Frollo (literally, the law) and rescues the hero, Quasimodo, from public humiliation and torture. As a Romani woman, justice for her people cannot be achieved until there is justice for all. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/large.gif"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-7534 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/large.gif" alt="large" width="245" height="245" /></a></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Defining moment:</strong></p>
<p><strong><i>Frollo</i>: </strong>You, Gypsy girl! Get down at once!<strong><br />
<i>Esmeralda</i>: </strong>Yes, Your Honor. Just as soon as I free this poor creature.<strong><br />
<i>Frollo</i>: </strong>I forbid it!<strong><br />
</strong>[<i>Esmeralda cuts the ropes tying Quasimodo to the wheel</i>]<strong><br />
<i>Frollo</i>: </strong>How dare you defy me?<strong><br />
<i>Esmeralda</i>: </strong>You mistreat this poor boy the same way you mistreat my people. You speak of justice, yet you are cruel to those most in need of your help!<strong><br />
<i>Frollo</i>: </strong>Silence!<strong><br />
<i>Esmeralda</i>: </strong>Justice!</p></blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/69c2c4a2e76c44e10480ea00e330aeb8.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7533 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/69c2c4a2e76c44e10480ea00e330aeb8-300x238.jpg" alt="69c2c4a2e76c44e10480ea00e330aeb8" width="300" height="238" /></a>Terra </strong>(Teen Titans)*cartoon</p>
<p>A hero who can&#8217;t control her Earth powers, Terra becomes the apprentice to the villain Slade and infiltrates the Teen Titans team with the sole purpose of betraying them. In the finale episode, &#8220;Aftershock Part II&#8221;, Slade has taken control of her body and her powers. There&#8217;s never been a more feminist and empowering fight for a young girl to (literally) take back her body and claim control of her life. When she fights against his control this is her kick-ass moment:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Defining quote: </strong></p>
<p><strong>Terra:</strong> You can&#8217;t control me anymore!</p></blockquote>
<p>The more examples of these fictional women we have, the more women in real life can stand with the same confidence because we&#8217;ve seen it&#8217;s possible to say <em>no </em>and survive. What other fictional female women can you think of who stand up, stand tall and tell the world <em>no</em> ?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women Writing Men</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/women-writing-men/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 16:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even though my year of reading books by women ended in May, it continues to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Even though my<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/raw-milk-reading-list-read-books-women-year/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> year of reading books by women</a> ended in May, it continues to shape which authors I read. But it&#8217;s more than reading books by women, it&#8217;s reading books with challenging and intricate female protagonists. As I explored in a <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/where-are-the-women-the-importance-of-female-protagonists/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">previous post</a>, there is a gender gap not just in the gender of the author, but in the gender of the protagonist. Women&#8217;s stories must matter.</p>
<p>My older brother once told me that I was not like other girl authors because I could write convincing male characters. This was a source of pride: I had the approval of a male audience. Somehow, I had become the exception to my gender; <em>I had made it. </em>I attended a women&#8217;s college and for my first creative writing class, I was determined to write a script about a male character, mainly to prove I was still a writer who could write across gender.  I, again, took pride in writing male characters and not being a <em>girl author. </em>In my personal writing journey, I tried every path to escape being a writer defined by womanhood.</p>
<p>Playwright Camilla Whitehill&#8217;s one-man show <em>Mr. Incredible (</em>2016) is a play about male entitlement, starring a male actor. In <a href="http://exeuntmagazine.com/features/writing-different-gender/">an article for </a><em>Exeunt, </em>she tells the story of how after the show, a  male actor she&#8217;d never met, &#8220;wanted to let me know that I had written a male character really well – for a woman.&#8221; Women are expected to write about women&#8211;not under the assumption that all female writers are feminists&#8211;but under the assumption that women&#8217;s writing is <em>for women. </em>That women&#8217;s writing is about women and therefore these stories are limited and alienating to a male audience (the only audience that matters). That&#8217;s a vicious cycle. Women can&#8217;t write about men without either being praised as the exception or criticized for a poor portrayal. But women can&#8217;t write about women without being shoved aside as authors of <em>chick lit. </em></p>
<figure id="attachment_7453" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7453" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/bea5781bb2e0bbc43fc3c1159028c4ee.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-7453 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/bea5781bb2e0bbc43fc3c1159028c4ee-300x300.jpg" alt="Genderbent Han Solo and Princess Leia at Emerald City Comic Con. cccakery.tumblr.com" width="300" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7453" class="wp-caption-text">Genderbent Han Solo and Princess Leia at Emerald City Comic Con. cccakery.tumblr.com</figcaption></figure>
<p>Whitehill raises similar concerns about her work: &#8220;the play doesn’t match the criteria for “all-female theatre” lists. It doesn’t pass the Bechdel Test. You can’t say it’s “female-driven drama”.&#8221;  But that doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s not feminist.</p>
<p>As Roxane Gay says in her collection of essays, <em>Bad Feminist (</em>2014<em>), “</em>We don’t all have to believe in the same feminism. Feminism can be pluralistic so long as we respect the different feminisms we carry with us, so long as we give enough of a damn to try to minimize the fractures among us.”</p>
<p>So, how can you best support female authors and feminism no matter the gender of an author&#8217;s characters?</p>
<ol>
<li>Don&#8217;t limit female authors to only write about female characters. Don&#8217;t shame (or praise) them for writing male characters.</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t limit yourself to only write about female characters. Don&#8217;t shame (or praise) yourself for writing male characters.</li>
<li>Love&#8211;publicly love!&#8211;your favorite female characters! Let the world know which women inspire you each day.</li>
<li>Cosplay! Halloween is a great excuse to dress up as an awesome female character.</li>
<li>Genderbend cosplay (but don&#8217;t appropriate a character&#8217;s race, please!)! Who says we can&#8217;t have a female Han Solo? Or maybe an agender Kamala Khan?</li>
</ol>
<p>What other ways can you think of to best support female authors?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Favorite Female Characters: Miss Martian</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/favorite-female-characters-miss-martian/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 15:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Miss Martian and I were hurtling toward a collision. She was the perky, popular cheerleader&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Miss Martian and I were hurtling toward a collision. She was the perky, popular cheerleader all freckled and dimpled and trying so hard to be adorable. And if she bonked herself on the head, with her little&#8221;Hello, Megan!&#8221; <em>one more time, </em>I was ready to bonk her in the head myself.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Miss-Martian-Young-Justice-Animated-Series.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7383 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Miss-Martian-Young-Justice-Animated-Series-121x300.jpg" alt="Miss Martian's Green Martian form" width="121" height="300" /></a>Miss Martian AKA Megan Morse (real name M&#8217;gann M&#8217;orzz) was my least favorite character in the superhero cartoon <em>Young Justice  </em>(2010-2013). The show is a more serious and complicated cartoon drama about the teenage heroes commonly associated with their Justice League counterparts. The initial team includes: Robin (Dick Grayson), Kid Flash (Wally West), Miss Martian, Aqualad, Artemis, and Superboy.</p>
<p>Miss Martian is Martian Manhunter&#8217;s niece. She is a martian. Her powers are pretty incredible and almost limitless: flight, shape shifting, telepathy, telekinesis, camouflage (basically invisibility), and density shifting (intangibility-she can pass through objects/objects can pass through her). <em>And</em> she was my least favorite character.</p>
<p>While she wasn&#8217;t the only woman on the team (Artemis being the second), she was treated as <em>the woman </em>on the team. She was the girly one in skirts and dresses, the more feminine one with her soft spoken voice. She was the one Wally would incessantly flirt with (though he winds up with Artemis later in the series). Miss Martian was every other <em>girl</em> hero I had suffered through watching before. I didn&#8217;t want another <em>girl hero </em>I wanted a hero who happened to be a girl. It was as if the creators wanted Miss Martian to be a walking stereotype.</p>
<p>It turns out, they did.</p>
<p>Everything I couldn&#8217;t tolerate about Miss Martian was a deliberate choice by her character. Growing up on Mars, Miss Martian was discriminated against as a <a href="http://dc.wikia.com/wiki/White_Martians">White Martian</a> among Green Martians. She fell in love with an Earth TV show <em>Hello, Megan</em>, and its main character Megan Wheeler. Miss Martian adopted her looks and her mannerisms (especially her &#8220;Hello, Megan!&#8221; catchphrase) from a fictional character! Miss Martian was a fan girl seeking her identity through fiction.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8T6ND4RrHCs">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8T6ND4RrHCs</a></p>
<p>This was now a character I could relate to. A young girl who created herself out of fictional characters she wished to emulate. She was a superhero and she still needed validation and acceptance. Over the course of one episode, she became my favorite character in Young Justice.</p>
<p>And that was just her character development in Season 1.</p>
<p>Season 2 jumps ahead 5 years and Miss Martian is the most morally grey character of the team (which has expanded significantly). She has no qualms about using her psychic powers to interrogate the bad guys, even if it means leaving them with permanent mental damage. So long as it helps the team and wins the day, she will do what it takes.</p>
<p>Whether or not you agree with her actions. This is a female character with character development. She makes mistakes and then <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RoHT-bSfZJc">has to live with them</a>. This is a female character I believe in because she is just as (if not more) complex than her male counterparts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Favorite Female Characters: Esmeralda</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/favorite-female-characters-esmeralda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 15:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fun fact: The Hunchback of Notre Dame is speculative fiction. And I&#8217;m not just talking&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fun fact: <em>The Hunchback of Notre Dame </em>is speculative fiction. And I&#8217;m not just talking about the Disney version with the talking gargoyles. Victor Hugo&#8217;s novel<em> The Hunchback of Notre Dame </em>(originally titled <em>Notre-Dame de Paris) </em>was published in 1833 but set in 1482: <strong>historical fiction </strong><strong>is speculative fiction. </strong></p>
<p>To be honest, I&#8217;ve never finished the novel (though I&#8217;ve tried at least five times through high school and then college), but the Disney movie has been my favorite Disney film (and possibly my favorite animated film) since it first premiered in theatres in 1996. Three-year-old me couldn&#8217;t really appreciate the score by Stephen Schwartz that uses real Latin in the lyrics, or realize how dark and sexual the whole premise is. But three-year-old me could appreciate Esmeralda.</p>
<p>In my childhood games, I danced around my living room with a scarf trying to mimic her. I had all her lines memorized and I wanted to be her. Without having the words or understanding, I wanted her self-assuredness that her body was hers. As a teenager when I returned to my favorite childhood film, I found a greater love for her bravery. She was the first female character I idolized. She was the first female character who could give voice to my burgeoning understanding of myself as a queer woman, and later a Jewish woman on a majority Christian college campus.</p>
<p>As an adult, I know I can&#8217;t &#8220;be&#8221; her and to try would be cultural appropriation and exoticization of Romani culture. But I can still aspire to her bravery. She was the woman who stood up from the crowd and rescued Quasimodo from public humiliation and torture. She was the woman who shouted <strong>&#8220;</strong><strong>Justice!&#8221; </strong>and demanded justice not for herself in that moment, but for all people who are oppressed.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve forgotten how daring this woman is, if you&#8217;ve never seen the film, or if (like me) this moment in fiction is a defining moment in your life, take another look at this scene:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Hunchback of Notre Dame Justice (original)" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/n2YiCqv28Vs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Esmeralda is more than a favorite female character. She is one of my heroes. She&#8217;s a reminder that if one of us is suffering then we are all suffering and must take a stand to end injustice in all its forms. Esmeralda is a reminder to stand up for what we believe in. Because yes, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MEEpavnk7Uw">&#8220;God Help the Outcasts&#8221;</a> but we are also responsible to aid those in need.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where Are the Women? The Importance of Female Protagonists</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/where-are-the-women-the-importance-of-female-protagonists/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 16:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I talked recently about doing a textual lineage with the high school students I work&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/textual-lineage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">talked recently</a> about doing a textual lineage with the high school students I work with. <em>What was your favorite book as a child? What is your favorite book now?</em></p>
<p>One trend I noticed is that most of the books students named as their favorites (or even books they remembered reading) had male protagonists. <em>Percy Jackson and the Olympians, </em><em>The Maze Runner, The Giver, </em><em>The Outsiders, </em>to name a few.</p>
<p>This should not have been surprising. <span class="entry-author"><span class="entry-author-name">Jo Eberhardt, a speculative fiction writer, recently encountered a similar issue, discussed in her article <a href="http://writerunboxed.com/2016/08/06/the-problem-with-female-protagonists/">&#8220;The Problem with Female Characters.&#8221;</a> As Eberhardt explains, there&#8217;s a gender disparity not just in books, but in movies, as well as in our everyday conversations, where &#8220;women are perceived as being more talkative and taking up more time&#8221; (though in reality, the difference is usually split 70/30 male/female&#8211;though I know this data does not take into account the multiplicity of possible genders).  For Eberhardt, the real core issue is that even informed readers (herself included) don&#8217;t always notice this gender gap!</span></span></p>
<p>But now&#8217;s the time to not just notice but to act. I started my column Favorite Female Characters because I realized that nearly all my fictional role models were men. I&#8217;ve been guilty of favoring male characters, and my own textual lineage is full of them: Bilbo Baggins, Armand (from the Vampire Chronicles series), Felix Harrowgate, and any number of characters not mentioned on my lineage but who influenced my literary development (Goku, Vegeta, Slade, Batman, Nightwing, etc).</p>
<p>Books with male protagonists are meant to be for all genders. Everyone should be able to relate to a man&#8217;s story&#8211;as if a man&#8217;s story is <em>the only </em>story. It shocks me to think about how many people (not just the small population of high school students I work with) are implicitly told that women&#8217;s stories don&#8217;t matter because we don&#8217;t read books that feature their journeys. If we read books starring women, women become humanized. And if people of all genders can see themselves in a female character, that&#8217;s one huge step forward in ending violence against women.</p>
<p>As of the <a href="http://ncadv.org/files/National%20Statistics%20Domestic%20Violence%20NCADV.pdf">2015 report </a>from the National Coalition Against Domestic Violence, a woman in the United States is assaulted or beaten every 9 seconds. Reading books with female protagonists is not going to change this statistic on its own, but it is an active way to ensure we are conscious in our book choices to emphasize women as human. Please, go through your bookshelves. Recommend your friends and family read books starring women.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
