<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>D. M. Domosea &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/d-m-domosea/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:55:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Angela Super</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-angela-super/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D. M. Domosea]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 11:53:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The S Word]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Angela Super earned two Bachelors&#8217; degrees from the University of Idaho in the Creative Writing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Angela Super earned two Bachelors&#8217; degrees from the University of Idaho in the Creative Writing and Theater programs. Currently, she lives in Kansas with her husband and fuzz-brained kittiots. She loves to make costumes, cosplay, and occasionally she plays D&amp;D or MTG with teacher-friends during summer vacation. Angela’s science fiction series, THE SEVEN STARS SAGA—written as AJ Super—debuts in 2021 with the first book, EREBUS DAWNING, now available and the second in the series, A STAR REBORN, hitting the &#8216;net on Tuesday, July 13th.</p>
<p><strong><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25306 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_Erebus-Dawning-200x300.jpg" alt="Cover of Erebus Dawning by AJ Super" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_Erebus-Dawning-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_Erebus-Dawning-684x1024.jpg 684w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_Erebus-Dawning-768x1150.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_Erebus-Dawning-1025x1536.jpg 1025w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_Erebus-Dawning-1367x2048.jpg 1367w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_Erebus-Dawning.jpg 1402w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />How did you come up with the idea of technological AI gods? </strong></p>
<p>The idea morphed from the concept of an all-powerful MC and how I would balance her with other characters. I wanted to make certain her, Nyx’s, sense of over-powered-ness was countered by something she not only cared about but something that could potentially be an obstacle. That and the grounding in Greek mythology that I kinda stole from a favorite anime led to AI gods and them being a mishmoshy family.</p>
<p><strong>Does your theater degree help you create your characters? Do you ever act them out? </strong></p>
<p>Absolutely. In theater, acting specifically, we learn how to REACT and INTERACT and how those are different. It helps to break down character actions and emotions into a more active and engaging language. And I have yet to meet an author that DOESN’T act out their characters in some way… (laughs). I happen to be a big “clown” actor, meaning I tend to squidge my face every which way, and it helps me to describe minute facial expressions in my characters when I get stuck.</p>
<p><strong>Does writing an antihero require a different mindset or technique than writing a hero’s story?</strong></p>
<p>It’s super hard, really. Especially writing a female antihero. Things that are okay for male characters to do, female characters can’t. In general, people don’t want to see an amoral woman… see Game of Thrones and Daenerys as an example. Balancing the likeableness, emotionality, and the bad judgement that comes with being an antihero is challenging. It requires the ability to tie a bunch of things together that don’t necessarily normally go.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25305 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_A-Star-Reborn-200x300.jpg" alt="Cover for A Star Reborn by AJ Super" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_A-Star-Reborn-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_A-Star-Reborn-682x1024.jpg 682w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_A-Star-Reborn-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_A-Star-Reborn-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_A-Star-Reborn-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_A-Star-Reborn.jpg 1706w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><strong>Did you do research for EREBUS DAWNING, and if so, what was the most surprising or interesting thing you discovered? Were you able to apply that to your story?</strong></p>
<p>I didn’t do much research for ED. It was a germ of an idea that l had while watching a particular anime. I wanted to incorporate the idea of an overpowered MC and see how I could make her approachable, not have a god-complex, and most importantly, be her own hero, as anime tends to do the damsel thing quite a bit. The little bit of research that I did, with the exception of things like nano-tech and AI were all spur of the moment rabbit holes. The computer language, the decompression in space, and the faster-than-light travel, things like that I did quick and dirty and with a lot of hand-waving. For the nano-tech and AI, I have a critique partner in upcoming technology fields and we discussed in depth what I could do with it and what it’s current limitations were. Of course, since my books are far far future, limitations are not applicable.</p>
<p><strong>From inception to publication, how long did it take to complete EREBUS DAWNING? What was the easiest part of that process? The most difficult? </strong></p>
<p>It was a five-year process from inception to pub. I would say the easiest part was the beginning, when I was blissfully unaware of how hard publishing actually is. When I was writing and editing just for me. The hardest part definitely is the waiting in between everything. Publishing is a slow process. And I’m an impatient person, so the snail’s pace at which everything moves is very hard to bear. But I will admit, when it does move, it moves fast!</p>
<p><strong><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25307 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_QueenOfTheBlack-200x300.jpg" alt="Book cover image of Queen of the Black by AJ Super" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_QueenOfTheBlack-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_QueenOfTheBlack-682x1024.jpg 682w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_QueenOfTheBlack-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_QueenOfTheBlack-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_QueenOfTheBlack-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Super-Cover_QueenOfTheBlack.jpg 1706w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />When will readers be able to pick up A STAR REBORN and QUEEN OF THE BLACK?</strong></p>
<p>A Star Reborn will be available on July 13th 2021. As for Queen of the Black, it’s TBA. But I’m hoping this fall or winter!</p>
<p><strong>Have you looked beyond SEVEN STARS SAGA to your next project, and if so, can you tell us a bit about it? </strong></p>
<p>I have this idea brewing. I hope I get to write it before it goes away… Or my passion for it dwindles. But it’s a bit of a “mirror, mirror” thing focusing on a middle-aged “evil queen” who will do anything to stay youthful in a society built on being young and beautiful and healthy. A society that uses mirrors to measure health and beauty quotients and when the MC doesn’t measure up, then a “reclamation” team comes to take her to a “home.” Since I’m a pantser, that’s really all I got of the story until I actually start writing it. I love the blank page and what I can turn it into, and I can’t wait to tell this story!</p>
<p>Follow Angela at <a href="https://www.ajsuperauthor.com/">ajsuperauthor.com, </a>on Twitter at <a href="https://twitter.com/AllBrevityWit">@AllBrevityWit,</a> and Instagram at <a href="https://www.instagram.com/angelajsuper/">angelajsuper</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculative-Inspired Arts: A Look Back and Ahead</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-a-look-back-and-ahead/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D. M. Domosea]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 12:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The S Word]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=21981</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In many ways, it’s hard to believe it’s been a full year since I started&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In many ways, it’s hard to believe it’s been a full year since I started the Speculative-Inspired Arts series here at Luna Station. But then, I’ve also felt every single minute of 2020. Haven’t we all? Yes, it’s been an oozing dumpster fire of a year, which makes it all the more important that we bring as much artistic beauty and joy into our lives as we can. I’ve been fortunate to virtually meet and interview many talented women-identifying artists for my column, so in celebration of a full year of SIA, I’ve reached back out to them to find out what they’ve been up to since we last talked and what new projects they have lined up.</p>
<figure id="attachment_21983" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-21983" style="width: 215px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-21983" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/wookiee.png" alt="" width="215" height="303" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-21983" class="wp-caption-text">The bellydancing Wookiee of Raks Geek!</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-dawn-xiana-moon/">Dawn Xiana Moon</a>: “This has been a weird year for art. Britain&#8217;s Got Talent flew me to London in January—I performed as the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iZGNPHS2lII">Bellydancing Wookiee</a>—but by the time my segment aired in May, the world had locked down and live performance and international travel had ceased to be viable. So I&#8217;ve been producing and performing in livestream shows. At this point <a href="http://raksgeek.com/">Raks Geek</a> and <a href="http://raksinferno.com/">Raks Inferno</a> have done 10 virtual productions of firespinning, bellydance, and circus with performers from around the country &#8211; we&#8217;ve even done private events for big corporate clients. (Hire us to entertain your company online!) I&#8217;m also producing a virtual festival featuring Asian-American artists (<a href="https://www.facebook.com/defiantsilk">Defiant Silk Bellydance Festival</a>) that will be coming in January.” You can watch Raks Geek’s latest public livestream shows here: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/raksgeek/live_videos">https://www.facebook.com/raksgeek/live_videos</a></p>
<figure id="attachment_21991" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-21991" style="width: 240px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21991" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/deneen-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/deneen-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/deneen-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/deneen-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/deneen.jpg 972w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-21991" class="wp-caption-text">Deneen Melody in her home studio.</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-deneen-melody/">Deneen Melody</a>: &#8220;Hello!! Since I was last featured, lots has happened in my VO career. I was cast as Rotten &#8220;Rottie&#8221; Dollhart, in the video game <em>Death end re;Quest 2</em>! We were fortunate enough to complete recording before quarantine started. Speaking of the quarantine, this caused voice studios to close down, which meant my partner and I had to put together a studio-quality booth in my home. Doing so allowed me to continue doing voice work, including several Netflix dubs! I play lead roles in the English dubs of <em><a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/81037850">Curon</a></em>, <em><a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/81218903">The Twelve</a></em>, <em><a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80074220">3%</a>,</em> and <em><a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/81302258">To The Lake</a></em> (all currently available on Netflix!) I also worked on <em>The Misfit of Demon King Academy</em>. I voice Nono Inota, part of a wonderful group of girls all voiced by some of my favorite voice ladies! I’m now narrating <em>Trapped in Wonderland</em> by author Dani Hoots! Audiobooks are new to me, so this has been something I’ve had to really step up and push forward with. I&#8217;ll be keeping everyone updated on Dani&#8217;s books on my <a href="https://twitter.com/DeneenMelody">Twitter</a>, so be sure to keep an eye out!&#8221;</p>
<figure id="attachment_21982" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-21982" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-21982 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/lady-elf-doll-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/lady-elf-doll-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/lady-elf-doll-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/lady-elf-doll.jpg 794w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-21982" class="wp-caption-text">Elven Witch by Erika Carlevarino</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-erika-joana/">Erika Carlevarino</a>: “During the pandemic, I have been contacted to create characters for a film in stop motion in Peru. I&#8217;m still working on the creation of characters, it&#8217;s a first phase and it&#8217;s not final, but I&#8217;m very excited to participate in such a project. Meanwhile, I continue with my fantastic creatures and colored lamps.” Erika is constantly adding new dolls to her Etsy shop, The Elven Refuge. See more of Erika’s work at her <a href="https://erikatelier.com/">website</a> and her <a href="https://www.etsy.com/es/shop/MagicGardenLights">Etsy shop</a>, and follow her on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/erikatelierr/">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/eltallerderika/">Instagram</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-shasta-schatz/">Shasta Schatz</a>: “Just after the interview was published, all of our events were canceled or moved to an online format, which was both heartbreaking and inspiring. I finished the Orko (Masters of the Universe) and Georgian Princess Allura (Voltron) projects, using the extra time to work on details that may have been lost in my normal &#8220;Con Crunch&#8221;—the cosplay equivalent of cramming for a test. I was also able to complete my dream project—a gown inspired by a 16th century painting, a medieval Link (Legend of Zelda) ensemble, and a basic 18th century kit. With all of the time at home, I&#8217;ve been able to focus on improving my sewing technique and narrowing my costume focus to the bits that I love most about the hobby like hand sewing and historical research.” Follow Shasta at her <a href="https://greenlinenshirt.com/">website</a> and on <a href="http://instagram.com/scificheergirl">Instagram</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/greenlinenshirt/">Facebook</a> or <a href="http://twitter.com/scificheergirl">Twitter</a>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_21984" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-21984" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-21984" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/gleo-300x300.jpeg" alt="" width="235" height="235" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/gleo-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/gleo-1024x1024.jpeg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/gleo-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/gleo-768x768.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/gleo-1536x1536.jpeg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/gleo-2048x2048.jpeg 2048w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/gleo-550x550.jpeg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 235px) 100vw, 235px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-21984" class="wp-caption-text">Courtesy of GLEO</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-gleo/">GLEO</a>: “It&#8217;s funny, because I&#8217;ve just been available where the opportunity has led me. And so in the midst of what the end of the world has felt like, I was painting a large-scale wall, where every day it was an internal mission to find that tranquility that we are all looking for in these times.  On this wall, I wanted to portray ‘good intention’—the opportunity to let our hearts flourish in the midst of pain.” See more of GLEO’s latest projects via her Instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/gleo_co/">@gleo_co</a>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_21992" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-21992" style="width: 273px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-21992" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/heartmuscle-300x225.png" alt="" width="273" height="205" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/heartmuscle-300x225.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/heartmuscle.png 347w" sizes="(max-width: 273px) 100vw, 273px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-21992" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot from Heart is Muscle by Heiden</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-heiden/">Heiden</a>: “The year has been pretty stressful, but I&#8217;ve been able to concentrate on my projects! I was selected to be part of this year&#8217;s (online) <a href="https://americanart.si.edu/events/saam-arcade">SAAM arcade</a> at the Smithsonian as well as IGDA DC&#8217;s <a href="http://www.igdadc.org/districtarcade/">District Arcade</a>. Despite there not being any in-person events this year, the SAAM arcade and District Arcade were a nice reminder that despite everything, there are still people out there interested in weird little indie games. Other than that, I&#8217;ve also been working on my newest project, <a href="https://heiden.itch.io/heart-is-muscle"><em>Heart is Muscle</em></a>, which I&#8217;m hoping to be finished in December.” You can find Heiden on Twitter at <a href="https://twitter.com/dieletztenrosen">@dieletztenrosen</a>.</p>
<p>I also recently interviewed dancer and choreographer <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-maura-garcia/">Maura García</a>, podcast creator <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-jessica-best/">Jessica Best</a>, and pumpkin sculptor <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-liza-slaughter-barker/">Liza Slaughter Barker</a>, so be sure to check out their interviews if you missed them. I follow every one of these talented artists on social media, and when they aren’t adding awesomeness to my timelines, they’re dropping knowledge and perspective on important social issues. I highly recommend giving them all a follow!</p>
<p>I want to thank everyone for joining me each month as we talked with—or about—female-identifying creatives whose work and projects touch on the speculative fiction themes we love so much. I’ll be stepping away from the column for a while to concentrate on finishing up some of my own projects, but I promise it won’t be a permanent absence. When I return, I hope to have even more conversations with talented speculative-inspired artists to share with you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculative-Inspired Arts: Liza Slaughter Barker</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-liza-slaughter-barker/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D. M. Domosea]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The S Word]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19786</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just in time for October, food artist Liza Slaughter Barker chats with us about creating&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just in time for October, food artist Liza Slaughter Barker chats with us about creating art with edibles and channeling her inner trick-or-treater to inspire her work.</p>
<p><strong>You work with many different mediums, from pumpkins to cakes and egg shells to clay. Which do you enjoy most?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_19833" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19833" style="width: 225px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19833" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/IMG_4236-225x300.jpg" alt="Artist Liza Slaughter Barker poses with her latest pumpkin carving." width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/IMG_4236-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/IMG_4236-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/IMG_4236-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/IMG_4236-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/IMG_4236-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19833" class="wp-caption-text">Liza Slaughter Barker with her latest carving.</figcaption></figure>
<p>That is a difficult question. I love sculpting clay because it is something that can be cast and reproduced. I can step away from a clay project and go back to it years later and resume sculpting. That in itself produces a problem because I have several unfinished projects knowing I can go back to it later. However, I enjoy sculpting pumpkins for the opposite reasons. Pumpkins are ephemeral and begin to deteriorate the moment they are cut from the vine. Once I start carving a pumpkin, I must work quickly to animate the big orange autumn vegetable. It won’t wait weeks or even days. It is already in a state of decomposition. Pumpkins force me to work quickly to its finality. And I look forward to pumpkins every year.</p>
<p><strong>How did you get into pumpkin carving?</strong></p>
<p>Well as a child, I did not celebrate any holidays, so carving pumpkins was not a tradition I was familiar with. However, I wanted my kids to experience carving pumpkins in the fall and decorating cookies and trees at Christmas, cakes on birthdays, eggs at Easter, etc. So I set out to carve the best damn pumpkin I could. I looked up pumpkin carvings and found Ray Villafane’s 3D pumpkins and was blown away by how realistic and whimsical they were. That is when I started carving pumpkins in a 3D fashion.</p>
<p><strong>Pumpkin carving is a field that seems to be dominated by men; have you faced challenges in establishing yourself?</strong></p>
<p>My goals in the pumpkin carving world, I would say, are to continue improving my skills and creativity. Right now, all my artwork is a hobby and establishing myself, in my mind, is more about being known for putting out high quality sculpted pumpkins. For the most part, up to now, pumpkin carvers (men and women) are super friendly and incredibly helpful and haven’t been a challenge at all.</p>
<p><strong>What is the most detailed and time-extensive project you’ve completed? And one you are most proud of?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_19857" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19857" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19857" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/pumpkin-300x296.jpg" alt="Pumpkin carving" width="300" height="296" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/pumpkin-300x296.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/pumpkin-768x757.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/pumpkin.jpg 805w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19857" class="wp-caption-text">Pumpkin carving by Liza Slaughter Barker.</figcaption></figure>
<p>I had a tallish large pumpkin I sculpted last year that had three female faces of different ages and ethnicities around it. Before sculpting that particular pumpkin, I remember wanting to try my hand at something more relatable to me rather than the typical monsters, men, or male-like figures carved into pumpkins. In this pumpkin sculpt, the older female had an aged hand covering her weathered face. I sculpted each figure so that their hair flowed and connected them. The pumpkin was quite dry but was also very thick, so it was difficult to sculpt. I approached this particular pumpkin in a more artistic and contemplative manner.</p>
<p><strong>From where do you draw inspiration for your designs?</strong></p>
<p>Most of the time, I have a clear idea of what I am wanting to sculpt. Right now I am carving a butternut squash that I will preserve by pickling. It is a crazy stylized clown skull complete with a round nose and clown hair. This was a request from my 3 year old daughter. She loves Halloween. Now, sometimes I don’t know what to sculpt and search for character ideas on the internet or in illustrated books. I look for interesting faces that can be carved into a pumpkin. Sometimes I just start carving with no particular direction and just use my imagination. The best sculpts are planned out and have been inspired by figures with the most emotionally provocative expressions.</p>
<p><strong>Name a fictional character you’d love to sculpt or carve but haven’t yet tackled, and in what medium would you create them?</strong></p>
<p>I am a huge fan of Lord of the Rings and have sculpted Gollum in pumpkin before. I would really like to sculpt Bilbo Baggins’ jumpscare scene face. I also am wanting to do a Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde Pumpkin this year as well.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any new projects on the horizon?</strong></p>
<p>With Covid, working full time, and homeschooling, I don’t really have any projects planned. My goals for this year are to stay home as much as possible and sculpt some cool pumpkins this fall. I am turning down any opportunities to travel and compete, so in the meantime I want to sharpen my observation skills and my technique. I really want my sculpts to be diverse in style and content, so my personal projects are to fine tune my artistic skills for better execution in the various mediums.</p>
<p>To see more of Liza&#8217;s work, follow her on Instagram at <a href="https://www.instagram.com/liza_slaughter_barker/">liza_slaughter_barker</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculative-Inspired Arts: Jessica Best</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-jessica-best/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D. M. Domosea]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 10:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The S Word]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19296</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This month in Speculative-Inspired Arts, Jessica Best talks about writing for dramatic podcasts, her artistic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This month in Speculative-Inspired Arts, Jessica Best talks about writing for dramatic podcasts, her artistic inspiration, and inclusivity in the stories she creates.</p>
<figure id="attachment_19298" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19298" style="width: 187px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-19298" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/me-225x300.jpeg" alt="" width="187" height="249" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/me-225x300.jpeg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/me.jpeg 240w" sizes="(max-width: 187px) 100vw, 187px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19298" class="wp-caption-text">Jessica Best</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="font-size: medium;"><a href="https://www.procyonpodcastnetwork.com/tscosi"><b><i><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">The Strange Case of Starship Iris</span></i></b></a><b><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"> is brilliant science fiction that is also expressly inclusive. Can you speak to how sci-fi naturally pushes for active inclusivity?</span></b></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">From the beginning, sci-fi has been all about using fantastical elements to explore the big questions. One of the biggest questions today is, “Given how we’re still grappling with racism, transphobia, homophobia, and so on in the present, how can we build something better for the next generation?” </span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">I think writing something set in the future, you have a certain responsibility to think about those issues, and try to imagine where things might go. You don’t necessarily want a spaceship full of just straight white cisgender people. That sends a pretty chilling message to everyone else, like are there not bisexuals in the year 2189? Where did they <i>go?</i> You want to be able to reach out to people in marginalized groups and say, in your own small way, “You have a future, too.”</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">All that said, though, I don’t know if sci-fi naturally pushes for inclusivity. Plenty of sci-fi stories aren’t inclusive. Plenty of sci-fi stories exploit some of the trappings or aesthetics of, say, Chinese or Japanese cultures, and then center only white people. I think it’s important to confront the ways in which stories, even stories we love, can cause harm. But sci-fi certainly has the potential to let us dream up a world in which more groups have a place at the table, and there’s a lot of value to that.</span></span></p>
<p><b><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">You’re also a staff writer for <a href="https://www.unwellpodcast.com/"><em>Unwell: A Midwestern Gothic Mystery</em></a>, where you alternate writing podcast episodes with other writers. Do you feel that limits your creativity or pushes it?</span></span></b></p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">It pushes my creativity, absolutely. Having some limitations forces you to rethink your ideas and come to novel solutions. Also, working with three super talented writers (and two super talented producers) is invigorating; I can’t slack off because I want to impress them!</span></span></p>
<p><b><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">What unique challenges does audio drama writing present that prose or novel writing doesn’t?</span></span></b></p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">With audio scripts, you often can’t rely on those subtle body language cues to express what a character is thinking and thus, save you a lot of writing. You have to find ways to convey where your characters are in space and what they’re doing. And transitions can be hard, smoothly re-orienting the audience using only sound.</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">That said, I’ve always enjoyed writing dialogue above all else, and when I write prose I have to push myself to include enough description of how things look or what people are doing with their hands. I finish scripts much, much faster than prose. Even though I’ve only been doing it for about four years, I think writing audio drama comes the most naturally to me.</span></span></p>
<p><b><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">From where do you draw inspiration for your stories?</span></span></b></p>
<figure id="attachment_19297" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19297" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19297" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/logo-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/logo-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/logo-1024x1021.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/logo-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/logo-768x765.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/logo-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/logo.png 1184w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19297" class="wp-caption-text">The Strange Case of Starship Iris</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">I don’t really know! I’m very focused on the dynamics between characters, though. That’s usually what comes first, or near first. With Starship Iris, I knew from the beginning that I wanted to write an ensemble drama with comedic elements, and shutting the characters together in a spaceship would make it easy for the audience to track where everyone was, while also creating instant drama. </span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">What first got me into the specifics of the show, though, was imagining the scene between Violet and Kay at the end of the first episode, all of the emotions at play. That was my jumping-off point.</span></span></p>
<p><b><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">In addition to podcasts, you compose music and have written a YA novel titled <i>Pretending to Date Gabe Novak. </i>Which of these artistic mediums brings you the most satisfaction and why?</span></span></b></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000; font-family: Calibri; font-size: medium;"> </span><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">Not to totally cop out here, but honestly I think the mediums each bring different kinds of satisfaction. </span></span><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">I will say that songs are probably the most fun to share. As a former theater kid, I love the chance to perform and get instant feedback. Writing the novel was tremendously rewarding and I really hope it finds a home someday, but nobody claps at the end of reading a manuscript, you know?</span></span></p>
<p><b><span style="font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="color: #000000; font-size: medium;">Can you share a bit about your current or upcoming projects?</span></span></b></p>
<p><span style="color: black; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">I have a handful of new podcasts that I want to make.  It’s a question of matching each project with the right team; I produce Starship Iris myself and fund it all on Patreon but in the future, I want to focus solely on writing. A few of the ideas are sci-fi, and one is a musical. </span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: black; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">I have one song written for the musical so far. It’s about the joy and heartbreak of the largest frying pan in Iowa. A group of people in Brandon, Iowa were trying to make the largest frying pan in the U.S. but <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19572 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/helinton-fantin-hbSzQTsLwQc-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/helinton-fantin-hbSzQTsLwQc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/helinton-fantin-hbSzQTsLwQc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/helinton-fantin-hbSzQTsLwQc-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/helinton-fantin-hbSzQTsLwQc-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/helinton-fantin-hbSzQTsLwQc-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />nobody actually stopped and researched what pans were already out there, and it turns out Long Beach, Washington already had a bigger pan. There’s something so beautifully human about that. </span></span></p>
<p><span style="color: black; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: medium;">You can find more of Jessica&#8217;s work online at <a href="https://jessicamarybest.com/">www.jessicamarybest.com</a> and on Twitter as <a href="https://twitter.com/Jesserbest">@jesserbest</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/starshipiris">@StarshipIris</a>.</span></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculative-Inspired Arts: Maura García</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-maura-garcia/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-maura-garcia/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D. M. Domosea]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 11:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The S Word]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dancer/Choreographer Maura García is an Indigenous woman (non-enrolled Cherokee/Mattamuskeet) whose work expresses the connections between&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_19253" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19253" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19253" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Maura-Garcia-photo-credit-to-Jenny-Wheat-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Maura-Garcia-photo-credit-to-Jenny-Wheat-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Maura-Garcia-photo-credit-to-Jenny-Wheat.jpg 266w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19253" class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Jenny Wheat</figcaption></figure>
<p>Dancer/Choreographer Maura García is an Indigenous woman (non-enrolled Cherokee/Mattamuskeet) whose work expresses the connections between past, present, and future through storytelling.</p>
<p><strong>When it comes to your choreography, how much derives from the story you want to tell and how much is based on the music? </strong></p>
<p>That depends on the piece. I have work I’ve created where poems were given to the composer [who] created music based on them, and then I came up with movement that was also based on the poems and then they were put together. So the movements were not necessarily made to go with the music. Sometimes they meet up, if you will, but it’s not a synchronized piece. I have other work where…I’ve sent them the choreography and they came up with the music based on the choreography. And lately, I’ve been asked to do music videos where they’ve already made the music, and I’m creating choreography to go with the music. So I create in all different types of ways.</p>
<p><strong>Native American culture is often viewed by non-Natives as supernatural or mystic in nature. Given that, does your expected audience affect how you might design a performance?</strong></p>
<p>No, because we can’t cater to racism or made-up stereotypes, so I don’t really worry about those types of things. I’m Cherokee and Matamuskeet, and the stories I’m drawing from are often Cherokee-specific, so even if it’s a Native audience, they may not understand things specific to our tribe.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Aniwisvsgo&#039;i (Trailer)" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/316690821?dnt=1&amp;app_id=122963" width="730" height="411" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/316690821">&#8220;Aniwisvsgo&#8217;i&#8221; Trailer</a> from <a href="https://vimeo.com/user17812215">Maura Garcia Dance</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com/">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>Oftentimes, before the performance I may talk a little bit about the piece because I like for whoever it is—whether they’re Native or non-Native—to have some understanding of the imagery and the story behind it. I’m not big into putting things into certain genres, but if I want to communicate with people, I like them to know, “Oh the reason I’m doing this seven times is because seven is a sacred number to us,” or “There’s a reason I’m going in a circle this way.” So those types of things I tell people so they can have some context. They feel good watching the piece because they have some understanding, which is the whole point.</p>
<p><strong>Your art primarily focuses on your Native American heritage. Do you draw inspiration from your other identities to any degree? </strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_19255" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19255" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19255" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/MGD-photo-by-ChrisRandle-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/MGD-photo-by-ChrisRandle-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/MGD-photo-by-ChrisRandle.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19255" class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Chris Randle</figcaption></figure>
<p>My answer would be yes, as I wouldn’t even know how to separate them or how anybody else does, actually. That’s a hard question to answer just because there’s many things I’m made of in terms of experiences and places I’ve been, and they all form a part of my work. I come from a place of being a Native woman, and my interest is in those stories, but I’m not so specific. One of my pieces, <a href="https://vimeo.com/387193866">“Hey Google!”</a> is a comedy. The elements and the colors and the aesthetics are specifically Cherokee, but it’s about Google Home Mini and privacy.</p>
<p><strong>You write poetry, which—like dance—requires a distinct sense of rhythm. Do you ever channel one to create the other? </strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_19254" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19254" style="width: 203px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19254" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/MauraGarciaDancePrograms-203x300.jpg" alt="" width="203" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/MauraGarciaDancePrograms-203x300.jpg 203w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/MauraGarciaDancePrograms.jpg 432w" sizes="(max-width: 203px) 100vw, 203px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19254" class="wp-caption-text">Maura Garcia Dance Programs</figcaption></figure>
<p>That’s interesting. I have used poetry and created dance from that or have created ideas for pieces from specific poems. I’ve included poems into performances and have choreographed them and have had someone else make them into music. I have not used dance to write poetry though. That’s an interesting thought. Someone else told me that “you write like it’s dancing” and I’m not doing that consciously, so I guess that’s just naturally how I write.</p>
<p><strong>You also dabble in visual art. What subjects do you gravitate towards?</strong></p>
<p>I actually have a background in weaving and embroidery, and I make a kind of traditional-style flat mat. I do incorporate that, where I’ve designed some of my own props and constructed and designed costumes. Lately, I’ve been trying not to do that and so work with people who are really—in terms of the sewing—artists of their own. I really loved weaving, but it takes a long time, and I don’t have time like that. I do gravitate towards painting, and there’s some of our traditional art forms that I also like to do, but I don’t make as much as I would like to.</p>
<p><strong>I’m intrigued by your work as an orchestrator of community art projects. What’s one of your most personally rewarding projects?</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/dKiUrknQ4rA"><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19252 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_20200703_161218_951-275x300.jpg" alt="" width="275" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_20200703_161218_951-275x300.jpg 275w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_20200703_161218_951-938x1024.jpg 938w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_20200703_161218_951-768x839.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_20200703_161218_951-1406x1536.jpg 1406w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/IMG_20200703_161218_951-1875x2048.jpg 1875w" sizes="(max-width: 275px) 100vw, 275px" />Center of the Universe</em></a>, which was a project funded by the Smithsonian National Museum of the American Indian and a Rocket Grant. I spent two weeks in DC looking at artwork and materials from ancient cities in the Midwest from a thousand to fifteen-hundred years ago. The whole project was drawn from the idea of urban Indian identity and what that means to us now. So working with the folks at the Indian Center, I was able to bring in other Native artists to teach different art forms. We did mapping and beadwork and we had a final presentation where people shared the dance we created based on the images and the artwork from Cahokia and Spiral Mounds, and all the artwork they had made over the course of six months was on display. So yeah, that was a great project because…I was able to really share what I had had the gift of seeing at the museum with the community. One young man told me that he had more interest in finding out more about his particular nation, but also in general about the greatness of Indigenous people.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any upcoming projects you can share with us?</strong></p>
<p>I just created a <a href="https://vimeo.com/441838181">music video</a> in collaboration with several other Native artists.</p>
<p>https://vimeo.com/441838181</p>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/441838181">In Tongue</a> from <a href="https://vimeo.com/user17812215">Maura Garcia Dance</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com/">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>The music is by Navajo-fronted hip hop/jazz/funk fusion band, DDAT, and it was recorded in front of a mural featuring Osage design and language, created by visual artist Mona Cliff (A&#8217;aniih/Nakota). And then I’ve got two performances in August that are virtual; one on August 14<sup>th</sup> presented by <a href="https://www.culturehub.org/events/downtown-variety-13">La MaMa and Culture Hub</a> in New York [as part of] a series they’re running, and the other one is hosted by <a href="http://www.calderaarts.org/caldera/">Caldera Artist Residency</a> in Sisters, Oregon. Also on the 9th of August I will be participating in a <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CCkmCJyseY8/?igshid=1xqqmk3ex2zoj">benefit concert</a> for several social justice organizations.</p>
<p>Follow Maura García’s work via her <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/mauragarciadance">YouTube channel</a>, <a href="http://www.mauragarciadance.org/">website</a> and/or on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/maura_garcia_dance/?hl=en">Instagram</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-maura-garcia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculative-Inspired Arts: Heiden</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-heiden/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D. M. Domosea]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 10:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The S Word]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This month in “Speculative-Inspired Arts,” visual novel designer Heiden gives us a peek at what&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This month in “Speculative-Inspired Arts,” visual novel designer Heiden gives us a peek at what goes into creating the beautifully diverse and drawn worlds of their (FREE!) online tales.</p>
<p><strong>What is the difference between a visual novel (VN) and an adventure game?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_18960" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18960" style="width: 206px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-18960" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/me-300x263.png" alt="Self-portrait of the artist" width="206" height="180" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/me-300x263.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/me.png 594w" sizes="(max-width: 206px) 100vw, 206px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-18960" class="wp-caption-text">Heiden, as drawn by the artist.</figcaption></figure>
<p>At first glance, VNs and adventure games seem very different. Visual Novels originated in Japan and play similarly to a choose-your-own-adventure picture book, where you read through text and are prompted with a choice which impacts your ending. They often focus on romance and calculating stats based on your previous choices. Adventure games were first pioneered by Western developers and play by walking the character around to solve puzzles while using items in an inventory, which advances the plot. Usually, there isn’t as much reading in adventure games and there are less story branches than seen in VNs.</p>
<p>Although from the outset, these two are very different, they both focus on narrative rather than an underlying game mechanic. In my own work, I like trying to meld these two together, taking elements of the puzzle mechanics of adventure games with the more traditional VN talking scenes. I’ve found that if you can get your player to help the protagonist through puzzles, they’ll bond to them faster. I find VNs and adventure games very fascinating because they’re an extension of literature, just with player interaction. I like playing around with that idea. As the developer you can control what the player sees, hears, and reads at any given moment, but you also allow the player to discover that story at their own pace.</p>
<p><strong>What are your biggest influences when it comes to conjuring stories for your work?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_18959" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18959" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18959" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/bogsheart-300x169.png" alt="Screenshot from The Bog's Hear" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/bogsheart-300x169.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/bogsheart-1024x576.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/bogsheart-768x432.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/bogsheart.png 1184w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-18959" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot from <em>The Bog&#8217;s Heart.</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>My biggest influences come from YA fantasy novels as well as JRPGs. I am particularly fond of Tamora Pierce, Megan Whalen Turner, and Garth Nix, and always found myself wishing that I could take the books I loved and make them more like the video games I liked, such as Final Fantasy, Fire Emblem, and the Mother series.</p>
<p><strong>Which aspect of game design do you take most pleasure in (art, code, storyboard, etc.,) and why?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_18962" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18962" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18962" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0067-300x169.png" alt="Capture from The Girl with the Gray Hair Awakens" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0067-300x169.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0067-1024x576.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0067-768x432.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0067.png 1366w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-18962" class="wp-caption-text">Capture from <em>The Girl with the Gray Hair Awakens.</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Of all the assets that go into making my games, I enjoy the designing and drawing the characters the most. My games are very character heavy, so all aspects of the game’s development are centered around making sure the characters are coming through.</p>
<p><strong>How long does it typically take to develop a project from start to finish?</strong></p>
<p>It depends. If the game is for a gamejam, typically it will take one to two months to finish. For games made outside of gamejams, those can take anywhere from a year to two years to create. Though sometimes I’ll get attached to a gamejam game and it turns into a full blown game! That happened with Dr. Frank’s Build-A-Boyfriend, which was meant to be finished in two months, but instead I decided to develop it into a full title which took a year.</p>
<p><strong>Given that several of your VNs were developed as part of “game jams” or festivals, tell us more about that!</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_18961" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18961" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18961" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/nb107a-300x187.png" alt="Screenshot from NB-107A" width="300" height="187" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/nb107a-300x187.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/nb107a-768x478.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/nb107a.png 954w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-18961" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot from <em>NB-107A.</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>Gamejams are challenges in which people will gather together for a short amount of time and attempt to make a game. Some of the most famous gamejams, Ludum Dare and Global Game Jam, take place over the course of a weekend in which people create games from scratch. Not much sleeping happens during those weekends. Other gamejams, usually ones online, tend to last longer and are usually more relaxed. Those jams tend to range from one to two months. Jams are fun because you always end up meeting new people and collaborating with others! The only danger is falling in love with your gamejam game more than the game you’ve been working on for a whole year, haha!</p>
<p><strong>What do you hope players take away from your games and VNs?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_18964" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18964" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18964" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0071-300x169.png" alt="Scene from Kill the Prince?" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0071-300x169.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0071-1024x576.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0071-768x432.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0071.png 1281w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-18964" class="wp-caption-text">A scene from Heiden&#8217;s newest game, <em>Kill the Prince?</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>I hope it opens their eyes to the different types of games out there. A lot of people will tell me that they don’t think they like video games but then say that they enjoyed the story parts of RPGs that they played growing up. VNs take away the difficulty of perfecting button press timing and deliver the story with no prerequisites. I hope my games do something similar, to show that there are games out there for everyone!</p>
<p><strong>Which of your projects is your favorite?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_18963" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18963" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18963" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0068-300x169.png" alt="Image from Dr. Frank Build-A-Boyfriend" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0068-300x169.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0068-1024x576.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0068-768x432.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/screenshot0068.png 1366w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-18963" class="wp-caption-text">Screenshot from <em>Dr. Frank&#8217;s Build-A-Boyfriend.</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>I had a lot of fun writing Dr. Frank’s Build-A-Boyfriend and thinking up all the different puzzle elements. Though Elvine holds a special place in my heart, as it was my very first game and showed me that I really could make a game if I worked at it hard enough. So for that, Elvine is my favorite.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>All of Heiden&#8217;s games can be downloaded at <a href="https://heiden.itch.io/">https://heiden.itch.io/</a></p>
<p>Follow Heiden on Twitter at <a href="https://twitter.com/dieletztenrosen">@dieletztenrosen</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculative-Inspired Arts: Supporting Black Arts Communities</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-supporting-black-arts-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D. M. Domosea]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The S Word]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s now Thursday, and the fervor that was #BlackoutTuesday is two days past, but active&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s now Thursday, and the fervor that was #BlackoutTuesday is two days past, but active antiracist support must continue if we’re to create real and meaningful change. This month for “Speculative-Inspired Arts,” I’ve put together a list of resources and organizations that support Black creators and artists. If you’re not in a position to provide material support directly through donations, sponsorships, or purchases, consider providing increased visibility for these organizations and artists through your social media platforms and online recommendations.</p>
<p>Remember that true change is best nourished through long-term commitment, so make active support of Black artists a regular and conscious habit. My apologies if I’ve left any artistic disciplines out. If I have, drop some support links in the comments section please!</p>
<p><strong>All Arts Disciplines</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.blackartfutures.org/">The Black Art Futures Fund</a>: This organization “provides grants to small ($750K or l<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-18846 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Black_Art_Futures_Logo_415px-259x300.png" alt="" width="207" height="240" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Black_Art_Futures_Logo_415px-259x300.png 259w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Black_Art_Futures_Logo_415px.png 415w" sizes="(max-width: 207px) 100vw, 207px" />ess) nonprofits working to enhance the future of Black arts &amp; culture.” Past grantees include organizations that provide Black-focused music, theater, and visual arts performances and services.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gofundme.com/f/artsleadersfund?fbclid=IwAR1yNBFOBl18Oy9KysozAdpQFfZeKN6Wq82ZMpVnlOqF84USeauRDhtnYEY">Arts and Culture Leaders of Color Emergency Fund</a>: This emergency fund was created to give small grants to working people of color artists or art administrators who are affected by COVID-19. If you have an artist friend or colleague who is struggling because of COVID-19, send them <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfv4AazvLFVUNAgXoxqBqfZ7jJVkrMroa-CET6Vt6XygR-CaQ/viewform">this link</a> to apply.</p>
<p><strong>Applied Arts</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/Pop_Reader/status/1267077455329796096?s=20">Etsy Artists</a>: Whether you seek purses, mugs, jewelry, scarves, party wares, art prints, shirts, candles, or even face masks, you can find it all on Etsy. Book blogger Jen with “Pop! Goes the Reader” has put together a thread of Black-owned Etsy shops whose owners make their artistic talents their business.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">? Here&#8217;s a thread of some amazing Black-owned businesses on Etsy that you can support right now and receive absolutely stunning creations in return! ?</p>
<p>1. The Pairabirds<a href="https://t.co/0gS20xaKRn">https://t.co/0gS20xaKRn</a> <a href="https://t.co/hernvYFdGp">pic.twitter.com/hernvYFdGp</a></p>
<p>— Jen (@Pop_Reader) <a href="https://twitter.com/Pop_Reader/status/1267077455329796096?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 31, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js">https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.blackdesigncollective.com/">The Black Design Collective</a>: The Black Design Collective “seeks to create a platform for designers of color to develop, produce and market their products globally as well as create a mentorship program for aspiring designers.” They’ve also established an emergency COVID-19 relief fund for black designers.</p>
<p><strong>Game Developers</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://radmagpie.org/blog/2020/2/6/support-black-game-developers">Black Game Developers</a>: Rad Magpie provides “underrepresented people greater access to creative collaboration, leadership, and technical skills through game development.” In February, they pulled together this list of Black game developers to follow.</p>
<p><a href="https://gamedevsofcolorexpo.com/">Game Developers of Color Expo</a>: The Game Developers of Color Expo is going virtual this year on September 19th. This event is looking for donations and sponsors to make it the biggest and best event yet for new and experienced game developers to share and learn.</p>
<p><a href="https://afrotech.com/games-created-black-entrepreneurs">Board Game Designers</a>: If you prefer low-tech games, here’s a short list compiled by AfroTech of board games created by Black developers.</p>
<p><strong>Literary Arts</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.pocinpublishing.com/">People of Color in Publishing</a>: POC in Pub is an organization “dedicated to supporting, empowering, and uplifting racially and ethnically marginalized members throu<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-18847" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Logo-Black-Writers-Collective-350sq-285x226-1.png" alt="" width="257" height="204" />ghout the industry.”</p>
<p><a href="https://blackwriters.org/">Black Writers Collective</a>: The Black Writers Collective seeks to connect, empower and educate Black writers with critique and beta reading opportunities, classes on craft and publishing, and much more.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.caapp.pitt.edu/">Center for African American Poetry and Poetics</a>: The mission of CAAPP at the University of Pittsburgh is to “highlight, promote, and share the work of African American and African diasporic poets and to pollinate cross-disciplinary conversation and collaboration.”</p>
<p><strong>Music and Film</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.aavadb.com/members/">The African American Voice Actor Database</a>: This site is designed “to facilitate connections between amazing talents and agents/voice-seekers” through its extensive database of Black voice actors. Fans of voiced animation, dubbed anime, or books on audio can support the work of Black voice actors here.</p>
<p><a href="https://cutaway.shift.io/resources-for-black-filmmakers-a-guide">Resources for Black Filmmakers</a>: Okay, I’m cheating with this one by linking to an already-published list from The Cutaway of resources that support Black filmmakers. Their list is extensive and thorough, and I couldn’t do any better.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.nanm.org/about">The National Association of Negro Musicians</a>: NANM has been around for more than one-hundred years, promoting, preserving, and supporting “all genres of music created or performed by African-Americans.” They also provide scholarships and grants for youth in musical education.</p>
<p><strong>Performing Arts</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://4caapa.org/index.html">The Coalition for African Americans in Performing Arts</a>: CAAPA “promotes opportunities for Black classical musicians and others in the performing arts through arts performances, education, and outreach.” Based in Maryland, United States, they’ve been hit hard by COVID-19 and are working to fund a CAAPA Artist Relief Fund to help Black artists affected by event cancellations. When life returns to normal, revisit the site for information on their latest events and ways to sponsor their programs.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.iabdassociation.org/">The International Association of Blacks in Dance</a>: The IABD “preserves and promotes dance by <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-18848 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/dance.png" alt="" width="293" height="172" />people of African ancestry or origin, and assists and increases opportunities for artists.” In addition to general donations to support their ongoing mission, they’ve established an emergency relief fund for dancers affected by COVID-19.</p>
<p><strong>Visual Arts</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1d9gokwVQLCOmqf8zfez6-yMRgHOq4P5veW7lfZF7BCs/htmlview?pru=AAABcpu_QzI*fDMN3_QPmFR1nvrgGCo1Dw#gid=653352977">Black Artist Directory</a>: Illustrator and Drawing While Black organizer Abelle Hayford has put together a full list of Black illustrators, graphic designers, animators, and comic artists. If you’re in need of illustrating services, make this list your first stop.</p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/ArtCampOfficial/status/1266472158429151237?s=20">#ArtShare on Twitter</a>: If you’re more visual-oriented, you can find a string of replies to an #artshare request on Twitter from Art Camp that is loaded with beautiful artwork from Black illustrators.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.womenwhodraw.com/category/race-ethnicity/african-american/">Women Who Draw Directory</a>: This directory by Women Who Draw allows you to search for illustrators by location, orientation, religion, or ethnicity, including—for our purposes—Black women-identified artists.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.exposuregroup.org/index.shtml">The Exposure Group</a>: The Exposure Group African American Photographers Association is a “participatory member-driven professional photographers association dedicated towards improving the skills, professionalism, and productivity of its members.” I couldn’t find a support function for the group itself, but you can find information and links to relevant events.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Sara T. Bond</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-sara-t-bond/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D. M. Domosea]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The S Word]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Born and raised in Atlanta, Sara is a southern tall-tale teller with a terrible poker&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_17964" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17964" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-17964 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/square-author-photo-300x278.jpg" alt="Author Sara Bond" width="300" height="278" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/square-author-photo-300x278.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/square-author-photo-768x712.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/square-author-photo.jpg 939w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17964" class="wp-caption-text">Author Sara T. Bond</figcaption></figure>
<p>Born and raised in Atlanta, Sara is a southern tall-tale teller with a terrible poker face. So, she writes fiction to better conceal the difference between truth and imagination. After dabbling in careers in academia, politics, and even a lucrative job in high-end fashion, she always found her way back to writing. Sara lives with her husband and two children, who think communication is best achieved through volume, repetition, and pure conviction. GRAVITY&#8217;S HEIR is her debut novel.</p>
<p><strong>First off, tell us about your debut, <em>Gravity’s Heir</em>. Is it based in our known universe? Where does the title come from? Will it be part of a series?</strong></p>
<p><em>Gravity’s Heir</em> is set in a completely unique three-star system, with multiple inhabited moons, planets, and quite a few asteroid mining and satellite systems linking everyone together. What allows for travel between those planets is a fun technology I developed that uses gravity and energized gravitons to push and pull small spacecraft between larger interstellar bodies. That’s actually where the title comes from, since my main character’s grandfather developed artificial gravity and gravity propulsion flight; Lena is the heir to the empire that technology created. Currently I do not have plans to write a sequel, though I suppose I could be persuaded to write in that universe again if there’s enough interest.</p>
<p><strong>How detailed do you get with the sciencey aspects of your world building?</strong></p>
<p>I probably spent more time developing the technology and science than I did writing the book itself! Though very little of the nitty-gritty makes it into the text of the book, I did confirm that my science was consistent with the theoretical physics of gravity, gravitons, and particle and quantum mechanics. Though, naturally, there is some hand-waving assumptions given we don’t actually have working artificial gravity, yet.</p>
<p><strong><em>Gravity’s Heir</em></strong><strong> touches on the concept of found families. Did you have any specific inspirations?</strong></p>
<p>The biggest inspiration for my found family is Joss Whedon’s <em>Firefly</em>. In fact, what I originally set out to write was my own <em>Firefly</em> set in a WWI-inspired conflict. I was influenced by <em>Battlestar Galactica</em>, Becky Chambers’s <em>Wayfarer</em> series, and Ann Aguirre’s <em>Sirantha Jax</em> series as well.</p>
<p><strong>In a previous life, you worked in high-end fashion. Is that experience reflected in how you discuss your character’s clothing or appearance?</strong></p>
<p>Sadly, I didn’t get to incorporate much of my fashion obsession into this book. Lena eschews her past as an heiress in favor of simple clothes that move and fit comfortably. She’s a tank-top and pants kind of girl. The main character in my current work in progress is a bit more into her appearance, so I may be able to incorporate some high fashion sensibilities in the next book. I may even send her on a shopping trip to Gucci and name drop some of my former colleagues. That will be fun to write!</p>
<figure id="attachment_17963" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17963" style="width: 206px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-17963 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Gravitys-Heir-front-cover-206x300.jpg" alt="Front cover for Gravity's Heir" width="206" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Gravitys-Heir-front-cover-206x300.jpg 206w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Gravitys-Heir-front-cover-702x1024.jpg 702w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Gravitys-Heir-front-cover-768x1121.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Gravitys-Heir-front-cover-1053x1536.jpg 1053w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Gravitys-Heir-front-cover-1403x2048.jpg 1403w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Gravitys-Heir-front-cover-scaled.jpg 1754w" sizes="(max-width: 206px) 100vw, 206px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17963" class="wp-caption-text">Gravity&#8217;s Heir by Sara T. Bond</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>How did you snag your publisher, Black Rose Writing?</strong></p>
<p>I got my publisher through the least glamorous, but most tested and true methods: a cold query. I spent over a year querying agents, participating in online pitch contests, doing everything I could to get my book in front of anyone who might be interested in it. While I got a lot of positive responses, I didn’t snag enough interest to get a contract. I was ready to give up, but my critique partners insisted I query a few small publishers that accepted unagented manuscripts. In early 2019, I sent it to about ten publishers that I thought would fit me, and within a month I had an offer from Black Rose Writing. They offered incredible terms, great distribution, and an accelerated publishing schedule to get my book in stores within nine months. It took a stressful few months to get everything edited and perfect for publication, but exactly nine months later, I had a book in hand and available for order from everyone from Amazon and Barnes and Noble to Target and Walmart. Then the pandemic hit. Oh well, timing in publishing is difficult in the best of times.</p>
<p><strong>You’ve got a great series on your blog called “Perfect Pairings.” Tell us more about that!</strong></p>
<p>My Pairings Project is a fun way to wed two of my favorite things: great books and great cocktails. I pair in depth book reviews of some of my favorite recent reads with drinks specially chosen to complement the book. I swear, lately I spend more time on this little passion project and promoting these brilliant books I’ve read than I do promoting my own book. It’s just so much fun to identify a theme or a character or a certain feel to the book I’m reading and then find a cocktail that evokes that same feel. I’ve literally spent an entire week calling up specialty liquor and grocery stores looking for just the right ingredient to go in a cocktail, and I’ve even made up my own recipes from time to time. I then mix up the drink and photograph the book and the cocktail for my blog. It’s been a bit of a success, with many of the authors featured choosing to use the cocktails for book events of their own. One of my cocktails, The Blueberry Cove, is even going to be featured in an upcoming sequel to Elizabeth Penney’s debut <em>Hems and Homicide</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Can you discuss your upcoming projects?</strong></p>
<p>For my own writing, it’s slow going at the moment. I’m homeschooling my five year old and taking care of my one year old, so I haven’t had as much time for my writing lately. But I am working on two books. One is an urban fantasy about a half-human fairy princess turned bartender in Atlanta who has to find and stop a killer. The other is a contemporary fantasy about a group of women who start a book club that slowly turns into a powerful coven. It’s <em>Practical Magic</em> meets <em>Angry Housewives Eating Bon Bons</em>. I also have a short story coming out next year in the annual JordanCon Anthology, alongside authors like Faith Hunter, Darin Kennedy, and David Alan Jones.</p>
<p>Follow Sara at <a href="https://www.saratbond.com/">www.saratbond.com</a> and on <a href="https://twitter.com/saramuse">Twitter</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sara.h.bond/">Instagram</a>.</p>
<p>GRAVITY&#8217;S HEIR is available for order through your favorite local bookseller via <a href="https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781684334216" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-content="https://www.indiebound.org/book/9781684334216" data-type="external">Indiebound</a> or order directly at <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Gravitys-Heir-Sara-Bond/dp/1684334217/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=gravity%27s+heir+sara+bond&amp;qid=1575346114&amp;sr=8-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-content="https://www.amazon.com/Gravitys-Heir-Sara-Bond/dp/1684334217/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=gravity%27s+heir+sara+bond&amp;qid=1575346114&amp;sr=8-1" data-type="external">Amazon.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculative-Inspired Arts: GLEO</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-gleo/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-gleo/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D. M. Domosea]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 10:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The S Word]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Street artist GLEO joins us this month to discuss both the inspiration and meaning of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Street artist <a href="https://www.instagram.com/gleo_co/">GLEO</a> joins us this month to discuss both the inspiration and meaning of her larger-than-life designs, which can be found around the world on structures in Spain, Colombia, Turkey, and throughout the United States.</p>
<p><strong>Your art has an otherworldly quality to it. What inspires your designs?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_17582" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17582" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-17582 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7921-300x300.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7921-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7921-1024x1024.jpeg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7921-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7921-768x768.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7921-1536x1536.jpeg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7921-2048x2048.jpeg 2048w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7921-550x550.jpeg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17582" class="wp-caption-text">Artwork by GLEO, Cancun, Mexico</figcaption></figure>
<p>A long time ago I’ve searched a lot between ancestral cultures and their symbologies; somehow, I was trying to find my creative source in the outside world, and in that search recently I found nature. I rediscovered her and I’m discovering myself. I learned to see the world since young with the eyes of curiosity, and now I&#8217;m learning to be curious about all the world that lives in me and in all of us. For a long time I have searched for a way to be able to feed my creativity, but with time I discovered that in life I have had a lot of good and bad experiences that have always left a great learning of which to inspire me. Among all the complex that is life, today I think my inspiration comes from every experience that she gives me and the rest only flows painting.</p>
<p><strong>There are two reoccurring themes in your art: flowers and the yellow and blue orbs. Can you share their meaning to your work?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_17581" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17581" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-17581 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7047-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7047-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7047-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7047-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7047-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_7047-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17581" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Inner World&#8221; by GLEO, Charlotte, North Carolina</figcaption></figure>
<p>Since I started developing my work, in some way very spontaneous and natural, the yellow circles were involved. Over time it is a constant repetition that I’m looking to give me meaning, but in reality, only it is a graphic way of feeling that I finished the painting. It is a game of infinite circles that play with millions of possibilities that can occur to me, as constant as my search for their meaning. On the other hand, the flowers are a company that I have since young, as my mother has always brought them into my life.</p>
<p><strong>How do you choose the subjects featured in your artwork? Are they people you know or historical figures?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_17580" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17580" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17580" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_4576-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_4576-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_4576-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_4576-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_4576-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_4576-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17580" class="wp-caption-text">Katherine Johnson by GLEO, Valencia, Spain</figcaption></figure>
<p>I have crossed several stages in the portraits: they were first imaginary characters that over time began to be more realistic. Nowadays at this point I continue portraying friends and people that I meet in my trips. Each person brings a story and experience that feeds the themes of my paintings. Sometimes I have been invited to portray historical characters such as Katherine Johnson, a wonderful and inspiring mathematician; in this case I’m looking to be faithful to the intention of the person through my interpretation in painting. But in reality, when you perform a portrait, the only thing that feeds the theme and the atmosphere of that portrait is the experience lived with and around the portrayed person.</p>
<p><strong>What is the biggest project you’ve worked on, both in time and in scale?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_17578" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17578" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-17578 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/10766515056_IMG_0589-300x200.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/10766515056_IMG_0589-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/10766515056_IMG_0589-1024x682.jpeg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/10766515056_IMG_0589-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/10766515056_IMG_0589-1536x1023.jpeg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/10766515056_IMG_0589-2048x1364.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17578" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;The Original Dream&#8221; by GLEO, Wichita, Kansas</figcaption></figure>
<p>&#8220;The Original Dream&#8221; in Wichita, Kansas, was a 4,500 square meters, three months painting with five persons supporting each other.</p>
<p><strong>Of all your finished projects, which one is your favorite, and why?</strong></p>
<p>In all the projects I find something special, but certainly &#8220;The Original Dream&#8221; has been the project that most taught me to understand the path I wanted to take: it showed me to look inside and listen to me, to learn to communicate with others. This wall is so great because of the message: the union, and much more powerful with all the people of the city of Wichita that they joined the project to make this giant mural possible.</p>
<figure id="attachment_17579" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17579" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17579" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_3226-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_3226-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_3226-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_3226-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_3226-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_3226-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/IMG_3226-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17579" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Interior Gold&#8221; by GLEO, Lyon, France</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>If you could pick any building and location in the world for your next project, where would it be?</strong></p>
<p>Actually, it would be where the possibilities of painting the best I can. I just want to always have the opportunity.</p>
<p>Follow GLEO around the world via her Instagram @<a href="https://www.instagram.com/gleo_co/">gleo_co</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-gleo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculative-Inspired Arts: Shasta Schatz</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-inspired-arts-shasta-schatz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[D. M. Domosea]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The S Word]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17233</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This month in &#8220;Speculative-Inspired Arts&#8221;, hobby costumer Shasta Schatz dishes the details on both the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This month in &#8220;Speculative-Inspired Arts&#8221;, hobby costumer Shasta Schatz dishes the details on both the work and play sides of costuming and how she comes up with her best creations!</p>
<figure id="attachment_17235" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17235" style="width: 254px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17235" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/HistoricalHogwarts-254x300.jpg" alt="Historical Hogwarts" width="254" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/HistoricalHogwarts-254x300.jpg 254w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/HistoricalHogwarts-869x1024.jpg 869w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/HistoricalHogwarts-768x906.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/HistoricalHogwarts.jpg 916w" sizes="(max-width: 254px) 100vw, 254px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17235" class="wp-caption-text">Designer Shasta Schatz in her Historical Hogwarts costume.</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>You design costumes to wear at fairs, conventions and other gatherings. How do you pick the character or persona for each event?</strong></p>
<p>My projects are based on what I’m reading, watching, or playing at any given time, then I tailor those choices to the event that I’m attending. I fall in love with costume ideas pretty easily, but I have to be mindful of fandom, audience, and functionality. I wear comic book costumes to comic cons, but I make sure that the design elements are going to fit my activities. It would be ill-advised to walk around a vendor alley with five-foot wings, so I keep those characters for photoshoots. When we attend “Wizarding Weekend” at the Renaissance faire, our 16th century garb undergoes a Ravenclaw makeover with house colors and wands to fit the theme.</p>
<p><strong>You draw inspiration from a variety of sources, from graphic novels to TV shows. Do you find one type of source material easier to develop costumes from than others?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_17234" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17234" style="width: 172px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17234" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GeorgianStormSF-172x300.jpg" alt="" width="172" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GeorgianStormSF-172x300.jpg 172w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GeorgianStormSF-588x1024.jpg 588w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GeorgianStormSF-768x1337.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GeorgianStormSF-882x1536.jpg 882w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/GeorgianStormSF.jpg 1094w" sizes="(max-width: 172px) 100vw, 172px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17234" class="wp-caption-text">The X-Men&#8217;s Storm by way of the Georgian Era.</figcaption></figure>
<p>Ten years ago, I would have said that comic books are easiest because you can just look at the art and construct the costume as you see fit. Today I’d say that movie sources are where it’s at. When studios started releasing character art and books detailing what went into their costume design, the floodgates opened. All of a sudden hobbyists were exposed to behind-the-scenes processes and fabric sources. Now everyone knows the exact cloak closure for <em>Game of Thrones</em> Stark Bannerman #3. Costumes are going on tours around the world, people can watch interviews with designers to see intricate textures and even tutorials. The beginner skill level of costumers has jumped from “my grandma sewed this for me” to “I learned tambour embroidery just for the beading on this skirt panel.”</p>
<p><strong>Your designs involve much more than sewing. What other materials and skills go into making a full costume?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_17237" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17237" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17237" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/TwiLinkSF-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/TwiLinkSF-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/TwiLinkSF.jpg 667w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17237" class="wp-caption-text">Shasta models her Twi&#8217;Lek meets Link mashup</figcaption></figure>
<p>As far as materials go, nothing in my home, the hardware store, or the thrift store is safe. I’ve worked with a variety of craft and hardware foams, clay, LEDs, thermoplastics, wood, resins&#8211;pretty much any substance is a candidate for costume manipulation. In the beginning, my projects were a way to expand my sewing skills to include specialties like embroidery, while dabbling in jewelry making, wig styling, and numerous ways to rework yarn. These days, most of my costumes involve some level of foamsmithing, 3D printing, painting&#8211;both body and costume, power tools, and non-fabrication work including basic photography and web documentation.</p>
<p><strong>What’s the quickest you’ve ever put together a costume, and which one has taken the longest to create?</strong></p>
<p>From scratch, I made a Murloc from the World of Warcraft MMO in four hours. It was entirely felt and hot glue that I purchased on my lunch break that day, and it looked like a really sad mascot when I was done. But, I won a costume contest with it, so that was neat. My longest costume build was probably Georgian Storm. She took six months, starting with undergarments, and technically, I was still doing wig work at my booth the morning of the comic convention. I hand stitched more of that costume than I’d planned, but she was worth it.</p>
<p><strong>In addition to direct interpretation of characters, you also create great mashups (my favorite is Victorian Beach Storm!). What kind of reactions do you get when you wear these?</strong></p>
<figure id="attachment_17238" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17238" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17238" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/VictorianStormTDP-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/VictorianStormTDP-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/VictorianStormTDP-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/VictorianStormTDP-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/VictorianStormTDP-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/VictorianStormTDP-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/VictorianStormTDP-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17238" class="wp-caption-text">Victorian-era Beach Day Storm</figcaption></figure>
<p>Thank you! She was a one week build and super fun to design. The looks that my mashups receive are priceless. They range from confusion to appreciation to anger&#8211;since some people don’t know how to act when you mess with their favorite fictional characters. Most of the feedback, especially from other costumers is incredibly positive, and we end up geeking out over one detail or another. Outside of the community, I get a lot of “What are you supposed to be?” Those instances are my opportunity to start a conversation about how I chose to integrate elements from each fandom into the project. A benefit of mashups is that I’m not beholden to specific versions of characters, especially the ones that tend to flood events after a new movie release. That is where my creativity is happily challenged.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have a favorite fandom you like to work with? Which of your costumes has been your favorite to date?</strong></p>
<p>In general, I love comics the most because the art is open to interpretation: how true to a design you want to be, which artist’s rendering you prefer, adapting a classic color scheme and logo for a different take on a character. As a bonus, the longer a story has been running, or the number of arcs it’s taken in the life of a superhero or villain, the more options you have.</p>
<figure id="attachment_17236" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17236" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17236" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/RenaissanceBatgirlSF-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/RenaissanceBatgirlSF-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/RenaissanceBatgirlSF.jpg 667w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17236" class="wp-caption-text">Shasta as Renaissance Batgirl</figcaption></figure>
<p>These days, creators have even allowed the line between canon and fan art to blur, much to the delight of costumers. The DC Bombshells phenomenon (2011), wherein our favorite heroines received 1940s makeovers (which costumers had been doing for years), is still providing fantastic material for the community.</p>
<p>Renaissance Batgirl is my baby! I made her in 2012 to wear opposite my husband’s Renaissance Superman that I made in 2009. The entire costume was made from fabric remnants and curtains that I had in my stash&#8211;you can even see spots where I had to piece the fabric together to make it work. I keep upgrading her accessories and making small repairs, but the base costume stays the same. She is a perfect blend of my love for historical costuming and comic books.</p>
<p><strong>What projects do you currently have on your table?</strong></p>
<p>Right now, I’m finishing up Orko from <em>He-Man &amp; The Masters of the Universe</em>, as part of a 50+ person cosplay group debuting in the spring. My current mash-up project, which will debut the same weekend, is an 18th century version of Princess Allura from Voltron&#8211;think “Pastoral Cat Lady”. For this one, I custom designed fabric which was such a neat experience!</p>
<p>Follow Shasta at her <a href="https://greenlinenshirt.com/">website</a> and on <a href="http://instagram.com/scificheergirl">Instagram</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/greenlinenshirt/">Facebook</a> or <a href="http://twitter.com/scificheergirl">Twitter</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
