<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Macabre Mama &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/macabre-mama/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 18:46:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Creature Feature: Koji A. Dae, Scars That Never Bled</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/creature-feature-koji-a-dae-scars-that-never-bled/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/creature-feature-koji-a-dae-scars-that-never-bled/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[C.S. Williams]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 18:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Macabre Mama]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m taking a little bit of a different approach this month. A friend of mine&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m taking a little bit of a different approach this month. A friend of mine released her first ever poetry chapbook early this August and it. Is. Gorgeous. Of course if you’re worried that poetry isn’t horror enough, then you’re in for a treat.</p>
<p>When I first got my hands on this chapbook I couldn&#8217;t wait to dig in. Horror-y goodness comes in <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19428 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freestocks-2UDlp4foic4-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freestocks-2UDlp4foic4-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freestocks-2UDlp4foic4-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freestocks-2UDlp4foic4-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freestocks-2UDlp4foic4-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/freestocks-2UDlp4foic4-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />many packages but for me, poetry is extra special. Emotional and deeply personal, poetry has a way of reaching to the core of who we are. It allows us introspection and a way to relate with the triumphs, pain, and struggles others face. Horror immerses us in a world where monsters roam unchecked and darkness pervades all we are. Put them together and we begin to question, what is man? What is monster? What separates us and what makes us the same? This book delivered on every level.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Koji-Dae/dp/6197588005/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;keywords=scars+that+never+bled&amp;qid=1597820906&amp;sr=8-1"><em>Scars That Never Bled</em></a> is an exploration of Frankenstein through poetic form, paralleling themes from Mary Shelley&#8217;s literary classic with issues that remain relevant today. If you’ve ever felt outcast, alone, or rejected, this book is for you. If you’ve ever felt like a stranger in your own skin, this book is for you. <a href="https://kojiadae.ink/">Koji A. Dae</a> isn&#8217;t afraid to explore the darker aspects of our humanity, questioning our morals, our need to categorize, the pains of womanhood, birth, and creation. She tackles themes of depression and self harm all with honesty and precise, beautiful language.</p>
<p>Each chapter has been beautifully divided into tarot cards—one of the first seven major arcana—shedding light on the creature&#8217;s journey from a different perspective. I worked through these chapters slowly. Often I would read two, maybe three poems in a sitting and take the time to meditate and reflect on what I’d read. I saw myself in each and every poem. I could relate to the struggles of the characters, of the author, on both sympathetic and personal levels.</p>
<p>The first chapter is admittedly my favorite. It follows the creature (The Fool) from his birth, to rejection, to his demand for another like him. The creature has always been my favorite as I see his struggle as the most human. The last poem in this chapter, titled :Language,&#8221; was, in my opinion, one of the strongest of the set. The creature learns to speak, a painful process with no guidance, but through the pain he learns to speak up for himself and gains the strength to say “no.”</p>
<p>If you enjoy Frankenstein, you’ll love this modern reinterpretation of a classic. I highly recommend this book for poetry and horror fans alike. If you’re intimidated by poetry, don’t be! Koji’s writing remains deep and beautiful without overly complex language. While it can easily be read in an afternoon, I recommend taking your time with this one.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/creature-feature-koji-a-dae-scars-that-never-bled/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>That&#8217;s Not Horror!: Elements of the Genre</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/thats-not-horror-elements-of-the-genre/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[C.S. Williams]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 10:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Macabre Mama]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I decided to write, I knew exactly the genre I would delve into. I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I decided to write, I knew exactly the genre I would delve into. I wanted to create realities suspended in darkness. Atmospheric and beautifully eerie. Something to make folks shriek and shiver with delight. Unfortunately for me, horror is decidedly a tricky genre to master.</p>
<p>Beside the already daunting task of pulling new ideas out of the abyss, horror often mixes in elements of other genres, making it more palatable for some audiences but also more difficult to pinpoint which elements make it a distinct genre all its own.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18063 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/vincent-price-394306_1280-300x216.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="216" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/vincent-price-394306_1280-300x216.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/vincent-price-394306_1280-1024x736.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/vincent-price-394306_1280-768x552.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/vincent-price-394306_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />At its most basic, <a href="https://www.vulture.com/2018/12/horror-is-not-defined-by-what-scares-you.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">horror is defined as an intense feeling of fear, shock or disgust.</a> Word that in any way you like. Terror, dread, revulsion, discomfort, unease. The idea is to scare the pants off the audience. But using individual or universal fears will only get you so far, because let’s face it, I’ve been watching horror for a long time. I have a hole in my soul where terror should live, and I’m probably going to laugh at a lot of what terrifies you.</p>
<p>Does this mean your kind of horror isn’t scary? Not at all, it just means that “scary” is subjective. Which means using “scary” to define horror as a genre is going to leave a few people screaming, “But that’s not horror!”</p>
<p>Oh boy, here we go.</p>
<p><a href="https://annieneugebauer.com/2013/06/03/what-is-horror/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Just because something doesn’t scare you personally doesn’t mean it isn’t scary to someone else.</a> Horror is much more than cheap scare tactics. So how do we reach into the largest portion of our potential audience? Let’s look at it from a different perspective.</p>
<p>If we shift the focus off you, the audience, and focus on our protagonist, then what matters is what your character fears most. After all, this story isn’t about you, is it? Our protagonist is the driving force behind the story. They’re the reason we’re indulging in such a gruesome and unsettling world. What they fear matters. What happens to them matters. Horror is an exercise in empathy, so if we care about our protagonist, we’ll be scared for them. This works a lot better than catering to the individual fears of our audience.</p>
<p>It’s all about that character agency. How does the protagonist react when they are immersed in danger? What decisions will they have to make in order to survive? How do they shape the story around them?</p>
<p>With horror, what really leaves us on the edge of our seat is watching the protagonist lose control in a world where loss of agency means death (or worse).</p>
<p><a href="https://storygrid.com/secrets-of-the-horror-genre/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">What makes horror unique</a> is the atmosphere the protagonist is immersed in. Their world is dark, unpredictable, and inhabited by terrible evils/forces bent on destruction. Failure doesn’t only affect the protagonist. Many lives are at stake, chances of success are slim, and the protagonist is our last line of defense. We fear that they will be injured, captured, killed, or faced with a fate worse than death. Once that happens, they are no longer able to progress in the story and all hope is lost. It&#8217;s life vs. death, good vs. evil.</p>
<p>Universal fears have their place, too. They use instantly recognizable imagery to exploit what <img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-18905 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/hand-984170_1280-300x224-1.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="224" />Stephen King calls our “phobic pressure points.” Monsters, darkness, isolation, the unknown: these elements challenge our feelings of security. They make us feel alone, vulnerable, helpless. Gore creates a visceral response, reminding us that we are human, we experience pain and face mortality.</p>
<p>Horror makes us face our deepest fears. We want the protagonist to succeed because their success represents our ability to overcome impossible odds, vanquish evil, and live on. It&#8217;s the ability to empathize with a character so deeply that we experience fear and distress on their behalf that makes horror truly shine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Homage to Horror Moms</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/homage-to-horror-moms/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/homage-to-horror-moms/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[C.S. Williams]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 14:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Macabre Mama]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another Mother&#8217;s Day has come and gone. I would be remiss not to pay homage&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17996 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bed-1293442_1280-300x207.png" alt="" width="300" height="207" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bed-1293442_1280-300x207.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bed-1293442_1280-1024x706.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bed-1293442_1280-768x530.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bed-1293442_1280.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Another Mother&#8217;s Day has come and gone. I would be remiss not to pay homage to the woman who, for better or worse, has largely shaped me into the person I am today.</p>
<p>That includes my lifelong obsession with horror.</p>
<p>My mom started it all. Rarely was she seen without a Stephen King or Dean Koontz novel in arm&#8217;s reach and I began raiding her bookshelves as soon as she would let me. We spent countless nights tucked onto the sofa with the enormous bowl of popcorn that would inevitably be up-heaved, peering wide eyed through buttery fingers at the terrors on screen. Vampires, demons, ghosts, serial killers, swamp creatures, aliens&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.imdb.com/list/ls097172256/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">My mom loves it all.</a></p>
<p>From campy flicks like <em>Evil Dead</em> and <em>Killer Klowns From Outer Space</em> to some seriously chilling paranormals like <em>The Conjuring.</em> (Hide and clap? Are you kidding?)</p>
<p>I slept with my ears plugged and face covered so I wasn&#8217;t invaded with jellyfish-like, alien tendrils. I didn&#8217;t look in mirrors after dark. And if there was a knocking or scratching on the wall, you can bet I didn&#8217;t stick around to figure out what it was!</p>
<p>I also liked to go bump in the night, convincing my siblings the knocking was real, their favorite blanket was possessed, Jason Voorhees lived in their closet, and there existed an otherworldly creature under the bed. Yeah&#8230;I was that sister.</p>
<p>Even though it led to more than a few sleepless nights and possibly a few night terrors, (Seriously, does anyone remember where the limbless, bearded fellow hung from the roof and bumping the window came from?) I wouldn&#8217;t trade those moments for anything.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.littlethings.com/health-benefits-of-horror-movies/6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Because Horror isn&#8217;t all bad.</a> It has given me a different perspective on the world. There may be some unholy terrors lurking in the dark, but dawn is so much sweeter when you&#8217;ve been watching shadows. Horror can be cathartic, giving you a safe space to explore primal fears. It connects us with the people around us, creating an intimacy and bond that would not be possible without enduring and surviving together, even if only through a 2 hour jump fest. It creates a sense of being &#8220;alive&#8221; and there is something empowering about watching a tough protagonist look Evil in the face and then kick its ass.</p>
<p>Not least importantly, there are beautiful things in the dark too. So much of our world hinges on what is &#8220;good&#8221; that we forget, good does not exist without evil. Not everything strange and unusual is a threat. Fear can stem from misunderstanding and through horror, we can explore the intricacies of character we would otherwise dismiss. Maybe that creature under the bed just really needed a friend?</p>
<p>So here&#8217;s to you, Mom. And to the <a href="https://filmschoolrejects.com/horror-moms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">horror moms</a> like you!<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18066 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/mask-2028211_1280-193x300.png" alt="" width="193" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/mask-2028211_1280-193x300.png 193w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/mask-2028211_1280-658x1024.png 658w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/mask-2028211_1280-768x1196.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/mask-2028211_1280.png 822w" sizes="(max-width: 193px) 100vw, 193px" /></p>
<p>Thanks for always allowing me to go to school in costume and for picking me up when mine was too scary for the faculty. Thank you for the books that I may or may not have returned. Thank you for enduring the sleepless nights, the bad dreams, the pranks and the spilled popcorn.</p>
<p>Even if it was totally your fault.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/homage-to-horror-moms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
