<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Atmosphere as Character &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/atmosphere-as-character/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 11:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Taxed</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/taxed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 10:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many of my favorite artists and content creators cannot be found on the shelves of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many of my favorite artists and content creators cannot be found on the shelves of Barnes &amp; Noble, or within the hydra warehouses of Big Box stores. But I try to support them as individuals through monetization platforms such as Etsy, Kickstarter, Patreon, Society6, and YouTube. These platforms are far from perfect, but that is not my main point today: I’m worried about the 2023 tax season, and how it’s going to negatively affect the US-based creators that I love.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27402 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />The purpose of <a href="https://www.irs.gov/businesses/understanding-your-form-1099-k">IRS form 1099-K</a> is to tax individuals for the money they earn based on goods/services that are filtered through a third-party payment network. For example, if someone sells a sculpture on Etsy and the payment of that sale is processed via Paypal. Previously, mandatory reporting of such sales was only required for those earning over $20,000 through at least 200 unique transactions. This rule makes some sense to me – many people earn a hefty living through such transactions on platforms like Airbnb.</p>
<p>However, as of March 11, 2021, reporting such transactions for tax purposes has been lowered to a mere $600 per year, and the threshold of transactions lowered from 200 to 1. One! This legislation, passed in Section 9674 of the American Rescue Plan, confuses me beyond belief. It’s so ridiculous that it makes me question my own reading comprehension. Why, in the middle of a pandemic that has forced millions into economic insecurity, would the government punch down this way?</p>
<p>The creation of art already costs plenty in labor, love, and time. But it also costs in materials and fees. For example, <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/economy/why-etsys-latest-fee-increase-has-inspired-thousands-of-sellers-including-its-most-marginalized-to-strike">Etsy charges sellers a flat 6.5% fee for every transaction</a>, a 20-cent fee for listing any item that is then <strong>re-charged </strong>every time it sells, and a whopping 12-15% fee for transactions that the almighty-algorithm determines to have been made as a result of on- or off-site advertising efforts. <a href="https://www.etsy.com/legal/fees/">This fee chain</a> doesn&#8217;t even address the monetary loss associated with returns/complaints due to supply-chain issues beyond creator control, or VAT on overseas shipping, or high consumer expectations that shipping be fast/free. The struggle of the artist is real.</p>
<p>Another concern I have with this newly altered legislation is privacy. For instance, content creators on Onlyfans are self-employed contractors in the eyes of the IRS. But the internet can be a dangerous place, and a creator having their <a href="https://pappas.house.gov/sites/pappas.house.gov/files/1099%20Letter%20-%20FINAL.pdf">social security number</a> confirmed to their account may place them in undue risk of social or financial repercussion. No commercial website is too big or small to be hacked and exploited.</p>
<p>I hope these tax changes become common knowledge for people who engage with and support individual content creators in the United States. There is no science to the price of art &#8211; but for many the cost of doing business has just risen. Thankfully, April 2023 is an entire year away, and <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/internal-revenue-service-taxes-irs-1099-k-form-tracking-payment-transactions-credit-card-venmo-privacy-breach-cybersecurity-11648745007">opposition</a> to the change is gaining traction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nightscapes</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/nightscapes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 11:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Living in a large metro area has economic advantages that I have relied on to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Living in a large metro area has economic advantages that I have relied on to survive, but one downside has been weighing on me more than most: <strong>light</strong>.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27192 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/full-moon-1869760_960_720-300x261.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="261" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/full-moon-1869760_960_720-300x261.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/full-moon-1869760_960_720-768x668.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/full-moon-1869760_960_720.jpg 828w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />The level of light pollution near my home is heavy, and keeps me from enjoying the actual &#8220;night&#8221; part of nighttime. I used to live in an International Dark Sky city (Flagstaff, AZ, USA), and that 3-year experience was pure magic in altering my perception of space. Oceans of stars interrupted by the black voids of mountains and plateaus. It was bewitching, and my first week there I struggled to accept how I could have lived 30 years on Earth before actually <strong><em>seeing</em> </strong>the sky.</p>
<p>During my time there as a college student, I cherished going for long walks after work and watching the common occurrence of meteor showers and falling stars. I could see the Milky Way, but not my hand in front of my face! Even the texture of the moon was crisp.</p>
<p>Now, being so preoccupied making the most of each day, I admit that sometimes I have taken darkness for granted. And living where I do now, without being able to experience nighttime, I fail to celebrate dusk the way I do the dawn.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27190 alignleft" src="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/milky-way-6657951__340-300x200.webp" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/milky-way-6657951__340-300x200.webp 300w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/milky-way-6657951__340.webp 510w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />But darkness is sacred and in urgent need of protection. As much as I want to travel back to dark skies whenever time and money permit, a better choice is to do all I can to encourage the restoration of darkness where I live. Tracing constellations on a computer screen or even through a telescope can’t compare to the immersive wonder of a full, panoramic nightscape that dissolves along the periphery of vision. It&#8217;s easy to be awestruck and inspired; I&#8217;m hardly an outlier in finding many of favorite speculative films and stories surround the mysteries of space.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27191 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/milky-way-2695569__480-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/milky-way-2695569__480-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/milky-way-2695569__480-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/milky-way-2695569__480.jpg 853w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />If you&#8217;re curious what we can do as individuals and communities to protect the night, I recommend checking out more information at the official website of the <a href="https://www.darksky.org/">International Dark-Sky Association</a>. It has a lot of guides detailing how nature and people are affected by light pollution, and positive steps to take that have proven effective. Maps are also included to direct you towards your nearest Dark Sky location. I hope one is close to you.</p>
<p>(Not to sound too much like Snake Plissken, but I hope dark skies are close to all of us someday).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Underwater</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/underwater/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 12:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Movies anchored underwater share a lot with movies set in space. Both locations provide ample&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Movies anchored underwater share a lot with movies set in space. Both locations provide ample opportunities to explore the mysterious and unknown. Both tend to focus on a small group of explorers being picked off – falling victim to the hazards of their environment or their own ranks.</p>
<p>I love it. But if I had to pick a favorite, underwater movies have the edge. Because, unlike space, being underwater is a feeling I know. I’ve touched it in baths, oceans, beverages, etc.. It composes most of my being, and I respect that it saves and ends lives. But you could not <strong>pay</strong> me to board a submarine.</p>
<p>Try. You&#8217;ll barely get me in a paddleboat.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26913 alignleft" src="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/helm-677990_960_720-300x202.webp" alt="" width="300" height="202" srcset="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/helm-677990_960_720-300x202.webp 300w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/helm-677990_960_720-768x518.webp 768w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/helm-677990_960_720.webp 960w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Some classics of the wet-n-spooky genre are <em>The Abyss</em> (1989) <em>Deep Star Six</em> (1989), <em>Leviathan</em> (1989), <em>Sphere</em> (1998), <em>Deep Blue Sea</em> (1999), and <em>Below</em> (2002). A newer release that I enjoyed is <em>Underwater</em> (2020).</p>
<p>I admit the title is – not great – and the movie was shelved for three years before being released direct to video in January. But the high points of <em>Underwater</em> readily outmatch the flaws.</p>
<p>My favorite element is how quickly the film conjures its atmospheric quality of actually <u>feeling underwater</u>. It maintains that tone the entire time, and it is this elusive quality so many movies with bigger budgets and better acclaim have failed to achieve.</p>
<p>Start with the beginning. The introductory credits are dark and moody in just the right way to make you feel <strong>submerged</strong>. They set the palette of the film, a reminder to turn off your lights and prepare for action. If I could compare it to anything, I’d say this intro feels like strapping into a carnival ride as metal tracks steer towards a tunnel. The soundtrack is excellent as well, thudding like the approaching footsteps of someone dangerous.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26914 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/bubbles-1836457_960_720-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/bubbles-1836457_960_720-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/bubbles-1836457_960_720-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/bubbles-1836457_960_720.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Heroine Kristen Stewart and her opening monologue provide the context needed for all that comes next. I love her portrayal and ability to be stoic in one scene, trembling in another, but always consistent to character. Her vulnerability and resolve are relatable, especially during interior shots in her dive helmet as she tries to recalculate options of survival. Interactions between her and the captain are particularly strong.</p>
<p>As a Lovecraftian creature feature, <em>Underwater</em> has predictable oodles of CGI. However, this was well balanced with practical effects – particularly via the dive suits. They look functional, industrial, and just plain <strong>heavy</strong>. I enjoyed how often they meshed with the plot, enough to feel like characters themselves.</p>
<p>Almost obligatory for the genre, <em>Underwater</em> is yet another monster movie featuring an autopsy scene of what the human characters are up against. That these characters were able to inspect a practical-effects creature model inside their rig helped provide weight to the CGI masses.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26915 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/bubbles-230014_960_720-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="324" height="243" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/bubbles-230014_960_720-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/bubbles-230014_960_720-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/bubbles-230014_960_720.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 324px) 100vw, 324px" />CGI, as much as it can make movies feel like a video game, really aided in providing consistent tension and maintaining that “under the depths” feeling. Paths of bubbles showcase the dangers of ascension as well as debris. The pluming of sediment and diffusion of light is phenomenal. Not being able to see <em>quite</em> as much as you want can be frustrating, but isn’t that true to life? Since when does shining a flashlight guarantee your shin from smacking that coffee table?</p>
<p>This movie is super worth the watch. TJ Miller is a low point, and you’ll crave a mini-map, but <em>Underwater</em> is solid action with some standout moments of aquatic perfection.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Collagen Games</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-collagen-games/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 11:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you ever assumed movie characters to be father and daughter, only to realize they&#8217;re&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26738 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Sleepy_hollow_ver2-220x300.jpg" alt="" width="175" height="238" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Sleepy_hollow_ver2-220x300.jpg 220w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Sleepy_hollow_ver2.jpg 270w" sizes="(max-width: 175px) 100vw, 175px" />Have you ever assumed movie characters to be father and daughter, only to realize they&#8217;re lovers? This happened to me, at least for the first time, when I saw the theatrical poster for <em>Sleepy Hollow</em> (1999). In it, Christina Ricci looks younger than her 19 years, and Johnny Depp older than his 36. This led to quite the surprise actually watching the movie, and that&#8217;s when I started to understand how Hollywood stamps women with some pretty ridiculous expiration dates.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t even say this is only a problem in obvious spaces like the <em>James Bond</em> franchise; it&#8217;s baked into each and every genre of film. Perpetual female youth is so embedded in the entertainment industry that minors are commonly cast and even scouted as the young partners of older men. Just one example is Keira Knightley, 17 when filming <em>Pirates of the Carribean: The Curse of the Black Pearl</em> (2001). Five films later, Knightley is approaching her 40s and clearly getting phased out in favor of younger flesh.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26739 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/p22964_p_v10_ad-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/p22964_p_v10_ad-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/p22964_p_v10_ad-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/p22964_p_v10_ad-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/p22964_p_v10_ad.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />In <em>Entrapment</em> (1999), Catherine Zeta-Jones is almost 40 years younger than romantic leading man Sean Connery. Some call it action/adventure, but it&#8217;s actually the director&#8217;s cut of a Cialis commercial.</p>
<p>Milla Jovovich with Bruce Willis in <em>The Fifth Element</em> (1997). Scarlet Johansson with Bill Murray in <em>Lost in Translation</em> (2003).Natalie Portman with Hugo Weaving in <em>V for Vendetta</em> (2005). The list is always getting longer, because casting directors tell us that men age like fine wine and women age like hot yogurt.</p>
<p>So that&#8217;s the bad. And while there&#8217;s nothing wrong with partners being noticeably different in age, Hollywood is too one-sided to claim the whole &#8220;love is blind&#8221; banner.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the good! If you&#8217;re craving a speculative movie that features an older actress in the badass headliner role she deserves, I&#8217;ve got some picks. None of these deal much with romance, but do reinforce this crazy idea that aging is a fact, actresses exist after wrinkles, and we&#8217;re damn lucky to have them.</p>
<p><strong>1. The Manor (2021)</strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26740 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tm-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tm-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/tm.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<p><strong>Plot:</strong> Barbara Hershey plays a widow who, after suffering a mild stroke, doesn&#8217;t want to burden her family and decides to move to a retirement home. Unbeknownst to her, but quickly&#8230;knownst&#8230;her new home has a dark side teeming with suspicious characters and a supernatural mystery.</p>
<p><strong>What I Loved:</strong> The family dynamic and dialogue are hyper realistic. Too many movies portray grandmothers as pearl-clutching-cardigan-clad-baking-machines. But Hershey&#8217;s character is quick-witted and active. She&#8217;s casually foul-mouthed without it feeling forced or played for laughs. She&#8217;s not ready for a Golden Girls haircut, or someone to monitor her vitamins. She encounters every situation with such true to life reactions as &#8220;holy shit&#8221; and &#8220;no fucking way.&#8221; Her character refuses to follow your assumptions, right through to the end credits.</p>
<p><strong>2. Relic (2020)<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26744 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/r-1-210x300.jpg" alt="" width="210" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/r-1-210x300.jpg 210w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/r-1-717x1024.jpg 717w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/r-1-768x1097.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/r-1-1075x1536.jpg 1075w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/r-1.jpg 1240w" sizes="(max-width: 210px) 100vw, 210px" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Plot:</strong> Robyn Nevin stars as a grandmother whose increasingly erratic behavior is attributed to dementia. Her middle-aged daughter and young-adult granddaughter round out the major characters, presenting a mystery to solve that is monstrous, tender, and will probably make you cry.</p>
<p><strong>What I Loved:</strong> The practical effects are gorgeous to look at, and the muted atmosphere works well to drive home the narrative of maiden-mother-crone inevitability. Writer/director Natalie Erika James really impresses with her camerawork, and knows how to make something as vast as the unknown feel claustrophobic.</p>
<p><strong>3. The Butterfly Room (2012)<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26742 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TBR-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TBR-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/TBR.jpg 534w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Plot:</strong> Although this only toes the line as a fantasy film, the story is so ridiculous that my brain boxes it into that neighborhood anyways. Barbara Steele plays a butterfly-obsessed, lonely woman. Her life is upended after she strikes up an unexpected friendship with a young girl. The child is not so naïve as she appears and a worthy match for Steele&#8217;s character, who is of course hiding some sinister secrets of her own.</p>
<p><strong>What I Loved:</strong> I could watch Barbara Steele make facial expressions all day. Her deep-set gaze and severe eyebrows are just TOPS. The character she portrays in the film is conniving and manipulative, but I found myself rooting for her anyways. She&#8217;s proof that an actress doesn&#8217;t have to be large or tall or muscular to be physically imposing. As a bonus that sets it apart from other films in this list, Steele&#8217;s character <em>could</em> have been a woman of any age and still made sense for the plot.</p>
<p><strong>4. The Taking of Deborah Logan (2014)<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26747 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ttodl-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ttodl-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ttodl-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ttodl-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ttodl-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ttodl-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ttodl.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Plot:</strong> An elderly woman, thought to have Alzheimer&#8217;s, allows a group of film students to document her at home and in the hospital while she undergoes experimental treatments.  As strange outbursts start to escalate and her behavior changes, the students realize how much danger they&#8217;ve actually wandered into.</p>
<p><strong>What I Loved:</strong> The first half of the movie. Honestly, I felt the plot twists could have been better. However, Jill Larson is fantastic in this. She spent over 20 years as a major character in <em>All My Children</em>, and those soap opera chops have clearly helped her perfect the art of the stare-down. As Deborah Logan, Larson spends a lot of time whiplashed between outrage and confusion. I&#8217;m sure her time in TV drama helped this portrayal feel as engaging as it does.</p>
<p>This movie has two scenes of nudity with an elderly female character, and that felt so defiant to me when I saw this. She&#8217;s shown as a person &#8211; a living, breathing animal that has breasts. I watched this feature with a guy, and his brain seemed to <em>completely</em> short circuit at the visual. He told me he felt embarrassed, like &#8220;watching something I&#8217;m not supposed to see.&#8221;</p>
<p>But breasts, just like the women they&#8217;re attached to, exist regardless of your feelings. They exist whether or not they&#8217;re youthful, and whether or not they&#8217;re sexualized.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26748 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0177a19e4d2c30c33bbda0a022c65382860ecec203d19878bce105372229401a._RI_V_TTW_-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0177a19e4d2c30c33bbda0a022c65382860ecec203d19878bce105372229401a._RI_V_TTW_-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0177a19e4d2c30c33bbda0a022c65382860ecec203d19878bce105372229401a._RI_V_TTW_-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0177a19e4d2c30c33bbda0a022c65382860ecec203d19878bce105372229401a._RI_V_TTW_-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0177a19e4d2c30c33bbda0a022c65382860ecec203d19878bce105372229401a._RI_V_TTW_-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/0177a19e4d2c30c33bbda0a022c65382860ecec203d19878bce105372229401a._RI_V_TTW_.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />It&#8217;s too early to know if 2022 will be a good year in film, but I absolutely want to see more middle aged and elderly characters, wholly embraced as protagonists.</p>
<p>One hopeful on my horizon is the reboot of <em>Urban Legend</em>, and 99% of that excitement comes from the promised return of Loretta Devine. She was <strong>hands down</strong> the best part of the first two films, and I&#8217;m super excited for her to come back and kick butt in the reboot. If the developers have any sense at all, they&#8217;ll put her on the cover this time!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fantasy Scrapbooks</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fantasy-scrapbooks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 13:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Scrapbooking can be a beast of a hobby. What begins as a simple project, at&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scrapbooking can be a beast of a hobby. What begins as a simple project, at least for me, spirals into piles of decorative paper, cat photos, stickers, illustrations, and did I say cat photos?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26591 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-7767-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-7767-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-7767-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-7767-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-7767-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-7767-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-7767-2048x2048.jpg 2048w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-7767-550x550.jpg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Yes. His name is David, and at sweet-sixteen he&#8217;s achieved true sassiness.</p>
<p>For years, I&#8217;ve made an annual scrapbook around Christmastime. They&#8217;re cute, cheerful, and I enjoy being able to almost document each year I&#8217;ve shared with my partner and our many pets. But I do have to admit the <em>almost</em>, because my scrapbooks are a bit of a fantasy.</p>
<p>Revisionist history, if you want to be strict about it. I  don&#8217;t allow any pain or negativity in these things.</p>
<p>Do you have a place like this in your life? Somewhere that you collect joy, or achievements, and refuse to cross-contaminate with the bleaker parts of daily reality?</p>
<p>I used to wrestle with that, and worry I was being deceptive. <em>Isn&#8217;t it manipulation, to only tell part of the truth? Isn&#8217;t it wrong, to pretend bad things aren&#8217;t happening?</em></p>
<p>Right now I&#8217;m working on my scrapbook for 2021, and I refuse to include anything to do with politics or hospitals or debt. In a way, it feels dismissive of true troubles. At the same time&#8230;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-26595 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-9962-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="730" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-9962-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-9962-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-9962-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-9962-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-9962-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-9962-2048x2048.jpg 2048w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-9962-550x550.jpg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /></p>
<p>&#8230;look at this puppy. Her name is Ellie, and she just turned two. In a strange way, keeping bad experiences away from my scrapbooks feels like keeping bad experiences away from her. It&#8217;s the same as when I used to keep a daily journal or diary &#8211; I&#8217;ve always tried to focus on the positive.</p>
<p>It felt transgressive, cropping the urn out of this photograph. And I felt a little guilty, as though I had cropped a loved one from my life.</p>
<p>But I need to remind myself that this is not true. The reality is that I don&#8217;t need reminders for the memories that weigh me down. I couldn&#8217;t forget, even if I wanted to. What lifts me up, without an undertow of sadness &#8211; those are the thoughts and memories I want to purposefully cultivate. It is a fantasy timeline, but my scrapbooks are condensed and portable joy.</p>
<p>Besides, they&#8217;re probably the only place I can swoon over how cute my aquariums are. Mammals are pretty easy to love, but let&#8217;s not forget the aqua life.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26597 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-8169-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-8169-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-8169-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-8169-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-8169-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-8169-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-8169-2048x2048.jpg 2048w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/IMG-8169-550x550.jpg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />That snail on the left is Bunny. She&#8217;s who-knows-how-old, and is photographed with one of her many daughters and grandbabies. I have oodles of fish and invertebrates at home. Some have teeth, some eat wood, some swim upside down. One likes to frolic in bubbles and many, like that corydoras in the background, look perpetually alarmed.</p>
<p>But in the scrapbook they go. And I really hope, with 2022 just around the corner, that you have a happy place like this in your world. Whether it&#8217;s an altar or website or journal &#8211; even just a corner of your mind. Joy is worth protecting.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Do You Like Your Movies?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/how-do-you-like-your-movies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 11:18:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26318</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In my life so far, there have been two movies that I really cherished going&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In my life so far, there have been two movies that I really cherished going to see in theaters. One is <em>The Mummy</em> from 1999, and the other is<em> The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers</em> from 2002.</p>
<p>Those two features felt perfect for the big screen. Sweeping landscapes, massive battles, and cutting edge (for the time) special effects. I remember feeling hypnotized, and in both films forgetting the audience of strangers all around me.</p>
<p>Looking back, though, I think that magic is gone. Not from the world exactly, maybe just relocated.</p>
<p>In 1999 and 2002, I didn’t have a lot of options. I was too young to buy electronics and was not trusted to cultivate my own space for relaxation. When I was just a kid at home, being loud or enjoying loud things was strictly off-limits.</p>
<p>Back then, the theater felt amazing because I really wanted to forget where I was.</p>
<p>But that was then.</p>
<p>Now, I’m an adult renting a single-family house. I make all the noise I want. And if my partner needs quiet, I’ve got a comfy headset. It gives me the surround sound of a theater, and <a href="https://canadianaudiologist.ca/movies-too-loud/#:~:text=Levels%20above%20115%20dB%20SPL,moviegoers%20to%20expect%20much%20change.">doesn’t try to break my eardrums</a>.</p>
<p>That comparison, between public and private movie viewing, has been clanking through my mind since yesterday &#8211; when I went to the theater for the first time in three years.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-26319 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0627-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="240" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0627-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0627-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0627-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0627-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0627-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 320px) 100vw, 320px" />It was creepy. And empty.</p>
<p>The parking lot was empty. The lobby was empty. The screening theater was empty. Even the person checking tickets was idle, despite also running the concessions counter <em>alone</em>.</p>
<p>I paid $13.50 for the ticket, $5.29 for a 20 oz bottle of water (no water fountains or reusables allowed), and $4.99 for a bag of gummies (no outside food allowed). After taxes, that’s $24.40.</p>
<p>And because the movie I chose turned out to be predictable and dull, that number was the only reason I didn’t walk out. I watched the movie, wishing I had waited for streaming. With patience, I probably could have rented it for under $4. In another few months, I could have bought the DVD for about the cost of the ticket.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26320 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0629-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="447" height="335" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0629-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0629-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0629-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0629-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/IMG-0629-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 447px) 100vw, 447px" /></p>
<p>When marketing movie theaters, a lot of positive is said about the “experience and atmosphere.” But I think I’ve grown spoiled by the convenience, comfort, and cost-effectiveness of home viewing. I like watching movies in pajamas. I like on-screen subtitles. Being about to pause to use the bathroom without missing anything. Being able to shout at the screen and interact with the film. And I love being able to walk the twenty steps to my kitchen to grab snacks. For the price of gummies and water at the theater, I could go a grocery store and buy a pound of grapes, a sleeve of crackers, and indulge my obsession with aged cheddar. I could rent at least three movies for the price of one ticket.</p>
<p>But let’s say I want to see a movie with a large group of people – too many for the size of my television. It is <strong>still</strong> cheaper to buy a digital projector or inflatable screen for home or backyard use. As the upcharge at theaters has risen, personal technology only continues to become more accessible.</p>
<p>Theaters were a happy part of my childhood. But if <em>The Mummy</em> or <em>The Lord of the Rings </em>were released tomorrow, I would choose to enjoy them at home. Afterwards, if I was really missing that certain kind of nostalgic atmosphere, I would find it elsewhere. Maybe I’d go play mini golf with some friends. Or we’d go to an arcade to play ski-ball. For little more than theater prices, we could do karaoke and Korean barbeque. If I&#8217;m craving a dim room with recessed colored lights, the smell of rubber floors, and the babble of strangers having fun nearby, I’ve got options. The red velvet curtains I associate with theaters are pretty, but I&#8217;d rather have a blanket in my lap. Coffee table beats cup holder any day of the week.</p>
<p>I wish I could say going to the cinema was still on my list of fun outings, because I truly cherish movies. But as a consumer, I honestly don’t know what could change to lure me back. When I found myself in that empty theater yesterday, watching a new release not available for streaming, my realization felt overdue. Mentally, I spent the runtime listing all the wonderful reasons movies have become so blissful to watch at home.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Allyship with Arkasha Stevenson</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/allyship-with-arkasha-stevenson/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 14:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26108</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When Arkasha Stevenson wrote and directed &#8220;Vessels&#8221; in 2015, she was still a film student.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When Arkasha Stevenson wrote and directed &#8220;Vessels&#8221; in 2015, she was still a film student. Yet for all her inexperience, she understood what many in Hollywood do not: the importance of representation behind and before the camera.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26109 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/MV5BMjM5MDExNjMyOV5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTgwOTcyMjM3NjE@._V1_-203x300.jpg" alt="" width="203" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/MV5BMjM5MDExNjMyOV5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTgwOTcyMjM3NjE@._V1_-203x300.jpg 203w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/MV5BMjM5MDExNjMyOV5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTgwOTcyMjM3NjE@._V1_-693x1024.jpg 693w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/MV5BMjM5MDExNjMyOV5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTgwOTcyMjM3NjE@._V1_-768x1135.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/MV5BMjM5MDExNjMyOV5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTgwOTcyMjM3NjE@._V1_-1040x1536.jpg 1040w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/MV5BMjM5MDExNjMyOV5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTgwOTcyMjM3NjE@._V1_.jpg 1102w" sizes="(max-width: 203px) 100vw, 203px" /></p>
<p>I’ve seen many films and TV episodes involving cisgender individuals playing a transgender role, and it’s always been disappointing (here’s looking at you, Sir Michael Cain). But &#8220;Vessels&#8221; doesn’t even so much as dabble in that bullshit. Instead, &#8220;Vessels&#8221; casts three transgender women to play three transgender characters, and their performances are achingly passionate. This is not a camp story; it’s a quiet drama that unfolds like a midnight fairytale.</p>
<p>&#8220;Vessels&#8221; is about the dangers transgender women face in our society, and how limited access to medical care can funnel them into risky situations. I don’t want to spoil what happens when or where, but I really encourage you to watch it <a href="https://vimeo.com/437969926">here</a>. The strategic use of lighting, color, and blur are immersive. Small gestures and expressions layer beautifully with the dialogue. There are moments you will want to look away, and Stevenson clearly knows how to use this to make her point.</p>
<p>So yes, watch it! But then hurry back, because I have to tell you about a longer Arkasha Stevenson project.</p>
<p><em>Channel Zero</em> was a speculative anthology series that had a much shorter run than it deserved – only four seasons (2016-2018). But if you’re looking for a Halloween mood that 1) isn’t over-rated and 2) you haven’t seen a dozen times, I recommend season three of <em>Channel Zero: Butcher’s Block</em>. Directed by Stevenson, <em>Butcher’s Block</em> is six episodes of unpredictable entertainment. In it, two college-aged sisters move to a new city, where they find themselves pulled into the multi-dimensional misadventures of a cannibal family that promises them freedom from sickness, mortality, and student loans (yes, really).</p>
<p>In <em>Butcher’s Block</em>, elder sister Zoe (played by Holland Roden) struggles with drug addiction and schizophrenia. Younger sis Alice (played by Olivia Luccardi) has her own set of troubles, ones that reveal themselves and intensify as the season progresses.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26110 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/3621e03f5747b577ed2dbefe0ebfa0cbc19f6002a62448d0b0336d0de83739b0._RI_V_TTW_-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/3621e03f5747b577ed2dbefe0ebfa0cbc19f6002a62448d0b0336d0de83739b0._RI_V_TTW_-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/3621e03f5747b577ed2dbefe0ebfa0cbc19f6002a62448d0b0336d0de83739b0._RI_V_TTW_-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/3621e03f5747b577ed2dbefe0ebfa0cbc19f6002a62448d0b0336d0de83739b0._RI_V_TTW_-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/3621e03f5747b577ed2dbefe0ebfa0cbc19f6002a62448d0b0336d0de83739b0._RI_V_TTW_-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/3621e03f5747b577ed2dbefe0ebfa0cbc19f6002a62448d0b0336d0de83739b0._RI_V_TTW_-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>The plot is engaging and <strong>deeply weird</strong>. But what stuck with me throughout was Stevenson’s careful representation of schizophrenia. Mental health issues have a terrible track record in entertainment, but Stevenson seems to have a knack for treating people like people – not on a pedestal, which is just another kind of Othering – but as fully developed characters whose choices can be just as savvy or frustrating as anyone else. Stevenson’s creative origin is in photojournalism, so perhaps this focus on “human interest angles” comes naturally for her. Roden&#8217;s character endures many situations that would be easy for the camera to exploit, but Stevenson is firm in her denial of salaciousness for its own sake.</p>
<p>It’s got gore, fair warning, but if you’re intrigued (you are), check out the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZW6MQwIYKwY">trailer</a>! I&#8217;m looking forward to seeing more work from this director, and witnessing how her style evolves in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Long and Winding Road to Relaxation</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-long-and-winding-road-to-relaxation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25578</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this month, I was in my happy place: nestled on the couch. Blanket on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, I was in my happy place: nestled on the couch. Blanket on lap, coffee in hand, puppy at side. Even better, it was pouring rain and dark out, so my lazybones felt no guilt to go “be active.” I had finally found some time, and was reading a recommended book.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft" src="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2017/09/07/17/48/chihuahua-2726117_960_720.jpg" alt="Chihuahua, Dog, A Book, Read" width="516" height="343" /></p>
<p>Unfortunately, this is where all my cozy happiness took a downturn.</p>
<p>Sure, the novel was fantastical and had a whimsical female lead – but it was also racist. The narration was spattered with derogatory stereotypes and epithets, as well as some of the dialogue. Not for character development, not for any purpose that advanced the plot or explained a timeline, it was just…there. It was the hero of the story, casual as anything and unchallenged by anyone, being racist for no damn reason. It would have felt like a wasted two hours, if my dog hadn&#8217;t been snoozing beside me in a state of bliss.</p>
<p>The next evening, I tried again: blanket, coffee, puppy. And this time, a movie. I’d read nothing but good things for the 2021 arthouse release. Reviews united in praise for the neo-grunge imagery and female-led exploration of dreamscapes. I was fully expecting to love it.</p>
<p>And, having scrapped my plan to write about racist-novel-from-Saturday, I kept a notebook near me as well. Surely, arthouse-fantasy-film wouldn’t let me down on Sunday?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignleft" src="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2021/01/13/23/07/woman-5915374_960_720.jpg" alt="Woman, Dog, Netflix, Tablet, Streaming, Video, Movies" /></p>
<p>Arthouse-fantasy-film let me down on Sunday.</p>
<p>While it <em>did</em> have a female lead, and the neo-grunge imagery was engaging, nothing could overcome how yucky the subplot was.</p>
<p>“You know, you’re smart for your age,” a grown man praises our movie’s protagonist. And that may be true, she seems smart. But she’s also a runaway high school student. And, as she has <strong>repeatedly </strong>told this man, she is scared and doesn’t know who to trust. She is emotionally scarred and physically injured. She has no money, no phone, no support network. She is starved and exhausted and experiencing seizures. So, what does this man do after promising to help? He takes her to his bedroom and has sex with her. She&#8217;s in true medical distress and passes out during the act, but the camera seems more interested in her body than her consciousness.</p>
<p>Crucially, the film treats the man as a genuine hero and love interest for &#8220;taking care of her.&#8221; I’m not going to describe any of the other appalling things he does to this teenager. Let&#8217;s summarize that my Sunday did not feel lifted by the experience.</p>
<p>Of course, my dog didn&#8217;t care. She was just happy I sat still long enough to snuggle up next to. Still, weekend over, I was left wondering, &#8220;What can I recommend this week for my <em>LSQ</em> post?&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;m going to recommend the album that eased my mood and lifted me into a place of joy: <em>Keeping Secrets</em> by Skye Edwards.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25905 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-cover-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="318" height="318" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-cover-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-cover-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/album-cover.jpg 355w" sizes="(max-width: 318px) 100vw, 318px" /></p>
<p>Although released way back in 2009, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Keeping-Secrets-Skye/dp/B002UF0R3I/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;keywords=skye+edwards+keeping+secrets+album&amp;qid=1631895520&amp;sr=8-1"><em>Keeping Secrets</em></a> has only been available for digital download since 2020. The influence of Sade is strong throughout, with Edwards&#8217; vocals attaining that same hypnotic mellowness without once playing second to the instrumentals. I can&#8217;t choose a favorite song, but &#8220;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8gPc5vpZkf0">Maybe to Spain</a>&#8221; showcases wistful emotions in a wonderful way. &#8220;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q0gtKOEGEvw">I Believe</a>&#8221; feels like encouragement to the listener just as much as the singer. &#8220;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uKl8-idc6Q4">Monsters Demons</a>&#8221; shows exactly how chilling a velvet voice can be. The whole album feels like some kind of luxurious magic.</p>
<p>The racist novel I read promised to take me on a fantastical journey, and it failed. The gross movie I watched claimed to be some feminine dreamscape wonderland, and it wasn&#8217;t. After these sour experiences, I was not in a good or even neutral mood. Only an uncommonly strong creative voice could smack me in the endorphins enough to smile, and Skye Edwards <strong>has</strong> that kind of voice.</p>
<p>In addition to the work mentioned here, Edwards has amassed a wonderful discography to explore &#8211; both as a solo artist as well as lead vocalist of Morcheeba.</p>
<p>So have you had a cruddy day? Cheer yourself with <em>Keeping Secrets</em>. Have you had a blissful day? Keep that rolling with <em>Keeping Secrets</em>. Have you just waded through a longwinded complaint about some stranger&#8217;s weekend?</p>
<p><em>Keeping Secrets</em>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reading for Writing</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reading-for-writing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 10:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve read plenty of &#8220;how to write&#8221; books focused on creativity and authorship &#8211; especially&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div dir="auto">
<div class="gmail_quote" dir="auto">
<div dir="ltr">
<p>I&#8217;ve read plenty of &#8220;how to write&#8221; books focused on creativity and authorship &#8211; especially when I first started out and had no confidence. Overall, these guides have been&#8230;disappointing. I&#8217;ve wasted too much time on myopic, condescending garbage that got sent straight to library donation. I just can&#8217;t seem to throw a book away, even if it IS trash.</p>
</div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div dir="auto">
<div class="gmail_quote" dir="auto">
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<div>
<div>
<p>But! Bad books swept aside, I want to tell you about my favorite writing book. It&#8217;s called <i>Now Write! Science Fiction, Fantasy, and Horror</i>. I appreciate the <i>Now Write!</i> series because each book (divided by genre such as nonfiction or mystery) is a compilation of <b><u>many different, expert voices</u></b>. Instead of most &#8220;how to write&#8221; books, cobbled in an echo chamber by someone I&#8217;ve <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25701 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image-300x143.png" alt="" width="300" height="143" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image-300x143.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image-1024x489.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image-768x367.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/image.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />never heard of, the <i>Now Write!</i> series highlights the advice of many. Each author is given a short chapter to make their own. Even better, at the end of each chapter, that advice is worded into a practical writing exercise that you can try out with your own work. For example, in a chapter about scene construction, author Lilian Stewart Carl describes her own writing process with a beautiful paragraph from her own published work. She compares/contrasts her style with other authors such as Tolkien and Lovecraft, and then offers up an exercise to complete. Her chapter-lesson is only 3 pages, but every paragraph is immediately useful.</p>
</div>
<div>
<div dir="auto">
<div class="gmail_quote" dir="auto">
<div dir="ltr">
<div>This book includes 87 different authors, all with their own blessedly concise chapter that details 1) a personal story about their writing process; 2) a practical example of their writing in action; and 3) a step-by-step writing exercise to try out for yourself. I was consistently amazed how applicable and challenging the chapters were as I read along. It&#8217;s always a good sign when my book is full of bookmarks &#8211; places to highlight and return to for a future visit.</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div dir="auto">
<div class="gmail_quote" dir="auto">
<div dir="ltr">
<div></div>
<div>Another aspect of this book I like is the attention to credibility. At the beginning of each author&#8217;s chapter, their accomplishments are given. <i>Now Write!</i> is packed with authors who have won international awards, had screenplays developed into films, been translated into dozens of languages, and more. This is especially enlightening when I don&#8217;t recognize the name of the author, but I recognize where their writing has appeared (such as <i>X-Files</i>, <i>The Outer Limits</i>, <i>Twilight Zone</i>, or <i>Star Trek</i>). I also love reading author blurbs, because third-person bios are an art form all their own.</div>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div dir="auto">
<div class="gmail_quote" dir="auto">
<div dir="ltr">
<div>Currently, the <i>Now Write!</i> series consists of five books, with <i>Now Write! Science Fiction, Fantasy, and Horror</i> being the most recent (and IMO best). I would love to see more of these in the future, perhaps tackling such temperamental genres as romance or humor.</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div dir="auto">
<div class="gmail_quote" dir="auto">
<div dir="ltr">
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div dir="auto">
<div class="gmail_quote" dir="auto">
<div dir="ltr">
<div>If you&#8217;re in the mood to be inspired, this book is a true one-stop-shop of encouragement, ideas, and guidance.</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recommended Ghosts for Busy People</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/recommended-ghosts-for-busy-people/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sometimes, no matter how much we wish for it, there just isn’t enough free time&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes, no matter how much we wish for it, there just isn’t enough free time in our day to watch an entire movie. And having only enough time to watch <strong>just one</strong> episode of a show can be its own problem – slapping you with a cliffhanger that will bother to oblivion until you see what happens next.</p>
<p>This is why I love anthologies. Encapsulated shorts are convenient and satisfying because they contribute to a larger narrative without relying on it. I’m especially fond of kaidan, a type of Japanese story similar to an urban legend or campfire tale.</p>
<figure id="attachment_25382" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25382" style="width: 217px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25382" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/A-Woman-Ghost-Appeared-from-a-Well-by-Katsushika-Hokusai-217x300.jpg" alt="" width="217" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/A-Woman-Ghost-Appeared-from-a-Well-by-Katsushika-Hokusai-217x300.jpg 217w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/A-Woman-Ghost-Appeared-from-a-Well-by-Katsushika-Hokusai-742x1024.jpg 742w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/A-Woman-Ghost-Appeared-from-a-Well-by-Katsushika-Hokusai-768x1060.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/A-Woman-Ghost-Appeared-from-a-Well-by-Katsushika-Hokusai-1113x1536.jpg 1113w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/A-Woman-Ghost-Appeared-from-a-Well-by-Katsushika-Hokusai.jpg 1484w" sizes="(max-width: 217px) 100vw, 217px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25382" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;A Woman Spirit Appeared from a Well&#8221; by Hokusai</figcaption></figure>
<p>Kaidan were originally recited as moralistic fables in the 1600s, but have grown into a larger category over time to include present day horrors and curiosities. They can describe yūrei (human spirits), yōkai (inhuman spirits), or similar categories of supernatural ghosts. Some kaidan focus on karmic retribution for misdeeds, while others frighten with the simple <em>wrong-place-wrong-time</em> chaos of a harsh world. Stories tend to grant strength to those who are more likely to be wronged by society; the majority of kaidan I have seen/read/heard focus on giving power back to women, young children, and nature. &#8220;Banchō Sarayashiki&#8221; is a famous example, and a personal favorite of mine, described <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Banch%C5%8D_Sarayashiki">here</a>.</p>
<p>There are many kaidan anthologies out in the world of film. While some try to scare and others aim to explain, they all share a warning to viewers that, “You don’t know as much about this world as you <em><strong>think</strong> </em>you do.”</p>
<p>So where to start? If you want to dip your toes into the film version of kaidan, I have 3 recommendations (based on attention span and genre preference):</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-25386 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kidan-211x300.jpg" alt="" width="211" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kidan-211x300.jpg 211w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kidan-721x1024.jpg 721w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kidan-768x1091.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kidan.jpg 1056w" sizes="(max-width: 211px) 100vw, 211px" /></p>
<p>1) <em>Kidan: Piece of Darkness</em> (2016). This anthology of 10 stories is based in present day and actively tries to scare you with the writings of Fuyumi Ono. Horror buffs may find the plot twists predictable, but I am and loved it anyways. My two favorites are “The Woman in Red” and “Let’s Carry On.” With each segment resting under the 20-minute mark, this is a good choice for those who enjoy modern suspense but are short on time or patience.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25388 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Dark-Tales-of-Japan-203x300.png" alt="" width="203" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Dark-Tales-of-Japan-203x300.png 203w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Dark-Tales-of-Japan.png 416w" sizes="(max-width: 203px) 100vw, 203px" /></p>
<p>2) <em>Dark Tales of Japan</em> (2004). Do you like campy? Intentional or not, this anthology of seven stories grows campier each year as the special effects become more outdated. This made-for-TV release may have lost much of its ability to scare, but is a lot of fun to watch with others. Because each short segment was written and directed by a different person, there is a distinct range of aesthetic and quality. My favorite is “The Spiderwoman,” and yes, it’s exactly what it sounds like.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25387 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kwaidan-211x300.jpg" alt="" width="211" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kwaidan-211x300.jpg 211w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kwaidan-720x1024.jpg 720w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kwaidan-768x1092.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kwaidan-1080x1536.jpg 1080w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Kwaidan.jpg 1123w" sizes="(max-width: 211px) 100vw, 211px" />3) <em>Kwaidan</em> (1965). This anthology of 4 stories was nominated for an academy award and deservedly won the Special Jury Prize at the Cannes Film Festival. Each traditional tale, by famed screenwriter Yoko Mizuki, is under an hour and uniquely gorgeous to look at – my favorite being “In a Cup of Tea.” This anthology leans much more into the supernatural than straight up horror, and has the kind of atmospheric quality that relishes in repeated viewing.</p>
<p>Even though each of these three films fall into the category of kaidan, they are vastly different viewing experiences. If you hate one, you may love the other. You may be like myself and enjoy all three. Whatever your taste, the great thing about anthologies is that you have time to try it out!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
