<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Opening the Fridge &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/opening-the-fridge/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 01:51:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Death of Lexa from the 100, Fridging or Bury Your Gays?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-death-of-lexa-from-the-100-fridging-or-bury-your-gays/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria Zelvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 11:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opening the Fridge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sometimes, in the business of television, it’s necessary to kill off characters. In the case&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25078 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/c5ec1c10-9a5e-11ea-baa5-933a2241783d_800_420-300x158.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="158" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/c5ec1c10-9a5e-11ea-baa5-933a2241783d_800_420-300x158.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/c5ec1c10-9a5e-11ea-baa5-933a2241783d_800_420-768x403.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/c5ec1c10-9a5e-11ea-baa5-933a2241783d_800_420.jpeg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Sometimes, in the business of television, it’s necessary to kill off characters. In the case of the 100, <a href="https://variety.com/2016/tv/news/the-100-lexa-dies-alycia-debnam-carey-boycott-fear-the-walking-dead-1201735453/">actress Alycia Debnam-Carey, who played the fearsome fan favorite Commander Lexa, had been booked as a series lead on another show on a competing network</a>, and thus the showrunners were faced with a conundrum — how to write off this popular, rather integral character from the show in a way that moved the story forward? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They settled on death, of course, but wanted to maximize the impact. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So Lexa was allowed to make plans with the woman she clearly felt a romantic connection with, an enemies to lovers, Romeo and Juliet-esque on opposite sides of a war Clarke Griffin. Lexa and Clarke make plans to unite their warring peoples against a greater threat, and begin to spend more time with each other with their guards lowered. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eventually, they spend one perfect night together, and wake up laughing together the next morning. They know that not everyone is going to be on board, and there will be a great fight ahead to convince their peoples to lay down arms after so much bloodshed, but they are ready to fight for the greater good, together. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But Lexa’s lieutenant was one of the people who disapproved, and when he tries to kill Clarke, Lexa is struck by the bullet instead. Lexa slowly bleeds out while Clarke holds her hand, and the sun sets on the same day that they woke up with such great hopes together. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The showrunner has gone on record as saying this was intended to be a reflection of the ultimate fragility of life. In practice, it allowed them to help Alycia Debnam-Carey exit to her new show, Fear the Walking Dead, with no strings attached, and plenty of drama to explore with Clarke left behind to deal with the rug being pulled out from under her. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now was Lexa’s death, strictly speaking, a fridging? It was senseless, and served to spur her lover Clarke to act in anger and grief, but it was no more than anything the already severely morally grey Clarke had already done to survive — a count which included poisoning a bunker filled with innocent people, including children, to save her people. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 100 was a darker show that sought to explore challenging concepts and survival situations with no good answer, and how the characters dealt with the fallout. A common refrain in the seasons leading up to Lexa’s death was how hard Clarke tried to “be the good guy” and how utterly shattering it was when she was forced to sacrifice and make the hard decision again, and again, and again. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which was why it was so jarring and cruel for the show to kill off Lexa, with whom she had just consummated a slow-burn relationship, and seemed poised to help shoulder the guilt and hard choices that Clarke had been dealing with. In that context, and within the overarching narrative of the story, I have to admit that Lexa’s death worked as a story beat and the showrunner&#8217;s hands were tied. Alycia Debnam-Carey was leaving the show. Lexa had to go. In a world like The 100, their easiest option was to kill her off — though the fact that Alycia Debnam-Carey came back for a few guest starring roles puts some weight in the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">they didn’t need to kill her</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> column. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But kill her they did, and fans reacted, in a word, </span><a href="https://variety.com/2016/tv/columns/the-100-lexa-dead-clarke-relationship-13-1201722916/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">negatively</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.eonline.com/news/751481/the-100-boss-apologizes-for-how-lexa-died-in-open-letter-to-fans"><span style="font-weight: 400;">So negatively the showrunner ultimately apologized. </span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Where the anger comes is in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">how </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">they did it. This may not have been a fridging — I would say on a technicality, if I’m being generous — but it was a textbook case of another problematic trope: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bury Your Gays</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_25127" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25127" style="width: 205px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-25127 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Tara_Mcclay-205x300.jpg" alt="" width="205" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Tara_Mcclay-205x300.jpg 205w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Tara_Mcclay.jpg 258w" sizes="(max-width: 205px) 100vw, 205px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25127" class="wp-caption-text">RIP Tara</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The trope works similarly to fridging, in that it is more about the shock value gotcha than the easy storybeat. Typically, a queer character will happily enter into some form of relationship — in this case, a homosexual one — and either immediately after consummation or some other milestone like the first “I love you” or their first anniversary, one of the happy couple will be killed off. Usually it is sudden, such as Tara’s death in Buffy from a random stray bullet meant for someone else or Lexa’s sudden death from a random stray bullet meant for someone else (surprise, surprise there’s a pattern to lesbians&#8217; deaths). The remaining character then is left adrift to have a breakdown over their death, given an excuse to act more evilly and brutally, and the cycle continues. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the reasons Lexa’s death had such a ripple effect through the community was likely the fact that her murder was steeped in hatred for her being with Clarke — and though the show handwaved and said it was what Clarke represented, not Clarke herself, the framing still feels more like blatant homophobia. It was not the parallel that the showrunners were trying to make, and one can only hope that if they intended to explore such a topic they might have approached it with more grace. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For many, myself included, Lexa’s hastily handled death was the breaking point and last straw of a show that seemed in hindsight to be running itself in circles. The 100 continued on for many, many seasons after this, and would run into more trouble for how they killed off characters and the treatment of their actors. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Lexa’s death, her demise seemed to strike a cord in the public consciousness, and </span><a href="https://screenrant.com/100-season-3-lincoln-death-ricky-whittle-exit/#:~:text=Lincoln%20was%20killed%20off%20on,with%20show%20creator%20Jason%20Rothenberg.&amp;text=In%20an%20interview%2C%20Whittle%20said,neglect%20my%20character%20and%20myself."><span style="font-weight: 400;">the Lexa Pledge, a written pledge for tv writers to treat LGBTQ+ characters with respect, gained some traction</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Time will tell how much of an impact Lexa’s death will have, but as of right now she’s just one of a long line of lesbian characters to be murdered just as she found happiness. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Star Trek (2009) Did Not Need to Kill Amanda Grayson</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/star-trek-2009-did-not-need-to-kill-amanda-grayson/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria Zelvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 10:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opening the Fridge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Across (at least) two universes, three shows, and two separate movie franchises, Amanda Grayson has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24754 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amanda_Grayson_alternate_reality-300x280.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="280" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amanda_Grayson_alternate_reality-300x280.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Amanda_Grayson_alternate_reality.jpg 638w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Across (at least) two universes, three shows, and two separate movie franchises, Amanda Grayson has gone through a lot of portrayals. She is a fan-favorite character, and a fascinating one at that: the human mother of the alien Mr. Spock, a woman who fell in love with a man who lives a life devoted to logic, and an integral part of the soap opera drama that composes Spock’s expanding extended family tree. (Two previously unmentioned chaotic siblings and counting!) Through it all, Amanda has been a guiding force, straddling the complicated line of Spock’s half-human, half-Vulcan upbringing and complicated relationship with his father, and providing her whole family with the love, and sometimes sharp wake-up calls, that they need. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So it was incredibly disappointing to see in the 2009 reboot movie of the franchise that Amanda Grayson, along with the entire planet of Vulcan, was unceremoniously killed so that Spock would be forced to display the only emotion that recent movies seem interested in letting break through his shield of logic: rage. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perhaps I shouldn’t have been surprised. After all, JJ Abrams has said that he </span><a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment/tv/la-xpm-2013-may-14-la-et-st-jj-abrams-star-wars-versus-star-trek-jon-stewart-20130514-story.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">didn’t like <em>Star Trek</em> growing up</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It is impossible not to see similarities to a movie franchise he actually does like in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Trek </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(2009). From the destruction of Vulcan to reliance on a one-man starcraft making the killing blow against a massive technologically superior superweapon, the fingerprints of <em>Star Wars</em> are all over the first film. Just slot in Vulcan for Alderaan, and that’s your character motivation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And, to be absolutely fair, functionally it works as a story beat. Jim Kirk has personal stakes in hating Nero because of the death of his father, and now Spock has one because of the death of his mother. Amanda Grayson’s death paints a sympathetic face on the destruction and loss of Vulcan, which is otherwise just an orb in space to the audience that isn’t a fan of the series. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, not only is this a criminal underuse of the incredible Winona Ryder </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wo6jRIewtLE"><span style="font-weight: 400;">whose deleted scenes give a peek into what we could have had</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but it&#8217;s completely unnecessary. Are we to believe that Spock would not be properly motivated to revenge by the literal, actual genocide of his people? Why is Spock not allowed more than a few moments of shell shocked grief for his planet and his mother before we skip right to anger? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why destroy Vulcan at all? </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Trek </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(2009) presents on purpose a more militarized Starfleet, which is an interesting choice that unfortunately also makes me feel like I’m watching an extended Mirrorverse episode in places. Again, this is more </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Wars</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> than </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Trek</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and reeks of the thinking that the source material is in some way “boring” or won’t resonate with modern audiences. Blowing up planets is a spectacle, and flashy, and fun, and killing off planets and mothers works well enough as an audience shorthand for “main character hates villain personally.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But that’s not very </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Trek</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We’re supposed to have long philosophical discussions about what it means to be human, and characters like Amanda Grayson are integral to that. Spock’s journey is one of self-acceptance and love, warring with two philosophies made literal in him — logic vs emotion, calculation vs impulse. Is it possible to be 100% logical in all situations? If Vulcan were </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">almost </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">destroyed, rather than completely obliterated, what ramifications would that have had on a society that professes itself to be 100% logical? What would happen if fear were to take hold? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personally I think that if we absolutely had to kill off one of Spock’s parents in Vulcan’s destruction, it ought to have been Sarek, Spock’s estranged father, with whom an emotional through line could have been set up with his trying to reconcile never having felt like he made his father proud, and provides a nice mirror to Kirk’s own attempts to live up to his lost father. Does Spock turn more toward the logical side in memory of what his father wanted of him? Does Spock try to abandon it in his grief? And for Amanda Grayson, the woman who loved and spent so much of her life on Vulcan, how would she cope? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24847 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/stefan-cosma-YGzV2u31o9Q-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/stefan-cosma-YGzV2u31o9Q-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/stefan-cosma-YGzV2u31o9Q-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/stefan-cosma-YGzV2u31o9Q-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/stefan-cosma-YGzV2u31o9Q-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/stefan-cosma-YGzV2u31o9Q-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />This is to say nothing of the inclusion of Spock Prime, Leonard Nimoy reprising his role as the actual Spock we all know and love from the original series. The movie kills off Spock’s mother, and we are given no chance to absorb this incredible blow from Spock Prime — whose mother lived a long, long life — whose presence has thrown the timeline of the universe off track. Her death is included solely as motivation for the new alternate universe version of Spock’s rage, and is not otherwise impactful on the story as it should have been. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fortunately, Amada Grayson has been “revived” in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Trek: Discovery</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and given more of a role to work with than “loving mother, immediately killed for maximum plot sadness.” The fate of the alternate movie universe is in limbo at the moment, though as of right now it appears that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Trek: Beyond </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">might be their last film. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the record, I do enjoy </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Trek</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (2009) for what it is. But the death of Amanda Grayson has always and probably will always irk me. Perhaps I am like alternate timeline Spock, because when it happens, instead of grieving for an amazing woman killed too soon, I skip right from shock to rage. There were so many other ways to motivate Spock to hating Nero, they just decided to fridge an incredible character as a shortcut. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The MCU Failed Natasha Romanoff in Endgame</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-mcu-failed-natasha-romanoff-in-endgame/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria Zelvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opening the Fridge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=23176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Overall, Natasha Romanoff aka the Black Widow has gotten the short end of the stick&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23179 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/black-widow-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/black-widow-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/black-widow-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/black-widow.jpg 480w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Overall, Natasha Romanoff aka the Black Widow has gotten the short end of the stick when it comes to plot points in the Avengers movies. While given quite a few badass moments in the first movie, she did fall prey to Joss Whedon’s scantily clad badass waif-fu favorite trope. The second movie reduced her to a love interest for a seemingly random character and had her declare herself a monster for being infertile. With all the other characters in Infinity War, she barely amounts to much screen time at all despite being an original Avenger. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then Endgame comes along, and in this film she is managing the Avenger response on Earth and coordinating the response on other planets as well, a position that should elevate her to the status of characters such as Nick Fury, her mentor. Natasha is understandably distraught and tries to hold the Avengers together by her fingertips. When the chance comes to go back in time, defeat Thanos, and bring back the world, she jumps at it without regard for her own safety. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Together with Clint Barton, she goes to the place where </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/this-is-not-love-and-the-murder-of-gamora/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gamora was murdered </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">and, like Gamora, dies so that the men can have a shiny gemstone. </span><a href="https://junkee.com/avengers-endgame-black-widow/203507"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The MCU fridged two women the exact same way, two movies in a row. Maybe, maybe I wouldn&#8217;t be so mad about this but I am because they did it TWICE.</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some, </span><a href="https://goat.com.au/avengers-endgame/the-avengers-endgame-directors-are-defending-that-black-widow-scene/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">including the directors</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, have claimed that this was meant as a poetic end to Natasha Romanoff’s character arc in the MCU, and don’t understand the backlash. After all, in the first Avengers movie, we hear her claim that “love is for children” and here she is sacrificing herself for love of her team and the man beside her who has been her partner for years. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But sacrifice is a very common trope when it comes to female deaths in fiction, and narratively this leaves only male characters behind to mourn for her. Later, Tony Stark likewise makes a sacrifice at the expense of his life, but his death is mourned on a much wider scale, from a battlefield farewell to his family, another virtual farewell, and a full funeral. The narrative places much more weight on his death, and charitably it could be that his death defeats the big bad once and for all and ends the climactic battle that has been happening since space was introduced in the MCU, but there’s one problem with thinking that in a vacuum. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tony Stark is presented as the least likely person to sacrifice himself, at first because of his selfishness and callous attitude, then in Endgame because he has a family with a daughter waiting for him at home. But every single movie that Tony has been in since Iron Man 1 has included him sacrificing himself at least once, selflessly putting his life on the line again and again and again. Tony Stark’s first plan always seems to be suicidal self-sacrifice.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Similarly, Endgame positions Natasha Romanoff as if she has nothing else to give, that she has no other worth outside her work so she must throw herself into it. She’s cold, calculating, and repeatedly says that she is incapable of love, yet we the audience know that isn’t true. She loves deeply, and is fiercely protective of her team and friends, often against her best interests. Natasha is shown comforting Steve Rogers after the funeral of his former love, and doing everything she can to rescue Clint Barton from his revenge-fueled path after his family’s deaths, and holding the Avengers together by the tips of her fingertips. We know she can love, and does, and is more than willing to put herself in harm’s way to protect everyone she cares about without a care for herself. Like Tony Stark, Natasha’s first plan always seems to be suicidal self-sacrifice. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So when she’s hanging by that cliff in Endgame, telling Clint Barton that she should be the one to die for the stone, it doesn’t feel like growth. Natasha is making the sacrifice play, and the thing is it could work as a tragedy, as a fatal flaw in a hero who can’t see the impact she’s had on others, but for one of the last things she says to Clint. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She tells him he should survive, because he has a family. Something she can never have, as alluded to in Age of Ultron when she referred to herself as a monster for being infertile. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This harking back to an extremely problematic film moment is a great deal of </span><a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/5/2/18524155/avengers-endgame-failed-black-widow"><span style="font-weight: 400;">what makes Natasha Romanoff’s death feel so gross in Endgame</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Rather than completing growth as a character arc, perhaps finding purpose and love for herself in her abilities managing the Avengers and saving lives, Natasha is shown to still be holding onto that comment in Age of Ultron. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The moment is plot relevant, and the rest of the movie cannot happen without getting the Stone, but her death makes it out as if Natasha does not have her own life worth living in comparison to Clint whose family is, at this point in time, also very, very dead. The movie all but endorses this by throwing a lengthy, well attended funeral for Tony Stark featuring his young daughter prominently for audience heartbreak, a funeral in which Natasha does not receive a shoutout. There is no mention of her receiving a funeral or being mourned at all aside from the scene where they discover she is dead. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The climactic battle of the movie includes a hero shot of every woman in the Marvel Cinematic Universe teaming up against Thanos — with one notable, obvious missing member. While we will be getting a delayed-by-the-pandemic Black Widow movie at some point, Natasha was the only female superhero in the MCU until Gamora in 2014. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She deserved a hero shot. She deserved to not be the only woman in her scenes. She and Gamora deserved to have scenes together. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gamora was forced, Natasha was willing, but in neither case was the death satisfying, fulfilling, or a completion of their character arcs. It was tragic in that they were only used as trading cards for a magic gemstone, and then to make the men feel bad briefly before moving on. The MCU needs to do better.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>This is Not Love, and the Murder of Gamora</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/this-is-not-love-and-the-murder-of-gamora/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/this-is-not-love-and-the-murder-of-gamora/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria Zelvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 11:46:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opening the Fridge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“This is not love,” Gamora says, as Thanos turns on her. In the theater watching&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22863 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Gamora_Guardians_of_the_Galaxy-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Gamora_Guardians_of_the_Galaxy-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Gamora_Guardians_of_the_Galaxy-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Gamora_Guardians_of_the_Galaxy-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Gamora_Guardians_of_the_Galaxy.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />“This is not love,” Gamora says, as Thanos turns on her. In the theater watching the scene on Vormir for the first time, in which the murderous villain Thanos with the goal of murdering 50% of all life in the universe is told that he must destroy that which he loves to receive an all powerful Infinity Stone, I thought she was right. Thanos did not love his “favorite daughter” Gamora, not truly. If he did, in so much as someone like him is capable of loving anything, it was as a possession, or a trophy a serial killer might take. He massacred her people, her family, forced her to be an assassin for him, tortured her, and her adoptive sister, and her found family after she defied him. The Guardians of the Galaxy truly loved Gamora. They had a whole climax of the first Guardians movie about it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This is not love,” Gamora says, and I was so sure she was going to be right that I wasn’t concerned for her safety as Thanos grabbed her and she struggled futilely in his grip. Even if he threw her off the cliff, I reasoned, the Infinity Stone would reject Thanos. Or maybe Gamora would be saved at the last moment by the Guardians coming in at the last second. But, no, surely it was more likely that the Stone would save her, because Thanos was Gamora’s abuser at his very best, and the Stone wanted him to throw away something he loved. Like a fairy tale, he should have had to give up his goal, or his strength, or some integral part of him that would ache like missing a limb. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But that is not what happened. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The universe does not agree with Gamora, a daughter of Thanos only through kidnapping and threat. Thanos gets the stone for his murder of a woman whose life has been haunted and tormented by his greed, his cruelty, and his ambition. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gamora was fridged so that Thanos — </span><a href="https://encrypted-tbn0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcSODfS15dIarmcPwmtCn9J2ETjnBlC4NCmOxA&amp;usqp=CAU"><span style="font-weight: 400;">whose arc in Infinity War is explicitly defined as that of the protagonist by the directors</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> — would feel bad in his quest to (</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">checks notes</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">) commit universe-wide genocide. She is quite literally his sacrifice to achieve his goals, a rich female character we’ve grown with over two movies distilled down to nothing more than an obstacle to a man’s goals, and then later an excuse for another man to be too emotional to complete the plan to save the universe. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As an aside: I am, for the record, extremely sympathetic to Peter Quill’s actions in Infinity War (</span><a href="https://screenrant.com/avengers-infinity-war-star-lord-worst-character/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">and I am well aware that not everyone is</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). His reaction is absolutely in character, especially given that Peter is victim of a man fridging a woman in his life so that they, the murderer, could continue on with their murder plans without her getting in the way but, like, totally feels bad about having had no other choice but to kill this woman they supposedly loved. His reaction to the murder of a woman he loves for the “greater good” twice now is understandable, and echoes my grieving rage at the situation. The movie however, frames his grief as the “weak point” of the heroes, and the wrong thing to do as it ultimately prevents our heroes from beating Thanos. The narrative seems to say that anyone loving Gamora dooms the universe, one way or another, and we’d all be better off if she was never loved at all. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanos quite literally trades a woman for a shiny gemstone, and Infinity War not only lets him get away with it, but says that his definition of love is more correct than that of his victim. </span><a href="https://www.syfy.com/syfywire/whats-with-all-the-fridging-lately#:~:text=I%20don't%20think%20that,Thanos%2C%20her%20evil%20warmongering%20father."><span style="font-weight: 400;">To steal a quote from a fantastic SYFY Wire article on the subject</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">: “It’s okay, though, because Thanos cries. Yes! You heard me right. When Thanos decides to murder his adoptive daughter Gamora, who he abused for most of her life, a redemptive tear rolls down his cheek. WORTH IT.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The next film brings back a version of Gamora, still serving Thanos, without the development of either of the Guardians of the Galaxy movies. Her only real scene with anyone who isn’t Nebula from her found family is to knee Peter Quill repeatedly in the balls (but ha ha he learned she was murdered by Thanos literally five minutes ago and is relieved she’s back but the joke’s on him). I hope there is a way to restore Gamora’s memories of this universe, and that direction is the one they’re going in the next films, but I am extremely skeptical after her treatment in Infinity War. <a href="https://www.denofgeek.com/movies/avengers-endgame-gamora-alive-dead-mystery/">Many fans are similarly frustrated, and have dubbed it the MCU&#8217;s Gamora Problem.</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unequivocally, Gamora deserved better. I will always wonder what could have happened if Guardians of the Galaxy 3 was her next movie and not Infinity War. And, if anyone deserved to ultimately defeat Thanos and kill him, it was her and her equally abused sister Nebula. Unfortunately, Gamora became a footnote in a story arc that ought to have been more focused on her than the Avengers, shifted off to the side so that people who had first heard his name the day before could have the big beef set up with him that bleeds into the next movie. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The only thing that makes me angrier than Gamora’s unjust death, and the fact that they wiped her character development slate clean just as she found true happiness within a life she built for herself free of abuse, is that they did it </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">twice</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both prominent original only female members of otherwise all-male superhero teams were killed for the exact same reason, for the exact same thing, and next month, I am talking about Natasha Romanoff. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/this-is-not-love-and-the-murder-of-gamora/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Game of Thrones Died When They Killed Missandei</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/game-of-thrones-died-when-they-killed-missandei/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria Zelvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 12:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opening the Fridge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22661</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are a lot of pent up things that I could say about the end&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-22662 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/J0CTCR-300x191.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="191" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/J0CTCR-300x191.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/J0CTCR-1024x650.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/J0CTCR-768x488.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/J0CTCR-1536x975.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/J0CTCR.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> There are a lot of pent up things that I could say about the end of <em>Game of Thrones</em> still, the kind of things that have festered and lingered (unlike the show’s post-series-finale cultural impact). But if I speak about just one thing, just one character who did not deserve her end, I want it to be Missandei from the isle of Naath.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Missandei deserved better. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And I do not say that in the naivety of someone who did not know what kind of show she was watching. “If you think this has a happy ending, you haven’t been paying attention,” was the often-quoted refrain in the fandom, spoken by the showrunner’s favorite villain (</span><a href="https://medium.com/@jeffersonvietanhday/game-of-thrones-problems-started-with-ramsay-bolton-6bfc0b110a9"><span style="font-weight: 400;">whose baffling, horrifying expanded role at the expense of other, more compelling </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">female </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">stories waiting to be adapted is a good microcosm of what the writers thought we wanted</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). <em>Game of Thrones</em> positioned itself as a show of shock deaths where no one was safe, where fan favorites and main characters could be killed at any point…</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Except, not really. At a certain point, <em>Game of Thrones</em> needed to become a coherent story with an overarching narrative. Just because the main characters weren’t who we thought they were doesn’t mean that there weren’t any. The story needed living main characters to complete the overarching Song of Ice and Fire. Fans began to recognize this, and these safe main characters from the still-standing pack started to be analyzed and pored over — people like Daenerys Targaryen, Jon Snow, Tyrion Lannister, and Arya and Sansa Stark — as fandom at large tried to guess what might happen in the end. And so, the showrunners tried to up the stakes, and killed off other characters with wild abandon and no foreshadowing, to include Missandei, just to keep the element of surprise in this horrible anti-spoiler culture world we’re in now.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clearly with fan reaction to the final season being what it was, the showrunners gravely misjudged why people liked the twists and shock deaths that came before. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ned Stark’s death due to incompetent political dealings was broadcast a mile away, and the only reason we the audience thought he was safe was because we thought he was the main character, and main characters in fantasy stories make the wrong call all the time and still win in the end. <em>Game of Thrones</em> was meant to be a show where actions had consequences. The most famous shock deaths were foreshadowed to kingdom come, and when they happened the audience, still reeling, could pinpoint what had gone wrong and why they died with a sort of horrified realization of decisions that happened sometimes whole seasons ago. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Red Wedding. Tywin Lannister. Oberyn Martell. Jon Snow, the first time. All these events were foreshadowed ahead of time, we just hadn’t noticed yet. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, then, what about Missandei’s? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the show’s only POC — </span><a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/hollywood/2019/05/game-of-thrones-nathalie-emmanuel-missandei-death-interview#:~:text=In%20Season%208%2C%20Episode%204,show's%20enduring%20racial%20blind%20spot."><span style="font-weight: 400;">before her death, one of only two named POC characters to survive to the end</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> — Missandei was a slave freed by Daenerys Targaryen in the first of her many dragon-themed city conquerings. Missandei was a translator and a trusted advisor to Daenerys, who not only valued her counsel but also saw her as a dear friend. Though never a main character, previous seasons showcased her relationship with Daenerys and her life outside of her, including a sweet blossoming romance with the general of the queen’s armies, Grey Worm. She was kind, and sweet, and a firm believer in the kind of justice only dragon fire could bring to slavers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was disappointing but not surprising to see less and less of her character as the others in Westeros began to shift support to the Mother of Dragons. Instead of seeing Grey Worm and Missandei, we instead got scene after scene of Tyrion and Varys drinking and saying shady things about the queen they supposedly believed in with all their hearts, laying clumsy exposition&#8211;then not quite with firm evidence&#8211;that Daenerys might be slipping into being more like her forefather, the Mad King. These scenes of dissent would have been better served by including someone who had been with her since the start voicing some doubts over her viciousness, rather than two men who had just arrived, but instead the pair of men drank and Grey Worm and Missandei became less visible advisors. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By the last season when they arrive in Westeros proper, Missandei’s role was reduced to one of reciting Daenerys’s titles at people and defending Daenerys from shady whispers happening right in front of her. She is seen in background shots, shares brief screen time with Grey Worm to physically declare their love, and then almost immediately after that she is kidnapped via an impossible series of actions happening in rapid succession. All told, the scenes leading to and of her death don’t last more than fifteen minutes, if that. It is a sequence that was less <em>Game of Thrones</em> and more bad 80s movie.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Euron Greyjoy, perhaps the luckiest pirate in all of Westeros, shoots down not just a flying, moving target of a supposedly invincible dragon perfectly in a shot a sniper would have been jealous of, using medieval era siege equipment on a moving boat, but also kidnaps the one person that Daenerys Targaryen cares about most by plucking Missandei from the ocean without being seen or caught. Missandei is then promptly beheaded on the gates of King’s Landing while everyone watches, her last words a seeming blessing to Daenerys to burn the whole city (as she eventually does): </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dracarys. </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is a lot that has already been said about Missandei’s death, and </span><a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/hollywood/2019/05/game-of-thrones-nathalie-emmanuel-missandei-death-interview#:~:text=In%20Season%208%2C%20Episode%204,show's%20enduring%20racial%20blind%20spot."><span style="font-weight: 400;">in particular the writing about the show’s lack of diversity and the problematic writing and treatment of POC characters is spot on, especially considering that Missandei dies in chains.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The death itself appears to be manufactured to be heartbreaking, but more importantly something that the fans wouldn’t see coming. </span><a href="https://www.tvinsider.com/774964/game-of-thrones-season-8-episode-4-missandei-death-women-backlash/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Her death sparked an immediate backlash, one which continued throughout the final episodes of the season.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Her death, rather than being about her, was framed as being about Grey Worm and Daenerys, the focus entirely on the pair of them and the brutal violence they enact upon King’s Landing in the very next episode. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the last season, Missandei was treated less like a character and more like a prop, and that is heartbreaking and inexcusable. She was a fascinating character and, like the other <em>Game of Thrones</em> women, was whittled down to almost nothing by the end of the series. Missandei is fridged so that Daenerys and Grey Worm can go conquer King’s Landing — which, frustratingly, was the thing they were always going to do anyway. Her death served no purpose other than the showrunners wanted to shock the fans, to surprise them in a way that no one on Reddit could have guessed, and give Daenerys and Grey Worm an “excuse” to murder civilians. There was no other reason to kill her in the story.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By throwing away character motivations and consequences for deaths, Missandei’s death stood out from other <em>Game of Thrones</em> deaths for being particularly brutal and nonsensical in the grander scheme of the story. “Haha, shocked you” doesn’t a good story make. It’s alienating, it most often affects marginalized characters, and it doesn’t make anyone want to watch your show again and again to pick up breadcrumbs when you don’t provide any. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-22764 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/andy-watkins-L6O2GaNSsWU-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/andy-watkins-L6O2GaNSsWU-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/andy-watkins-L6O2GaNSsWU-unsplash-1024x575.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/andy-watkins-L6O2GaNSsWU-unsplash-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/andy-watkins-L6O2GaNSsWU-unsplash-1536x863.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/andy-watkins-L6O2GaNSsWU-unsplash-2048x1151.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Those who rely on shock deaths are often shocked when they kill off their own story too.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Missandei’s death was one of the first nails in the coffin of <em>Game of Thrones</em>’s legacy, and I like to think that was her revenge. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dracarys. </span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vanessa Carlysle and Not Quite Escaping the Fridge</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/vanessa-carlyse-and-not-quite-escaping-the-fridge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria Zelvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opening the Fridge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22410</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The life of a superhero girlfriend is a precarious one, and Vanessa Carlysle, the significant&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/3e/SDCC_2015_-_Morena_Baccarin_%2819749967192%29.jpg/1200px-SDCC_2015_-_Morena_Baccarin_%2819749967192%29.jpg" width="249" height="165" />The life of a superhero girlfriend is a precarious one, and Vanessa Carlysle, the significant other of the merc with the mouth Deadpool, should be well versed in its pitfalls by now. She and Wade had a twisted sort of storybook romance for the first part of the film, told primarily in a humorous montage, but the tragedy of Wade’s impending death via cancer puts an intense strain on both of them. Despite Vanessa’s attempts to help him and to stay with him through it all, the man who would be Deadpool leaves her behind to seek treatment, intent on sparing her suffering. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After he puts on the mask, Deadpool tries to spare her some more, though more from the sight of his disfigured skin than the angry mercenaries that he’s hunting. Said mercenaries find his weak spot in her, and kidnap her anyway, and Vanessa ends that movie in a happily ever after back together with her love, but only after she’s let her anger at being left behind and then being used as a bargaining chip known. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the first film, Vanessa was a fun character who was more than capable of keeping up with Deadpool, and in fact challenging him. That is why it was such a disappointment that the sequel seemed intent on broadcasting her impending doom from the word go, and then killed her off in a manner built from Deadpool’s personal nightmares. She then appears in dream sequences, to motivate like the ghost of girlfriends past. Despite being saved at the end of the movie, her death has one lasting, permanent consequence:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vanessa is barely in the movie at all. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Deadpool is popular for his irreverent humor and the way that his character pokes fun at superhero tropes, from fourth wall breaking antics to storylines mocking more serious comics narratives. Some have tried to argue that this was a masterstroke of storytelling gone wrong, that the writers meant to comment and poke fun at the fridging stereotype, that “saving Vanessa was so easy, why don’t more movies/heroes/comics do this?” was the point of it all. But if it was the point, it is somewhat lackluster in that it happens at the end of the movie and not the start where it could have been brushed off. Deadpool could have stared directly into the camera judgingly, and then the movie moved on.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most egregious as evidence for the writers not doing this on purpose is the fact that the Deadpool 2 screenwriters admitted in an interview that </span><a href="https://www.vulture.com/2018/05/deadpool-2-writers-defend-treatment-of-female-characters.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">they did not know what fridging was until the film came out</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. One of the writers goes on to confirm in that interview that there was originally a plan not to kill Vanessa off, but rather for Vanessa to leave him and the events of Deadpool 2 to be him trying to win her back. But then someone suggested that Deadpool “works best when he’s had everything taken from him” and lo and behold, we’re back to the same old stale formula. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Superhero has girlfriend. Superhero’s girlfriend gets murdered. Superhero goes on to have an action movie while sad about it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though technically reversed in the last moments with Deadpool’s irreverent use of a time travel machine, again, the fridging still happened. The only influence that Vanessa’s untimely murder has on the plot is the fact that Deadpool is a little bit more suicidal than usual, and he gets to share brief moments of mourning with Cable who lost his family—in between the jokes that Cable and Deadpool are in love, of course. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vanessa’s death stinks of the writers not knowing what to do with her character anymore. This is a recurring problem especially in action movie franchises, where one movie ends with the hero getting his trophy, his prize of the girl and the happily ever after, only for the sequel writers to have to properly motivate the hero to do some heroing in the next movie.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, killing off the girlfriend isn’t the only way to motivate the hero or to handle having had a “happy” ending in the last movie. For a superhero example, look at Ant-Man and the Wasp — <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22563 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unicorn-5823999_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unicorn-5823999_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unicorn-5823999_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unicorn-5823999_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unicorn-5823999_1920-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/unicorn-5823999_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Hope is brought to more prominence in the sequel, allowed to be her own superhero and take the stage with the titular male hero. In the comics Vanessa is the mutant Copycat who could have been treated in much the same way as the Wasp. Deadpool 2 could have included Vanessa learning her newfound powers, and being introduced as a new member of X-Force, with Wade fluctuating between allowing her to be badass in her own right and the not baseless fear of losing her. Deadpool is, after all, functionally immortal, and here could have been the opportunity to do something about the fridging so prevalent in the industry with a few jokes and callouts that only someone like Deadpool can make.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Any potential future Deadpool movies are now tied up in questions of crossover with the Marvel Cinematic Universe and how to combine the X-Men into existing franchises, and we’re a long way away from anything being confirmed. However, </span><a href="https://wegotthiscovered.com/movies/vanessa-reportedly-wont-deadpool-3-shell-return-deadpool-4/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">with some troubling indications that Morena Baccarin won’t be returning</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, more than a few alarm bells are ringing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Franchises, and especially action movie franchises, have a disappearing woman problem. Think of your Jason Bournes and Mission Impossibles, where all the male side characters get to come back for every sequel, but the female ones are either killed in the first few minutes or suffer from never being mentioned ever again. For comic books and the movies they have spawned, this also holds true. Wolverine gets the girl, but she gets killed in the first few minutes. The Punisher finds half a second’s worth of peace, but nope, she’s been shot now, and he’s back to square one. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The writers instead recycle the old formulas, never seeming to want to explore a happy couple struggling through the plot of the movie together, and the audience loses out on a cool character given the chance to breathe and grow into her own. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Hollowing Out of Padmé Amidala</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-hollowing-out-of-padme-amidala/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-hollowing-out-of-padme-amidala/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria Zelvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opening the Fridge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Often in fridging, the deaths are brutal. Usually they are tragic, a loss of what&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium alignleft" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/e/ee/Amidala.png" alt="Padme Amidala" width="346" height="287" /> Often in fridging, the deaths are brutal. Usually they are tragic, a loss of what might have been. The death of Padmé Amidala, the very pregnant mother of the protagonists of the <em>Star Wars</em> trilogy so many grew up with, strangled by her husband, and then sort of just fading away after delivering her twins, is more elongated than the typical shocking fridging death, but her treatment by the narrative, especially of <em>Revenge of the Sith</em>, is absolutely something we see again and again in fridging stories. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a prequel story, the audience has some idea of how it will end. At the very least, we know the general position of the characters in the next story — Anakin Skywalker will become Darth Vader, Obi-Wan becomes the hermit Ben on Tatooine, and Padmé Amidala, as confirmed by her daughter Leia in Return of the Jedi, dies while Leia is young. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The problem is not that Padmé Amidala died, or any logical fallacies pertaining to Leia’s memory of her (the Force works in mysterious ways, after all). The problem lies in how Padmé was killed. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To briefly summarize for those who may have forgotten, by the third movie of the <em>Star Wars</em> prequel trilogy, Padmé Amidala has married Anakin Skywalker in secret, and they are both nervously anticipating the arrival of Padmé’s baby (having not figured out she’s having twins). Fueled by fears for Padmé’s health and the health of his child, Anakin betrays the Jedi Order and slaughters his former compatriots, including friends and the children in the Jedi Temple, becoming Darth Vader in the process.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Padmé’s purposes, all this culminates in a confrontation she has with her husband on the volcanic planet Mustafar. Angered at her assumed betrayal after seeing Obi-Wan has stowed away to presumably kill him, Anakin chokes her with the Force and she passes out after Obi-Wan convinces Anakin to let her go. This, the audience has to assume, is what ultimately kills her much later after Obi-Wan has won his duel and brought Padmé back to receive medical treatment and give birth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To quote, verbatim, the diagnosis of the medical droid: “</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Medically, she’s completely healthy. For reasons we can’t explain, we’re losing her… She’s lost the will to live.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are, presumably, meant to assume she died of a broken heart. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But what lesson is Anakin supposed to take from this? What, then, is accomplished by killing Padmé? Narratively, much like poor Shmi Skywalker before her, it is a shortcut to allow Anakin violence. He can be the killing machine of the next trilogy. Though he’s already killed several people, including children, he now has no reason to feel bad about it even by proxy. Because of his wife&#8217;s death, Darth Vader has also lost the will to live, making Padmé&#8217;s arc entirely about him and his feelings rather than her own agency. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The real tragedy of Padmé Amidala is the loss of potential and, as the Expanded Universe of books, comics, television shows, and so many other things has shown, there is clearly an appetite for more stories in this universe, and specifically women’s stories. Which brings me to: if the problem is not that Padmé is killed, how could her inevitable death been handled better? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s look at <em>Revenge of the Sith</em> alone. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taking the movie as given, one would be forgiven for wondering if Padmé remained a practicing senator or if her full-time job was staring sadly out of floor to ceiling windows. But the deleted scenes of <em>Revenge of the Sith</em> paint a different picture of what could have been. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Only briefly hinted at in the final film, </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3_eqf6WRQ4o"><span style="font-weight: 400;">several deleted scenes from <em>Revenge of the Sith</em> such as these</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> show Padmé as a driving force in the foundation of the Rebel Alliance her children would one day champion. These scenes, like much of the prequel trilogy, are far from perfect, but they do lay the groundwork for what could have been an interesting espionage-like story, pitting Padmé into a Cold War spy’s shoes as she faces down evil political power in echoes of how her daughter Leia would in the future. However, these scenes were cut, and what remains of Padmé’s arc in <em>Revenge of the Sith</em> is barely existent at best. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a recurring problem of the <em>Star Wars</em> universe. Pivotal, plot-relevant information and <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22226 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/tommy-van-kessel-_sDlQf6f7gc-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/tommy-van-kessel-_sDlQf6f7gc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/tommy-van-kessel-_sDlQf6f7gc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/tommy-van-kessel-_sDlQf6f7gc-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/tommy-van-kessel-_sDlQf6f7gc-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/tommy-van-kessel-_sDlQf6f7gc-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />character development is hidden in the Expanded universe, cut scenes, or creator interviews — who can forget the whiplash of getting all the setup and reveal of Palpatine being alive in the first five minutes of <em>Rise of Skywalker</em> when the previous two movies of the trilogy had never mentioned him? But what happened to Padmé bothers me more than a questionable (and baffling) lack of planning, because it </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">was </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">planned. The scenes were not only written but shot, edited, VFX updated, only to be discarded. At what point and why were these scenes of the building of the Rebellion determined to be irrelevant to a prequel story about the rise of the evil empire that the next trilogy spends so long rebelling against? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of all the characters in the prequel trilogy, Padmé’s role was the one that was the most consistently undercut and underdeveloped, scenes cut across the trilogy to make room for longer lightsaber fights. </span><a href="https://thefandomentals.com/%EF%BB%BF-padme-the-lost-scenes/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Fandomentals has a pretty interesting breakdown of all the scenes across the trilogy that were cut</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and the conclusion reached that, especially as the trilogy wore on, any of Padmé’s scenes that were not about Anakin were cut is a fair one. Had these scenes been included, Padmé would have been a more fleshed-out character rather than the cardboard cutout, carrot-on-a-stick existing solely for Anakin to feel sad about. Had these scenes been included, Padmé might’ve gotten to grapple with a moral choice of her own. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That struggle, </span><a href="https://comicbook.com/starwars/news/padme-almost-killed-anakin-in-revenge-of-the-sith-original-ending/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">along with reports that the original script included a more dramatic scene of Padmé attempting to kill Anakin for the greater good</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, could have been fodder for not only a more interesting death, but an arc in the narrative for Padmé. She could have literally and figuratively given birth to the Rebellion, she could have challenged what Anakin was doing in her name, she could have played a major role in challenging Palpatine independent of Anakin where the Emperor was forced to act against her as a true threat. Instead, the former Queen of Naboo is sidelined, downplayed, and ignored in favor of the action. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’d like to be able to end this and say that the <em>Star Wars</em> movies learned how to treat their female characters better. Maybe by the fourth trilogy. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-hollowing-out-of-padme-amidala/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Alexandra DeWitt, Fridging, and “Disposable” Female Characters</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/alexandra-dewitt-fridging-and-disposable-female-characters/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/alexandra-dewitt-fridging-and-disposable-female-characters/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria Zelvin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 11:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opening the Fridge]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you ever heard the term fridging? It is a trope that, put most generally,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-19885 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/fdqfzhy9ig4-300x200.jpg" alt="silver French-door refrigerator" width="345" height="230" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/fdqfzhy9ig4-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/fdqfzhy9ig4-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/fdqfzhy9ig4-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/fdqfzhy9ig4-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/fdqfzhy9ig4-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 345px) 100vw, 345px" /> Have you ever heard the term fridging? It is a trope that, put most generally, refers to the brutal death and/or harm of a usually female character solely to motivate the male protagonist. That is not to say that using death in a story is always wrong, or that the death of a character must never motivate another, but that stories are not real life and nothing within them is random. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In this case the trope of “fridging” a female character is used more as a shortcut to let a male character do bad things without tarnishing their hero’s reputation than serving any main plot point. </span><a href="https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/StuffedIntoTheFridge"><span style="font-weight: 400">As TV Tropes notes, this gruesome death is meant mostly to insult or cause anguish to someone</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">, and is the hallmark of “supremely lazy writing” that is used to get the hero from Point A to John Wick as soon as possible.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The term fridging can be traced back to one female character, a cookie-cutter stereotype of a comic book girlfriend named Alexandra DeWitt. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Stop me if you’ve heard this backstory before: Alexandra “Alex” DeWitt is a headstrong woman who works for a newspaper, who&#8217;s interested in the male protagonist romantically but holds an on-again, off-again relationship with him because she thinks he’s immature. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">But when Kyle Rayner finds a power ring, Alex heroically puts that hesitation aside and helps him design a costume, learn his newfound powers, and defeat his first villain. They even (mostly) get together for real. How nice for them! Kyle’s reward is a long career as an awesomely powerful Green Lantern.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Alex’s reward is to be murdered, mutilated, and stuffed into a refrigerator for Kyle to find when he comes home — the literal, grotesque origin of the term “fridging.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">And the worst thing about her death was that there wasn’t anything truly shocking about it happening, especially not to her character archetype, just that the manner hadn’t been used before. Especially in comics, it is a dangerous thing to be close to a hero, particularly a woman close to the hero. How many superheroes keep their identities secret out of fear of something happening like what happened to Alex? In comic book universes, the proof is more than there to justify their paranoia. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Alex DeWitt was just the latest in a long line of superhero significant others killed, tortured, mutilated, or raped to push their hero’s to tortured, dark actions. It&#8217;s the poster woman of lazy writing at all stages — and was the straw that broke the camel’s back. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Comics writer Gail Simone responded to DeWitt’s death by crafting the</span><a href="https://lby3.com/wir/index.html"> <span style="font-weight: 400">Women in Refrigerators</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> website in 1999, listing female characters who have met “icky” ends in an attempt to try to figure out why this trend exists. “It’s not healthy to be a female character in comics,” Simone wrote, before going on to insist she is neither editorializing nor trying to assign blame, but rather trying to figure out why this plot device was so pervasive. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This type of rhetorical device has existed forever, back to Homer and beyond when threats to female characters drive men into a frenzied, overly violent reaction. It’s present in the Odyssey, the Iliad, the Aeneid, Beowulf, and so on. If comic books are modern-day myths, and heroes like Green Lantern are the modern-day Hercules, then it makes sense for the storytelling devices to be used as inspiration as well. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Again, tropes are not inherently indicative of bad writing. The modern understandings of tropes, which can mean anything from a literary device with recurring use across different works or a cliche, isn’t quite what the term originally refers to. Things like allegories, hyperbole, irony, metaphor, oxymorons — those were tropes, and it is no wonder with those siblings that we began to associate the building blocks of stories with the technical devices of storytelling. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Some of those building blocks, while technically adequate for moving a story along, have aged poorly or have become prevalent enough in pop culture that serious discussion is merited — fridging is the example I’m exploring here, but it could easily be the Black Guy Dies First or Bury Your Gays — and then hopefully cause conscious cultural change for the better. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In Alex’s case, </span><a href="https://comicsalliance.com/gail-simone-the-comics-alliance-interview-part-one-batgirl-birds-of-prey-and-women-in-refrigerators/"><span style="font-weight: 400">thanks in large part to writers and comics fans like Simone</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">, there is something of a silver lining. Alex herself has been brought back off and on in the Green Lantern comics, and a few notable instances include an alternative universe version where she was chosen as Green <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-21936 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Green_Lantern_and_Green_Lantern_cover-196x300.jpg" alt="" width="196" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Green_Lantern_and_Green_Lantern_cover-196x300.jpg 196w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Green_Lantern_and_Green_Lantern_cover.jpg 255w" sizes="(max-width: 196px) 100vw, 196px" />Lantern with Kyle fridged instead, and then as a Black Lantern during the Blackest Night storyline. Alex’s death has also spawned more than a decade&#8217;s worth of criticism. The work to consciously bring attention to this problematic trope hopefully has also helped some characters survive the short-cut writing that killed her, or at the very least given them a more interesting death than “it’ll make the hero sad.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">But even today, writers, and especially writers of Green Lantern, have not quite entirely learned to stray from fridging female characters. There was an incident where Kyle Rayner, who must be starting to seriously distrust kitchens at this point, thinks he comes home to find his dismembered mother in an oven, but it was just a mannequin outfitted to trigger his PTSD. The term has definitely entered the conversation around pop culture tropes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In this monthly column, I’m going to try to Open the Fridge as much as I can, profiling the characters who have been fridged, what happened, and their legacies. This trope began with comics, but like superheros it is everywhere in movies, tv shows, and books too. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The characters who get treated as “disposable” to the story tend to be women or marginalized, and deserve to have their lives be just as meaningful to the story as the protagonist&#8217;s. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/alexandra-dewitt-fridging-and-disposable-female-characters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
