<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Musings on Heroism &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/musings-on-heroism/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:11:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What Makes a Hero? How to Cultivate Magic Within Your Authentic Self</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-makes-a-hero-how-to-cultivate-magic-within-your-authentic-self/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Imelda Wistey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Musings on Heroism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“the ultimate self” is who you really are  Creation is action . . . Gives&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em>“the ultimate self” is who you really are</em><em> </em></p>
<p><em>Creation is action . . . </em></p>
<p><em>Gives rise to existence beingness</em></p>
<p>&#8211;Mani Rao’s translation of the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bhagavad-Gita-Translation-Mani-Rao/dp/0984303618/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1520315243&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=mani+rao">Bhagavad Gita</a> (p. 56)</p></blockquote>
<p>In this post, I aim to explore the beauty that is the <em>authentic self</em>. I’ve mentioned this term several times in previous posts and I’d like to break down how to cultivate authentic self-hood through <em>being </em>versus <em>doing</em> while encompassing the enlightening magic within heroism.</p>
<p><strong>The Heroic Identity</strong></p>
<p>We’ve become accustomed to believing that what makes a hero are the deeds he or she successfully does in defeating an enemy or triumphing over impossible tasks. The main goal is usually for one’s name to live on after the hero is long gone from this world. How many times in multiple hero narratives, from<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sWppk7-Mti4&amp;index=27&amp;list=PL8dPuuaLjXtNCG9Vq7vdvJytS-F-xGi7_&amp;t=0s"> Gilgamesh</a> to<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Beowulf-Translation-Commentary-J-R-R-Tolkien-ebook/dp/B00J3V9PTO/ref=sr_1_5?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1520313492&amp;sr=8-5&amp;keywords=beowulf"> Beowulf</a>, is the sole focus of many of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/anna-sullivan-575433-unsplash.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10423 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/anna-sullivan-575433-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" /></a>these heroes to have their story last forever because they, as flesh and blood, will not? It&#8217;s interesting to see how many of these hero tales end in bittersweet triumph and heartbreaking success as if the achievements of these heroes were not enough to render happiness in their lives.</p>
<p>If the hero’s sense of self and happiness is wrapped up in achievement, it’s already a lost cause. Validating one’s worth with just outward achievements will never satisfy because it will never be enough. The desire to have one’s accomplishments define their earthly existence limits the totality of one’s heroic identity. The focus on the self in this regard coalesces into: “If I have done nothing, then what is my worth?” The main fear of these heroes is: “Will I be no one?” (Cue craftiness of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MS4jk5kavy4">Odysseus</a> to Polyphemus . . .)</p>
<p>Here is where the shift of heroism should happen. It’s not by “making something of yourself” that makes you heroic. It’s by <em>being: </em>surrendering to an inner guidance that thrives within.</p>
<p>It is in loving the authentic self, or the magic within, that cultivates the true heroic identity.</p>
<p>So let’s discover this magic.</p>
<p><strong>The Magic Within</strong></p>
<p>The authentic self as a source of magic that we all possess makes it more appealing, doesn’t it? Now, even though we all have this magic, it takes practice and skill to make the magic work for us rather than against us. This is where “being” comes in. Magic exists in the <em>being</em> versus the <em>doing</em>. Those who use this magic effectively do not necessarily know how it is done. It is only observed after the fact because they were <em>being </em>in the moment. And that is OK. If we knew how the magic worked, the wonder of its power would disappear, almost by a paralysis of analysis&#8211;an attempt to prod and question into exasperation. This concept is expressed in Keats’s narrative poem, “<a href="http://keats-poems.com/lamia-part-1/">Lamia</a>,” when the poet cries:</p>
<blockquote><p>Do not all charms fly<br />
At the mere touch of cold philosophy?<br />
There was an awful rainbow once in heaven:<br />
We know her woof, her texture; she is given<br />
In the dull catalogue of common things.<br />
Philosophy will clip an Angel&#8217;s wings,<br />
Conquer all mysteries by rule and line,<br />
Empty the haunted air, and gnomèd mine—<br />
Unweave a rainbow, as it erewhile made (lines 229–238)</p></blockquote>
<p>And just like that, the magic is gone. The angel’s wings are torn from the base of what is pure, and the rainbow is no more a painted artwork heavenly plastered in an elusive sky.</p>
<p>In observing authentic selfhood, the concept of “being” is vastly different from the “go-getter” attitude that inhabits the success/failure dichotomy of societal pressure. The strictness of this external system breeds “produce or die” conundrums and “achieve, lest become a failure” focus that haunts those trying to “make” something of themselves. People will beat themselves up mentally and physically just to make sure they don’t fall into the cracks of becoming “no one” in a world that is already unforgiving to begin with. Those pursuing greatness in life can become numb to the pressures of performing for a sliver of outward recognition and glory, inadvertently dissecting the magic rather than enjoying it.</p>
<p><strong>A Highest Good</strong></p>
<p>How one maintains an authentic sense of self during initial displacement assists the growth of the soul because what was unfamiliar and unknown is now a place of internal peace. It is not through beating one’s humanity into submission that accomplishes a task of herculean force, but rather a gentle nudge of the spirit that fuels the passion of creativity. It’s in finding that peace that one finds their authentic self. The magic rests within the heart center and radiates to help whenever needed, whether through people or through circumstance, but all emanating from you and your power.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/giulia-bertelli-94235-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10424 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/giulia-bertelli-94235-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>In the end, there is a highest good in all that occurs in life and observing yourself in moments of doubt and despair may help change the conversation in how you treat yourself. If we remember that these vulnerable moments pass and heal with doses of self-love, navigating the murky turbulent waters of life becomes more manageable. Of course, effort through perseverance and hard work is important, but it is how you use that effort: is it in love of self or in hatred of self?</p>
<p>Think of your authentic self as a child. Would you tell this child that he or she is nothing? A failure? Worthless? No. Of course not. Then why would you put yourself down?</p>
<p>Empowering your conscious self with a child-like love leads to oneness with your authentic self. By being within the authenticity of who you are, the peace will reveal itself as an emblem of hope as you tackle another goal with a passion reared from the magic that is all your own.</p>
<p>In this way, you allow yourself to be a mirror to others, inspiring others to find the magic within and cultivate the truth of their own heroic, authentic self.</p>
<p>Let me know your thoughts! Tweet me <a href="https://twitter.com/imelda_corazon">@imelda_corazon</a> with the hashtag #heromusings and I&#8217;d be happy to continue the discussion with you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rebirth and Renewal: The Underworld Journey as a Heroic Beginning</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/rebirth-and-renewal-the-underworld-journey-as-a-heroic-beginning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Imelda Wistey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 10:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Musings on Heroism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“One does not become enlightened by imagining figures of light, but by making the darkness&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“One does not become enlightened by imagining figures of light, but by making the darkness conscious.”</p>
<p>Carl G. Jung</p>
<p>In the archetypal hero’s journey, the <em>katabasis</em>, or journey to the underworld, is an iconic component for the hero’s process of transformation. The underworld, of course, can be an actual underworld, or it can be interpreted as a state of darkness for the individual. Many mythological tales from around the world speak of the underworld journey not only as a realm of the dead but also as an environment of knowledge and discovery. In this post, I will t<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/tunnel-1756856_1920.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10079 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/tunnel-1756856_1920-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a>alk about how the underworld journey is a process for rebirth and renewal to usher in new beginnings.</p>
<p><strong>Transformation</strong></p>
<p>The concept that the hero has to undergo trials to attain a semblance of enlightenment goes hand in hand with the underworld journey. Joseph Campbell mentions in the monomyth that this underworld journey is the <a href="../../Desktop/0*l1tqNuM4W71grYhi.jpg">“crossing the threshold”</a> into the “belly of the whale.” However, I also like to think of the <em>katabasis</em> as more of a state of unknown that heroes must venture into in order to experience the symbolic death and rebirth into required knowledge and understanding before setting off to complete the rest of their tasks. It’s only after encountering this dark unknown that a transformation and rebirth of the hero can happen.</p>
<p>The unknown reflects the underworld journey inward into the place of one’s own fears and shadows, haunting even the most optimistic adventurer. These shadows reflect the mythical aspect of the human condition: the repressed, often frightening elements of the psyche. The shadows, according to <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Man-Symbols-Carl-Gustav-Jung-ebook/dp/B006V3E2MC/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1522988404&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=man+and+his+symbols">C.G. Jung</a>, also symbolize “natural attempts to reconcile and reunite opposites within the psyche,” and naturally “heal the split” within one’s soul.<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1">[1]</a> In many stories, the underworld may be a cave, a forest, or even an otherworld. But these are just placeholders for the actual delving into the shadowy realms of our souls. These places are symbols for the powerful transition that happens that is not exactly of our world. It is a world that mainly exists for pivotal self-reflection. Metaphorically, by being in the dark alone, it’s impossible not to face yourself. This is why, symbolically, the underworld journey is so important to the heroic transformation<a href="#_ftn2" name="_ftnref2">[2]</a>. The hardest thing for people to do is to actually look at themselves, to really look and peer into the depths of their souls. People will avoid facing themselves because it is painful. It’s easier to ignore or dull the pain with outside distractions. In the underworld lies truths that cannot be hidden because within the dark, everything can come to light. This is where the underworld journey can take flight. Being courageous to look at the darkness within allows for a conscious transformation to take hold, a death of the shadow and rebirth into a new way of living.</p>
<p><strong>Returning to Self</strong></p>
<p>Because there are countless heroic experiences that happen in stories and in our lives, the transformation part of the heroic journey is a cyclical process. There are so many unknowns in this world that the only “known” thing is returning to self. Each transformation is another layer peeled, bringing you closer to your magical, authentic self. Yes, you are magical! Own it!  Little victories happen often if you let yourself take the time to acknowledge them. Unfortunately, for many of us, we don’t like to celebrate the little successes because we know there is still more to be done, more mountains to climb, rivers to cross, and monsters to defeat. But it’s important to take a moment after the underworld journey to admire yourself and accept that you are an amazing individual, even with those dark moments. If we don’t realize that we are constantly transforming, traveling into our own underworld journeys and coming out reinvigorated and wiser, then we don’t give ourselves the credit for striving and thriving in a world that can sometimes be unforgiving.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/butterfly-1518060_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10080 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/butterfly-1518060_1920-230x300.jpg" alt="" width="230" height="300" /></a>A New Beginning</strong></p>
<p>You’re never the same person that you were yesterday. This change allows you to venture deeper into your being and grant you time to reconnect with your authentic self. This is a time of reprieve, a time after being submerged completely in the River Styx (not dipped by the heel, because, well…you know…) to unify your sense of self once more. The process of beginning again, albeit countless times, is a catharsis, a cleansing to start again on the next task and the next trial with full speed ahead. Each plunge into the dark abyss of facing yourself and all your fears will only lead you closer to recognizing the profound strength that already exists within the entirety of your being.</p>
<p>So much to muse about with the transformations of underworld journeys! Let me know your thoughts! Tweet me <a href="https://twitter.com/imelda_corazon">@imelda_corazon</a> using the hashtag #heromusings and I’d be more than happy to continue this discussion further.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1">[1]</a> Carl G. Jung (1964) 90. Jung is great in understanding the psychological importance of myth and mythmaking.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref2" name="_ftn2">[2]</a> (Spoiler!) In <em>Black Panther, </em>both T’Challa and Erik “Killmonger” take a shamanic “journey” by dying into the otherworld / <a href="https://i.redd.it/f9xjrevhacg01.png">ancestral plane</a> to see their ancestors and are then “reborn” back into this world with greater understanding. In doing this, they also face themselves and recognize truths that only this underworld “journeying” could reveal to them.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The New First Step: Why Displacement is Crucial for Heroism</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-new-first-step-why-displacement-is-crucial-for-heroism-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Imelda Wistey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 10:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Musings on Heroism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9872</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Let everything happen to you: beauty and terror. Just keep going. No feeling is final.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Let everything happen to you: beauty and terror.</em></p>
<p><em>Just keep going. No feeling is final.</em></p>
<p><em>Don’t let yourself lose me.</em></p>
<p>-Rainer Maria Rilke</p>
<p>In previous blog posts, I have mentioned the term “displacement” as a necessary and crucial step for the hero’s journey. To become heroic, the individual chooses to rise above their predicament and achieve an innate sense of self. In this post, I will explain how displacement functions in heroic tales and how to recognize the value of displacement in our own lives.</p>
<p><strong>Why Displacement?</strong></p>
<p>If we look at the “steps” that are usually within the hero monomyth, it usually starts out with the “Call to Adventure,” <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/liana-mikah-393878-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9867 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/liana-mikah-393878-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>which can also be looked at as the “Initiation” part of the adventure for the hero’s journey. However, the hero must get out of his or her comfort zone before he or she can receive “the call” to be “out-of-place” or “dis-placed.” This displacement can be physical, psychological, and/or literal.</p>
<p>Once you notice that everyone at some point in their life has been displaced, you can start to recognize this concept pop up in a majority of narratives. For instance, displacement can be seen easily in fairy tales such as <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Phoenix-Ashes-Elemental-Masters-Book/dp/0756402727/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1517791129&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=Phoenix+and+Ashes">Cinderella</a><a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1"><strong>[1]</strong></a></em>and <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/East-Sun-West-Moon-Editions/dp/1606600036/ref=sr_1_2?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1517791452&amp;sr=1-2&amp;keywords=east+of+the+sun+west+of+the+moon">Beauty and the Beast</a><a href="#_ftn2" name="_ftnref2"><strong>[2]</strong></a></em>. I know there are many versions of these two stories, but I will just talk about the general premise of each. Cinderella is displaced within her own home and given a demeaning name. Beauty offered herself in her father’s place in the Beast’s castle away from her family and literally becomes displaced from her home. However, Cinderella (with magical help) went to the ball, rebelled against her step-family, and lived happily ever after, even owning up to her name as it has now empowered her. Beauty learned about the true nature of the Beast as a kind soul (through dreams) and ironically found freedom within the midst of the enchanted castle as it became her new home. These heroines may not have been in ideal circumstances, but they learned what they needed in order to manage their situation and rise up stronger and more capable than ever.</p>
<p><strong>Understanding Displacement</strong></p>
<p>Displacement in hero stories shows that it is possible to persist in the direst of circumstances. Stories about fairy tale heroes are essentially about humans attempting to understand and survive in the world because these stories appeal to <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/john-jason-383954-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9868 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/john-jason-383954-unsplash-180x300.jpg" alt="" width="180" height="300" /></a>an audience even if the audience did not have the same experience. However, stories evoking the collective unconscious through heroism remain essential to understanding the world since humans are constantly displaced. The heroines in fairy tales (and many other narratives—think about Sansa and Arya Stark in <em><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6uE04nQfO-Q">Game of Thrones</a><a href="#_ftn3" name="_ftnref3"><strong>[3]</strong></a></em>) reveal how these narratives are tales of human fortitude. Many fairy tale plots gain momentum when the hero or heroine enters the woods (or a magical castle), which then becomes transformed into an area of enchantment, danger, and even discovery. This displacement is what really propels the heroine to realize her own agency within the narrative and in her own life. Because the heroine recognizes what has happened and strives to do her best in her situation, she realizes that her displacement was for her highest good and crucial to her development as a human being.</p>
<p>However, if these heroines were to become destructive to themselves or others, then they would not realize the possibilities of their own heroism—they become unheroic. Only those who rise to their predicament become heroic because they do more than just conquer their foes and their fears—they understand their undeniable resilience to the displacement.</p>
<p><strong>Working with Displacement</strong></p>
<p>Because displacement is a common theme in hero stories, it is therefore important for heroism and for life. Since we as humans are constantly being displaced, we must work with our displacement so we can transcend to better understand ourselves and the world around us. We can never avoid being uncomfortable. And the world may not live up to our ideals. But in an attempt to avoid discomfort and disappointment, we ultimately avoid the chance to empower ourselves. This is when you can choose to be heroic. To get to the state of transcendence after displacement, the choice is yours to see your displacement’s greater potential. Everyone has the opportunity to grow from their displacement, to express the profound freedom and love that comes from staring reality straight in the face and finding a creative way to manage that reality. In this way, you don’t lose yourself—you discover your amazing potential for greatness already inherent within you.</p>
<p>Remember, the meaning behind these important hero stories explores how to live life to the fullest even when displaced, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/patrick-fore-557732-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9869 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/patrick-fore-557732-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>shifted, challenged, and questioned in life. Since each journey is unique to a hero’s situation, every displacement will feel and look different. However, even though displacement can be an ever-occurring cycle, it is never final. It’s uncomfortable, but like many painful feelings, it does not last forever. Like Rilke states, “Just keep going.” Unearth the heroic greatness within, for it is already yours to discover.</p>
<p>As always, if you want to continue the discussion, or have questions about the ideas of displacement and heroism, feel free to tweet me <a href="https://twitter.com/imelda_corazon">@imelda_corazon</a> with #heromusings. I would love to hear your thoughts on this subject!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1">[1]</a> I love the fact that many modern books have taken these classical fairy tales and added their own displacement twists. Click on the links to see one of my favorite Cinderella-esque story.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref2" name="_ftn2">[2]</a> <em>East of the Sun and West of the Moon</em> is such an iconic story that has similar themes to <em>Beauty and the Beast</em> and <em>Cupid and Psyche</em>. The link is Kay Nielsen’s beautiful illustrations of the story on Amazon.</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref3" name="_ftn3">[3]</a> If you are on a <em>Game of Thrones</em> let down like me, I have provided a YouTube link to History and Lore of the Game of Thrones universe. These were originally in the Blue-Ray versions of the series and are accessible on YouTube. Such great visuals and storytelling from the actors playing their characters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reimagining Heroism: Three Ways to Rethink the Hero&#8217;s Journey</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reimagining-heroism-three-ways-to-rethink-the-heros-journey/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reimagining-heroism-three-ways-to-rethink-the-heros-journey/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Imelda Wistey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 11:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Musings on Heroism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“If a story is seed, then we are its soil. Just hearing the story allows&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>“If a story is seed, then we are its soil. Just hearing the story allows us to experience it as though we ourselves were the heroine who either falters or wins out in the end.”</p>
<p>Dr. Clarissa Pinkola Estés, <em>Women Who Run with the Wolves</em> (p. 418)<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1">[1]</a></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sylwia-bartyzel-442.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9609 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/sylwia-bartyzel-442-300x198.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="198" /></a>Heroism remains a prevalent topic, especially as we head into the new year. Many readers and writers are well aware of the hero’s journey within stories and the steps that heroes take to become heroic. In this post, I look at how we can reimagine heroism by rethinking the process of the hero’s journey when applied to reading and writing stories and into our own consciousness as we navigate this new year.</p>
<p><strong>1. The Hero’s Journey as a Guide</strong></p>
<p>Each journey is unique to a hero’s situation. Of course, there are many similarities and motifs, types and archetypes that repeat throughout different time periods and cultures, but all in all, each hero’s journey is one’s own. So even if we can apply (and should apply) the lessons we glean from the heroic stories, we still have to discern what is appropriate for us in our own circumstances. We are not necessarily fighting actual dragons, demons, or monsters (though if you are, that is awesome, and I commend you for your bravery), but we <em>are</em> taking a similar approach to storybook heroes when we encounter our own fears, as our own version of warriors<a href="#_ftn2" name="_ftnref2">[2]</a>. Therefore, we should see the Hero’s Journey as a guide rather than a formula because although we can break down the steps and see on the surface how each component leads to the next, this insight in itself takes away the potency of how heroism allows for sincere understanding and transcendence. Heroism should go farther than a cursory literary analysis; the hero’s journey should ring true on levels not limited to the mind. Does the hero story <em>feel </em>right to you? Did the heroine discover her <em>authentic self, </em>her true sense of greatness? If you can walk away from the story feeling like the hero established this innate sense of self, transcending the human ideas of achievement or success, then we can be fully immersed as creators to be inspired to bring into being our own heroic stories.</p>
<p><strong>2. Storytelling as a Basis for Heroism</strong></p>
<p>Heroes must return to tell their story. After going through “the separation” and “the initiation” (trials and ordeals), “the return” allows us, as human beings, to transform into storytellers. Joseph Campbell states that the hero achieves, “a transmutation of the whole social order . . . so that through every detail and act of secular life the vitalizing image of the universal godman who is actually imminent and effective in all of us may be somehow made known to consciousness.&#8221;</p>
<p>With this understanding, heroism then comes from finding the “godman” or “godhuman,” <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/tim-foster-548560.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9610 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/tim-foster-548560-300x194.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="194" /></a>which elevates the ordinary human to creator status. This creation of stories all begins from our authentic self, the “godhuman,” the “true creator,” who reflects on all that has transpired in his or her ordeals and finds the inspiration that invites others to become creators in their own lives. Dr. Estés’ quote above explains the necessity of each hero returning to tell of his or her heroic experience to inspire others to do the same because this creative and integrative undertaking is a continuous, never-ending process.</p>
<p>Storytelling brings people together and encourages everyone to discover and bring forth greatness and a unique sense of self. Think about it. If everyone worked on embracing and understanding themselves, communing with their souls in a way, it would not be as hard to connect with others and achieve a sense of deep, genuine purpose, especially if there have been others that have returned to tell their tale of heroism<a href="#_ftn3" name="_ftnref3">[3]</a>. This shows us: “Yes! No matter what challenges I’m going through, I will overcome!” and: “This will be a great story!”</p>
<p><strong>3.) Becoming the Hero in Your Own Story</strong></p>
<p>I admit, I kind of went on an existential, metaphysical explanation of reimagining heroism. And it will continue to be this type of inquiry unless applied in practice. This practice, again, involves embracing your authentic selfhood, which can be challenging. This communing with one’s soul is not easy. It takes effort to realize that there is so much more to human life than the day-to-day, the mundane, the scary, the middle part of every story. The middle part of the story takes so much longer in life, but it is within the middle <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/jesse-orrico-487694.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9611 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/jesse-orrico-487694-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>that the most opportunity for growth can occur; it is here where the trials of developing your authentic self build momentum. Just as the heroes return to tell their stories, so can you learn to listen to yourself within your challenging ordeals and be a more authentic <em>you. </em>It all starts with letting go of attachment to how your story ends. You’re not supposed to know how your story ends. Yes, the stories that celebrate a hero’s amazing success all have incredible endings, but in reality . . . there is no end. Everything is constantly being, without a beginning or end. The greatness is ever present, no matter the situation of the beginning, the middle, or the end. And this greatness, this discovery of self, is heroic.</p>
<p>I would love to hear your thoughts on reimagining the idea of heroism as it can be applied to this daily creative process called life. Tweet me @imelda_corazon with the hashtag #heromusings and I will be happy to continue discussing this creative endeavor of heroism with you!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1">[1]</a> I highly recommend this book! It’s very inspirational and deep in regard to living the heroic life</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Women-Who-Run-Wolves-Archetype/dp/0345409876/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1514928964&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=women+who+run+with+the+wolves">https://www.amazon.com/Women-Who-Run-Wolves-Archetype/dp/0345409876/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1514928964&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=women+who+run+with+the+wolves</a></p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref2" name="_ftn2">[2]</a> Because I love the trope of heroic warrior women and pure awesomeness, <em>Rejected Princesses: Tales of History&#8217;s Boldest Heroines, Hellions, and Heretics </em>is a great read!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062405373/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1">https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0062405373/ref=oh_aui_detailpage_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1</a></p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref3" name="_ftn3">[3]</a> Dan Millman touches on the authentic self quite a lot in his books. <em>The Way of the Peaceful Warrior </em>is a great one to start off to understand the greatness that resides in each individual.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Way-Peaceful-Warrior-Changes-Lives/dp/1932073205/ref=sr_1_4?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1514929011&amp;sr=1-4&amp;keywords=the+way+of+the+peaceful+warrior">https://www.amazon.com/Way-Peaceful-Warrior-Changes-Lives/dp/1932073205/ref=sr_1_4?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1514929011&amp;sr=1-4&amp;keywords=the+way+of+the+peaceful+warrior</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reimagining-heroism-three-ways-to-rethink-the-heros-journey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Heroism: A Discussion for Discovery</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/heroism-a-discussion-for-discovery/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Imelda Wistey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 12:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Musings on Heroism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Above all, be the heroine of your life.” – Nora Ephron Throughout human history, heroes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><em>“Above all, be the heroine of your life.” – Nora Ephron</em></strong></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/david-marcu-114194.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9257 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/david-marcu-114194-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a>Throughout human history, heroes prevail among the great stories of legend, myth, and fairy tale. Stories about heroism speak to a desired past of noble deeds and virtuous character. However, I believe heroism can also be seen through people’s exposure to everyday life, even though everyday life is different for everyone. That’s why we continue to read and listen to stories of great heroes of the past and the continuing future. These stories resonate with us because we can see the universal truths and meaning behind important hero tales.</p>
<p>In this blog, my aim is to open up the conversation of heroism in stories and in life through the power of narrative. The goal is to interrogate how the hero&#8217;s journey prevails in many stories, especially myths, fairy tales, and legends, because stories from different cultures and time periods written or spoken are interrelated on the basis of human experiences.</p>
<p>My own journey with the concept of heroism began when I was a child, listening to stories my father read to me and then the books I would eventually read about the epic heroes of old. This love grew when I read the ancient Greek and Roman myths<a href="#_ftn1" name="_ftnref1"><strong>[1]</strong></a> followed by my venture into the Norse legends and eventually into the realm of world mythology. In college, I decided to major in English with a minor in Classical Studies so I could keep reading heroic stories. But even then, I was not satisfied. I knew there were so many stories out there, even modern stories, that portray heroism in a new light of discovery of who we are as human beings, rather than just a constant trope reappearing time and time again.</p>
<p>I then pursued a Master’s degree in English Literature, hoping to uncover more of the Hero’s Journey in regard to storytelling and in life. My thesis, “Displaced Heroism in 18<sup>th</sup> and 19<sup>th</sup> Century American Literature” was created by accident after taking a class on <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/jamie-street-331990.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9258 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/jamie-street-331990-250x300.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="300" /></a>Gothic literature. I was reading <em>Edgar Huntly: Memoirs of a SleepWalker<a href="#_ftn2" name="_ftnref2"><strong>[2]</strong></a></em> and I realized how the main character, Huntly, was anything but the ideal hero. He was destructive and unreliable, even though he claimed to be an epic hero in his own narrative. In analyzing his failure as a hero, I came up with the idea of displaced heroism due to Huntly’s displacement into the American wilderness whilst sleepwalking. “Displaced heroism” was the attempt to reconfigure the hero’s journey instigated by Joseph Campbell and his iconic book <em>The Hero with a Thousand Faces.<a href="#_ftn3" name="_ftnref3"><strong>[3]</strong></a></em> While the initial step for heroism is “The Call to Adventure,” I proposed that the first step is actually displacement, which extends the initial “call” because the hero/heroine must be “displaced” in order to be heroic, moving the hero from an original state that is comfortable, to an entirely new and unknown existence, which can usually pose danger. The research into the Hero’s Journey really opened my eyes to how displacement leads the hero to growth and discovery into who they are as great beings that have transformed into their best authentic selves because of what they had to overcome on their journey.</p>
<p>However, there is so much more to be discovered within the realm of heroism. With your help, I will review themes and stories from across all genres and also my own life experiences, to talk about the importance of heroism and how it allows us as readers to not only understand heroism within the story, but to also find the hero within our own being. With the hashtag #heromusings, feel free to tweet me @imelda_corazon with your questions and comments as we continue to discover heroism in all aspects of stories and in life. Essentially, the journey of the hero is the journey of what it means to be human. And to be our best selves in this lifetime, we must be the heroes (and heroines!) of our own lives.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref1" name="_ftn1">[1]</a> I started with the classic <em>Bulfinch’s Mythology</em>&#8211; <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bulfinchs-Mythology-Legends-Charlemagne-Chivalry/dp/0440308453/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1514929570&amp;sr=8-3&amp;keywords=bulfinch%27s+mythology">https://www.amazon.com/Bulfinchs-Mythology-Legends-Charlemagne-Chivalry/dp/0440308453/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1514929570&amp;sr=8-3&amp;keywords=bulfinch%27s+mythology</a></p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref2" name="_ftn2">[2]</a> If you want to traverse into a trippy tale, read this-<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Huntly-Memoirs-Sleep-Walker-Penguin-Classics/dp/0140390626/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1514929625&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=edgar+huntly">https://www.amazon.com/Huntly-Memoirs-Sleep-Walker-Penguin-Classics/dp/0140390626/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1514929625&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=edgar+huntly</a></p>
<p><a href="#_ftnref3" name="_ftn3">[3]</a> The quintessential book of heroism. Read it. Read it now- <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Thousand-Faces-Collected-Joseph-Campbell/dp/1577315936/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1514929687&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+hero+with+a+thousand+faces">https://www.amazon.com/Thousand-Faces-Collected-Joseph-Campbell/dp/1577315936/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1514929687&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+hero+with+a+thousand+faces</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
