<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pop Culture Profiles &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/pop-culture-profiles/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:17:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Food: More Than for Eating</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/food-more-than-for-eating/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristen Julia Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 16:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Profiles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new crock-pot, rice cooker and hand mixer sit above the cabinets in our kitchen.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new crock-pot, rice cooker and hand mixer sit above the cabinets in our kitchen. A brand new, still unused food processor is tucked in a corner between an end table and a kitchen table. My husband and I live in a small 1 bedroom apartment and the kitchen (refrigerator, sink, and stove) is built into one side of its hallway. The other side is a wall and the door to our bedroom. Cabinet space is scarce, as is counter space. We make it work though and, when time allows, cooking is one of our favorite hobbies to do together despite the space limitations of our hallway kitchen.</p>
<p>When we first started dating, we decided to make homemade potato pancakes together. I didn’t even have a stand-up grater, just a small hand-held one that is more meant for shredding cheese more than anything else. Making the potato pancakes took double the time we anticipated, but it was time we spent together, getting to know one another. Food is a part of our relationship: making food, eating food, and even talking about food.</p>
<p>Perhaps this is one of the reasons why, when we aren’t sure what we want to watch on TV, we’ll search for a food show to watch. They are not only enjoyable to watch, but they introduce us to new cuisines, educate us about food and food prep, and inspire us to try new flavors – to be bolder, more comfortable with our own cooking, which is especially important given our dairy and gluten restrictions.</p>
<p>Some of our favorites food shows to watch include Chopped, Good Eats, Cutthroat Kitchen, and Parts Unknown. Anthony Bourdain’s Parts Unknown episode about Thailand was an undeniable influence on our decision to visit Chiang Mai during our honeymoon to the country. It’s also where I realized my food bravery is far less than my new husband’s.  I may have tried durian (a fruit that when opened smells like dirty socks) but I drew the line at eating insects – he, on the other hand, went for it.  Luckily we never came across a restaurant serving the blood soup Mr. Bourdain eats on the episode.</p>
<p>Food – it fills our bodies with nutrients, and our minds with memories so strong they become a part of not just what we eat, but how we relate and connect to others. Food is a central to so many families and traditions. It unites new friends and can build relationships between strangers. Trying foods, especially those unfamiliar or from a different culture, is a way to reach beyond ourselves and embrace the beauty of our differences.  I hope that the food my husband and I make, serve, and eat as we grow as a couple not only serves to strengthen our relationship, but that we, as people, are enlightened, continually, through the diverse flavors and food of our vast world.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Horror Season</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/horror-season/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristen Julia Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Profiles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fall. The nights are crisper and get darker earlier.  The front yards of houses throughout&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Fall. The nights are crisper and get darker earlier.  The front yards of houses throughout neighborhoods are decorated with cobwebs, ghosts, and cemetery scenes.  Trees have an eerie sort of dance to them as they change color from green to orange, red and yellow and begin to shed their leaves. Fall also means horror movies.</p>
<p>They just fit. Yes, horror movies can be watched any time of year but there is simply something about the shift between hot summer nights and cold winter evenings that influences my viewing decisions toward choosing those that fit someplace within the horror genre.  Sometimes this means going to the movie theater but more often it means re-watching movies from my youth that I haven’t seen in years or watching seasonal favorites.  This year’s older horror movies have included <em>The Birds</em>, <em>The Blob, The Shining, Carrie</em>, <em>Children of the Corn</em>, <em>Lost Boys, </em>and <em>Misery. </em></p>
<p>Movies produced today may offer advanced special effects and more gore than any of these, but there will always be something about villains like blood-thirsty  birds and a murderous father that chill like no other because they make us think about the what-ifs. The scare isn’t about 4-D surround sound theater experiences but the simplicity of  possibility and the unknown. The likelihood of someone who is secluded from society during the entirety of winter entering a homicidal state of insanity and hallucination – that has a greater chance of being a real news headline vs a zombie outbreak (though give me a creature feature any day too!).</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/index-1.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7502 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/index-1.jpg" alt="index" width="176" height="263" /></a>Within my seasonal horror rotation are also those I have somehow missed through the years.  Always too is at least one movie that is so horribly and ridiculously bad it’s oh sooo good. This year &#8211; I give you <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0100740/">Tales from the Darkside:  The Movie</a>. </em>It connects 3 separate spooky tales together in one overarching wraparound story.  In the wraparound story, a woman, Betty, (played by Deborah Harry (yes Debbie Harry from the band Blondie)) is preparing for a dinner party which features a child named Timmy as the main course.  The three segments, one about a mummy, another about a killer cat, and one about a gargoyle, feature quite the star studded cast, even by today’s standards. For example, the mummy one “Lot 249” stars Steve Buscemi, Christian Slater, and Julianne Moore.</p>
<p>The fall season passes fast. By the time this blog posts it will already be November and we’ll be getting closer to winter and snow. What better atmospheric time of year to watch one a movie based on a Stephen King movie set during a blizzard.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harry Potter and the Lost Magic</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/harry-potter-and-the-lost-magic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristen Julia Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 15:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Profiles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve written before about Harry Potter – I suppose it’s one of my go-to subjects,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/index.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7175 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/index.jpg" alt="index" width="259" height="194" /></a>I’ve written before about <em>Harry Potter</em> – I suppose it’s one of my go-to subjects, especially when I’m running behind on writing an article.  Not to mention that 2016 has provided plenty of HP material for me to think about and use, including, of course, <em>Harry Potter and the Cursed Child.</em></p>
<p>What can be said about the book?  The first thing to remember, if you haven’t read the script yet, is that it is just that: a script (not a novel).  This means that scenes which may in a typical novel take hundreds of pages, maybe even an entire installment in a book series, to cover are introduced and addressed in a couple pages.  Events move along fast &#8211; very fast. Time travel is a major part of the play; however there is only teasingly brief time spent in any of the alternate realities. Nevertheless, as a play, there&#8217;s only so much space/time available for details. There are secondary (though I would like to learn more about them) characters mentioned merely in passing (such as Harry and Ginny’s children Lily and James Potter) or those who didn’t end up quite where, I suspect, many fans expected (Ron?).  Yet there are also clever nods to minor characters which in the few paragraphs focused on them provide more insight into their character than all of the previous 7 books combined (the Trolley Witch).</p>
<p>There is actually much to contemplate philosophically throughout the script and for an avid HP fan fiction writer, there is certainly also much room for side stories to develop. A major focus of the play is to destigmatize house Slytherin as being the “evil” house as well as the development of the Malfoy / Potter relationship through their sons.  The theme of good and evil and the power of the individual to determine their own path based on their own choices remains an important theme. Further, the inclusion of time travel as experienced by three of the play’s main characters (Scorpius Malfoy, Albus Severus Potter, and  Delphi Diggory) emphasize how the world can be greatly and negatively altered when we try to change a past event – no matter the reason (I can hear Doctor Who saying something like: “I told you about fixed events! Will you ever listen!” to himself).</p>
<p>Overall, do I think that <em>Harry Potter and the Cursed Child</em> was necessary or that it adds anything to the original series which I felt was missing – no. Do I feel it ruined the original series? Again no, not at all. Does this mean I am ambivalent to the play?  I want very desperately to say no – that I have a strong opinion &#8211; but I think that’s just it. I’m glad I read it; I hope to see it one day when (if) the play comes to Broadway, but the overall magic that filled me as I read the original series – I didn’t exactly get this time around.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Female Role Models: They Matter</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/female-role-models-they-matter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristen Julia Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 16:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Profiles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I admit it. Sometimes I live in a bubble. Sometimes I selectively forget or ignore&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I admit it. Sometimes I live in a bubble. Sometimes I selectively forget or ignore how much inequality exists in our world.  This is not a good trait of mine. It’s too easy for me to pretend. I shrug it off with an awkward smile when someone exclaims to me “you look so young!” or “you look like a little girl still” even when I am wearing a slacks and a sensible shirt.  I’m told these comments are meant as a compliment, especially after the speaker finds out that I’m nearly 40-years-old; however being told I look like I’m still in high school doesn’t help me to be taken seriously among colleagues who are much more assertive than I.  Being told I look so young is not a compliment.  I constantly work at being less passive, more confident, and I’m still working on it. I&#8217;ll always work at it. That will never change how I look though.</p>
<p>This past week a major political party nominated a woman as its presidential candidate for the first time since elections began 227 years ago. This matters.  Nobody should vote for a person (or not vote for a person) based on a candidate’s gender, race, ethnicity, or sexuality.  However, every child who aspires to be president should feel they too can reach their goal if they work hard enough toward it.  Growing up, I never thought about being president.   Girls simply were not presidents; the presidents of the United States were all white men. Then Obama was elected as president. And now Hillary Rodham Clinton is the presidential candidate for the Democratic Party. By having a female presidential candidate, it opens the door for so many others to not just dream, but to realize that they can reach their goals as long as they keep true, work hard, and do not give up or give in to naysayers. I’m not saying that we’ll have, for an example, an Asian American transgender woman running for president in eight or twelve years even, but with each pre-assumption of what a candidate should look like that falls, the more doors open for a range of leaders of tomorrow to emerge.</p>
<p>Am I, by the way, allowed to modify or rather expand upon something I wrote in <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/some-thoughts-on-the-ghostbusters-remake/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">my previous article about the new Ghostbusters movie</a>?  In it I wrote that “I am a fan of the original movie and I have my concerns just like I do when any movie I have fond memories of is remade.  [My concerns], though, have nothing to do with the casting choices for the lead characters.  I’d feel the same concerns if the cast had consisted of people like Paul Rudd and Seth Rogan.”</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/88566096_hi031789832.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6920" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/88566096_hi031789832-300x169.jpg" alt="_88566096_hi031789832" width="497" height="280" /></a>This was only a half-truth. My hopes  for what the all-female cast symbolize and mean to our society was/is far greater of an issue than I emphasized in that first article. How by casting the movie with female leads, rather than male leads, the movie helps to chisel away at the gender divide long upheld in our society.   How by portraying independent, brilliant female characters focusing on a common goal together despite their differences or past conflicts emphasizes girl-power at its core (I also have to admit that I highly appreciated the role reversal of casting a stereotypical dumb blond female secretary role with a male actor).</p>
<p>I saw the movie on its opening weekend. There weren’t many people in the theater to be honest.  Did I walk away thinking I’d just experienced the most life changing movie of my life as a woman? No. No I didn’t. However, had I seen it as a 10-year-old girl for the first time, would I then have looked at those four women and thought – <em>wow they kick ass! Maybe I can be like them one day too?</em>  I think so. I’d like to also think that young girls who see the new <em>Ghostbusters</em> movie, or who see a woman as presidential candidate for the Democratic Party, are inspired to not just dream but to realize they can reach their goals in life just like anyone else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Some Thoughts on the Ghostbusters Remake</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/some-thoughts-on-the-ghostbusters-remake/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/some-thoughts-on-the-ghostbusters-remake/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristen Julia Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 16:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Profiles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6759</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stories are often rewritten by those who want to share their personal vision on an&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stories are often rewritten by those who want to share their personal vision on an original tale – this is nothing new.  From picture book renditions of source materials to blockbuster movie adaptations, there are countless retellings of stories like<em> Cinderella</em>, <em>Little Red Riding Hood</em>, <em>Rapunzel </em>and <em>Beauty and the Beast</em>. Recently <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3040964/">Jon Favreau’s interpretation</a> of Rudyard Kiplinger’s novel the <em>Jungle Book</em> presented a darker take in live action/ CGI format.  In Favreau’s movie, “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=15rUJuKCM90https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=15rUJuKCM90">I Wanna Be like You</a>,” the iconic catchy jazzy tune from the original Disney animated version sung by King Louie, takes a slightly more sinister spin as presented through the recognizable voice of Christopher Walken. However, while my inner child was nostalgic for the original light-hearted song, I also appreciated Walken’s representation as well.   Other popular movie remakes (some with several) include <em>Godzilla</em>, <em>Robin Hood</em>,<em> Tarzan</em>,<em> The Nutty Professor</em>, <em>The Karate Kid</em>, <em>The Bad News Bears</em>,<em> The Parent Trap</em>, <em>Clash of the Titans</em>, and the list goes on and on.  Sometimes a new interpretation, like <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0905372/">John Carpenter’s version of </a><em>The Thing, </em>may even surpass the original or become the preferred version among fans.</p>
<p>When a remake is announced, sure, some might roll an eye and think “can’t anyone come up with an original idea” or “I really liked the first version – why did they have to go and remake that movie?” but being a fan is, after all, being defensive in a sense. The release of next week’s remake of the 1984 <em>Ghostbusters</em> movie with its all-female cast replacing the original foursome of Aykroyd, Murray, Hudson and Ramis seems to be taking more hits than usual though.  Much of the criticism surrounding the reboot stems from whether or not Kristin Wiig, Melissa McCarthy, Leslie Jones and Kate McKinnon can do justice to the original film not as actors but, specifically, as female actors. So, rather than media focus centering on how the cast has the potential to, perhaps, motivate young girls to pursue careers in the sciences, it is instead focusing on whether or not women can carry a blockbuster movie.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ghostbusters-2016-cast.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6763" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ghostbusters-2016-cast-1024x684.jpg" alt="Ghostbusters Day 16" width="450" height="301" /></a>When the trailer released in 2015, naysayers took to social media like YouTube and Twitter posting misogynistic remarks regarding the all-female cast. An article posted on MSNBC.com,<a href="http://www.msnbc.com/msnbc/sexist-ghostbusters-backlash-coincides-2016-gender-divide"> “Sexist &#8216;Ghostbusters&#8217; Backlash Coincides with 2016 Gender Divide</a>” by Adam Howard notes how “after just two trailers and a few commercial spots, legions of fanboys have taken to comment sections to lambaste the project. Its first trailer, released in March, set a record for most dislikes on YouTube and prompted one popular online critic to refuse to even review it.”  The article further emphasizes how the success or failure of the movie with its all-female cast has the potential to affect the careers of female comedians both directly and indirectly.</p>
<p>Not all the backlash points fingers at the female cast. For example, movie producer Ivan Reitman, as shared in a <a href="http://time.com/4390604/ghostbusters-producer-reboot-backlash-sexism-nostalgia/">Time.com article</a>, claims that criticism isn’t based on anti-feminist rants but rather from overly protective hardcore fans of the original movie. And, yes, many fans are most likely annoyed at a remake in general.   However, the fact that any criticism suggests that the movie’s all-female lead cast is a negative simply because they are women is a disappointingly sad reminder of how closed-minded many can still be.</p>
<p>I am a fan of the original movie and I have my concerns just like I do when any movie I have fond memories of is remade.  My concerns, though, have nothing to do with the casting choices for the lead characters.  I’d feel the same concerns if the cast had consisted of people like Paul Rudd and Seth Rogen. Ghostbusters was one of the first movies I saw in the theaters – it presented the perfect combination of comedy and horror for my childhood self. I am personally less concerned with how Wiig, McCarthy, Jones and McKinnon will portray their characters as I am with how and if the movie will do justice to the highly memorable opening library ghost scene.  If they get that scene wrong – this librarian will be highly disappointed!  And they better not mess up Slimer or The Stay Puft Marshmallow Man either! I guess I’ll find out on Friday July 15 when the movie releases nationwide.</p>
<p>Sources:</p>
<p>http://time.com/4390604/ghostbusters-producer-reboot-backlash-sexism-nostalgia/</p>
<p><em>http://www.gossipcop.com/ghostbusters-backlash-trailer-reactions-female-reboot-fans-women-2016-remake/</em></p>
<p><em>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/30/12027882/ghostbusters-reboot-all-female-backlash-sexism-sony</em></p>
<p><em>http://www.msnbc.com/msnbc/sexist-ghostbusters-backlash-coincides-2016-gender-divide</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/some-thoughts-on-the-ghostbusters-remake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Magic of Harry Potter</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-magic-of-harry-potter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristen Julia Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 16:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Profiles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A now former coworker introduced me to Harry Potter in 2002. Four books were published&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A now former coworker introduced me to <em>Harry Potter</em> in 2002. Four books were published in the series at the time; I spent the next 5 years eagerly waiting for each new book to release. I was in my early 20s and never questioned if I was “too” old to enjoy the series.  Friends ten years older and several years younger were hooked just like me.  I immediately found myself mesmerized by the world JK Rowling shared with her readers.  Part of the everlasting appeal of the series is that it is ageless and timeless. Visiting the world is also, in a sense, comforting.  To paraphrase what my friend Jackie recently explained regarding why she rereads the <em>Harry Potter </em>series: it is because reading the books is like visiting familiar friends.</p>
<p>When I would finally get my hands on the newest Harry Potter release, I’d stay up all night, devouring every sentence and plot twist.   While I have since had the opportunity to re-watch the movies many times, I still need to find time to reread all the books from start to finish.   There is so much value in rereading a text because with each new read, there is new discovery.  The more one reads a series or book, the better they grow to know the characters and worlds within the pages. The better they mature from a passive reader to one who is fully engaged and able to question the whys and whats of that particular fictional world.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/harry-potter-and-the-cursed-child.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6622 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/harry-potter-and-the-cursed-child-300x186.jpg" alt="harry-potter-and-the-cursed-child" width="300" height="186" /></a>The <em>Harry Potter </em>series remains highly popular; this was true even prior to the announcement of either <a href="http://www.harrypottertheplay.com/"><em>Harry Potter and the Cursed Child</em> </a>or <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ViuDsy7yb8M"><em>Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them</em></a>.   If I didn’t work in a public library and receive requests for books in the <em>Harry Potter </em>series multiple times a week, I may not believe just how popular the series is among today’s youth.  If anything the series isn’t fading in popularity, it’s increasing and continuously finding new audiences. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/index-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-6621 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/index-2.jpg" alt="index" width="184" height="273" /></a></p>
<p>Parents of children between the ages of 7-9 sometimes ask me if <em>Harry Potter</em> is appropriate for their child. I’ve had other parents tell me that their 9-year-old has finished the series and needs something more challenging. I’ve had others ask me for recommendations other than <em>Harry Potter</em> because it’s the only series their son or daughter seems to want to read.  These are far from simple answers because a child’s maturity isn’t always based on age. Rereading shouldn’t be stigmatized as a “bad” either.   What I wish I could say is let your child grow up with Harry, Hermione, and Ron because that is part of the magic and overall experience.</p>
<p>Seeing how children as young as 7 are starting with the series did make me start to re-question whether or not I was too old for it myself. This self-questioning didn’t linger long. Harry Potter’s appeal seamlessly crosses the age divide. I saw this come to life when I visited the Wizarding World of Harry Potter.  Walking into Diagon Alley was like being transported into the books themselves.  Children, teens, and adults walked around wearing Hogwarts robes, drinking butter beer and casting spells.  Though I resisted the serious buying impulse to purchase my own robe, I did purchase one of the interactive wands.  Around Diagon Alley and Hogsmeade are markers letting people know where they can “cast a spell” to make something happen.  Each marker has directions for how to move the wand and what to say.</p>
<p>I was a bit nervous and self-conscious to try it at first. And again that voice returned, asking “am I too old for this?”.  When I looked around though, I saw people of not only different ages, but also different cultures, genders, and races each trying their best to cast spells.  So I gave it a go … and I tried again &#8230; and again … and nothing!   Then from the corner of my eye I saw a young girl, maybe age 10, approach me. I thought she wanted to use her wand, so I started to step out of the way. However, instead she asked me if she could help me out.  I of course, said yes! She first demonstrated how to move the wand and where to point. She then stood by my side, instructing me as I attempted to cast the spell again – this time with actual success! That moment, that was one of my favorites of my visit. It reminded me that no one else thought I was too old to be roleplaying; I was the only one having those thoughts. Being an adult does not have to mean losing the magic of fantasy.</p>
<p>I was even able to (somewhat) defeat my life-long fear of roller coasters thanks to the Wizarding World of Harry Potter. As someone who has held a severe fear of roller coasters and moderate motion sickness her entire life, I was pretty unsure of my decision to finally ride one for the first time in over 20 years.  However,  though I’m far from ready to conquer the thrill rides at Six Flags Great Adventure, the Harry Potter 3D rides (Escape from Gringotts and the Forbidden Journey) are so entirely immersive, I was able (with the assistance of motion sickness meds)  to forget my worries and just enjoy the experience.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Life Without Cable Television</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/life-without-cable-television/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristen Julia Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 16:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Profiles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I haven’t had cable television for over two years and I don’t miss it.  Well,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/AA_orphanblack_thumbnail_s2_02_web.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6386 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/AA_orphanblack_thumbnail_s2_02_web-300x169.jpg" alt="AA_orphanblack_thumbnail_s2_02_web" width="300" height="169" /></a>I haven’t had cable television for over two years and I don’t miss it.  Well, not really. There are times I miss watching some of the shows I used to watch when they first aired – but those are far fewer than the ones I’m now, finally, catching up on.</p>
<p>When I moved and decided that one way to save a bit of money was to cut my monthly cable bill, I worried that I would miss out on viewing some of my favorite shows when they first aired like <em>Doctor Who, American Horror Story </em>and <em>Orphan Black</em>. However, while I often favored shows that aired on channels like SyFy Channel, AMC, BBC, much of my TV viewing was often of shows on channels like the Food Network, Discovery Channel or Animal Planet. These, while they were entertaining and even informative (I’ve learned more than a bit about cooking from the shows on Food Network), they were TV stations that I could still live without. If you haven&#8217;t heard of any of the shows mentioned throughout, be sure to check them out. With this being said, if you are in countries where some shows are restricted, you can use a VPN (Virtual Private Network) to allow you access.</p>
<p>Using VPNs to access programs in different countries can be both beneficial and risky. The risk being some providers may choose to take a look at your encrypted internet traffic. And some of this information could get logged. For example, UK based company HideMyAss, <a title="" href="https://privacy.net/best-vpn-services/">HMA caught logging</a> evidence on one of their users. They claimed not to have logged the content of the internet traffic, but did record the IP address of this user’s device when he connected and disconnected the VPN. With this being said, the user had committed an offence, where the police needed information to arrest him for.</p>
<p>Regardless, the main issue was that this company had that information to give away in the first place.</p>
<p>I knew I needed to keep internet access for multiple personal and job related reasons. So, I spent some time reviewing cable and internet package options in my area. If I was going to pay extra for cable, it only made sense to me if the package included the BBC and SyFy channel and these, I soon realized, were only included in the pricier plans. There are often enrollment incentives that present lower monthly payments on packaged deals. However, the monthly prices go up (sometimes a lot) after the first year or two depending on the plan itself.  I couldn’t afford to end up paying $125 or more a month for cable and internet after the initial deal ended – which is exactly what would have happened.</p>
<p>Another major reason for my decision was that I tended to use Netflix streaming and DVDs borrowed from the public library more often than I actually watched shows on cable television. I didn’t want to give Netflix up because they were starting to come out with some well-written, engaging, addictive original programming too. If you haven’t seen <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3339966/"><em>Unbreakable Kimmy Schmidt</em> </a>or <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3322312/?ref_=nv_sr_1"><em>Daredevil</em></a>, you should!  Unfortunately not all shows are available on Netflix streaming, like <em>Doctor Who</em>, but I manage. I suppose not having access to everything is helping me become both a more patient and more focused person, when it comes to my TV viewing habits at least.</p>
<p>I may be a season behind on <em>Doctor Who</em>, which makes me feel a bit like a disloyal fan, but having to wait isn’t the end of my world.  Season nine released on DVD about 1 month ago (April 2016) and that means I’ll be borrowing it from a library soon and binge watching for a couple weeks.  And sure, I may be missing some new shows that sound intriguing and that I may actually like, but I can wait until they are available on DVD or streaming to watch them. I’ve found that I’m more focused on the TV shows I watch. When there were so many options, I felt like I could never go back and watch series that I somehow missed or only caught a few random episodes of when they first aired. I’m finally working my way through all the seasons of two shows I’ve had on my to-watch list for a quite a while: <em>Gilmore Girls</em> and <em>X-Files</em>.</p>
<p>At some point, I may end up getting cable TV again, but with other media options that I have yet to fully take advantage of (Amazon Prime and Hoopla) or even try, like Hulu or HBO Go, I feel like I won’t need to. Having fewer options also means I actually have more time to watch TV – which as a person who has many interests, I highly appreciate.  Now, if I only could somehow figure out a way to make the list of all books I want to read more manageable…my Goodreads “want to read” list is frightening!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>More to Librarians Than a Stereotype</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/more-to-librarians-than-a-stereotype/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/more-to-librarians-than-a-stereotype/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristen Julia Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 16:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Profiles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Picture a librarian. Do you picture a librarian who works at your school or public&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="abody">Picture a librarian. Do you picture a librarian who works at your school or public library? Or do you, perhaps, picture a generic middle- aged woman wearing a cardigan — probably covered in cat fur — with her hair in a tight bun and low-lying thin-rimmed glasses, perhaps sitting with her long, bony index finger pressed against her pursed lips as she whispers “shhhhhh.” Perhaps you picture a younger woman — still in cardigan and glasses of course. Maybe you see a librarian from a film or TV show like Rupert Giles from “Buffy: the Vampire Slayer,” Evelyn Carnahan from “The Mummy” or Marian the Librarian from “The Music Man”.</span></p>
<p>The librarian stereotype is perhaps one of the most well- known and iconic in American culture. I’ve been told, many times, that I even “look like a librarian.” I’m never sure if that is supposed to be taken as a compliment or not. I wear glasses; I wear cardigans; and, yes, I even own a cat! However, while I certainly don’t want to be seen as a stiff, shushing, craggy woman, I can’t deny that I’ve had to tell a child or 10 to quiet it down in the library.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/librarians.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-6271"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6271" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/librarians.jpg" alt="librarians" width="450" height="405" /></a>So, as a proud cardigan-wearing librarian, I’m here to tell readers and defend the reason there just might actually be some — very basic — truths that lead to the out-of-proportion librarian stereotypes. Let’s start with the cardigans: cardigans are convenient! They are easy to put on and take off. Library HVAC systems<span class="abody"> are anything but reliable. Many libraries are freezing in the wintertime due to poor heating and also freezing in the summer due to arctic air-conditioning. It’s not always cold though; sometimes the AC will decide it just doesn’t want to work — usually on the hottest days of the summer — or, on rare occasions, it might actually be a comfortable temperature. Plus, different people feel comfortable at different temperatures and keeping a cardigan nearby is usually just a library staff member’s way of preparing for fluctuating, and even extreme, indoor temperatures.</span></p>
<p>Next up: eyeglasses. A lot of people wear eyeglasses; I’m pretty confident this is not something exclusive to librarians. Yes, some people, including librarians, even wear eyeglasses like a fashion accessory or because glasses fit their personality. Most people wear eyeglasses, though, so they can see better. Wearing contacts for hours on end can also be pretty uncomfortable — dry eyes or eye strain come to mind. So, like wearing cardigans, wearing eyeglasses is also partly about convenience.</p>
<p>What about cats you ask! Why do so many librarians own cats? Well, first off, I’m not sure that’s true. And cats are liked by many — if they weren’t, cat videos wouldn’t be so popular on the Internet;<span class="abody"> admit it, you probably just watched one a few minutes before reading this column. Cats are unpredictable and that’s part of the fun; one minute they want nothing to do with any human and the next they might be purring away on your lap like a personal furry heating blanket and then suddenly jumping off to tackle a toy mouse that has been sitting in the same corner of the room, unmoved, for three weeks. Librarians don’t hate dogs — well, at least I don’t. I know and have even worked with many librarians who own dogs! I’m sure there are some who own other pets as well.</span></p>
<p>Librarians are always saying “shhhhh.” Not always, but sometimes, yes, especially in libraries, where people might be gaming online and doing homework only a few feet away from one another. Part of being a librarian is helping to manage the atmosphere of the room and this always means dealing with volume control. Youth service librarians probably say “shh” more than others. Children in a library get rowdy. It happens. They’re children.</p>
<p>Librarians do nothing but read all day, every day! I would absolutely love it if I could read every book published for older children and teens; it would make me the most knowledgeable youth services librarian ever! But the truth is, who has the time to do nothing but read? Not me! Like most librarians, I try my best to read as much as I can so that I can better provide recommendations and also be knowledgeable<span class="abody"> about my area of focus; but, saying that I’ve actually read every children’s and young adult book would be a huge lie. Of course, I could be lying and keeping safe the librarian secret that we are actually able to manipulate time to our will — but that’s just ridiculous … or is it?</span></p>
<p>In all seriousness, being a librarian is a rewarding job in which we get to work with the public and, yes, even at times get to read new book releases in advance. Still, the stereotype is one that tends to hover over us in a not-good way. Recently, many librarians have even tried to combat the old stodgy stereotype by promoting the tattooed, hipster stereotype to the public. One stereotype isn’t better than another though. There is also no librarian-approved attire as a whole, although each individual library may have their own culture of dress.</p>
<p>What matters most shouldn’t be what we wear, the pets we own or the corrective lenses on our faces — what matters is the job we do each day and how well we serve our patrons. We, like all people, have off days. Hopefully, overall, we [&#8230;] are doing our profession and community proud by providing top-rate librarian services regardless of what else might be going on in the background. That’s our goal each and every day.<span class="abody"><b><br />
</b></span></p>
<p><span class="abody"><b>This article first appeared in the  West Orange Chronicle and News-Record of Maplewood &amp; South Orange on 3/31/16.</b></span></p>
<p><span class="abody"><b><br />
</b>Kristen Julia Anderson is the teen librarian at the West Orange Public Library in NJ.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/more-to-librarians-than-a-stereotype/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Visit Your Public Library Today!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/visit-your-public-library-today/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristen Julia Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 15:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Profiles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mention popular culture and libraries together and many will probably think of the New York&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mention popular culture and libraries together and many will probably think of the New York Public Library and Ghostbusters. But this blog post isn’t going to be about fictional libraries – instead it’s about what’s really going on and why public libraries, more than ever, need your support.  Most of us probably have positive real-life memories of visiting a public library at some point – whether as an after school job, attending programs, or getting lost among the rows of books. More than memory makers, public libraries are essential in their communities.  However, in the state of New Jersey, public libraries all too often struggle just to keep their doors open due to inadequate funding.</p>
<p>NJ public libraries are financially supported through local taxes and are required to be funded, at minimum, at a third of a mil. In other words, a person pays 33 cents to their local library for every $1000 her property is valued at being worth. So a person who has a property that is valued at a million dollars will have $333 of their total property taxes go to their local public library.  When you are looking at numbers and how much it costs to keep a library running, the minimum library funding is rarely enough. For this reason, many libraries also rely on donations and fundraisers, but this still may not be enough to keep things going.</p>
<p>Think of it this way: libraries need budgets for materials, programs, technology,  online databases, staff, maintenance, and so much more. In order to function within the minimum funding, libraries have to make tough cuts. Like when any business faces cuts, the first thing to go is often personnel. When there isn’t enough staff to run them, programs and hours also need to be reduced. It’s a domino effect of the worst kind.</p>
<p><a class="left-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/593820313v1_350x350_Front_Color-White.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-6185"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-6185 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/593820313v1_350x350_Front_Color-White-300x300.jpg" alt="593820313v1_350x350_Front_Color-White" width="300" height="300" /></a>We need public libraries. They are not a luxury. People throughout our country struggle with financial hardships and public libraries provide free resources and services to help them find jobs and work on resumes. People for whom English is a second language turn to the library for ESL tutoring and to practice for the TOEFL test. Children use the public computers to do their homework and yes, play games. To someone who walks in and sees five kids standing around a couple computers watching others play an online game may seem distracting or wasteful – to me, though, when I see how they help each other complete levels, when I see friendships form, when I know they are in the library having a good time rather than outside in the cold or hanging on the streets – I am grateful.</p>
<p>One of my proudest moments as a teen librarian happened at a recent town budget meeting where people spoke on behalf of increasing the budget of the library where I work for above the state mandated minimum. I never expected to get teary-eyed at a town council meeting but listening to everyone talk, especially teens, with such passion for their library and for their librarians made dry eyes impossible.</p>
<p>If we in NJ receive the increased funding we need, that doesn’t mean we, won’t or other public libraries, won’t face similar struggles in the near or distant future.  However, the support from our community at the town council meeting was nothing less than heartwarming and inspirational. People from as young as age 10 to those who are old in age and young in spirit stood up at the podium and spoke about why the library deserves increased funding.  Hearing them also validated my decision to leave the corporate world and lets me know that I am making a difference, that all public librarians are making a positive difference in the lives of the people we serve.</p>
<p>If you haven’t been to your local library in the past week, month, year – go &#8212; go today – go right now. Most public libraries are no longer the brick-and-mortar quiet buildings you may remember from years past – they are the community centers of their neighborhoods. There is still, though, nothing like seeing the wide-eyes of a child who walks into the children’s room for the very first time and sees all the books she might borrow and read one day. Public libraries more than matter, they are nothing less than magical.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Supernatural Story: Or Why I Still Watch Supernatural After All These Years</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/my-supernatural-story-or-why-i-still-watch-supernatural-after-all-these-years/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kristen Julia Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 17:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Profiles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ If you, like me, find yourself up to date and hooked-in by the show Supernatural&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/SupernaturalPic.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5927"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5927 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/SupernaturalPic-300x204.jpg" alt="SupernaturalPic" width="300" height="204" /></a></p>
<p><em> If you, like me, find yourself up to date and hooked-in by the show </em>Supernatural (<em>despite some really disappointing episodes and seasons) then you’ll probably relate to much of what I write below. </em></p>
<p>My first time watching an episode of <em>Supernatura</em>l was completely unintentional. My roommate at the time (still a good friend of mine) was having mutual friends over to watch the finale of Season 4, “Lucifer Rising.”  At the time I was pursuing my MA in English – which involved a great deal of reading and writing papers and limited TV watching.  The time I had to spend with friends was pretty much non-existent.  So, when I heard my roommate was having our good mutual friends over to watch the show,  I decided to work on an assignment while sitting in the living room with them. I figured that since I didn’t really care about the show, I could easily block it out and concentrate.</p>
<p>Well, I was wrong.</p>
<p>I remember sitting with my laptop on my knees, searching for documents to use to support a paper I was working on at the time.  My original plan was that I would also work on the paper itself.  And I sort of did.</p>
<p>I didn’t know who Sam, Dean, or Castiel were; I didn’t know who Ruby, Zachariah or Lilith were or what was going on in the show.  But from the moment <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ymFHRex9dI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kansas’s “Carry on My Wayward Son” played during the opening of the episode</a>, I kept sneaking glimpses at the screen until I finally gave up on grad school work and just watched.</p>
<p>Want to guess what I did after the episode’s end?  I somehow found time to binge watch seasons 1-3 over the next 6 months. I was drawn in by the family relationship of the Winchesters, their loyalty, their flaws, their humor. The monster of the week stories gave me a better understanding of the type of life the boys were raised in and how they lived. Plus learning about the lore of various monsters and demons was just cool to learn about  &#8211; there was more than one time that I looked up information on a monster or lore from the show (What’s a “Wendigo”? What’s the truth behind the Scandinavian pagan god in the “Scarecrows” episode?) For this then-English grad student and now Librarian, it also didn’t hurt that the show often featured Sam and Dean (well mostly Sam) doing research and using multiple sources (Looking up information on online, interviewing experts, referring to notes written by their father)!</p>
<p>Then when the demon and angel / Lucifer and Sam storylines really took off, that was it for me – if I wasn’t hooked already (which I was!), I was then.  By the time season 5 started I was completely caught up.</p>
<p><em>Supernatural</em> quickly became a show my friend and I would watch together every week. At first we would watch it when it aired. Eventually, when the show moved to a night that I have to work late, we switched to watching it on-demand.  Eight years later, the show is still on and my friend and I still watch it together.  We even stuck it through seasons 6 and 7.</p>
<p>Sure, there are predictable plot lines; while watching it we can pretty much say the dialogue before Sam or Dean.  Predictability comes, though, because of both how long the show has been on and how thoroughly fans understand the characters&#8217; personalities. Since the show has gone on for so much time after its original story arc – I, like probably all fans, feel  invested and concerned about whether or not the show’s writers and producers will, or can, give the show an ending that won’t disappoint or be predictable. How can they at this point?  However, regardless of how long the show runs for (which I don’t think can be much longer) I know I&#8217;ll still keep curiously watching the road ahead and re-watching  the one they&#8217;ve left behind.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
