<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Writer Mentality &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-writer-mentality/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 03:22:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Publishing Formats &#038; amp; Platforms for the Ambitious Writer (part 2)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/publishing-formats-platforms-for-the-ambitious-writer-part-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Britny Brooks]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 15:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Writer Mentality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Let&#8217;s see what we&#8217;ve got so far: Some form of story: check. The type of publishing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s see <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/publishing-formats-platforms-for-the-ambitious-writer-part-1/">what we&#8217;ve got so far</a>:</p>
<p>Some form of story: check.<br />
The type of publishing you&#8217;d like to toil through: check.<br />
An idea of what format you want to use: check.</p>
<p>Okay, well how about these:<br />
Book cover design?<br />
Page layout?<br />
ISBN number?<br />
Social media platform? Marketing and PR plan?</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5176 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/ebook_library--300x200.jpg" alt="ebook + books" width="300" height="200" /></p>
<p>You might be thinking, &#8220;Wait, where did all that come from?&#8221; but you have to remember that self publishing is an interconnected process. A choice that you make in the beginning has a pretty high chance of affecting choices that you might need to make later on down the road. Realistically, working with a publishing platform is going to be one of the last things that you&#8217;ll do, but it&#8217;s important to remember that formats and platforms are directly connected to each other so it&#8217;s a good idea to get into the habit of planning ahead.</p>
<p>E-book publishing platforms are tools that can help you format and distribute your work. If I had to name a few off the top of my head it would be the Big 3: <a href="http://www.amazonkdp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kindle Direct Publishing</a>, <a href="https://www.nookpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nook Press</a>, and <a href="http://www.apple.com/ibooks-author/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">iBooks Author</a>. One of the nice things about working with these platforms is that you don&#8217;t really have to worry about picking a format because it&#8217;s &#8220;preselected&#8221; for you. For example, when you write something in Word you get a .docx file, when you work with Kindle you&#8217;ll get a .kindle file. These are also popular names and you might have an advantage working with their large audience group for you to distribute to your e-book to.</p>
<p>Just because they are popular doesn&#8217;t mean that these three are the only publishing platforms out there. It might be a good idea to check out other platforms like <a href="https://store.vook.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vook</a>, <a href="http://www.ebookit.com/index.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">eBookIt</a>, <a href="http://www.bookbaby.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bookbaby</a>, <a href="http://www.smashwords.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Smashwords</a>, <a href="https://www.kobo.com/writinglife" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kobo</a>, <a href="http://www.blurb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Blurb</a>, or <a href="https://www.scribd.com/publishers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Scribd</a>. However, while all publishing platforms with help you distribute your e-book, not all will offer design or book formatting services and might require that your e-book already be polished and ready to go before they will distribute it. Also keep in mind that many platforms can cross devices (meaning that you can read something on your e-reader and then move to your tablet or smart phone), but that doesn&#8217;t mean that your work can cross platforms. For example, if you upload your work on to the Nook platform that doesn&#8217;t mean that people on a Kindle platform will be reading it. You&#8217;ll have to figure out if your work is going to appear on multiple platforms and be ready to commit to the extra work to get it up if it isn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>Honestly, platforms aren&#8217;t scary or really all that difficult to work with because, by the time you get to this point, you&#8217;ve done most of the hard work already. So the best thing you can do is plan ahead&#8211;do some shopping around, a little research, and play around with some platforms to see which works the best for you. Then hold that thought and roll up your sleeves because it&#8217;s time to transform your story into an e-book.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Publishing Formats &#038; Platforms for the Ambitious Writer (part 1)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/publishing-formats-platforms-for-the-ambitious-writer-part-1/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/publishing-formats-platforms-for-the-ambitious-writer-part-1/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Britny Brooks]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 17:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Writer Mentality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Okay, so last time we took a look at the different types of &#8220;self&#8221; publishing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so last time we took a look at the different types of &#8220;self&#8221; publishing available to writers. The reason self is in quotation marks is because, if you remember, we found out that there are varying levels of professional help that you can ask for with each type of publishing. Many writers don&#8217;t realize that self-publishing doesn&#8217;t mean &#8220;all alone&#8221; publishing, and that it&#8217;s okay to ask for help sometimes. Keep in mind with this post that I&#8217;m not going to talk about the writing or revision process that should be occurring (and reoccurring) while getting ready to go through the publication process. I like to plan ahead and some writers might like to have an idea of what type of publishing, format, and platform you&#8217;re interested in using in advance. If you aren&#8217;t that kind of writer, no worries. Just come back to this when you are ready.</p>
<p>Now, we&#8217;ve decided to take the publishing route that gives us all the control (huzzah!) and all of the work (yay&#8230;): self publishing an e-book. My strategy for this post is to break it into two separate posts. Part one will be about publishing formats and then part two will be publishing and distribution platforms. While they are different aspects of the publishing process, formats and platforms have the potential to be more compatible in certain pairs. Also working with one platform or format verses another can sometimes effect the look and the level of ease that you complete your project.</p>
<p><b>ebook Formats</b><br />
First, what is a format anyway? Well, an easy comparison to the ebook format would be a document type. When you save your novel/short story collection/chapbook/etc. in your word processor, it&#8217;s saved as a specific document type (i.e., .doc, .docx, pdf, .pages, etc.) and an ebook format is very similar. Each format allows certain aspects of your document to be accessed or manipulated by different platforms. Don&#8217;t worry, while some formats are more popular than others, they all do basically the same thing.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">The 4 most popular (or commonly known) ebook formats are:</p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: left;"><strong>EPUB</strong></li>
<li style="text-align: left;">Kindle</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">iBook</li>
<li style="text-align: left;">eReader</li>
</ul>
<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-4608" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/EPUB_logo-218x300.png" alt="bright green &quot;e&quot; with word &quot;pub&quot; underneath" width="100" /></p>
<p>EPUB is bolded because it&#8217;s the most accepted and popular of the formats. EPUB allows for a document to have the option of being reflowable content (content that can be shifted to match any reading device) or fixed-layout content (useful for publishing houses so they can use one format from in-house to distribution and sale). This is now the official standard format for the International Digital Publishing Forum (IDPF).</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-4611 size-thumbnail" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/kindle-itunes-logo-150x150.png" alt="blue background with silhouette of a tree and a child reading" width="150" height="150" /></p>
<p>Kindle, iBook, and eReader formats all seem to tie for second place. Both Kindle and iBook formats are similar to EPUB with the only differences being in a few html and CSS tags. However, there is a hitch with iBooks in the End-User Licensing Agreement &#8211; if a writer wants to charge a fee for their work formatted with .ibook generated with the iBooks Author, it can only be sold or distributed through iBooks.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-4609 size-thumbnail" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/IBooks_OS_X-150x150.png" alt="orange circle with white book" width="150" height="150" /></p>
<p>eReader was top dog before EPUB because it treated the published content like a book and nothing more. It would only allow one page to be shown at a time and you could create footnotes, or bookmark a page, but that was pretty much it. At first this was great, because readers just wanted an way to access and keep a larger number of books in one place. But once readers decided that they wanted to read their e-books on different types of devices and be able to have more interaction with the text, the eReader format just seemed too simple and EPUB was formed.</p>
<p>There is no &#8220;correct&#8221; format, but a good rule of thumb to follow is to be accessible to as many platforms, and people, as possible. If you&#8217;ve worked in a particular format before or know more about it, go with it. If you&#8217;re in doubt, go with the EPUB format. Once you&#8217;ve decided what format you want your work in, next is deciding what platform you&#8217;re going to use, but that&#8217;s for part two.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/publishing-formats-platforms-for-the-ambitious-writer-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>You&#8217;ve Written a [Insert Something Here]&#8230;Now What?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/youve-written-a-insert-something-here-now-what/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Britny Brooks]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 16:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Writer Mentality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome, fellow writer. You&#8217;re here because you have created something that you&#8217;d like to share&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome, fellow writer. You&#8217;re here because you have created something that you&#8217;d like to share with the world and maybe get a hard copy to strategically place on your coffee table &#8211; and maybe your mom&#8217;s coffee table. Okay, let&#8217;s be realistic &#8211; on all of the coffee tables. It&#8217;s also possible that you clicked on the wrong column and you actually wanted to read what&#8217;s on <em>RWX</em> or <em>KC on YA</em>, but it&#8217;s too late. You&#8217;re stuck here now.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Woman-writing.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" size-medium wp-image-4354 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Woman-writing-300x199.jpg" alt="Woman sitting on a yellow sofa on her laptop writing" width="300" height="199" /></a></p>
<p>The beautiful and terrible thing about self-publishing is that anyone can do it. Yes, when I say anyone I mean: any person in the world with a decent grasp of a human language and access to a device with the internet. Anyone can self-publish, but that doesn&#8217;t mean that they do it well, and that&#8217;s the trick. Self-publishing isn&#8217;t hard, but it can be stressful and time-consuming.</p>
<p>With self-publishing, you aren&#8217;t just a writer anymore. Now you are a designer, publisher, marketer, and many other things for your work and it will require you to think and make decisions while in those roles instead of as writer. That can be tough to do, but that is one of the terms that you will have to understand and accept if you want your work to stand out from the rest. The second of these terms is that everyone is going to have their way—most likely in list format—of doing things. This is not a list of what to do or the best way to go about self-publishing. It&#8217;s just information that I&#8217;ve gathered and placed before you in a style similar to a lavish banquet. First course on the menu: publishing models.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/typeset.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" size-medium wp-image-4358 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/typeset-300x201.jpg" alt="a pile of wood block and metal typeset keys for traditional printing presses" width="300" height="201" /></a></p>
<p>There are different ways to go about self-publishing, but there are four main branches: <strong>Subsidy</strong>, <strong>Vanity</strong>, <strong>Self-Publish</strong>, and <strong>Print On Demand</strong>. Really the biggest difference between the four is where your money is spent on the process of publishing and the responsibilities of the publishing house or company that helps you. You might be saying to yourself: &#8220;Wait, I just want to publish an e-book. Isn&#8217;t that what self-publishing is?&#8221; Yes and no, but hold on a little longer—self-publishing is kind of like an iceberg and we&#8217;re sitting at the top.</p>
<p><strong>Subsidy </strong><br />
You pay for your work to physically become a book—the binding and printing parts—and the publishing company will help pay part of the costs for your work to be edited, marketed, and distributed. Similar to Vanity, but the writer will own the book until it&#8217;s sold and then makes money off of royalties.</p>
<p><strong>Vanity</strong><br />
You pay for all of the services to make your work into something physical, but you own the book and the all of the profit when the book sells, instead of receiving royalties. However, you will not receive any help with editing or promotional services. This type reminds me of a mercenary—they&#8217;ll take any job as long as you have the money to pay for their services, but that&#8217;s it.</p>
<p><strong>Print On Demand</strong><br />
You pay for a publishing company to produce a printed copy of your book to fulfill a specific order. You&#8217;re not paying for the company to warehouse any &#8220;unsold&#8221; copies of your work so it&#8217;s a lot more cost-effective. You can pay extra to have help with editing, promoting, and all that other jazz, and you make money off of royalties.</p>
<p><strong>Self-Publishing</strong><br />
You pay for the production, marketing, and distribution/warehousing of your book—so basically everything. While this puts all of the cost on you, it also gives you the most control over your book because you control when the book is published and what format it&#8217;s in. You also keep all of the rights and all of the profits, but you also are doing all of the work so it&#8217;s only fair.</p>
<p>Most of us are going to want to take the Self-Publishing route, but it isn&#8217;t a bad idea to understand the other types and make sure that self-publishing is the best fit for you. There are plenty of companies that are willing to help edit, design, and promote your work, but be careful that you don&#8217;t end up paying for things you don&#8217;t need. Since the desire to self-publish has risen so have the endless companies that are there to &#8220;help you&#8221; and it might take some research to know which one might be the best equipped for your needs. Don&#8217;t forget there is always traditional publishing too—it&#8217;s just off in a dark corner somewhere pouting.</p>
<p>Next course in our banquet: Formats and Publishing Platforms!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing Programs or Self-Publishing</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-programs-or-self-publishing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Britny Brooks]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 18:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Writer Mentality]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Writers love to write. Even though we struggle and sometimes we&#8217;ve got to beat a story&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Writers love to write. Even though we struggle and sometimes we&#8217;ve got to beat a story out with blood, sweat, and a few creative curses, we can&#8217;t help but continue to write. Now, with the help of the internet and countless apps in the palms of the avid pen scratcher, not only the creation, but the distribution, of countless stories has become easier. Suddenly, it&#8217;s as if every one has realized that writing was never reserved for just the scholars and the students blessed by an ancient muse, but for anyone. If you don&#8217;t believe me, look at the free stories on Kindle or the growth of independent, online literary magazines. However, this begs the question: if anyone can publish their work on the internet and be a writer, what is going to set you above the rest?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-4200 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/coffee-569178_1280-300x198.jpg" alt="coffee cup with notebook, phone and computer in background" width="300" height="198" />My answer was to study and obtain a Master&#8217;s degree, but having already graduated with a Bachelor&#8217;s in English &amp; Creative Writing, a part of me understood that even if I went back to school it still might not be enough. That wasn&#8217;t what was important to me though&#8211;I didn&#8217;t want the fast track to stardom, I just wanted to be a better writer. Which is why my father shakes his head and laughs when he calls to check up on me. He was the one who introduced me to the Fantasy and Science Fiction genres and we still recommend favorite books or authors for the other to read, but he doesn&#8217;t understand why I needed to go back to school to write. My father jokes and points out the authors of .99 cent Kindle books that he has been reading and says that they&#8217;re pretty good if you ignore the surface errors that occasionally pop up. Then he casually mentions that I should upload a few of my short stories; I&#8217;d make some extra money.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s tempting, but at this point I don&#8217;t feel like I&#8217;m continuously producing the caliber of work that I want people to read from me. Honestly, it takes a lot of courage and self-awarness as a writer to say, &#8220;I&#8217;m just not ready yet&#8221;, and I don&#8217;t think there is anything wrong with that. At the end of the day you have to remember that there are always going to be other writers that will create and publish amazing stories, and some will have a degree and some won&#8217;t. While I think self-publishing gives you the opportunity to get your stories out there, going back to school could give you the edge and the experience to set yourself apart from the other keyboard junkies. There are no steadfast rules on how to become a writer and that&#8217;s the best part.</p>
<p>Of course there are things that you always have to think about as a writer, self-publishing or not, like deadlines, grammar rules, peers to read your work, and then other peers to help spread the word, but we&#8217;ve all seen that before. This isn&#8217;t going to be a bulleted list with the &#8220;tricks&#8221; and &#8220;tips&#8221; to getting published, writing a novel, or staying motivated. Instead, this column is going to be the extra hands that you need when you are a writer thinking about (or already in the process of) self-publishing. Just because you&#8217;re going to publish your work on your own doesn&#8217;t mean that you&#8217;re alone, but when tackling self-publishing you have to be ready to carry more than just your title as a writer.</p>
<p>Do you accept this challenge? Are you ready to get your stories out and make them look good from cover to ISBN? Then the Writer&#8217;s Mentality is for you. I&#8217;ll bring the advice, ideas, resources, and details that a self-publishing writer should know about and you&#8217;ll bring the fabulous stories. Deal? Alright let&#8217;s get started.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
