<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Frequently Asked Questions &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/frequently-asked-questions/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:07:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Where Are All the Everyday People?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/where-are-all-the-everyday-people/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elora Powell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 11:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is a long tradition of science fiction protagonists being in a very specific set&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14535 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/rawpixel-781987-unsplash-300x212.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="212" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/rawpixel-781987-unsplash-300x212.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/rawpixel-781987-unsplash-768x542.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/rawpixel-781987-unsplash-1024x723.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />There is a long tradition of science fiction protagonists being in a very specific set of occupations. Many of the earliest examples were scientists, or so-called &#8220;gentleman explorers.&#8221; Think of Dr. Victor Frankenstein from Mary Shelley&#8217;s <em>Frankenstein, </em>or Phileas Fogg from <em>Around the World in 80 Days</em> by Jules Verne. Captain Nemo, Dr. Jekyll, and the Time Traveler from <em>The Time Machine</em> are other notable examples. The nature of these characters and their careers made it easy to create a fantastical situation or world that totally defined the expectations of readers.</p>
<p>As technologies progressed, and new instruments of war began to reveal their awesome, devastating power, more and more science fiction protagonists were in the military, or had a military background. Edgar Rice Burroughs&#8217; John Carter fought in the American Civil War. The crew that intercepts Arthur C. Clarke&#8217;s Rama is full of military personnel and scientists. This approach to speculative storytelling uses the training and experience of military protagonists to get them through ordeals that ordinary readers could never face. It still remains a popular story mechanism. The fairly recent <em>Stargate</em> shows were based around a top-secret U.S. Air Force program.</p>
<p>Probably the most common type of protagonist is the one that is somehow employed by the government, or a secretive, higher organization. <em>Many</em> science fiction shows follow this pattern. Almost all <em>Star Trek</em> main crew members across all the series are in the employ of the United Federation of Planets. The Marvel show, <em>Agents of SHIELD</em> reveals the occupation of its characters in the title.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not saying this to dismiss any of these characters or stories. In fact, I&#8217;m a fan of most of them. I think it&#8217;s exciting to find patterns like this, because it opens up new questions to be explored by sci-fi writers and creators, such as: where are all the everyday people?</p>
<p>The world today is full of strangeness: new scientific discoveries; technologies that seem like magic to the lay person. It doesn&#8217;t take a scientist or a starship captain to explore strange, new worlds anymore. There is room, now, to look at what it means to be a suburban mom, an inner-city kid, a barista, a mechanic, or a traveling musician in a science fiction context.</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t a completely new concept. Ray Bradbury was known for putting a speculative edge on everyday situations and characters in his short story collections. Read &#8220;There Will Come Soft Rains&#8221; from <em>The Martian Chronicles</em> for an eerie tale of a futuristic suburban family that feels <img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14536 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/rawpixel-1054587-unsplash-300x281.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="281" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/rawpixel-1054587-unsplash-300x281.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/rawpixel-1054587-unsplash-768x718.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/rawpixel-1054587-unsplash-1024x957.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />almost more at home in a modern anthology than one from 1950. Comedic shows such as <em>Lost in Space</em> and <em>Alf</em> also brought the extraordinary into ordinary living rooms.</p>
<p>But what about when the extraordinary is ordinary? Those are the questions I see answered more and more in current speculative media. What would it be like to live in a horror-trope filled, Lovecraftian small town in the desert? Listen to <a href="http://www.welcometonightvale.com/"><em>Welcome to Night Vale</em></a> to find out. How would you survive as the only human on an intergalactic cooking show? Read the comic <a href="http://www.natalieriess.com/space-battle-lunchtime"><em>Space Battle Lunchtime</em> </a>for the answers.</p>
<p>We live in a world full of strange and extraordinary things that previous generations could never have dreamed of. All you need to do is tip the scales a bit &#8211; exaggerate a small element of modern, everyday life, and you get a fascinating and compelling speculative fiction concept. As they say, the future is now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is the Best Way to Enjoy Speculative Fiction?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-is-the-best-way-to-enjoy-speculative-fiction/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-is-the-best-way-to-enjoy-speculative-fiction/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elora Powell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 11:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, there are more ways than ever to get your fiction fix. Novels, musicals, comic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/julius-drost-1052294-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11988 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/julius-drost-1052294-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>Today, there are more ways than ever to get your fiction fix. Novels, musicals, comic books, movies, television shows, and video games have all dabbled in the realms of the strange and other worldly. They each have their own avid fans, claiming that their medium of choice is the best. Complicating the matter even more is the fact that many stories and franchises have crossed over into multiple forms of media.</p>
<p>So, how do you decide which way is the best way to enjoy a certain story?</p>
<p>You could play it as a video game, fully immersing yourself in the story by taking in the sights and sounds of the world from the perspective of the main character. The screen becomes your eyes and the game controller becomes an extension of your hands, which can impact what happens in the game-world. However, many games require an immense amount of time to complete, and bring with them a steep learning curve.</p>
<p>You could immerse yourself in a story through reading a book. The words translate into images in your mind, creating an experience of the story and characters completely unique to you. However, it is hard to have a communal experience when reading a book.</p>
<p>You could experience a story through a movie or a television show. This provides the auditory and visual simulation, and the potential for human interaction over the same set of images and sounds. However, film has long been criticized as providing an incredibly biased view of a story, often limited by the conventions of society at large and the whims of the industry.</p>
<p>You could read a comic book or graphic novel &#8211; a unique combination of images and words that seems to combine the best of movies and novels. The motion takes place through the same process of internalization that takes place in reading a novel. However, the combination of images and words can easily go wrong, leading to something either incoherent or redundant.</p>
<p>So, what is the best way to enjoy a science fiction story? Personally, I usually like to experience a story in the medium it was first created in. But that isn&#8217;t a requirement by any means. <em>Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide to the Galaxy</em> made an excellent transition from <a href="http://www.thegeektwins.com/2015/01/how-to-listen-to-original-hitchhikers.html">radio to novels</a>. Comic books continue to be a resource to which film and TV creators turn to with varying results.</p>
<p>Maybe <em>all</em> the ways are the best way to experience speculative fiction. Great stories can be found in all traditional media formats and creative people continue to find new and exciting ways to tell stories. Whether you&#8217;re settled in your medium of choice, or dabbling in a little bit of everything, I hope you find stories that fit your interest and give you beautiful moments of revelation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-is-the-best-way-to-enjoy-speculative-fiction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Makes a Female Protagonist Great?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-makes-a-female-protagonist-great/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elora Powell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 10:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In American pop culture and genre fiction, it&#8217;s been a long and rocky road to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/nicolas-gras-772446-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11767 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/nicolas-gras-772446-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>In American pop culture and genre fiction, it&#8217;s been a long and rocky road to representation for women. In the early 20th century, as comic books and science fiction became an industry, many people believed that women weren&#8217;t even an audience for those types of stories. That, plus the lingering belief from previous centuries that there was less psychological and temperamental variation among women than among men, (which psychologist <a href="http://www.feministvoices.com/leta-hollingworth/">Leta Stetter Hollingworth</a> did a great deal of work to disprove), led to a long tradition of women in comics and genre fiction being sporadically represented; and when they were represented, deeply stereotyped.</p>
<p>As various women&#8217;s movements throughout the century addressed this discrepancy, creators and publishers made an attempt to remedy the situation. Unfortunately, the writers were often still men, and many of them had a poor understanding of how women wanted to be represented in stories. As always, there were notable exceptions, but that idea that women were somehow less diverse than men pervaded and many female characters fell into predictable tropes.</p>
<p>How then, do you write a good female protagonist? Even women writers have sometimes confessed to struggling with writing female characters in science fiction and fantasy. Our own perspective has been buried and misconstrued in our favorite media so much that it is hard to reclaim it as our own.</p>
<blockquote><p><em><strong>I think the most important key to writing women in genre fiction is making them human. That is both the simplest answer and the most complicated.</strong></em></p></blockquote>
<p>As humans, women in fiction need to have their own thoughts, feelings, and motivations, which they express independently of the men in the story. The 1960s Batman henchwomen, who are &#8220;poor, deluded children&#8221;, and really didn&#8217;t mean to do anything bad have thankfully fallen out of fashion. However, many female characters are still motivated solely by male influences.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/aman-ravi-92428-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11768 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/aman-ravi-92428-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>The problem with trying to remedy this is that sometimes, it works. Many women in the real world are motivated and influenced by the men in their lives. Whether it be a break-up with a male romantic partner, or the expectations of a father, it is not unreasonable to portray a woman as influenced by a man. It can be a realistic motivation. The trouble arises when men are the only motivation a female protagonist ever has. That&#8217;s completely unrealistic.</p>
<p>As independent, holistic human beings, women have just as complex thoughts, feelings, desires, and motivations as men. And they deserve to be written and represented that way in media. That shouldn&#8217;t be a revolutionary statement. But, as long as women continue to be on the sidelines of genre fiction, stereotyped and relegated to a specific set of roles, I&#8217;ll keep on saying it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who Needs a Sidekick?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/who-needs-a-sidekick/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elora Powell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The concept of a sidekick is a slippery one in today&#8217;s storytelling climate. Traditionally, at&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The concept of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_comic_book_sidekicks">sidekick</a> is a slippery one in today&#8217;s storytelling climate. Traditionally, at least as far as superheroes go, sidekicks have been junior partners to a hero—usually adolescents (yikes!), training under the tutelage of the titular hero of the book in question. Many were introduced to relate to the presumed audience of young, adolescent males.</p>
<p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2_mo2T7msL4</p>
<p>Sidekicks have been—ahem—kicked to the curb lately in superhero media. Traditional sidekicks have been either aged up to make them equal partners with their heroes, such as Captain America&#8217;s friend, Bucky; or implied to have been killed off-screen in some vague point in the past, and never given a second mention (thanks for that, <em>Batman v Superman</em>. You&#8217;d better give us a Red Hood or Nightwing film now&#8230;). To some extent, this is understandable. It&#8217;s a little bit terrifying if you really think about a 13-year-old fighting in the streets of Gotham City, or the front lines of WWII.</p>
<p>But is there still any place for the concept of sidekicks in comics and genre fiction today? I think there is.</p>
<p>Simply from a storytelling perspective, sidekicks serve some very important purposes. Especially for very powerful, and very iconic heroes, sidekicks give the reader an &#8220;in-character&#8221;—someone they can relate to. Most of us don&#8217;t have superhuman strength, incredible mental capacities, or unlimited social stature and capital. So, it&#8217;s the sidekicks that really get us invested in the stories.</p>
<p>In addition, by their very presence, sidekicks humanize their heroes. They give them people to talk to, relate to, and<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/robin-1115934_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11492 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/robin-1115934_1920-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a> care about. They up the stakes due to their comparative disadvantage in whatever skill or power the hero possesses. No one exists in a vacuum. Sidekicks give us a chance to see the way our heroes practice teamwork and interpersonal conflict.</p>
<p>As speculative fiction and comics continue to move away from and individualistic model of character development, I expect to see the importance of sidekicks and supporting cast members increase. The movie <em>Black Panther</em> was a good example of community-based storytelling. T&#8217;Challa was far from the only fleshed-out character in the story. He and his family and friends relied on each other to protect the innocent, and overcome the villains.</p>
<p>Superhero sidekicks may have moved away from 13-year-olds in tights saying &#8220;gosh, yes!&#8221; to everything their hero says; but I believe they are far from obsolete. Even the most lonely, brooding characters need someone to bounce off, because we, as readers, need to see people in established relationships working together, just as we see in real life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Makes a Superhero a Superhero?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-makes-a-superhero-a-superhero/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elora Powell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My dad recently tried to convince me that Luke Skywalker is a superhero. Both my mom&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/miguel-bruna-503098-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11231 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/miguel-bruna-503098-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" /></a>My dad recently tried to convince me that Luke Skywalker is a <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/the-superheroes/201003/what-is-superhero">superhero</a>. Both my mom and I vehemently denied it.</p>
<p>He&#8217;s a hero.</p>
<p>He&#8217;s a protagonist.</p>
<p>But he&#8217;s not a superhero.</p>
<p>Why, though? What makes the notion of Luke Skywalker being a superhero seem so absurd?</p>
<p>Could it be the fact that he doesn&#8217;t have some kind of superpower? Well, technically, he <em>does</em> have a type of superpower. His sensitivity to the Force provides him with a great deal of supernatural abilities. By a definition of superheroes that requires superpowers, Luke Skywalker would be a superhero, and someone like Batman or Black Widow would not; even though stories about the latter two are generally categorized under the &#8220;superhero&#8221; genre.</p>
<p>Is it because he&#8217;s not originally a comic book character? That sort of definition would exclude characters such as The Incredibles, or Terry McGinnis&#8217; Batman from <a href="http://batman.wikia.com/wiki/Batman_Beyond"><em>Batman Beyond</em></a>, as they originated in other mediums. It could also classify other characters, such as Archie and Tintin, as superheroes solely because of the medium in which they originated. It is important to distinguish between the <em>medium</em> of comics, and the <em>genre</em> of superheroes. While superheroes have been a mainstay of comics for decades, there are many comics of different genres, and many superheroes in different mediums.</p>
<p>What makes a character a superhero, then? Why does it seem right to say that Wonder Woman is a superhero, but not as correct to say that The Doctor from <em>Doctor Who</em> is a superhero? Aside from the capes and cowls, and primary motivations of justice, revenge, and compassion, I think that superheroes need to have some aspect of duality to their character.</p>
<p>Superman is also ordinary reporter Clark Kent some of the time. Batman&#8211;while not necessarily <em>ordinary</em>&#8211;has a life <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/patrick-fore-557732-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11232 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/patrick-fore-557732-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>outside of his caped crime fighting. Spiderman is a high school student.</p>
<p>While we see a transformation in Luke Skywalker&#8217;s character, we don&#8217;t see him having a separate life outside of being a Rebel and a Jedi. The Doctor, although they have taken many different forms, is always The Doctor.</p>
<p>Of course, this is just one possible definition of superheroes. The genre is so broad and diverse that it is hard to narrow down to specific characteristics. However, I think this definition explains quite a bit about our fascination with superheroes.</p>
<p>One of the reasons we love superheroes so much is that they are like us, but they are also very different. Like gods of ancient mythology, they are characters with human characteristics, as well as superhuman abilities. We shape these emblems of power into our own image in order to say what we would do, should do, or should <em>not</em> do with the same type of power. I believe superheroes give us a feeling of rightness&#8211;of control over our surroundings&#8211;so we continue to turn to them for comfort.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Does Science Fiction Look Like?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-does-science-fiction-look-like/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elora Powell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10869</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When you hear the words &#8220;science fiction&#8221;, you may get a very particular image in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-baker-421759-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10893 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/john-baker-421759-unsplash-300x198.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="198" /></a>When you hear the words &#8220;science fiction&#8221;, you may get a very particular image in your head, whether it be the bridge of the <em>U.S.S. Enterprise</em>, a strange, alien planet, or the vast, starry void of space. Science fiction has very strong visual and aesthetic elements, many of which have influenced real-life design and architecture. There is the futurism inspired by Jules Verne at the turn of the century; the sleek, space-age stylings of the mid-century; the neon colors and dingy corners of cyberpunk.</p>
<p>But what does science fiction <em>really</em> look like? How can you say if a visual piece of art or design is speculative or not? Does it need to be in space? Does it have to be in the future? Does it have to conform to a preexisting science fiction or futurist aesthetic? That seems rather limiting. The problem with trying to define speculative fiction as a particular set of visuals or aesthetics is that speculative fiction is too broad a category.</p>
<p>Personally, my favorite type of speculative stories and imagery usually stem from the ordinary. Whether it by science fiction, fantasy, or horror, I love pictures and plots that begin with something familiar. It could be a place, like a coffee shop, or a library, or a music store, or an era, like the 1960s. Then, slowly but subtly, the speculative trope is introduced, and an alternate world is created.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/stephane-delval-554284-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10894 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/stephane-delval-554284-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>But there is a complete opposite realm of speculative literature and design, (created by people vastly more creative than me), which imagines the unimaginable. Some science fiction, fantasy, and horror creators have the ability to dive into the depths of otherness and strangeness. Their aliens are far more than green-painted humanoids. They are truly alien. Their fantasy worlds are not mere allegories for our political climate. Their monsters are monstrous because they show how much we really don&#8217;t understand about the world.</p>
<p>Both are good. Both are speculative. Both can provide culturally meaningful images and narratives that shape the minds and ideas of fans. And the same goes for all the shades and nuances that fall somewhere between these two camps.</p>
<p>So, what does speculative fiction look like? I suppose the most specific thing that we can say is that it looks like <em>otherness.</em> It may be an otherness that at first glance seems normal, but causes an unease that demands a second glance. It may be an otherness that is awe-inspiring, and all-consuming. But it is that otherness that lies at the very heart of speculative fiction. It causes us to look up from ourselves, and our routines, and imagine what else might be out there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who is Science Fiction For?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/who-is-science-fiction-for/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elora Powell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last month, in this very same column, we talked about speculative fiction generally, and science&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last month, in this very same column, we talked about speculative fiction generally, and science fiction particularly, in terms of their place on the literary fiction/genre fiction spectrum. I concluded that while it may be perfectly accurate to consider science fiction “genre fiction”, we are entering an era in which media does not have to be labeled as “high art” or “literature” to be thoughtful, thought-provoking, and culturally meaningful. But enough recap. If you are interested in that <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/is-science-fiction-genre-fiction/">post</a>, go back check it out, and meet me here when you’re done. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You ready? OK. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/alice-hampson-5714-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10663 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/alice-hampson-5714-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This month, I wanted to talk about some of the practical implications of science fiction as genre fiction. What has this meant to previous generations, and what does it mean now? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the past, different genres of popular fiction were marketed to very specific audiences. Romance catered to women, pulp science fiction, like <a href="https://www.edgarriceburroughs.com/">Edgar Rice Burroughs</a>’ stories, were tailored to the presumed tastes of young men and boys. A strange and fascinating phenomenon occurred, though: people actually just liked whatever they liked. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is a concept that is still catching on in the present era. Women like comic books. Men like romance novels. Nonbinary people like science fiction stories. And on and on and so forth in infinite combinations. It turns out that people’s tastes in stories and concepts cannot be predicted by their gender, age, or race. Individual personalities and preferences are broader than the narrow categories society, publishers, and advertisers still attempt to fit them into. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What does this mean for the present day? How do science fiction and related genres press forward without the traditional demographic constraints to and define them? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I hope the answer is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">incredibly</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">powerfully</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">beautifully</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/jonathan-francisca-606247-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10662 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/jonathan-francisca-606247-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>When the genres of speculative fiction are open to more voices, and broader representation, the old, tired-out tropes that no longer surprise and mystify will fall away, and be replaced by new ideas. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This kind of transformation in the genres can only take place when the people who love science fiction- in all their diversity and creativity- are unleashed to share their stories with one another. “Gatekeepers”, people who decide who is “in” and who is “out” of the fandom, only hold the stories that they love back from becoming even better, and wilder, and more exciting. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who is science fiction for? Science fiction is for the people who love science fiction. And the stories of science fiction will become a powerful force for cultural change, and meaningful imagery precisely when they come from the minds of the people who love them the most. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Science Fiction Genre Fiction?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/is-science-fiction-genre-fiction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elora Powell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’d like to take the next few posts in this column to ruminate on what&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/chuttersnap-553860-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10441 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/chuttersnap-553860-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>I’d like to take the next few posts in this column to ruminate on what speculative fiction&#8211;specifically science fiction&#8211;really is. What is its place in our culture? Who is the core audience for it? How do fans interact with it on an individual and communal level? How is it expanding and changing as our societies expand and change?</p>
<p>Today, I’d like to dig into one of the main criticisms of science fiction: the reason that historically, it has been dismissed and considered an embarrassment for cultured adults to read. Science fiction is often shelved as “genre fiction”, a category which has been <a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.com/steven-petite/literary-fiction-vs-genre-fiction_b_4859609.html">seen as derogatory</a> by those who pit it against the more pretentious sounding “literary fiction.” Other examples of genre fiction include westerns, mysteries, romance, fantasy, and horror. A “genre” is defined as a set of tropes that are understood by and accessible to readers of the genre.</p>
<p>It is true that there are certain <a href="https://io9.gizmodo.com/5628989/ten-tropes-youll-find-in-science-fiction---over-and-over-again">tropes and ideas</a> that carry through science fiction. Artificial intelligence, alien lifeforms, space travel, superweapons, apocalypse, and time travel are just a few examples. However, they can take a lot of different forms, and spawn a myriad of plots, characters, and outcomes. How <i>Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy</i> treats space travel is wildly different from how Arthur C. Clarke’s<i> Rendezvous With Rama</i> treats it. Ray Bradbury’s <em>Mars</em> is not even close to the same world as C.S. Lewis’ <em>Mars</em>.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/bill-jelen-555144-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10442 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/bill-jelen-555144-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>Does that mean science fiction isn’t a genre? I don’t think so. There are obviously common ideas and predictable themes throughout the body of literature that we can roughly describe as “science fiction.” Does that make every science fiction story necessarily lesser than every “literary fiction” story? Hardly.</p>
<p>You see, we are living in a time where the distinction between “high art” and “popular art” is almost non-existent. Few in the young generation would be afraid to list the release of &#8220;Sgt. Pepper’s Lonely Hearts Club Band&#8221; as an important moment in music history, alongside the completion of Beethoven’s &#8220;9th symphony.&#8221; A graphic novel, like <i>Persepolis</i>, is no less a work of literature than <i>Crime and Punishment</i>. Beauty is beauty, wherever it may be found. Cultural importance is cultural importance. Meaning is meaning.</p>
<p>And there is a great deal of cultural importance to be found in science fiction in this day and age.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The World Spinning &#8216;Round- Time Loops and Regret</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-world-spinning-round-time-loops-and-regret/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elora Powell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do you ever stay up late at night, lying in the dark, with some event&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/hourglass-620397_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9902 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/hourglass-620397_1920-300x226.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="226" /></a>Do you ever stay up late at night, lying in the dark, with some event or conversation from the day playing over and over in your head? Each time, you think of some alternate way it could have happened, some other word you could have used, some detour you could have taken, some tip you should have remembered. And each time, you feel sicker and sicker with yourself because it&#8217;s too late for that now. It&#8217;s finished. It happened. It&#8217;s done.</p>
<p>Maybe you&#8217;ve wished, in those dark, weak moments, that you would go back and change things. I know I have. There&#8217;s something agonizing about the hindsight we&#8217;ve been given as humans- tied up in time, trapped moving forward. We can see how things could- should, even- have gone differently, but we can do nothing about it other than remember and regret.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s always been a tantalizing concept for fiction (especially speculative fiction). What if you had a chance to do that thing over again? What if you had infinite chances? Probably the first film that comes to many people&#8217;s minds when this subject is brought up is <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107048/?ref_=nv_sr_1"><em>Groundhog Day</em></a>. While it&#8217;s more of a romantic, inspirational comedy than hard science fiction, it has strong speculative themes.</p>
<p>Interestingly enough, Bill Murray&#8217;s protagonist doesn&#8217;t have much regret at the end of his day at the beginning. Not until he&#8217;s repeated the same day over and over again does he realize that something needs to change. Unlike most of us, though, he has the ability to change them. It&#8217;s an interesting look at how one day can cause us to rethink our entire lives.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0709218/"><em>Stargate SG-1</em> episode, &#8220;Window of Opportunity,&#8221;</a> parodies the film in a more traditional science fiction setting. When radioactive interference from a strange alien device sends a network of stargates into a time loop, Jack O&#8217;Neill and Teal&#8217;c are the only people with memories of previous loops. Through a hilarious series of missteps, they figure out the source of the interference. The story ends with a touching twist that revolves around a bere</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="align-right alignright wp-image-9903 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/time-3098699_1920-300x188.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="188" /></p>
<p>aved scientist. The episode poses the question: if you had to go through the pain of losing a loved one all over again, would it be worth it to go back and be with them?</p>
<p>The ability to repeat days- to loop time- would bring with it all sorts of questions: is time fixed, or fluid? Is there such a thing as destiny or fate? But perhaps the closest and most personal question would be: if you could go back and change the things that caused you pain and regret, would you? Would it be right?</p>
<p>For now, though, I suppose that all we can do on those long, dark nights, are accept, forget, and maybe even fall asleep.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who Are the Bad Guys? Reflections on Dystopia</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/who-are-the-bad-guys-reflections-on-dystopia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elora Powell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Frequently Asked Questions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8460</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dystopian civilizations have been on the brain lately. Don&#8217;t know why . . . Hmmm.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/brandon-wong-263419-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9675 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/brandon-wong-263419-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a><a href="http://www.vulture.com/article/best-dystopian-books.html">Dystopian civilizations</a> have been on the brain lately. Don&#8217;t know why . . . Hmmm. Couldn&#8217;t tell you.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been thinking about how, in the books we read and the movies we watch, it&#8217;s always pretty easy to pick out who the bad guys are right away. And it&#8217;s pretty easy for people to agree on who the bad guys are, too.</p>
<p>Give a staunch liberal and a staunch conservative each an identical copy of <em>The Hunger Games</em>, and they can probably come to a consensus on who the villains are&#8211;maybe not <em>why</em> they are the villains, but hey, no need to ask for miracles here. (Actually, there are plenty of reasons to ask for miracles. Please send help.) Maybe <em>The Hunger Games</em> is too simplistic of an example. Fine. I&#8217;ve yet to hear a student or teacher of literature, regardless of their leanings, try to argue that the Firemen of <a href="http://www.sparknotes.com/lit/451/"><em>Fahrenheit 451</em></a>, or Big Brother of <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/01/26/books/why-1984-is-a-2017-must-read.html"><em>1984</em></a> are good.</p>
<p>Then why is it, in the real world, which continues to look more and more dystopian every day, that we can&#8217;t come to the same agreement?</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/andre-benz-248760-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9676 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/andre-benz-248760-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>If you don&#8217;t mind me referencing the <em>Wonder Woman</em> movie, there was a part that particularly resounded with me for alas, I am young and idealistic and would love it if we could pin all the bad things in the world on one arch fiend and go about living at peace with one another. Like Diana, I think, we all falter when forced to face the fact that in everyone&#8211;including ourselves and our loved ones&#8211;there is a streak of evil. We are all the villains sometimes, just like we are all the heroes sometimes.</p>
<p>Outside of our favorite fictional universes, good and bad aren&#8217;t so cut and dry. Like everything else, they&#8217;re not a perfect binary. I&#8217;m not saying that everyone is so evil that there is no point in trying to make the world a better place. I just think that when we&#8217;re living in dystopia, a little understanding goes a long way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
