<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Well-Tempered Pull List &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-well-tempered-pull-list/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:46:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Free Comic Book Day 2019 is upon us! I&#8217;m so excited!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/free-comic-book-day-2019-is-upon-us-im-so-excited/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 12:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Well-Tempered Pull List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s a holiday tomorrow! Besides being May 4th (May the Fourth be with you) it&#8217;s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-15195" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fcbd-220x300.jpg" alt="" width="220" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fcbd-220x300.jpg 220w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fcbd-768x1045.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fcbd-753x1024.jpg 753w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fcbd.jpg 1120w" sizes="(max-width: 220px) 100vw, 220px" />It&#8217;s a holiday tomorrow! Besides being May 4th (May the Fourth be with you) it&#8217;s also FREE COMIC BOOK DAY! All around the U.S. comic book shops have generously ordered a selection of comic books special for the day and will be giving them away.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve been interested in comic books but not sure how to get started, this is a great day to give it a shot. It won&#8217;t cost anything but a bit of time. If you&#8217;re nervous about what to expect, here&#8217;s a few tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>You might enjoy getting in line early (stores are often open extra hours for the day) and chatting with the other folks in line. Don&#8217;t worry, you can show up later as well if that makes you more comfortable.</li>
<li>Yes, the comic books are free. Some stores give away one book per person, others give a whole pile. There will be extra employees on hand, often with a FCBD tshirt on so you can find them easily. They&#8217;ll be able to explain that store&#8217;s policy.</li>
<li>Stay as long as you like. There will often be other fun events going on as well. Artists selling their art, cosplayers, creators doing signings, raffles, etc.</li>
<li>It will be crowded, but everyone is there to have a good time. Ask questions if you have any, it&#8217;s a holiday and you&#8217;ll likely get a cheerful response.</li>
<li>If you&#8217;d like, you can bring a few dollars with you and buy a comic book or two as well. Stores often have special sales and making a purchase is a great way to show your thanks, but it&#8217;s not required! Comic book stores usually have other related merchandise as well.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><img decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-15194 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/lumberjanes-198x300.jpeg" alt="" width="198" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/lumberjanes-198x300.jpeg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/lumberjanes-768x1165.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/lumberjanes-675x1024.jpeg 675w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/lumberjanes.jpeg 791w" sizes="(max-width: 198px) 100vw, 198px" /></strong></p>
<p>So, what kind of comic books will the stores have available? It will depend on what your store has ordered, but there is a whole list of books on the <a href="https://www.freecomicbookday.com/catalog">FCBD website</a>, including previews so you can check the titles out and decide which ones you want to look for.</p>
<p>The comics given away on FCBD are all good representatives of their monthly counterparts. Often they are stand-alone stories that wrap up in just a single issue and sometimes they&#8217;re the first issue in a new series. If it still seems overwhelming, here&#8217;s a few titles I can recommend as I&#8217;ll be picking them up myself:</p>
<p><strong>Lumberjanes: Shape of Friendship</strong><br />
This series is one of my favorites of all time. It&#8217;s about a group of girls who find themselves at a mysterious summer camp that&#8217;s full of weird animals, greek goddesses, and other strange goings on and they get through it all through the POWER OF FRIENDSHIP.</p>
<p><strong>Doctor Who: The 13th Doctor</strong><br />
This one is for fans of the show. It&#8217;s the first issue of a new series, written by Jody Houser.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-15196" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/malika-197x300.jpeg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/malika-197x300.jpeg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/malika-768x1173.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/malika-671x1024.jpeg 671w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/malika.jpeg 786w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" /></p>
<p><strong>Malika: Fire &amp; Frost</strong><br />
This looks interesting! The publisher focuses on African creators, with this title featuring a young woman whose vision leads her from home to do battle against some epic evil.</p>
<p><strong>Under the Moon: A Catwoman Tale</strong><br />
Written by Lauren Myracle, is a sneak peek of a forthcoming graphic novel about a teenage Selina Kyle on her journey to becoming Catwoman.</p>
<p><strong>Kodansha Sampler</strong><br />
Some companies publish a special sampler of a few titles. This one is a manga publisher and features Witch Hat Atelier, which looks really cute.</p>
<p>That should get you started! If you didn&#8217;t see something that piqued your interest here, you can check out the whole list. Even better, go to your local comic book store tomorrow and browse for yourself! Don&#8217;t know where your local is? The FCBD website has you covered with their <a href="https://www.freecomicbookday.com/StoreLocator">store locator</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-15198" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/drwho-198x300.jpeg" alt="" width="198" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/drwho-198x300.jpeg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/drwho-768x1165.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/drwho-675x1024.jpeg 675w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/drwho.jpeg 791w" sizes="(max-width: 198px) 100vw, 198px" />If you don&#8217;t have a store near you, be sure to check out <a href="https://www.midtowncomics.com/">Midtown Comics</a> and <a href="http://mycomicshop.com/">MyComicShop.com</a> for a couple of days after the event. They often let you order free comics and will send them to you for just the shipping costs.</p>
<p>Just writing this got me excited all over again. I need to go read some comic books right now! Happy FCBD and if you go, leave a comment here and let me know what you picked up!</p>
<p>Resources:<br />
The Official <a href="https://www.freecomicbookday.com/">Free Comic Book Day Website</a> has a store locator, the list of books, and lots of other information about the day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pride is full of rainbows, and sometimes dragons</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pride-is-full-of-rainbows-and-sometimes-dragons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 10:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Well-Tempered Pull List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I thought I would write about something for Pride this month, but what to focus&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10611 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/human-2620298_640-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" />I thought I would write about something for Pride this month, but what to focus on? Ursula K. Le Guin&#8217;s <em>Left Hand of Darkness</em> has been dissected many times. <em>Swordspoint</em> by Ellen Kushner is ground-breaking and a great fantasy representative. There are more options available to me than I can count, but I finally found my topic: comic books.</p>
<p>Still pleasantly faced with many options (Do I talk about Batwoman? Do I profile Magdalene Visaggio?) I decided this time to focus on fantasy stories in comics. No capes today, no superheroes. You might be surprised at how many choices are out there in the LGBTQIA+ fantasy comic genre. Yes, there are actually enough options for me to call it a genre! Yes, there are tons of wonderful fantasy comics out there!</p>
<p>I hope that the importance of LGBTQIA+ representation in literature, no matter the medium or format, is an obvious one, but maybe it isn&#8217;t. Perhaps this is your first experience touching the fringes of Pride and are wondering why it&#8217;s important. From my heart to yours, I tell you this: yes it really does make a huge difference in the life of every person that falls under the rainbow-colored umbrella. Knowing we&#8217;re not alone is important for everyone, but beyond that, knowing we&#8217;re valid, accepted, loved even if we were the only one like us is even more so.</p>
<p>So, let&#8217;s talk now about comics celebrating that rainbow, with characters who are valid, accepted, and loved. We&#8217;ll start with classic floppy copies available at your local comic book store (or big bookstore, if you have none nearby).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10605 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/51LQUyWCxPL-196x300.jpg" alt="" width="196" height="300" /><em><strong>&#8220;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Sandman:_A_Game_of_You">The Sandman: A Game of You</a>&#8221; by Neil Gaiman and more amazing artists than you can shake a stick at</strong></em></p>
<p>To be honest, <em>The Sandman</em> is the ultimate classic of the fantasy genre period. This is the one multi-volume story that I think anyone who has any interest in comic books and fantasy should read. That said, &#8220;A Game of You&#8221; is a gem within the dragon&#8217;s hoard of stories told in the series. It features no less than three queer characters, a no-bullshit witch, and has a another woman as its lead protagonist. It&#8217;s some of Gaiman&#8217;s most female-centric work and on top of it all is an amazing story.</p>
<p><em><strong>&#8220;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Spire_(comics)">The Spire</a>&#8221; by Simon Spurrier and Jeff Stokely</strong></em></p>
<p>Spurrier describes the book as &#8220;one part &#8216;<a title="Mad Max" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mad_Max">Mad Max</a>,&#8217; one part &#8216;<a title="Blade Runner" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blade_Runner">Bladerunner</a>,&#8217; one part &#8216;<a class="mw-redirect" title="Dark Crystal" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_Crystal">Dark Crystal</a>,&#8217; one part nutfuck insanity&#8221; and I have to agree. But in a <em>good</em> way. This is story a of Sha, the police detective who deals with religious zealots, a new Baroness in charge of the city, and her own modified biology while investigating a series of murders. It&#8217;s surreal and inventive.</p>
<p><em><strong>&#8220;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isola_(comics)">Isola</a>&#8221; by Brenden Fletcher and Karl Kerschl</strong></em></p>
<p>This book. Such gorgeous art, I can&#8217;t even. The story is good too, though so far we only have three intriguing issues to give us a taste of this world. It&#8217;s a great time to hop on this book, where a soldier guards her queen, who has been turned by some kind of magic into a beautiful blue tiger. The prologue is <a href="https://isola.ca/readonline/">available online</a> and I double dog dare you to not want to read the series after seeing it.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10606 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/4588177-193x300.jpg" alt="" width="193" height="300" /></p>
<p>Those are frankly the tip of the iceberg, but they&#8217;re some of my favorites. And now, for those who want to read something RIGHT NOW, I give you some web comics to choose from.</p>
<p><em><strong>&#8220;<a href="http://www.goodbyetohalos.com/">Goodbye to Halos</a>&#8221; by Valerie Halla</strong></em></p>
<p>You know that rainbow I&#8217;ve mentioned? This comic has characters from just about every color on it. A coming-of-age story about the main character, who falls from one world into another and discovers her powers, along with making strong friendships and figuring out the mysteries that surround her past.</p>
<p><em><strong>&#8220;<a href="http://www.eths-skin.com/post/71812472945">Eth&#8217;s Skin</a>&#8221; by Sfé R. Monster</strong></em></p>
<p>Gosh I love this one. The art is gorgeous, the world is inventive, the story is utterly charming. I will warn you ahead of time that this is not a finished tale, and it hasn&#8217;t been updated in a while. Like the best fanfic on AO3 that&#8217;s left you hanging, this story will leave you wanting more. But trust me, it&#8217;s still worth the read. Maybe if we all read it the author will be encouraged to come back and continue.</p>
<p><em><strong>&#8220;<a href="http://emcarroll.com/comics/anu/page01.html">Anu-Anulan &amp; Yir&#8217;s Daughter</a>&#8221; by Emily Carroll and &#8220;<a href="https://tapas.io/episode/523191">Corner Witches</a>&#8221; by Sam</strong></em></p>
<p>OK, OK, as an antidote to the unfinished stories above, I&#8217;ll leave you with a couple of short stories. These two webcomics are some of my favorite examples of the power of the medium. Both are interestingly of a similar theme, that of love that is sought and found through a sharing of magical items. They&#8217;re gorgeous and charming and lovely tales. I encourage you to go read them, they won&#8217;t take very long, well, unless you&#8217;re like me and need to pour over them over and over.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10609 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Selection_003-300x209.png" alt="" width="300" height="209" />That&#8217;s my brief round up of favorites in the world of fantasy LGBTQIA+ comics. There are TONS more out there and remember I only focused on fantasy stuff I&#8217;ve actually read! If you want to explore some more, Comicosity has two stellar lists of comics that will serve you well. &#8220;<a href="http://www.comicosity.com/were-here-and-were-queer-35-indie-titles-doing-right-by-lgbt-fans/">We’re Here and We’re Queer: 35 Indie Titles Doing Right by LGBTA Fans</a>&#8221; is a fantastic list of print comics you can find at your local store (and yes, often these are available digitally as well). &#8220;<a href="http://www.comicosity.com/queer-and-online-40-lgbta-webcomics-to-know-and-love/">Out, Online, and Proud: 40 LGBTA Webcomics to Know and Love</a>&#8221; will give you plenty of reading material to keep you going for a while.</p>
<p>As for me, the next book I&#8217;m going to sit and read is &#8220;<a href="http://teadragonsociety.com/comic/chapter-1/">The Tea Dragon Society</a>&#8221; by Katie O’Neill. Lovely artwork and it&#8217;s about tea and dragons and memories. I&#8217;ll save you a cup! Happy Pride!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Life in Pictures (and Text)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-life-in-pictures-and-text/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 18:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Well-Tempered Pull List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9703</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve spoken before (and will again) about how flexible comics are as a medium. Easily&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve spoken before (and will again) about how flexible comics are as a medium. Easily spanning genres and enabling a creative vehicle for storytelling, they allow an author to put their own stamp on a tale in a unique way. This is doubly true when the tale being told is the author’s own personal life story.</p>
<p>There are a <a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.com/off-the-shelf-/10-compelling-graphic-mem_b_9938556.html">few</a> <a href="https://mashable.com/2015/03/21/autobiographical-graphic-novels/#5hxltZ4DVmqY">lists</a> around of the best graphic memoirs and I’m going to give you my own thoughts on a few I’ve read (which all also happen to be on those lists). One of the best things about this genre of story is how vast and varied it is, just as with their prose counterparts. Interestingly enough, the three I’ll mention are all coming-of-age stories. Something about that time period in one’s life seems to lend itself well to memoir, I suppose.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9705 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/10602435-300x271.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="271" /></p>
<h3><em>Persepolis</em></h3>
<p>First is the seminal Persepolis and Persepolis 2 (also available as <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/991197.The_Complete_Persepolis">The Complete Persepolis</a>) by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marjane_Satrapi">Marjane Satrapi</a>, which tells the author’s coming of age story in the time of the Islamic Revolution in Iran. Satrapi is in her formative years when the revolution begins and the massive, overnight cultural shift in her homeland is stifling to a young woman just starting to express herself as a person. When she later travels to Vienna for high school, she is again challenged by culture shock during those already tumultuous years of transition toward adulthood. The book was later made into an animated film (which follows the book very faithfully).</p>
<p>It’s a beautiful read, heartbreaking in some places, wise and witty in others. The simple art style (it’s all in black and white) lends a weight to the book and I don’t think it would be the same if there were bright colors everywhere. As with most comics, the art is used to set the tone and emphasize the mood of the book as much as the text.</p>
<h3><em>Relish</em></h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9712 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Huevos_2-219x300.jpg" alt="" width="219" height="300" /></p>
<p>Next is a much lighter book, Lucy Knisley’s “<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15786110-relish">Relish</a>”. I’ve followed Knisley’s work online for years now, though her “<a href="https://www.lucyknisley.com/comics/">Stop Paying Attention</a>” strip has gotten much more rarely updated the last few years as her life has changed. Relish is about three things: growing up, food, and the memories where the two intertwine. Raised by foodies (mom is a chef), Knisley’s most vital memories are inextricably connected to the food she was eating or making at the time, either to cope, understand, or celebrate the moment.</p>
<p>I love how this book is at turns funny and poignant and I have a lot of my own memories embedded in the food I eat or what someone made. Not only is this book about food and memory, it also has a lovely selection of recipes drawn in a charming style that’s easy to follow and makes me want to get up and scrounge for ingredients.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9713" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/funhome-preview.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="430" /></p>
<h3><em>Fun Home</em></h3>
<p>The final book I’ll talk about is one I haven’t actually read yet. However, I recently bought a copy and I’m going to be reading it soon. It’s Alison Bechdel’s “<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26135825-fun-home">Fun Home: A Family Tragicomic</a>”, which tells the story of her childhood and the complex relationship she had with her closeted homosexual father. Yes, Bechdel is the same person who the “<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bechdel_test">Bechdel Test</a>” is named for as well as being the author of the seminal comic strip “<a href="http://dykestowatchoutfor.com/strip-archive-by-number">Dykes to Watch Out For</a>”.</p>
<p>“Fun Home” falls somewhere between “Relish” and “Persepolis”, darker than the story of sweetly poignant recipes and recollections of a budding artist, yet much less dangerous than that of growing up in the aftermath of a culture-changing revolution. It’s also got a much more formal tone, referencing works of literature and myth. Additionally, it also happens to be critically-acclaimed and award-winning, well beyond the usual confines of the comic book medium, making it kind of a must-read.</p>
<p>I hope I’ve been able to give you a little glimpse into something unexpected here and further build the case that comic books really are for everyone. For every genre in literature and many in non-fiction as well, there is a comic book there waiting for you. It’s worth taking the time to look. You never know when one of your favorite books might just be a comic book.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sleepless, but this isn&#8217;t Seattle</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/sleepless-but-this-isnt-seattle/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 12:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Well-Tempered Pull List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9313</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the best things about comic books is that there is always something new&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9316 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Sleepless_01_cvrB-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" />One of the best things about comic books is that there is always something new to read. For the last couple of years, this has been especially true as a plethora of titles have been published by smaller companies, many of which are definitely not your usual super hero books. There may be capes in these books, but they tend to be woolen.</p>
<p>With so many new titles coming out, it’s very easy for someone new to comic books to hop on board. Most are only a few issues, or a collection or two, into their runs and many are limited series, so it’s simple to dip in and get a whole story in a few issues.</p>
<p>I have a particular passion for all of the fantasy books now on the shelves and tend to gravitate towards those, avoiding the Marvel and DC books with their incredibly long histories and interconnected story lines. There’s nothing wrong with reading those books and I’ve gone through multiple periods in my life when I’ve devoted my comic reading time to Batman and his extended family. Lately, though, I am much more likely to pick up a book like <em>Sleepless</em> and for any of you interested in comics but unsure where to start, this is definitely a great choice.</p>
<p><em>Sleepless</em> is a young adult romance set in a Renaissance-inspired fantasy. A young princess and her sleepless protector knight have to navigate the complex world of court intrigue as the girl’s uncle (rather than her recently-deceased father) takes the throne.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9317 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/Sleepless-01_cvrB-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></p>
<p>The comic is only on issue #2, so we don’t have a full picture of the world yet, but so far it’s got a comfortable feel to it, like a fairy tale you already know but have forgotten and our main characters already seem familiar. I look forward to seeing where this adventure takes them, and where the little hints of romance lead as well. We don’t know much yet about the magic in this world, though there are hints, such as the Sleepless knights themselves and the lovely little fox-like creature kept as a pet by Princess Pyppenia.</p>
<p>Created by a largely female and POC team, the book has a diversity of characters, with an inviting art style that has plenty of texture which really helps set the tone of the book. It’s also nice to see a fantasy that isn’t an alternate version of medieval England, but is instead more like Venice at its height, with trade and close relations with an African-inspired country as well.</p>
<p>Only two issues in and I’m already a huge fan, looking forward to the next issue due out next month. This is a great time try out that local comic book store you may have been nervous to go into. This book is worth it.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a preview of the first couple of pages here: <a href="https://imagecomics.com/comics/releases/sleepless-1">Sleepless #1</a></p>
<p>If you’d like to learn a little more about it, you can find an interview with the creators here:<br />
<a href="http://comicsalliance.com/sarah-vaughn-leila-del-duca-sleepless-interview/">Sarah Vaughn and Leila del Duca Bring Renaissance Romance To Comics With ‘Sleepless’</a><br />
and here: <a href="https://www.bleedingcool.com/2017/09/15/sleepless-sarah-vaughn-leila-del-duca/">Image Comics Is ‘Sleepless’ This December</a></p>
<p>And a more traditional review of issue #1 here:<br />
<a href="https://www.cbr.com/sleepless-1-review-image-comics/">REVIEW: Sleepless #1 Tantalizes with a Brand-New Fantasy World [Image’s Sleepless #1 Tantalizes with a Brand-New</a></p>
<p>If digital is more your thing, you can pick up both issues from the publisher:<br />
<a href="https://imagecomics.com/comics/series/sleepless">Sleepless | Series | Image Comics </a>or on <a href="https://www.comixology.com/Sleepless/comics-series/107092">Comixology- Sleepless Digital Comics</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Of Wolves and Killjoys: Comic Artist &#038; Writer, Becky Cloonan</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/of-wolves-and-killjoys/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 12:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Well-Tempered Pull List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8900</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are the artists, writers, and creators that we love, and then there are the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8902 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/leave_no_eye_open_to_weep_for_the_dead_by_beckycloonan-d770n8d-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></p>
<p>There are the artists, writers, and creators that we love, and then there are the ones that hit you just so. Their work strikes a deep chord somewhere and you feel like they are making things just for you, like you share something on a soul level. Becky Cloonan is one of those creators for me.</p>
<p>We’re of a similar age, Ms. Cloonan and I, and cut our teeth on some of the same books, particularly Dracula, and pop culture. It’s possible this contributes to why I love her work so much. It doesn’t hurt that she’s super talented either.</p>
<p>Cloonan is a triple comic book threat. She writes and draws, both incredibly well, but she also self-publishes. When she was first getting her career off the ground webcomics weren’t a thing yet and so she printed mini comics and shopped them around at conventions, getting her name out there at a ground level. What’s awesome is that she continues doing that to this day, doing small print runs of stories, though the paper stock has improved and she gets to sell them online now.</p>
<p>Her work with collaborators has been outstanding, earning her two Eisner award nominations. To me, her outstanding work as a collaborative artist has been on “Demo” and a recent “Conan the Barbarian” run (both with Brian Wood writing) as well as</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8904 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/CloonanSonja-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Killjoys&#8221; with Gerard Way and Shaun Simon. When Cloonan has picked up the pen to write instead of draw, she’s done outstanding work on her original story, “Southern Cross”, as well as “Gotham Academy”, based in the Batman Universe.</p>
<p>Speaking of Batman, she was the first woman artist to draw the mainstream Batman book, no small thing in an industry dominated by male creators. She’s also worked for both DC and Marvel, as well as the large “indie” comic book companies, Image and Dark Horse, producing consistently great work both on the writing and art sides of the process.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8905 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/tumblr_lq8jt54Vqx1qgf3d3o1_1280-227x300.jpg" alt="" width="227" height="300" /></p>
<p>But to me, Cloonan’s most magical work comes when she takes both sides into her own hands, writing and drawing a trio of tales known collectively as “By Chance or Providence”.</p>
<p>BCOP is medieval fantasy, full of tragic love and the supernatural, and everyone in it is so very pretty. It is a bit difficult to write about without spoiling anything. The tales are short, easily readable in a sitting, but the depth and beauty stays with me long after I’ve put the book down.</p>
<p>Set in a shared world, though not interconnected in any real sense, I would describe these stories as darkly magical. Though it sounds like a cliche description, when the subject is combined with masterful use of the comics medium, it starts to transcend its genre boundaries into simply wonderful storytelling.</p>
<p>Cloonan dedicates the collected version of the tales to “those of you who have crushes on your characters”. Much like the best fan fiction is born out of passionate love for its subject, that love for the world she’s discovered, and the characters inhabited by it, shines through. It’s wonderful to see a creator who is so taken with what she&#8217;s making that she reacts like a fan. It would be lovely to see more folks as enamored of what they’re working on as she is with this book.</p>
<p>Lest you think that Becky Cloonan is limited to comic books, she’s also a talented illustrator. She’s created an illustrated version of Dracula that brings a new perspective to the classic tale. She’s also designed t-shirts and posters for various bands, as well as for her own enjoyment and continues to produce illustrations that feel like they are created by someone who truly loves what they do.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8911 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/dracula__jonathan_harker_by_stabstabstab-d4vco3r-300x124.jpg" alt="" width="276" height="114" /></p>
<p>I’m not sure if it’s true or not, but it feels like when she’s writing she keeps a hand in her drawing life and vice versa, so both skills remain at her fingertips. A recent example was her October “Inktober” experiments, appearing on Instagram (and Twitter) which she gathered into a sketchbook, all the while writing Southern Cross and various other works.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8906 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/beckycloonan-300x215.jpg" alt="" width="254" height="182" /></p>
<p>Have I sold you on her yet? Hopefully some of the images on this post will nudge you even more than my words do. Want to check her out?</p>
<p>“By Chance or Providence” is, of course, my suggested starting point for all things Cloonan. You can get it easily from Amazon or Barnes &amp; Noble, of course, but I encourage you to stop by your local comic shop. Most stores will have a copy and then you can check out what else they have in stock. You may find a new favorite artist or writer waiting within those colorful pages.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.beckycloonan.net/">Becky Cloonan’s website</a><br />
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Becky_Cloonan">Wikipedia entry on Cloonan</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Linda Medley and the Fabulous “Castle Waiting&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/linda-medley-and-the-fabulous-castle-waiting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 15:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Well-Tempered Pull List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve been a lapsed comic reader lately, which has made me a bit sad. I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-f12NPbVNJcI/TYaNa0mtF6I/AAAAAAAACwI/_w58-6-cNJY/s1600/CW02.jpg" alt="" width="403" height="261" /></p>
<p>I’ve been a lapsed comic reader lately, which has made me a bit sad. I thought I might share a favorite of mine with you, in hopes that talking about it will rekindle my interest. If this goes well, expect to see quite a bit more comic talk, because oh have I got some awesome comics to share. But I digress.</p>
<p>I’m here to talk to you about Linda Medley and <em>Castle Waiting</em> which is one of my hands down favorite comics of all time. This book is one of those rare treasures that can be summed up with a simple word: charming. Most books you might describe thusly tend to teeter on the edge of crying, but not <em>Castle Waiting</em>. Here, there is both sly, deftly handled humor, and glimpses of deep emotions and hurt, but all wrapped in a package so irresistible and full of warmth that you’ll keep turning the pages and wish there was more when you get to the end.</p>
<p>Now that I’ve started what amounts to a sales pitch, I’ll step back a bit. <em>Castle Waiting</em> is set in a seemingly typical fairy tale medieval-style world, but in many ways it feels quite modern. Perhaps it’s the way the characters are portrayed, even the less human looking ones of the bunch. Speaking of which, among the denizens of this crumbling old castle, there is a stork who runs the place and tries to keep up with repairs. There’s an imp who taunts a saucy, bearded nun (she’s amazing and quite willing to share a sandwich with him). There are a load of equally interesting and wonderfully rendered characters, but I don&#8217;t want to spoil the fun of discovering them on you. And then there’s the castle itself, full of sprites and brownies and the stories it holds in its bones.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright" src="https://www.lambiek.net/artists/image/m/medley/medley.gif" alt="" width="430" height="322" /></p>
<p>&#8220;A fable for modern times, Castle Waiting is a fairy tale that&#8217;s not about rescuing the princess, saving the kingdom, or fighting the ultimate war between Good and Evil, but about being a hero in your own home.” That’s what the official description says and perhaps that’s part of what pulls me toward this book, the idea of being a hero of the every day. From Lady Jain, pregnant with another man&#8217;s child and on the run from her husband, to the quiet Iron Henry, to the sweet Simon, all the characters have their own special stories and Linda Medley draws and writes them with wonderful realism.</p>
<p>Linda Medley is currently working on the next installment of this marvelous book and I cannot wait. But there’s a hitch in the proceedings, the bane of any artist or writer: Linda has some hand problems going on. What’s more, she’s another wonderful artist who makes her own way through the world and dances that financial tightrope along with her fellow freelancers.</p>
<p>So, if you go out and read Castle Waiting and love it the way I do, I highly encourage you to support Linda and her work.</p>
<p>She’s got a <a href="https://www.patreon.com/lindamedley">Patreon</a>, a <a href="https://www.gofundme.com/lindamedley">GoFundMe</a>, and you can buy her artwork on her <a href="https://www.etsy.com/shop/LindaMedleyArt?ref=l2-shopheader-name">Etsy</a> shop. Of course buying copies of Castle Waiting and giving them to everyone you know would be lovely, too.</p>
<p>I hope by now you can tell how passionate I am about this comic book. I hope you go check it out soon and definitely let me know if you fall for it like I did, long ago and far away.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We had fun at Free Comic Book Day!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/we-had-fun-at-free-comic-book-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 14:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Well-Tempered Pull List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Luna Station Press had a great time this past Saturday. We had a table at&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_2514.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-4344 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_2514-e1430833832746-1024x768.jpg" alt="IMG_2514" width="591" height="443" /></a></p>
<p>Luna Station Press had a great time this past Saturday. We had a table at the <a href="http://www.freecomicbookday.com/Home/1/1/27/992" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Free Comic Book Day</a> event at <a href="http://timewarpcomics.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Time Warp Comics &amp; Games</a> in Cedar Grove, NJ.</p>
<p>I was lucky enough to have <a href="http://erindemoss.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Erin DeMoss</a> (our LSQ cover artist) and <a href="http://www.thewastedseries.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">C. Elizabeth Vescio</a> (one of LSP&#8217;s star authors) with me. Look at those lovely faces! They traveled all the way out from Oklahoma City and Las Vegas, respectively. We had a great visit and they represented LSP, and their own work, with the fun and spirit that I knew they would bring to the table.</p>
<p>We handed out plenty of bookmarks and sold a couple books. We met lots of people and had some great conversations, I even got a visit from one of my old high school English teachers. Always great to hear that someone from your past is proud of the work you&#8217;ve done.</p>
<p>We were also interviewed for <a href="http://bigkevsgeekstuff.com/wpress/?p=4706" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Big Kev&#8217;s Geek Stuff</a> podcast, a real treat. The episode is already online and you can hear Erin and I interviewed starting at the 50:00 mark.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m so glad we did it and I&#8217;m grateful to Dave and the staff at Time Warp for helping us make the outing a success.</p>
<p>And yes, I did indeed get a whole massive bag of free comic books.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_2512.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-4345 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/IMG_2512-1024x768.jpg" alt="IMG_2512" width="584" height="438" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Reading and Collecting</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-reading-and-collecting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 18:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Well-Tempered Pull List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I buy comic books for a single purpose, to read them. There is a very&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>I buy comic books for a single purpose, to read them. There is a very large collector’s market and I don’t judge it. Comics should be enjoyed however you want to enjoy them. That being said, I do think it’s easy to get caught up in how much a book is worth monetarily and lose sight of what makes them so special in the first place: the art and stories.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Do I have any books that are worth a bit of money? Sure. Not tons, I’m not retiring anytime soon by selling the collection, but I definitely have a few books in my collection that are worth multiple times their cover price. Only one of those (Birds of Prey #8, the “date” issue) I bought knowing what it was worth, and even that one I bought it because I really really wanted to read it. (Dick and Babs, swoon).</div>
<div></div>
<div>I guess I’m just one of those people who isn’t overly precious about my collection. The twenty or so short boxes in my basement are filled with books I loved reading and, from time to time, go back and read again. I bag them, but mostly because they really do get messed up in the box if you don’t, but that’s about all the special handling they get outside of my love and attention.</div>
<div></div>
<div>On the other hand, my dearest friend bags, boards, and takes extremely good care of her mint condition collection. But then, she does that with all her things because that’s how she enjoys them. And she does read her comics, we share that about our books. With no intent to sell, she takes care of her collection for its own intrinsic value to her.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I do, from time to time, purge books, which my friend would never do. I have a back catalogue of stuff that DC has put out in the last couple years. I tend to fall behind on my reading and so, as DC has lost its way (hello Batgirl #37 that I did not buy), I have less and less of a desire to even open the books up.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Reading comics should never be a chore. It’s supposed to be fun, engaging, etc, etc, but never feel like work. When it feels like work, it’s time to drop the book. I have a LOT of DC books that feel like work.</div>
<div></div>
<div>So, they’re going back to my LCS (local comic store). Someone will want to add them to their collection, or will be able to sell them at an inflated price, and good for them. So long as they’re out of my hair, I don’t care what you do with them.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Getting a bit of store credit means I get to make more room for stuff I’m actually into right now. Reading, seeing great art, exploring new titles, that’s all the “value” I need to get from my comics.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Ephemeral Nature of Comic Books</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-ephemeral-nature-of-comic-books/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 18:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Well-Tempered Pull List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3048</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sometimes you start reading a comic book and wonder if it was really worth the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you start reading a comic book and wonder if it was really worth the cover price. It happens occasionally, but instead of being a bad thing, it&#8217;s actually rather good and I&#8217;ll tell you why.</p>
<p>Part of the beauty of comics (at least when you read single issues) is that you don&#8217;t know what you&#8217;re going to get from issue to issue, from year to year. Of course prose books are a mystery, too, and you don&#8217;t know when you pick a book up if you&#8217;re about to read a new favorite or want to throw it across the room, but either way you can generally be sure that you&#8217;ll end the book having read a single author&#8217;s vision. With comics, that is not usually the case.</p>
<p>Limited series and &#8220;graphic novels&#8221; (I&#8217;ll explain why that&#8217;s in quotes another time) are usually written by a single person, and drawn by one as well, sometimes one person handling both jobs. But continuing series are known for having multiple authors, artists, inkers, etc. Sometimes a favorite artist will be paired with a writer you don&#8217;t like, sometimes the writing is great, but you have to suffer through some art that makes you question the publisher&#8217;s intelligence. And of course that&#8217;s all subjective, as any fan who has gotten into an argument over an artist or writer can tell you.</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s part of the adventure of reading this kind of storytelling, too. You never know what the next storyline is going to bring, and when you get your favorite artist and your favorite writer working together on your favorite character, it&#8217;s just magic. You ride that wave of reading magic for as long as that team&#8217;s run lasts, because it will end one day and then the search for your new favorite book begins again.</p>
<p>Sure, you could just read graphic novels or limited runs, but what&#8217;s the fun in that? Part of what makes comics unique are their ephemeral quality. They started out as cheaply printed children&#8217;s entertainment and, while they have evolved far beyond that, there will always be something about those monthly titles that will maintain a toehold in that foundation.</p>
<p>As creators, storylines, characters, even various publishing companies, rise and fall in popularity and quality, there is always an opportunity for new, amazing stories and art to rise to the surface. Indie publishers can become big enough to go mainstream. A side character can step into the hero&#8217;s shoes. Sometimes it means you&#8217;ll stop reading characters that were your favorites only a few short months ago, but all you have to do is wait a bit and the tide will shift. It&#8217;s one of the things I love about comics.</p>
<p>There are few other forms of storytelling that have stretched as many boundaries, have morphed and changed aa much as comics have and lived to tell the tale.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wednesday is New Comic Day!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/wednesday-is-new-comic-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 15:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Well-Tempered Pull List]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I usually have my post up on a Tuesday, but scheduling dictated a little change&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I usually have my post up on a Tuesday, but scheduling dictated a little change and here I am. I thought, it being a Wednesday, that I&#8217;d introduce those of you new to comics to a bit of regular comic buyer lingo and such.</p>
<p>There are a couple important components to buying comic books. Most important is your LCS, your Local Comic Store. Mine is <a href="http://www.timewarpcomics.com/">Time Warp Comics &amp; Games</a> here in NJ, run by a couple great guys and their savvy staff (including more than a couple ladies! yay!). Yes, Barnes &amp; Noble does stock some comics, but if you&#8217;re really looking for the full experience, <a href="http://www.comicshoplocator.com/Home/1/1/57/575" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">find a shop near you</a>. If you don&#8217;t like that one, try another! They&#8217;re all different and run in a lot of different ways. I&#8217;ll expand on the stores themselves in a future column.</p>
<p>At your LCS, you&#8217;ll be able to start a pull list. What&#8217;s a pull list? It&#8217;s the list of comics you want to get on a regular basis that the staff use to &#8216;pull&#8217; your books aside for you. It means they go through the shelves and make sure that you get your books, even if they&#8217;re running a bit short. You might also call it a subscription.</p>
<p>Some stores require that you have a certain number of books on your list, but it&#8217;s usually not too many. Ten titles is pretty common, but remember they don&#8217;t all come out every week. Also, once you get started, there are so many great books out there that it&#8217;s very easy to reach twenty or thirty (the die-hards top 50 or more). Just remember you&#8217;ll have to buy all the books that are being pulled. If I&#8217;m unsure I&#8217;m going to get a book regularly, I&#8217;ll often pick up the first issue or two on my own to be sure before adding it to my list.</p>
<p>Of course the fun part of all this is going to the store to pick everything up. I get my bag of comics, but I also take time to go around the store and check out what else is new or what looked interesting on the Diamond list that I might get as well.</p>
<p>The Diamond list isn&#8217;t as fancy as the name might lead you to believe. Diamond is the one and only distributor and the only way comic book stores get their books to sell. It&#8217;s a monopoly and no one likes them, but they&#8217;re the only game in town. I&#8217;ll save you the rant and just tell you that they publish a list ahead of time of what should be on the shelves that week. I&#8217;ll peruse that before going to the store, just to see what stuff will be waiting for me in my box.</p>
<p>The last and probably best part is the store itself. I&#8217;m lucky, I&#8217;ve got a great store and been going there for about 18 years now. I know the owner and the employees and there are a lot of us who&#8217;ve been going to the store for a long time now. I&#8217;ll often end up chatting with everyone for a bit, just chatting and often ranging far from the topic of comics.</p>
<p><strong>Now, just for fun, I&#8217;ll show you my pull list from this week:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>LUMBERJANES #5 &#8211; Yay! Lumberjanes is one of my favorite books right now. I&#8217;ll be reading this as soon as I get it home.</li>
<li>USAGI YOJIMBO SENSO #2 &#8211; So awesome to see my favorite rabbit ronin on the shelves again. This may look cartoonish, but it is ART.</li>
<li>FAIREST #29 &#8211; I admit to being completely behind on this book. I&#8217;ll often save up a bunch of issues so I can read a whole storyline in one sitting.</li>
<li>BLACK WIDOW #10 &#8211; Ooops. I only read up to issue 4 on this book. Time to get caught up!</li>
<li>FIGMENT #4 &#8211; A comic based on EPCOT&#8217;s mascot, which is a whole lot of fun.</li>
</ul>
<p class="p1"><strong>And here are a couple things I&#8217;m going to check out when I get to the store tomorrow:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>GOD HATES ASTRONAUTS #1 &#8211; Interesting title and it&#8217;s a #1. If the art is good I may pick it up.</li>
<li>RED SONJA: BLACK TOWER &#8211; Not sure who&#8217;s writing this, but I enjoyed Gail Simone&#8217;s run.</li>
<li>WOODS #5 &#8211; This book is five issues in, but I keep getting drawn in by the covers. I may see if all the back issues are available (something else Barnes &amp; Noble doesn&#8217;t have! Back issues!)</li>
</ul>
<p class="p1">So, there&#8217;s my list and I&#8217;m ready to go read some comics! I&#8217;ll see ya there.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
