<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Aesthetic &#8220;Core&#8221; &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-aesthetic-core/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 16:59:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>“Sing Me a Sunrise”: Weaponizing the Fractals of Synesthesia</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/sing-me-a-sunrise-weaponizing-the-fractals-of-synesthesia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arielle Amante]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Aesthetic "Core"]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If I could hear colors, I wonder if yellow sounds like Vincent Van Gogh’s sunflowers,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28566 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/f4i5l_hy1e8-200x300.jpg" alt="bunch of yellow chrysanthemum flowers" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/f4i5l_hy1e8-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/f4i5l_hy1e8-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/f4i5l_hy1e8-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/f4i5l_hy1e8.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />If I could hear colors, I wonder if yellow sounds like Vincent Van Gogh’s sunflowers, or the first sip of honey turmeric milk tea; or the word “infatuation” tastes like rosewater and lavender white chocolate; and every Thursday has the personality of a blue hour morning.</p>
<p>At least, this is what I think whenever someone mentions synesthesia.</p>
<p>I hope the perceptual phenomenon would stimulate the senses for a poetic benefit.</p>
<p>In the short story, “<a href="https://lackingtons.com/issues/issue-23-spring-2021/">Synesthesia</a>”, by Devin DeMarco, published in <em>Lackington’s</em> Issue 23–“Battles”, synesthesia is tangibly weaponized to battle against opposing teams for glory.</p>
<p>For example, you can manifest and hurl a “bright pumpkin orange explosion” at an opponent when your senses are triggered by your teammate sending you certain musical notes–like Bach’s short appoggiaturas and Debussy’s augmented triads–through an earpiece. Classical music would be a “cocoon of purples, blues, and greens”–cold and constricting but stabilizing–to block out the onslaught of your opponent (nicknamed the &#8216;Falcons&#8217;) “launching prismatic projectiles” as brutal olfaction of choice.</p>
<p><em>I loved this story. </em></p>
<p>As a speculative fiction writer and poet, I can never get enough of the sensations and textures of words themselves. DeMarco’s short story reminded me of how fun it is to unapologetically write colorful prose!</p>
<p>I take my work way too seriously sometimes, to where I get too caught up in the process and focus more on how a piece will be received as opposed to dedicating my best efforts to producing it. There isn’t anything wrong with that; in fact, I believe it’s normal for any creator, no matter their medium, to get lost in the creative sauce.</p>
<p>When I came across “Synesthesia”, it was during a time where I began questioning how I wanted to define my writing voice in fiction and try writing short stories. For years prior, I stayed in the comfort zone of speculative poetry because fiction intimidated me. To be honest, it still does, but it was a genre I always wanted to explore. That’s not to say my relationship with poetry wasn’t sincere–rather, I believed it was the only genre where I could express my best work.<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28526 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/5ui5glvjuaq-225x300.jpg" alt="multicolored abstract illustration" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/5ui5glvjuaq-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/5ui5glvjuaq-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/5ui5glvjuaq.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></p>
<p>“Synesthesia” was exactly what I needed to give myself the push to explore fiction despite my fears, delve deeper into its style and craft, and see how my poetry background might enhance my fiction voice altogether.</p>
<p>One thing I knew for a fact while reading this short was this: DeMarco had a blast writing it.</p>
<p>I forgot that writing can just be fun, and not every piece I create has to be published, award-winning, or recognizable to be valid–although that would be phenomenal. I don’t need to pressure myself to create a perfect piece of poetry or fiction every time I open a blank page. I can simply write for myself and explore the potential of writing for a new genre and test the limits of my imagination. Most of all, I can take the time to produce an incredible piece of writing and allow myself to wholeheartedly experience the sensations it triggers. I love that words can feel alive, tangible, and intimate. It’s pretty wild that they have the power to elicit sensations at all.</p>
<p>Thank you for writing “Synesthesia”, Devin.</p>
<p>I know exactly where I want to take my narrative voice in fiction writing now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>She Only Looks Like a Villainess: Thoughts on Unintentional Evil</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/she-only-looks-like-a-villainess-thoughts-on-unintentional-evil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arielle Amante]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 10:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Aesthetic "Core"]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[***Spoilers for the short story “What the Earth Bore” by Mary Rajotte, ahead!  Death and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">***Spoilers for the short story “What the Earth Bore” by Mary Rajotte, ahead! </span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Death and decay are the last elements I would associate with any form of good–or at least, when I was a child, reading fairy tales and hoping the heroines would save the day or defeat the scary monster.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As an adult looking back, I can’t help but smile and shake my head because I know today that there are more shades of grey than there are black and white in the world; the circumstances and individuals I unconsciously judged throughout my life are often more complex than I originally assumed. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes, we create villains and villainesses because we simply do not understand them, and it’s easier to constrict the image we have of others into a box in our heads to validate the narratives that comfort us about their differences from us; their otherness, if you will. It’s a heartbreaking truth of life: those we consider villains were never evil nor had any intention of evil in their hearts–until we forced them to be such. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Grimm &amp; Dread: A Crow’s Twist on Classic Tales</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a short story anthology collection edited by Cassandra L. Thompson, with contributions by Lucas Mann, we follow the fairy tale retellings of the Grimm Brothers’ fairy tales through a gothic lens. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of my favorite stories from the collection was “What the Earth Bore” by Mary Rajotte, a Sleeping Beauty retelling, especially because of its opening line: “The way you gaze at me with such adoring intensity makes me believe you could love even my darkest side.” </span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-28107 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/ms371wlcgpo-1-719x1024.jpg" alt="woman wearing dress and lying on teal cloth" width="719" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/ms371wlcgpo-1-719x1024.jpg 719w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/ms371wlcgpo-1-211x300.jpg 211w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/ms371wlcgpo-1-768x1093.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/ms371wlcgpo-1.jpg 843w" sizes="(max-width: 719px) 100vw, 719px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sleeping Beauty–known as Rosamund–in this story, uses a “magical glamour” to hide her true form from her beloved, Edmund. That true form is one that was born from death and decay, where everything she touches spoils and turns to rot; spiderwebs are woven into her hair to add the illusion of a lustrous sheen while crushed iridescent insects and fruits add color to her eyes and lips. To Rosamund, she believed she couldn’t truly be loved if she wasn’t beautiful. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To her dismay and heartbreak, the villagers who raised Edmund could feel the palpability of her glamorous lies, and sought to destroy and banish her for tricking Edmund as well as creating an aura of ill omen around her–so expose her they did. Deep into the forest, they chased her, brutally stripped her of the glamour, and presented her to Edmund–who found her even more beautiful in her true form, and found that her ability to heal the wounds afflicted on him by the villagers out of spite for his ignorance was a miracle rather than a blasphemous event.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s safe to say I raged when I read the villagers killed Edmund because he would accept Rosamund as she was rather than their definition of a beautiful woman. As a result, Rosamund shed the last of the glamour on herself and drew the magic of death and decay she was born with to kill every villager because all she wanted was to live a quiet life with her beloved. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In tales like this, I find the true villain to be intangible: it’s the circumstance of misunderstanding and misguided fear that can create evil without meaning, or intentionally fit a narrative that makes a person feel the most comfortable and validate a misconstrued perspective. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rosamund only looked like a villainess to the villagers, but she was never one nor wanted to be one until they pushed her into the dark. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cyberpunk and the Aesthetic Expendable</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/cyberpunk-and-the-aesthetic-expendable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Arielle Amante]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 10:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Aesthetic "Core"]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27746</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My favorite emotional and sensory experience is absorbing a story or poem’s aesthetic core like&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My favorite emotional and sensory experience is absorbing a story or poem’s aesthetic core like a sessile sponge.</p>
<p>While aesthetics naturally set the tonal mood, I love how they also create the foundation of a story’s immersive, emotional experience and help us make sense of central themes that emphasize what a world is lacking–or is trying to emphasize at all.</p>
<p>At the tender age of 14, I fell in love with the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyberpunk">cyberpunk</a> aesthetic. Neon metropolitan cities with blinding hologram advertisements, citizens wearing PVC coats with popped collars, and buildings bathed in underworld shadows? Let’s just say my neurons never stopped firing into the sun, since. But beyond these iconic elements and impeccable visuals of cyberpunk, there was always something else that moved me I couldn’t explain.</p>
<p>Fast forward more than a decade later to college, after taking more literature classes and majoring in creative writing, I began to understand and was able to articulate why the cyberpunk aesthetic affected me so deeply: I’ve always gravitated towards morally grey characters, darker aesthetics, and human experiences driven by self-guided principles rather than the confines of the law; it’s these complex nuances that fascinate me the most today because they compel me to make sense of my own life–even though my favorite antiheroines and antiheroes are worlds apart from mine, in more ways than one. That’s not to say I didn’t appreciate cyberpunk as a teenager. It’s that I learned how to comprehend its core aesthetic and how it translates into emotional impact, through a lens of writing craft and intention, besides spontaneous enjoyment.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, I read <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27831609-squid-s-grief">SQUID’S GRIEF by DK Mok</a>. To give a quick summary, it’s about a car thief named Squid who discovers an amnesiac in the car&#8217;s trunk she meant to steal. No spoilers ahead, but I can tell you we go on a cyberpunk adventure in an adrenaline-inducing, ever-developing city, but we feel small and almost insignificant in it alongside Squid.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-27754 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/27831609._SY475_-194x300.jpg" alt="" width="291" height="450" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/27831609._SY475_-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/27831609._SY475_.jpg 307w" sizes="(max-width: 291px) 100vw, 291px" /></p>
<p>Past all the cheap and accessible luxuries or pleasures of a cyberpunk world, those elements emphasize how lonely one can be in their own society despite all the opportunities for advancement and innovation. What’s ironic in cyberpunk is that communication is easier than ever with technology and instant gratification being created at an accelerated pace–but human connection feels like the most distant or least important intangible, or at least that’s the impression I get.</p>
<p>Reading SQUID’S GRIEF naturally elicited a sensory experience whenever I went deeper into its worldbuilding, but it was one of the first cyberpunk books I read that didn’t focus on the darkness and cynicism associated with the genre. Rather, it used the aesthetics of cyberpunk to emphasize how more susceptible the world is to apathy as opposed to empathy, especially when life has a tendency to deal more unfortunate rather than good hands to you–or your position is so privileged that nothing phases you in pursuing fulfillment, in whatever end goal that means to you.</p>
<p>To Squid, the goal is to survive another day and find some scraps of happiness or peace in a society that perceives her as expendable and insignificant in comparison to the technology and economy built around her, and the traumas that aren’t her fault.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, what gets me the most about cyberpunk is the conviction some characters have despite the odds or circumstances stacked against them. Although their worth seems dictated by higher powers, they exercise the agency to still make a life for themselves. Cyberpunk isn’t just about the high-tech, low-life aesthetic of neon, smoke, and shadows–it’s about how these aesthetics drive home how we can always have hope and tenacity in the darkest places. If anything, why not be relentless?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
