<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 042 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-042/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 12:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 042 Author Interview: Hannah Frankel and &#8220;TheraBot&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-hannah-frankel-and-therabot/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 10:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 042]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For those looking for more summer reading, our Issue 042 is still available! It has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">For those looking for more summer reading, our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-042/">Issue 042</a> is still available! It has 12 stories by 12 fantastic women authors, including Hannah Frankel&#8217;s &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/therabot/">TheraBot</a>,&#8221; the topic of today’s author interview.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: This story strikes such a chord right now, in a time when it seems like so many jobs are being either done by machines and computers already, or where AI replacement is being investigated. Was there any particular incident that inspired you to write &#8220;TheraBot&#8221;?</em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Hannah: I was inspired by a genuine curiosity about what tech-augmented mental health looks <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19313 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/psychology-2706902_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/psychology-2706902_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/psychology-2706902_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/psychology-2706902_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/psychology-2706902_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/psychology-2706902_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />like, in a world that is (happily) clamoring for more mental health, but in the context of needing it to be more affordable for more people to have access. In our economy, affordability often comes from technology and/or scalability. What would therapy look like as a corporate product? Would that be a bad thing? What would it do to people like me who are very happy inhabiting the field as it currently exists?</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: Velma was instantly relatable for me. Her observations of her colleagues and her interactions with them were so interesting and, at times, seemed painfully spot on. How concerned were you with accurately depicting this slice of the working world?</em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Hannah: The thread of this story that is closest to my heart was depicting a working person’s efforts at emotional survival in a deeply hierarchical setting that legitimizes itself as a meritocracy. And this is such a common workplace type for our time that I thought other people might be able to relate. In that kind of day-to-day existence there’s so much wearisome bullshit, that most of us censor speaking in daily life because it’s counterproductive to our needs and goals, and happens to get censored out of most stories that get told because we assume it’s universal to the point of being boring. I have always admired the people who work in those settings, like Velma, who are aware of the bullshit, but somehow also remain resolute in being decent and generous to others.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: This story was fascinating in part because it felt so realistic. Do you think we’re looking at a TheraBot future?</em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19314 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/robot-3010309_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/robot-3010309_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/robot-3010309_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/robot-3010309_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/robot-3010309_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/robot-3010309_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Hannah: I wish I had that crystal ball! We’re starting to see products like TalkSpace and BetterHelp in the last few years, decentralized tech-driven mental health packages that let you access therapy remotely and asynchronously (such as over text) but also require tradeoffs. Chief among these, from what I’ve heard, is that people have a harder time forming a relationship and trust with their therapist. That said, in the age of COVID many therapists are exclusively seeing clients over video telehealth platforms, and since we’re forced into getting lots of practice I’ve noticed myself and my clients are getting better at using the technology in a way that feels more focused and intimate.</p>
<p dir="ltr">For the most part mental health treatment works as kind of a decentralized cottage industry right now and while that protects practitioners like me, it keeps the product expensive and difficult to access. And yet, I believe I will do better work when I am allowed to do it on my own terms, in a way that I’m not confident I would if I were overworked and underpaid as a franchise worker. So it keeps it expensive, but it keeps providers healthy and able to give their best. The best solution to balancing everyone&#8217;s needs, however, is clearly not TheraBot as she appears in this story.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: Who did you think of first when you were doing characterization for this story: Velma, Angie, or JoyCE?</em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Hannah: Velma came first. I wanted to heroize an unglamorous working woman who tries to do the right thing with the system that she’s given. Someone with very little ego and very little interest in herself as a hero, and who deserves more recognition than she will ever get in her world. Good thing she is the heroine of a short story in ours!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 042 Author Interview: Dana Berube and &#8220;The White Place&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-dana-berube-and-the-white-place/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 042]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18789</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to another Issue 042 author interview, dear readers! Today we chat with Dana Berube&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-042/">Issue 042</a> author interview, dear readers! Today we chat with Dana Berube about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-white-place/">The White Place</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This is a wonderfully intense story! What was the inspiration for it?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19270 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/winter-village-2936487_1920-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/winter-village-2936487_1920-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/winter-village-2936487_1920-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/winter-village-2936487_1920-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/winter-village-2936487_1920.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />Dana: Thank you! So, Ti is one of the protagonists of a fantasy trilogy I’m writing. The idea for this story was sparked by a line in one of those novels, set many years later, where he grudgingly confesses to a friend, “I never sold myself…but I perhaps bartered a few times.” In that novel, Ti’s circumstances are improved, but he’s still trying to fill that empty place within himself. I wanted to explore how moments in his past led him to be the man he is in the present, where he desperately wants to connect with people but still struggles to do so.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I also wanted to explore a failure of intersectionality. In fantasy, prejudice against magical beings has sometimes been used as a metaphor for some other kind of injustice. I’ve never seen the point in keeping it metaphorical. Ti lives in a messy colonial empire that is churning with inequality, racism, sexism, homophobia, <em>and </em>anti-wizard hatred. As Ti reflects, his society’s prejudice against wizardry and homosexuality take different forms but stem from the same place. Logically, he and Berron should be allies. However, as we see in our own world, that’s often not how things work out. Systemic oppression grinds people down and keeps us fighting among one another for scraps. Berron isn’t a bad person; he’s just someone who found his own safe corner of an unkind world and never risked peeking beyond it. And for Ti, being both queer and a wizard just leaves him even more isolated.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I don’t claim to have any answers or lessons to share about these big issues. Most of my writing is me trying to work through it all for myself.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There are a lot of interesting tidbits of a larger world sprinkled through this piece. Do you think you’ll write in this world again?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Dana: Absolutely! It’s a big world that I’ve put a lot of time and love into. I’ve got maps! As mentioned above, this story is a standalone piece that is part of a much larger project that includes a novella and a trilogy of novels, set years later than this story. In the novella, Ti’s past as the exiled scion of a wealthy family and his quest for love and stability again collide, but this time with a much bigger bang. His attempts to repair the damage he’s done spark the three books of the trilogy (and more broken hearts and explosions).</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I am currently querying the first book in the trilogy, and I’d love to find a home for the novella.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Ti is a fascinating main character, and his awkward relationship with Berron feels so relatable. How do you approach characterization? What was the first thing you thought of when you came up with Ti?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Dana: Ti has existed in my head in one form or another since I was in fourth grade (he was originally a cat-sized talking horse who could fly and do magic—yes, really). In his later incarnations, I’ve tried to take the archetypical strong, handsome, sword- and magic-wielding fantasy hero and deconstruct him. I’ve always been curious about the psychological scars that fantasy adventures would leave on the characters who live through them. And surely depressed and traumatized people can be fantasy heroes too? Ti is a powerful wizard who ultimately up-ends a kingdom, but he’s also deeply hurting inside.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">In this story, he’s not yet a roguish hero, deconstructed or otherwise. He doesn’t have a sword. He doesn’t have anything. He’s just a hungry kid trying to outrun himself. One artistic choice I made to emphasize that was to have him think of himself as just “Ti” instead of his usual “Tiberius.” Those extra syllables are too heavy for someone who’d rather dissolve their sense of self into nothing.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I don’t have any set methods for characterization, but since I’m an artist, drawing the characters <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19271 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/portrait-3138131_1920-300x211.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="211" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/portrait-3138131_1920-300x211.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/portrait-3138131_1920-1024x721.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/portrait-3138131_1920-768x541.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/portrait-3138131_1920-1536x1082.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/portrait-3138131_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />is a big part of how I try to “find” them. Do they come out looking cheeky or haunted? Do they dress a certain way, and why? I tend to let projects marinate for years before I put a pen to paper, so by then I usually feel like I know the characters pretty well. Of course, sometimes I’ll think I have a solid grasp on a character, and as soon as Istart writing, the character flips the script. I’ve had bad guys turn into good guys, genders and species change, you name it.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us a bit about your other writing projects. </strong></em></p>
<p>Dana: Quarantine did something unexpected to my brain. After working on speculative fiction for the past twelve years and assuming that was my lane, my brain went, <em>hey! Let’s write a realist fiction novella!</em> It’s focused on the same themes I often write about—relationships, trauma, mental health struggles, and found family—just without any wizards (…yet). Writing non-fantasy has been funny because I keep accidentally defaulting to metaphors about swords and kings for characters who live in modern-day Boston. I don’t know if it will go anywhere, but if the novella does nothing other than keep me sane during these odd times, I’ll be satisfied.</p>
<p>I have a short story about a pair of near-future, empty-nester Mongolian herders who adopt a Chinese reconnaissance drone coming out in <a href="http://www.zombiesneedbrains.com/">Zombies Need Brains</a>’ MY BATTERY IS LOW AND IT IS GETTING DARK anthology in July. I’m incredibly excited to be a part of that with so many other great writers. I’ve also got a bunch of other ideas percolating, including some short stories set in this world and an unrelated fantasy novel about revenge, power, and linguistics!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 042 Author Interview: Michèle Laframboise and &#8220;Ganymede&#8217;s Lamps&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-michele-laframboise-and-ganymedes-lamps/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 10:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 042]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, dear readers! How is Issue 042 treating you? Have you read Michèle Laframboise&#8217;s &#8220;Ganymede&#8217;s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello, dear readers! How is <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-042/">Issue 042</a> treating you? Have you read Michèle Laframboise&#8217;s &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/ganymedes-lamps/">Ganymede&#8217;s Lamps</a>&#8220;? We have an interview with her below that you won&#8217;t want to miss!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Multiplying lava lamps, smart carpets, and moving walls⁠—this story and its setting are wildly imaginative! Where did you come up with these ideas?</strong></em></p>
<p>Michèle: My first inspirations were from the mind-blowing pics of Ganymede and Jupiter taken by NASA, where the swirls and bands looked to me like a lava lamp. It became one of the first sentences in the story, and it stuck there, even when I computed the angular size of Jupiter in the <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19211 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-2061231_1920-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-2061231_1920-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-2061231_1920-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-2061231_1920-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-2061231_1920-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-2061231_1920.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />sky of a satellite in a locked down orbit (always facing its planet). The smart, litter-disposing carpet was not such a great stretch of imagination for anyone doing the chore of picking up litter. (Of course, make sure to choose a good setting if you want to keep your guests!) And the “stupid” walls blaring music and scrubbing the air were fun.</p>
<p>My way of finding ideas for setting is to look at annoying problems (like, flossing my teeth) and imagine solutions (like, the dental cleaner microbots featured in my first published novels).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story and why? What was the hardest part?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Michèle: Easier was finding the lamps’ characteristics and describing the little rituals of cappuccino coffee in social gatherings. I loved coming up with the formidable Big Martha as the head of the colony (I’m working on a story about her own difficult youth). It was fun seeing the relationship between Beth and the adults around her, and their mixed reactions to her gift. The hardest thing was computing the apparent diameter of Jupiter in the sky and justifying the characters&#8217; extra digits. I loved writing the mind-boggling images first and then checking the feasibility later. In the story, Jupiter’s strong magnetic field clashes with Ganymede’s, so the settlers link their under-ice machines with insulated wires (and typing in hexa-code works faster with 8-digit hands).</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any other projects you&#8217;re currently working on? If so, could you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Michèle: Yes I do. I am currently working on a steampunk trilogy with a different style of narration for each one. The first novel is done and in revision. In editing I take the occasion to enrich the culture, the names, and the idioms used. It is a risky project but I love building that universe and<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19210 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/steampunk-3006650_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/steampunk-3006650_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/steampunk-3006650_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/steampunk-3006650_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/steampunk-3006650_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/steampunk-3006650_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> its inhabitants.</p>
<p>A second SF novel, in a different setting, is in French, and will be out in 2021. The story is about friendship, guilt, and hope among teens growing up on a weird and hostile world.</p>
<p>My own small company <a href="https://echofictions.com/">Echofictions</a> reprints my short-stories and publishes fun and upbeat F&amp;SF stories, and some semi-sweet stories.</p>
<p>Too many projects, too little time.</p>
<p>A lot of wonderful women in my life have been big women. They have had to cope with the social repercussions of not having the perfect silhouette. I love to put fat &amp; savvy women in my stories. My short-story, “Women are from Mars, Men are from Venus”, follows a fat Martian scientist who lives through fat-shaming and overcomes her own difficult situation. I am preparing a short-story about Big Martha’s teenage days, the moral hazing and harassment she went through, and how she later went on Ganymede. There are people on the other Jovian satellites too, that should get their stories.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 042 Author Interview: EJ Sidle and &#8220;Minor Mortalities&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-ej-sidle-and-minor-mortalities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 10:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 042]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18716</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tuesday again? No problem. Our interview with Issue 042 author EJ Sidle on her story&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="gs">
<div class="">
<div id=":lz" class="ii gt adO">
<div id=":ly" class="a3s aXjCH ">
<div dir="ltr">
<div>Tuesday again? No problem. Our interview with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-042/">Issue 042</a> author EJ Sidle on her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/minor-mortalities/">Minor Mortalities</a>&#8221; is sure to get you through the day.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><em>LSQ: Your story starts with quite the reader-grabbing line. Where did the idea for a necromancer-hitman come from?</em></strong></div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19169 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/human-1219543_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/human-1219543_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/human-1219543_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/human-1219543_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/human-1219543_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/human-1219543_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div>EJ: The answer isn&#8217;t as exciting as you might be thinking! The idea for the whole story was sparked by a Springsteen song (&#8220;Atlantic City,&#8221; if anyone is curious!). The necromancer angle felt like a natural progression as it all came together; I liked the idea of a hitman who could just keep bringing his victims back. Plus, I&#8217;d been researching necromancy for an unrelated project, so I think it was just on my mind!</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><em>LSQ: We only see Theo and Alec in this story, but there&#8217;s major groundwork for a whole magical world here, especially with that cliffhanger of an ending. Have you written anything else set in this world, or do you plan to?</em></strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>EJ: I&#8217;m really good at making plans to write more within a world, or to turn a flash piece into something longer, but I&#8217;m far less good at following through! I certainly enjoyed writing &#8220;Minor Mortalities&#8221;, and I think there&#8217;s more of Theo and Alec&#8217;s story to tell. I suppose that means I have vague plans to carry on, but no real idea of what those plans will actually be!</div>
<div>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: What was the most enjoyable part about writing this story? The most challenging?</em></strong></p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>EJ: My favorite part of starting a new piece is always the characters. It&#8217;s exciting to have a new dynamic to explore, and I always end up having an idea of who I&#8217;m writing about before I get to the actual plot!</div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19170 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/heaven-4349025_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/heaven-4349025_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/heaven-4349025_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/heaven-4349025_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/heaven-4349025_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/heaven-4349025_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Most challenging was probably keeping the piece flash-sized. I wanted to make sure that the interaction between Alec and Theo came together in a way that felt plausible, but at the same time it needed to be succinct enough to allow the piece to keep moving forward without turning into a novel! It worked out in the end, but not without some heavy lifting on behalf of my amazing beta team!</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Who and what are your major sources of inspiration?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>EJ: I&#8217;m a music lover, so often I get ideas for story aesthetics/character concepts from songs. Having the idea is only half the battle, though, so after that I think most of my inspiration to actually write comes from my critique partners and beta readers. Plus, I&#8217;m a member of an absolutely amazing writing group, and I think I get a lot of my long-term inspiration from sharing everyone&#8217;s trials and tribulations. It really does take a village!</div>
</div>
<div class="yj6qo ajU">
<div id=":me" class="ajR" tabindex="0" role="button" data-tooltip="Show trimmed content" aria-label="Show trimmed content" aria-expanded="false"><img decoding="async" class="ajT" src="https://ssl.gstatic.com/ui/v1/icons/mail/images/cleardot.gif" /></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 042 Author Interview: Rachel Brittain and &#8220;Moonlight Plastics&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-rachel-brittain-and-moonlight-plastics/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 10:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 042]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s Tuesday again, and we have for you another dose of Issue 042 author interviews!&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>It&#8217;s Tuesday again, and we have for you another dose of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-042/">Issue 042</a> author interviews! Read on and let Rachel Brittain&#8217;s thoughts on her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/moonlight-plastics/">Moonlight Plastics</a>&#8221; satisfy your craving.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><span class="im"><strong><em>LSQ: At first, Sana thought she was being rescued by a mermaid or a siren. Explain the idea behind Em’s prosthesis.</em></strong></span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19133 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/underwater-4731696_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/underwater-4731696_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/underwater-4731696_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/underwater-4731696_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/underwater-4731696_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/underwater-4731696_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Rachel: That was actually the inciting image that inspired this story! I don’t know why, but the idea of someone appearing to be a mermaid, but whose existence could be explained by technical rather than magical means, just came to me one day. And I thought the idea of mermaid fin prosthesis seemed really awesome, to be honest. I’m not entirely sure how effective it would be in real life. But I liked the idea of a double amputee sort-of underwater recluse scientist making herself a prosthetic specifically suited to her environment.<br />
<span class="im"><br />
<em><strong>LSQ: Talking about scars, Sana said, “It meant your survival was hard fought. Proof of life.” What does this say about Sana as a character? Or the society she lives in?  </strong></em></span></p>
<p>Rachel: Sana comes from a very corporate, capitalistic world, where the life and health of everyday people aren’t prioritized. It’s given her a survivalist mentality that, in some ways, reflects the society she was raised by—every person for themself. That said, I do think her perspective on scars is an optimistic one. It reflects the reality of her situation, sure—scars happen—but it also lends respect to those scars. Scars show the body’s ability to survive and heal. And for someone like Sana, they also show how hard you’ve had to fight to survive, all the times you’ve been shot down and gotten up again. She probably glamorizes them a little more than is healthy, though.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Given the state of today’s oceans, how much of your story is meant to be a cautionary tale?</strong> </em></p>
<p>Rachel: I don’t know if it’s meant to be a cautionary tale so much as a reality, if a somewhat futuristic one. Part of the inspiration behind this story was when I stumbled across information on the Great Pacific Garbage Patch, a particularly polluted area of the Pacific Ocean where warm water currents from the South Pacific and cold water currents from the Arctic converge into this huge field of spinning debris. It’s mostly broken down microplastics that aren’t even visible to the naked eye. So that really does exist today.</p>
<p>I think it’s hard to see the reality of the effects we’ve had on the natural world and not think about where we’re headed. It’s not just up to individuals to make that difference, though. The fact that the corporate bottom-line matters more, in the end, than the choices either of these characters make is really telling.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: &#8220;Moonlight Plastics&#8221; is part science-fiction and part spy/thriller. What genre speaks most to you as you write. What was the part of your story that you found most exciting?</strong></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19134 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/fishing-1545695_1920-300x240.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="240" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/fishing-1545695_1920-300x240.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/fishing-1545695_1920-1024x819.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/fishing-1545695_1920-768x614.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/fishing-1545695_1920-1536x1229.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/fishing-1545695_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div>Rachel: I’m definitely an SFF girl at heart, but I also love a good spy story. I think the spy/thriller aspect is the one that developed more over the course of writing, whereas the science fiction was pretty established from the start with the idea of an underwater laboratory. But moral ambiguity is one of my favorite things to explore in writing, and I think the corporate espionage aspect really brought that out.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><span class="im"><span class="im"><strong><em>LSQ: Can you tell us about other projects you may be working on?  </em></strong></span></span>Rachel: Definitely! I have several short stories in the works, ranging from alternate history to flash sci-fi, including a story being published in <em>Andromeda Spaceways</em> that I’ve been describing as a radioactive fairy tale. My agent and I are also working on finding a home for my YA contemporary fantasy novel about a magical coffee shop, as well as revising a YA book that’s basically my love letter to fandom set at a sci-fi convention. And working on several middle grade and adult SFF projects as well because I just have no chill, basically.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 042 Author Interview: Aimée Jodoin and &#8220;The Glitch&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-aimee-jodoin-and-the-glitch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 10:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 042]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How&#8217;s your day going, dear readers? Are you ready for your weekly dose of Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">How&#8217;s your day going, dear readers? Are you ready for your weekly dose of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-042/">Issue 042</a> author interviews? Today we&#8217;re satisfying your craving with Aimée Jodoin&#8217;s insightful answers to our questions about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-glitch/">The Glitch</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: The concept of Rehabilitation is fascinating, as a sort of a time slavery. How did you come up with the idea?</em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Aimée: I adore time travel stories; they are to me a test of creativity and skill, plus they’re just entertaining. We often hear stories about people using time travel to change the past, but I am more interested in self-fulfilling prophecies, stories where people know that time cannot be changed and that they must make terrible sacrifices to maintain a time stream in which they are the victims in a power structure. While it doesn&#8217;t seem like it on a day-to-day basis, that&#8217;s the situation we are in: stuck in a time stream heading at the same pace in one direction with no way<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19074 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/prison-1331203_1920-245x300.jpg" alt="" width="245" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/prison-1331203_1920-245x300.jpg 245w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/prison-1331203_1920-835x1024.jpg 835w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/prison-1331203_1920-768x942.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/prison-1331203_1920-1253x1536.jpg 1253w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/prison-1331203_1920.jpg 1566w" sizes="(max-width: 245px) 100vw, 245px" /> to change it. I look at that as a beautiful thing in my personal life, but in stories it&#8217;s more interesting to show the dark side of that. I knew I wanted the time traveling in the story to be involuntary, like the time structure is in our lives; unfortunately, people in private prisons today are essentially treated like slaves, and I believe it wouldn’t be far fetched, if people from the future needed laborers, for prisons to send convicts in this way. That’s the sad, brutal truth of the current system. In terms of the content of the story itself, like many writers I took an image from a dream I had. Cliche, I know. I don’t believe in any of that dreams-tell-you-things business; it was just an intriguing image of a person walking through a sort-of door frame that I knew in the dream to be a time travel device, and the person losing an arm, which was left behind in the future. I wish I had a better origin story than a dream, but sometimes that’s just how it goes. It’s what you do with the dream, how you develop the idea, that makes the story what it is.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: The moral implications of the main character’s planned glitch are complicated. What do you think is the main factor that drives her to make that decision?</em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Aimée: Ultimately, she wants her husband back, and she’ll do anything to save him from the clutches of Rehabilitation. She disregards the fact that she’s risking hurting someone else in causing a glitch, and she ignores the fact that trying to save him and only him instead of attempting to dismantle the whole system is morally questionable. Would it be more effective in the long-run to expose the wrongdoings of Rehabilitation to the public and try to shut it down? Of course. But it’s hard for people in those types of situations to step back and look at the big picture when they’re so emotionally involved in the details.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: Your ending is somewhat ambiguous, but also terrifying in its implications. No matter what the outcome, something bad has happened. But also maybe something good. Did leaving it open ended heighten the sacrifice and risk?  </em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Aimée: Yes, that was my goal: heighten the sacrifice and risk. I enjoy open endings because they leave questions and make you think, so long as they fulfill the purpose of the story and don’t leave you frustrated. I think “The Glitch” shows that people are willing to risk their lives and livelihoods when they’re in a horrible situation, and I don’t think it was necessary to show what happened to Michael in order to do that. I know what happens next in the story in my head, and if I added that to this story, it would be another one hundred pages rather than one or two to bring closure to this tale.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: What about your story did you find to be the most interesting to write?</em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19075 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/lost-places-2963766_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/lost-places-2963766_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/lost-places-2963766_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/lost-places-2963766_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/lost-places-2963766_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/lost-places-2963766_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Aimée: From the start, the voice of the story was the hardest to get down. The main character is no-nonsense, doesn’t care about the details, just wants to get to the point. So that consistency of sharp language was difficult but fun to write. Content-wise, it was the minutiae of the time travel that was most interesting to me. I want to write a million different time travel stories that have different methodologies, different moral implications, different characters driving the action. There are so many ways to write a time travel story. I never get sick of reading them!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have anything else you are working on at the moment? Or do you have future plans? </strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Aimée: I was working on a novel about a pandemic, but I&#8217;m taking a break from that for now considering our current situation. I have a few short stories in the works and a handful of novel ideas that may come to fruition at some point in the future. I have played around with continuing “The Glitch” from where it left off and turning it into a novel-length story; it’s an exciting but intimidating prospect!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 042 Author Interview: Dianne M. Williams and &#8220;Accidental Kaiju&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-dianne-m-williams-and-accidental-kaiju/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 10:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 042]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18813</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to Tuesday, when we interview authors from our latest issue about their stories, writing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Tuesday, when we interview authors from our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-042/">latest issue</a> about their stories, writing processes, and inspirations! Today we&#8217;re talking with Dianna M. Williams about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/accidental-kaiju/">Accidental Kaiju</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What were the challenges in writing from the perspective of a lava monster who is also a precocious 13-year-old girl? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Dianne: Great question. How exactly does a teenage lava monster work a cellphone? I don&#8217;t know. Very carefully, I suppose. She must poke the screen with her claws and I bet she scratches the glass all the time. I don&#8217;t know how she sets up her science experiment, either, or who makes enormous red wagons for kaiju children. But I think that&#8217;s part of the fun in writing a world like this. Readers will populate the world with thoughts and images based on their own interests. One person might wonder about how big a kaiju cellphone has to be and another might think about insurance rates in a kaiju world, but there&#8217;s room for all of that. I like to leave room in stories for the world to grow its own roots in the minds of each reader.</div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19036 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-flow-1803289_1280-300x197.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="197" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-flow-1803289_1280-300x197.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-flow-1803289_1280-1024x672.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-flow-1803289_1280-768x504.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/lava-flow-1803289_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I think that, for me, writing from the perspective of a 13-year-old was harder than writing from the perspective of a lava monster! It&#8217;s been a long time since I was a teenager. I was an awkward kid and I have no wish to revisit those early years all over again. I never felt like I fit into the world quite right. My thoughts and feelings were so big at 13, like they couldn&#8217;t fit into the world around me, and they were still growing. It was easy to believe that there might be lava monsters out there who feel the same way. I had to change the details (I passionately wanted to be a marine biologist at Grendela&#8217;s age, which is definitely NOT suited to a lava monster) but that same awkward, out of place feeling was easy enough to find.</div>
<p><span class="im"><br />
<em><strong>LSQ: Grendela&#8217;s livestream made me very curious: how do you think humans would react to a livestream from a kaiju?</strong></em></span></p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>Dianne: I think that humans have an enormous capacity to adapt to the strange and abnormal around us. There are all kinds of unusual things going on that I accept as part of my daily life. Whether it&#8217;s living through a historic lockdown right now, astronauts launched into space, or a viral video of a skydiving cat, life goes on for most of us. We take it all in and then we get back to our day-to-day living. I think Grendela would be equal parts fascination and vexation for the world. Some people would love her, some would hate her, but for the most part I think she&#8217;d be one more oddity on the internet that people mention at parties and then forget about. I do hope that she&#8217;d connect with some kids her own age who also care about the sciences so that she doesn&#8217;t have to feel so out of place.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Even though Grendela and her family are monsters, they read just like a normal human family. What advice would you give on effectively writing nonhuman characters with human attributes?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Dianne: That&#8217;s such an interesting question because Grendela and her family were always just people to me. Giant people with odd rituals, yes, but Grendela still has wants and needs like any human child. The story exists because she has a need for acceptance, both within her family and within her larger community. Without that, she could do whatever she wants without looking for anyone&#8217;s approval. Families come in lots of shapes and sizes. Any sort of family you can imagine<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19035 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/tail-1566250_1920-192x300.jpg" alt="" width="192" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/tail-1566250_1920-192x300.jpg 192w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/tail-1566250_1920-656x1024.jpg 656w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/tail-1566250_1920-768x1199.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/tail-1566250_1920-984x1536.jpg 984w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/tail-1566250_1920.jpg 1230w" sizes="(max-width: 192px) 100vw, 192px" /> is out there somewhere. Put the right types of personalities together, the right pressure points, and you have a story. Here you have parents who want to accept Grendela, but they don&#8217;t understand her. You have a human community that doesn&#8217;t want to accept her, but they have the greatest chance to understand her. And you have one terribly awkward teenager in the middle. Grendela could just as easily be a human kid who doesn&#8217;t want to become a doctor like her parents. The biggest difference that I considered when writing her family wasn&#8217;t that they&#8217;re emotionally different than humans but that they have a different physicality. Claws instead of fingers, giant red wagons, tentacle hugs. Those things are just fun for me to write. But Grendela herself was always just a complex being trapped in a complex situation.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have any other projects you&#8217;re working on? If so, could you tell us about them?  </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Dianne: I always have a few projects going, but nothing is set in stone just yet. I hope that by the end of the fall you&#8217;ll be able to read a story of mine about a much smaller type of creature who wants his own type of acceptance in the world.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 042 Author Interview: Caite Sajwaj and &#8220;The Wish&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-caite-sajwaj-and-the-wish/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 10:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 042]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18759</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tuesdays at LSQ are kind of a big deal, because each week we drop an exclusive interview&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div>Tuesdays at <em>LSQ </em>are kind of a big deal, because each week we drop an exclusive interview with one of our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-042/">current</a> authors. Today let us treat you to our delightful chat with Caite Sajwaj, author of &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-wish/">The Wish</a>.&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: Reading the end of this story put a huge smile on my face. It reminds me of my favorite fairy tales, the ones with happy endings. What was your inspiration for it?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Caite: When I was very young—seven or eight, probably—my mother took me to a school book fair and I picked out a collection of short stories called &#8220;Instead of Three Wishes&#8221; by Megan Whalen Turner. Those stories have been knocking around in my head for decades at this point, and &#8220;The Wish&#8221; is very much an ode to <a href="http://meganwhalenturner.org/images/pdfs/ex_instead.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://meganwhalenturner.org/images/pdfs/ex_instead.pdf&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1590539813210000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEgEDmiGhupVLJy0oOaoPCXNm8Y1Q">the titular story of the collection</a>.</div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18975 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/acorn-3694035_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/acorn-3694035_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/acorn-3694035_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/acorn-3694035_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/acorn-3694035_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/acorn-3694035_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />There&#8217;s this trope in a lot of fairy tales that fairies and witches and whatever else are very <i>transactional </i>with their favors. The miller&#8217;s daughter owes Rumpelstiltskin her firstborn child. The Little Mermaid owes the sea witch her voice, and sometimes more. In most fairy tales, you probably couldn&#8217;t ask for a piece of gum or bum a cigarette without trading your soul or something. &#8220;Instead of Three Wishes&#8221; explores the flip side of this trope, and that was my intention with &#8220;The Wish&#8221; as well. The only thing I hadn&#8217;t figured out when I started was the ending. I fully intended for Cressida to spite Rowan with an airtight wish that he couldn&#8217;t misconstrue, but she apparently had her own ideas&#8230;</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: Your descriptions are so vivid, especially of smell, that I was ready to get off that bus with Cressida too. Do you jot down interesting things you experience that you think you might put into a story later?</b></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>Caite: All those sensory details are pulled from my own experiences, but I don&#8217;t usually write them down. I prefer to let these experiences age a bit before I use them. Memory is fallible, but when writing fiction that can be a good thing! A fuzzy memory is easier to embellish and repurpose. Cressida&#8217;s original description of the bus is inspired by an hour I spent in transit from my hotel to the airport. The man behind me reeked of smoke and he kept coughing on the back of my head. I felt like I was hot-boxed with the embodiment of pestilence. So those feelings of disgust and claustrophobia became the inside of the bus.</div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div><span class="im"><em><b>LSQ: What’s the first thing that comes to you when you’re plotting a story? A particular scene, a character, a word or phrase?</b></em><br />
</span></div>
<div></div>
<div>Caite: The first thing that came to my mind when plotting this story was a phrase, and it was &#8220;the final resting place of a thousand ancient farts.&#8221; Just kidding. Okay, I&#8217;ll be serious now. For me, stories always start out with a scene. In &#8220;The Wish,&#8221; it was Rowan giving the wish/business ca<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18976 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bus-731317_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bus-731317_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bus-731317_1920-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bus-731317_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bus-731317_1920-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/bus-731317_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />rd to Cressida. Once you have that initial scene, the rest of the plot comes from asking questions. Why did Rowan give her the wish? What does she do with it? In the first scene of the piece I&#8217;m working on now, a man steals a witch&#8217;s handbag and I won&#8217;t say any more than that.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: This was a fun, complex, satisfying short story. Do you have a preferred story length in your writing?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Caite: Novels are my first love, but writing short stories is a great way to hone your craft and feel the satisfaction of actually finishing something. The authors I love most—Kelly Link, Holly Black, Neil Gaiman—are masters of long and short form and I aspire to the same.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 042 Author Interview: Jennifer Lee Rossman and &#8220;Depth and Meaning&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-jennifer-lee-rossman-and-depth-and-meaning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 10:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 042]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Strap in, dear readers, for another Issue 042 author interview. Today we chat with Jennifer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="gs">
<div class="">
<div id=":lz" class="ii gt">
<div id=":ly" class="a3s aXjCH ">
<div>
<div dir="auto">Strap in, dear readers, for another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-042/">Issue 042</a> author interview. Today we chat with Jennifer Lee Rossman with her relatable story, &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/depth-and-meaning/">Depth and Meaning</a>.&#8221;</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: This story hit me hard because it&#8217;s just so darn relatable. How did you feel while writing it? What called you to write it?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Jennifer: I have struggled with depression since my late teens. Almost half my life now. When I’m<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18924 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/paint-2985569_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/paint-2985569_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/paint-2985569_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/paint-2985569_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/paint-2985569_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/paint-2985569_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> depressed, I can create. I can put words on paper and people tell me my work is good, but good isn’t good enough for me. I don’t feel the magic of writing, I’m just going through the motions while I’m going through the emotions. And if I don’t feel the magic, usually those are the stories that don’t get accepted for publication.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">But if you don’t suffer, people say, your art won’t be good. And if you take antidepressants, you’re giving up and you’re letting yourself be changed by the medication. You’re not yourself anymore. Well, you’re not yourself anymore if you’re depressed, either, and what good is suffering for your art if the suffering kills you? It’s hard enough to get good mental health care, and people like that don’t help by adding to the stigma. I am personally not a fan of antidepressants. They don’t get along well with my body and my mind. But they save lives and they need to be an option.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: Dex asking Emi, &#8220;What do you have to be depressed about?&#8221; gave me a physical jolt. What advice would you give to someone in Emi&#8217;s shoes, when someone you love and trust belittles your struggles?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Jennifer: Most people in your life do not mean you harm. Most have your best intentions at heart. But that doesn’t mean they can’t hurt you by mistake. It probably doesn’t even occur to them, because they are not going through the same things you are.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">It is OK to love and trust someone conditionally. It is OK not to agree with them, and to only trust them with certain parts of your life. I have people I would trust with my life, and who I tell everything, and then there are people I trust with my life, who I know just aren’t capable of understanding certain things about me. I love them and I would do anything for them, but they are not the people I go to all the time when I am in a crisis.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect of this story to write and why? What is your favorite part of it?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18926 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/drip-871152_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/drip-871152_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/drip-871152_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/drip-871152_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/drip-871152_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/drip-871152_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div dir="auto">Jennifer: It&#8217;s always hard when you write about something personal because the feelings aren&#8217;t just your character&#8217;s. They&#8217;re yours.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">The ending is my favorite part, mostly because it mirrors the beginning visually in a way I did not consciously plan. I love when my stories surprise me, and the ending gives me goosebumps.</div>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">
<p><strong><em>LSQ:</em>  Are there any other projects you&#8217;re currently working on? If so, could you tell us a bit about them?</strong></p>
<div></div>
<p>Jennifer: I&#8217;m currently procrastinating on the edits of two different stories about dinosaurs. I don&#8217;t know when I will have permission to properly announce them, but basically they are &#8220;Joan Of Arc… but with dinosaurs&#8221; and &#8220;Armageddon… but with dinosaurs.&#8221;</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 042 Author Interview: Carol Scheina and &#8220;The Midwife&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-carol-scheina-and-the-midwife/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-carol-scheina-and-the-midwife/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 10:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 042]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18855</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Issue 042 is still brand-spankin&#8217;-new, and we have plenty of author interviews coming your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-042/">Issue 042</a> is still brand-spankin&#8217;-new, and we have plenty of author interviews coming your way! Today we&#8217;re talking with Carol Scheina, author of &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-midwife/">The Midwife</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><span class="im"><em><strong>LSQ: A major theme that runs through your story is “the narrow thread between birth and death”.  What made you focus on the connection between the two? How powerful is the space between?</strong></em></span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18867 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sculpture-3270181_1920-208x300.jpg" alt="" width="208" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sculpture-3270181_1920-208x300.jpg 208w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sculpture-3270181_1920-709x1024.jpg 709w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sculpture-3270181_1920-768x1110.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sculpture-3270181_1920-1063x1536.jpg 1063w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/sculpture-3270181_1920.jpg 1329w" sizes="(max-width: 208px) 100vw, 208px" />Carol: My first child and I both had a difficult time with the birth process, though thankfully we bounced back. Afterward, I rocked my child and thought, “If we’d lived just a century ago, there’s a good chance we wouldn’t have made it.” History is full of women dying due to childbirth complications, and another heartbreaking fact is that even today, childbirth can be a risky act for a woman. Yet despite the pain and risks, birth is also the act of bringing new life into the world.</p>
<p>I’ve thought a lot about women of the past who watched their peers die in childbirth, yet they were also expected to bear children as their primary role and full well knew the dangers involved with childbirth. History is full of tales of wars and politics, but to me, the courage of those women is profound as they balanced the risk of death with the hope of life.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Hannah makes mention about how important her anger is for the task </em></strong><strong><em>ahead. Why this particular emotion? How does the anger keep her </em></strong><strong><em>focused?</em></strong></p>
<p>Carol: When channeled properly, anger at a particular situation or injustice can be followed by a desire to change things for the better. Hannah draws upon her anger to remind herself to not become complacent, even if childbirth deaths are rather the norm for this setting. Anger is a<br />
wonderful emotion for change, and in Hannah’s case, she uses it to push herself harder to prevent the loss of life.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Hannah also said that “Guilt was a power of its own”. Jobelle is </strong></em><em><strong>a beautiful manifestation of this, though she no longer wants to be. </strong></em><em><strong>Could you explain their relationship and the complex nature of the </strong></em><em><strong>guilt that ties them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Carol: The character of Jobelle came to life when I wondered, “What if your one failure followed you the rest of your life?” For a midwife, a failure means death. Hannah feels, like I do, that even one loss of life is one too many, yet under Hannah’s watch, Jobelle and her child died.</p>
<p>The relationship between Hannah and Jobelle is complicated, as Hannah sees her failure every day in the spirit of Jobelle and the child, and the guilt pounds away at her. It pushes Hannah to strive harder and test boundaries to keep her charges safe.</p>
<p>When Jobelle whispers in Hannah’s ear to come back, that’s a reminder that Hannah cannot accept death or retirement, for there is always a need to atone. There will always be more <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18869 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/gothic-3173129_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/gothic-3173129_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/gothic-3173129_1920-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/gothic-3173129_1920-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/gothic-3173129_1920-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/gothic-3173129_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />women needing help. Guilt eats away at Hannah, yet it also keeps her from giving up or allowing<br />
herself to die. Guilt is a complicated thing, indeed.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What emotions of your own did you experience while writing this?</strong> <strong>Was there a part that was more difficult? Or fulfilling?</strong></em></p>
<p>Carol: I wanted to emphasize the tension and uncertainty of childbirth, and I drew from personal experiences and stories I’d heard from other women. Some of my own dark places went into this story, with remembering my own miscarriages prior to finally having a successful birth.</p>
<p>The most fulfilling part of the tale, for me, was the moment when the baby cries, for despite all the chaos and uncertainty, a new child is born and cries out for the first time. In spite of Hannah’s pain and Jobelle’s inability to rest in peace, new life arrives and a mother can hold her child for the first time. I can instantly go back in time to that moment when I first got to hold my child for the first time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-042-author-interview-carol-scheina-and-the-midwife/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
