<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Balancing Act &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/balancing-act/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:04:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Breaking Up is Never Easy</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/breaking-up-is-never-easy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A. Francis Raymond]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 10:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Balancing Act]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How do you break up with a story? I’m asking for a friend… OK, maybe&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How do you break up with a story? I’m asking for a friend… OK, maybe that friend is me.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we last met, I described the writing tasks I was going to attempt in the new year. It was a <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15516 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/kelly-sikkema-530092-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/kelly-sikkema-530092-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/kelly-sikkema-530092-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/kelly-sikkema-530092-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />deliberate ploy to hold myself accountable to my writing. I talked about two techniques I wanted to try. The first technique was going to be rewriting a story line by line based on this Pinterest post: </span><a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/531635931009863433/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Writing advice you’re not going to like</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How’d it go?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, I did attempt to rewrite and edit in order to finish one of my stories. It’s a short story I started a few years ago. I fell in love with the original idea and concept, but was having a hard time finishing it. I even brought it to my local writers&#8217; critique group to get some help. That was almost two years ago. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even though it&#8217;s been a few years, I’ve been telling myself that I still wanted to finish this story. So I sat at my computer and opened up a blank document. Next to it, I opened up the story. And then… I stared at it. I read the first sentence in the original version. Should I re-write it exactly as written? Did I want to change it?  For a while, I did nothing substantial. Excuse number one was that I wasn&#8217;t in the right frame of mind. Excuse number two was that I had bills to pay that I should take care of right then and there. Excuse number three was all the other ways that have made me an expert procrastinator when it comes to writing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eventually, I started. I re-wrote the first few sentences. Then I let it sit for a few days. Then wrote a few more. I made it through the first section before pausing for a couple of weeks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As I was working on this story (or thinking about it and not working on it), I realized I wasn&#8217;t loving my story. I wasn&#8217;t into it. The passion I originally had for it was gone. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was stuck. Caught between the “do I finish” or “do I abandon” this story?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If I turn to the Internet, several writing blogs I subscribe to all talk about making sure you finish what you start. And the logic behind that makes sense to me. If you keep starting new things before finishing anything, you&#8217;ll never finish anything, never publish, and never be on a best- seller list. Like this post: </span><a href="https://medium.com/@shauntagrimes/writer-finish-what-you-start-10a773e18da1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Writer, Finish What You Start!</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But then I was with my local writers&#8217; critique group again, bemoaning this dilemma, and my fellow writers there told me it was time to abandon this story. If my heart was no longer in it, they argued, I should move on. All the time I spent angsting over this story was now wasted time and energy that I could be pouring into something I cared about. Good points, right?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15517 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/jeshoots-com-523925-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/jeshoots-com-523925-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/jeshoots-com-523925-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/jeshoots-com-523925-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Back to the original question:  How (and when) do I break up with this story?  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For what it’s worth, I didn’t invent this problem. Neither did anyone else, by the way… this problem is as old as time. I recently read a biography on Leonardo da Vinci. He was notorious for shiny-new-object syndrome.  Even with the propensity for hopping from one subject to the next, he still managed to accomplish quite a bit which challenges the “if you never finish, you never get anywhere” argument. His success rested on how prolific he was in all areas of his life.  I could probably afford to move on and on and on and only finish a little if I was a full time writer. But with the Job, the Family, the House, and the fact that I do enjoy other things in my spare time besides writing, I’m not as prolific as I think I should or could be.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead, I circle back to thinking I want to give this story one more change and turn to articles <a href="https://medium.com/the-1000-day-mfa/3-ways-to-combat-shiny-new-thing-syndrome-cc87850c0e6d?sk=f1fd2f0b3891997d0a03b18ecf362e89">like these</a> to help me combat Shiny Object Syndrome.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s been a couple weeks since I started this blog post and first contemplated breaking up with my story.  I haven’t cut the cord just yet. With these options in mind, I slog on with this story… What do you think? Is it time to cut the cord?</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing Tasks in the New Year</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-tasks-in-the-new-year-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A. Francis Raymond]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 11:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Balancing Act]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Can you believe we&#8217;re already a month into the new year? Like so many people,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/brandi-redd-122054-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12667 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/brandi-redd-122054-unsplash-209x300.jpg" alt="" width="209" height="300" /></a>Can you believe we&#8217;re already a month into the new year?</div>
<div></div>
<div>Like so many people, there&#8217;s a good chance you&#8217;ve recently reflected on the past year and made some resolutions or goals for the upcoming year. As writers, there&#8217;s a good chance writing is one of the things you evaluated heavily. We regret all the time that has past where we didn&#8217;t write and make ambitious resolutions to write massive quantities in the upcoming year.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Yeah, me too.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Last year was not at all about writing for me. It was about bringing my second child into the world and finishing my master&#8217;s degree. (Woo hoo!) I managed to keep somewhat up to date on my journal, and of course write a little bit about writing. But creating new fictional content, or even revising and editing some of my works-in-progress just wasn&#8217;t in the cards. And that&#8217;s okay. Even though one must write to be a writer, sometimes there&#8217;s the rest of life, you know?</div>
<div></div>
<div>This year is going to be different. It&#8217;s a new year and I don&#8217;t know about you, but I&#8217;m going to fulfill old promises to myself of working on my writing. Almost every year I renew my personal commitment to myself, and some years have gone better than others. This is going to be one of those better years.</div>
<div></div>
<div>But I&#8217;ve decided to do something different this year. Instead of resolving to write so many words per day or month, or to finish that novel that&#8217;s been itching at my brain, I decided to set up some tasks instead. A list of tasks feels more imminent to me (something I can&#8217;t ignore), rather than a list of resolutions (something that doesn&#8217;t have to get done because it&#8217;s not on my to-do list).</div>
<div></div>
<div>The tasks are trying two new things with the intent of making progress on my writing. To not entirely overwhelm myself, I&#8217;m limiting both of these experiments for now to short stories instead of one of my work-in-progress novels.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Task #1:</strong> Re-write one of my short stories based on this Pinterest post: <a href="https://pin.it/btkti4ki6u5btb">Writing advice you&#8217;re not going to like</a></div>
<div></div>
<div>Of course I had to find out what this advice was once I read the title. The advice is to take out a fresh piece of paper, or open a new document and completely re-write your work. Line by line. The idea feels . . . magical. Yes, completely re-writing sounds insane, but it also feels like it might be genius. I&#8217;m a little nervous that it won&#8217;t change my life or be as revolutionary as the post states, but I&#8217;m willing to try it. I feel like I <em>need</em> to try it.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Task #2:</strong> Write a complete story on my mobile device (Based off <a href="https://medium.com/@augustbirch/what-i-learned-writing-an-entire-novel-on-my-phone-f1655d09b00b">this Medium post.)</a></div>
<div></div>
<div>This dude wrote a full 70,000 word novel on his mobile device! He is my writing hero. I want to be the person who did <em>that</em>.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I always struggle to find the perfect writing setup. Theoretically, the perfect writing setup is in my office at home. The problem is, I&#8217;m often not there and have always struggled to figure out the best way to write when I&#8217;m away. While I love physical journals, I&#8217;m never consistent and I don&#8217;t always carry them with me, and I don&#8217;t like the idea of transcribing what I wrote (which, if you&#8217;re paying attention, you&#8217;ll notice is kinda a contradiction to the first idea . . . but ignore that).<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/thought-catalog-354861-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12668 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/thought-catalog-354861-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></div>
<div></div>
<div>I <em>do </em>always have my phone with me. But while I&#8217;m reasonably speedy when it comes to input, I&#8217;m not as fast as I am on a regular keyboard, which is frustrating. I have a bluetooth keyboard, but there&#8217;s again the problem of always having it handy.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Instead, I&#8217;ll accept that I&#8217;m going to write a sentence here and a sentence there. I might write one or two while waiting for a meeting to begin. Another in the checkout line. Maybe while standing in the kitchen waiting for a pot of water to boil. Or while I wait for the Kiddo to tie his shoes. Places where I don&#8217;t need to write pages and pages at a time.</div>
<div></div>
<div>(August Birch, the guy who did it, also wrote a <a href="https://medium.com/@augustbirch/how-to-write-a-full-novel-on-your-phone-85c1e27a9fed">&#8220;how-to&#8221; follow-up post</a>. The primary difference is that I&#8217;m going to work in Evernote. Okay, maybe I&#8217;ll use Google Docs. I have both and use both and do you see how I have these issues of figuring out the best way to do that that prevents me from getting started?)</div>
<div></div>
<div>Each of these tasks should result in a complete story. Then I&#8217;ll evaluate the techniques and see if they worked and see if it&#8217;s useful for the future. Hopefully I&#8217;ll be able to tell you how it went in my next blog post.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Good luck on your own writing journey this year. I&#8217;d love to hear about your resolutions and goals in the comments, especially any non-traditional ones.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breaking the Habit of the Writing Break</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/breaking-the-habit-of-the-writing-break/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A. Francis Raymond]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Balancing Act]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11701</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Write every day. Ten minutes a day. A thousand words a day. Just write. Free&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/kinga-cichewicz-594504-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11811 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/kinga-cichewicz-594504-unsplash-300x214.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="214" /></a>Write every day. Ten minutes a day. A thousand words a day. Just write. Free write in a journal. Write your book. Start some kind of specialty journal. Whatever you do, do it every day. Lots of advice and ideas on what to do as part of a daily writing habit abound. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the keys is getting it done every day. Every day. Until it becomes a habit.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.developgoodhabits.com/how-to-form-a-habit-in-8-easy-steps/">Creating a habit</a> (they say) takes 21 to 28 or even 30 days.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Some even claim you need as much as <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/inspired-life/wp/2015/03/02/expert-ten-super-smart-ways-to-build-good-habits-and-make-them-stick/?noredirect=on&amp;utm_term=.c77fc0dde3d6">90 days</a> for the habit to stick.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> There are also methods that say developing a habit isn’t something to do daily, but that there’s a method to returning to it. This is called Spaced Repetition and there’s an easy guide to getting started with this method right <a href="https://betterhumans.coach.me/using-spaced-repetition-to-supercharge-your-habits-9f4f0d31bd3b">here</a>.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Problem is, I’ve been out of the writing habit for a while and I’ve become overwhelmed with all the advice-mongers on how to get back in. I’ve spent so much time browsing Pinterest on writing without actually writing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In theory, to me, the advice to simply write ten minutes a day sounds the best. Who can’t spare ten minutes in their busy day? Ten minutes is nothing! I know I can easily spend ten minutes a day checking Facebook, Pinterest . . . or staring at a wall. I also know I can write a solid few hundred words in that ten minutes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But when? If I’m going to write ten a day, it should be at the same time every day, right? I used to write first thing in the morning. I used to be the first one up in my house every day. I would grab my cup of coffee, sit at my computer, and go!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That changed when The Child started getting up at the same time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After work? That’s a terrible time (for me). I’m beat from the day. My brain is mush and I need to recharge.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During the day? Right now The Job is so busy I don’t get any breaks (I even eat my lunch at my desk while I’m working <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/david-iskander-599066-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11812 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/david-iskander-599066-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>almost every day). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I realized that trying to find a set time every day is 1) a lost cause and 2) just another excuse for not writing those ten minutes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The other problem (OK, I’ll call it an excuse, because that’s all it is) is: <em>where</em> do I write? Do I carry a journal around with me everywhere? Can I do it on my phone? Honestly, I’m still working this one out. I alternate between my phone and a journal &#8211; never completely satisfied. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So instead, I’ve been on a writing break. I won’t admit to how long it’s been since I’ve been away from my core writing activities. Being on a break hasn’t stopped me from thinking about writing, reading about writing, taking notes when they come to me, or other tangentially related activities.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But this break is dangerous because it, too, is a habit and one that’s gone longer than 28 days. (OK, longer than 90 now.)  So yeah, a real habit.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stop Using Pinterest (no, not really &#8211; just stop letting it suck your precious time away)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/stop-using-pinterest-no-not-really-just-stop-letting-it-suck-your-precious-time-away/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A. Francis Raymond]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Balancing Act]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I did it again. I let Pinterest steal more than a half hour of my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/eder-pozo-perez-32852-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10787 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/eder-pozo-perez-32852-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a>I did it again. I let Pinterest steal more than a half hour of my precious time away. It started out innocently enough. I opened the app &#8211; I’m not sure exactly why. Nothing else special was happening at the moment, or I was bored, or I was procrastinating from something I should have been doing. I figured I would scroll down a little, see the fronts of a few interesting pins, save them for later, and be on my way. Nope. A half hour later I found recipes that I might try, crafts I’ll probably never do, and of course things added to my writing board that I might not ever fully read.</p>
<p>As of this moment, that writing board consists of 368 pins. I haven’t spent the time to organize them into sections yet (a relatively new feature on Pinterest), but these pins cover everything from basic how-to start your novel, what to do at the beginning, middle, and end, and to how to create the best characters ever to writing exercises and lists from other famous writers with their tips, to words to use in place of other words. (The only thing noticeably absent from my own collection are writing prompts. Coming up with new ideas is not something I struggle with. Coming up with ways to preserve my precious writing time is.)</p>
<p>Since I started pinning, my collection of writing books hasn’t seen an increase. I guess I figure that if I need to get some inspiration or want to know “<a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/531635931005993150/">10 ways to hit your reader in the gut</a>” or what “<a href="https://writeandco.com/character-intros-make-readers-fall-love/?epik=07gAoE_IW33By">character intros will make readers fall in love</a>” it’s all right there accessible from my smartphone.</p>
<p>As handy a resource this is, those other boards call to me… instead of writing, maybe I should be figuring out a new <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/thought-catalog-217861-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10788 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/thought-catalog-217861-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>exciting meal plan for my family for the next week (the total number of pins I’ve saved spread out between several food-related boards total over 2,700). Or, it’s the time of the year where weekends are perfect for gardening. I should stop throwing away my banana peels because apparently I can learn to make <a href="http://grdnng.com/using-banana-peels-in-the-garden-for-fertilizer-and-pests/?epik=0gwAoE_IW33By">excellent plant fertilizer</a> with them.</p>
<p>You see my problem? I’ve developed a love-hate relationship with this app. Even looking at it as research for this blog post just caused another lost 20 minutes. But I’m back. With my own strategy:</p>
<p>I vow to not spend more than 20 minutes a week* randomly browsing through Pinterest. (*Note: I might need to start this week with 60 minutes and work my way down to 20.) If I really am stuck with my writing project and need to grab an idea for a<a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/531635931006816604/"> character flaw</a>, for instance, I am allowed to open the app, and go directly to my target. Once done, I shall close the app.</p>
<p>If only I could close the app and get back that time, which my strategy should allow, I will finally be able to improve my “<a href="https://www.hustleandgroove.com/improve-your-writing-10-minutes?epik=0GAAoE_IW33By">writing in 10 minutes a day</a>!” Ask me in a month how that’s going…</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Green Monster Motivation</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/green-monster-motivation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A. Francis Raymond]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Balancing Act]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9272</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Intense and utter jealousy. That’s how I feel right now. I just finished reading the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/monster-309688_1280.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10193 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/monster-309688_1280-300x228.png" alt="" width="300" height="228" /></a>Intense and utter jealousy. That’s how I feel right now. I just finished reading the <em>Bobiverse</em> trilogy by <a href="http://dennisetaylor.org/about/">Dennis E. Taylor</a>. I’m insanely jealous over the fact that I wasn’t the one to write this series of books.</p>
<p>(*Side note . . . by “read” I really mean listen. Between the Day Job, the Hubby and Kiddo, and everything else, I have no time to read, are you kidding me? For the last couple of years, all my “reading” has been in the form of listening to audio books purchased through Audible, or borrowed from my local library through the Overdrive app.)</p>
<p>First, if you’re a fan of straight-up science-y science fiction, then this is a great set of books. Computers, aliens, artificial intelligence, space travel&#8211;without any harsh language, over the top gore for the sake of gore, or over the top passionate affairs appreciated mostly by teenage boys. Just pure science fiction.</p>
<p>But finishing a book or a set of books like this also makes me feel kind of lousy, too. Not surprising, since &#8220;lousy&#8221; is part of &#8220;jealousy.&#8221; It’s the fact that I can’t (yet) point to the same sense of accomplishment. What’s worse is that at the beginning of the third book in this trilogy, there’s an author’s note where he talks about thanking his wife for supporting him in his decision to work on this full time.</p>
<p>Full time! Is that the only way to get a book done?</p>
<p>I know it’s not. In fact, there are lots of people who have managed to complete and publish books &#8212; <em>good</em> books &#8212; while maintaining their other life commitments. The <em>History</em> channel gave us one <a href="https://www.history.com/news/history-lists/9-famous-authors-with-day-jobs">list.</a> Not as inspiring as I would have hoped; given the exception of Toni Morrison, none of these are modern writers with the same kind of commitments you and I have.</p>
<p>In fact, Mr. Taylor didn’t quit his own Day Job until he’d published already. He wrote a significant portion of his works with that commitment.</p>
<p>Every now and then I do have the thought of what it would be like to quit the Day Job and write full time. When <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/brooke-cagle-609875-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10194 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/brooke-cagle-609875-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>I have these thoughts, I realize I’m not ready for that. Maybe I never will be. My day job (as a software engineer) adds a lot to my life. Of course there’s the tangible financial security with health benefits. That alone is worth so much, if only to not have the stress of knowing that I can make the mortgage payment. But as a mostly introvert, a lot of my social interaction comes from work. Especially since I’m around similar people to myself and in our down time, I can even talk to some of my coworkers about my writing ideas knowing that these people are not fellow writers, but potentially fellow readers. It’s unofficial beta time with a potential audience.</p>
<p>Lastly, I get that dedicated commuting time where I can read/listen to a variety of stuff to get jealous, learn from, and remain motivated to someday join that group of science fiction writers that someone else will read, fall in love with my work, and daydream about doing the same thing, too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My time! (slaps hand) Mine!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/my-time-slaps-hand-mine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[A. Francis Raymond]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 12:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Balancing Act]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Life is a series of neatly compartmentalized blocks of work, family, hobbies . . .&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/brandi-redd-99307.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9390 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/brandi-redd-99307-300x220.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="220" /></a>Life is a series of neatly compartmentalized blocks of work, family, hobbies . . . Wait, hold on a sec &lt;<em><strong>insert laughter of insanity</strong></em>&gt; Sorry. We all know what a load of crud that is. Oh, the blocks are there! Work, family . . . we all have our unique building blocks that make up our lives. Mine include (in no particular order): the Day Job, the Hubby, the Kiddo, the Never Clean Enough House, and of course the UNTMM (Unfinished Novels That Mock Me). There are also 142 other Hobbies that come and go as the weather changes or thoughts pop into my head.</p>
<p>There are moments I can <em>pretend</em> are compartmentalized&#8211;rare moments when I’m focused on one and only one of these things. Those are the most precious moments . . . which last briefly when another block intrudes. I guess they’re really more like blobs than blocks. Blobs that are constantly changing shape and overlapping the other blobs that make up my never really neatly compartmentalized life.</p>
<p>As a writer, I should be spending as much time as possible writing. That part of my life is incredibly important to me and to be a writer, one must write. But it’s so incredibly hard to squeeze out those words after a long day of work, followed by family time, followed by getting ready to do it all again the next day.</p>
<p>To date, my completed works are all short stories and flash fiction. I’ve told people (and myself) that I’ve focused on short fiction because I love the medium. It’s true that I do love short fiction, but the second half of that truth is that short stories are easier to finish. Since they require less time, I can actually attain and savor that sense of completion. (I did complete a novel once many years ago, but it’s a piece of crud that will never see the light of day. I call it my practice novel. I also call it the Novel of Catharsis since I wrote it immediately after my last bad breakup pre-Hubby and it is loosely about all jerky ex-boyfriends I’ve had. Seriously &#8211; it will never see the light of day. In fact, I should probably just go ahead and delete it from my hard drive right now . . .)</p>
<p>But here I am writing during a time that I specifically blocked out and scheduled for myself. It’s a rare day where I have off from the Day Job, but the Kiddo is in school and the Hubby is at work. Yes, I have errands and other household things to do, but I specifically scheduled this time to write this.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/dustin-lee-19667.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9391 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/dustin-lee-19667-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>It’s part of getting back and building up the habit of writing. While ideas and snippets come to me at any time, and I have mechanisms in place to take notes no matter where I am (primarily with EverNote on my phone), to really get some meat written, I need chunks of no less than a half hour at a time.</p>
<p>And I can schedule them. I can block out that time.</p>
<p>Luckily, today’s block is when no one else is in the house. I’m not expecting anyone and it’s rare that we get random solicitors. The TV is off. There’s no background music. My phone is on silent and plugged in far away where I can’t see it (the school can call my Hubby, too, if there really is that rare emergency with the Kiddo). My email program is off. The internet is . . . well . . . I’m writing this in Google Drive, so I have one browser with one tab open and I’m <em>pretending</em> that the internet is off. What if I need to look something up? I’ll insert a placeholder and come back to it during a time I designate as “research” time.</p>
<p>I even went as far as turning off my second monitor.</p>
<p>Guess what happened? I just checked and in less than ten minutes, I wrote 350 words. Distraction free!</p>
<p>I’m going to have to schedule more time like this to get more bulk words written. I’m not always going to be able to do it when no one is home, but I can do it when the Hubby is known to be in another room watching football.</p>
<p>Scheduling time for our own work is probably one of the most powerful (and FREE!) tools we have in our Arsenal of Awesomeness. I have been doing it at the Day Job for years. Time management professionals and even neuroscientists generally are in agreement that focusing on one thing at a time, not multi-tasking, is the most effective way to get things done. (If you have any interest in the brain, then read or listen to “<a href="https://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/brain-myths-exploded-lessons-from-neuroscience.html#">Brain Myths Exploded: Lessons from Neuroscience</a>.” There’s a whole chapter that debunks the myth of multitasking.)</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/greg-rakozy-76571.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9392 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/greg-rakozy-76571-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>Last week, I was in a conversation with a much younger colleague. We were generally lamenting the ridiculous quantities of work to do and he further complained: “I’m invited to too many meetings and have no time to do my own work!” After gently suggesting that he say “No” to some of the meetings (for some reason, that never goes over well &#8212; a LOT of people still have trouble saying “No”), I told him to do what I do. Block off time for his work on his own calendar. People will see that he’s busy and if they really need him at the meeting, they’ll schedule around it.</p>
<p>Writing is work, too, and it takes time. By raising it to the level of importance where we schedule time on our calendars for it, we are demonstrating that it’s a serious block of our lives. I have always had a lot of things going on in my life at any given time and when people ask how I get it all done my response has always been that we make time for the things that are important to us. (Then I feel terrible that none of my novels in progress are anywhere near completion . . . but that’s another blog for another day . . .)</p>
<p>We do have the ability to compartmentalize our lives somewhat. With some tools at our disposal (a calendar, the ability to turn devices ‘off’), and some good old-fashioned will power, we can wholly devote ourselves to one block at a time. Ensuring that writing is a significant block, with dedicated time, is my plan for 2018.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
