<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tips for Writers &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/tips-for-writers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 02:42:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Three Basic Tips for New Writers</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/three-basic-tips-for-new-writers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sandra Wickham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 17:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips for Writers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It can be exciting to plunge into a writing career, but at the same time,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_2923" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2923" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/13982652008_711081724e.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-2923 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/13982652008_711081724e-300x240.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="240" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2923" class="wp-caption-text">By: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/matiluba/13982652008/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Maria Teresa Ambrosi</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>It can be exciting to plunge into a writing career, but at the same time, it can also be quite daunting. Are you just starting to write, or are thinking about it? Check out these three basic tips to get you started and help you cross the finish line to publication.</p>
<p><strong>1. Commit Yourself</strong><br />
If you want to be a writer, if you want to be published, you need to put in the time. It doesn’t happen magically, despite us wishing it would. Treat it like any other job where you need to put in the hours and learn and improve as you go. As a Professional Fitness Competitor, I had no choice but to train and diet six days a week. There was NO OPTION. Now I treat my writing (ediitng, researching, outlining) the same way. There’s no option, no excuse. You just have to do it.</p>
<p><strong>2. Support Group</strong><br />
Gather supportive people around you, whether you join a writing group, create one yourself, or simply keep close any of those people who will cheer you along. I’ve found my support people by attending workshops, writing retreats, conferences and conventions, which I also highly recommend. Writing is NOT easy. When times are tough, those in your support group can give you the applause, shoulder to cry on or give you the kick in the butt that you need.</p>
<p><strong>3. Submit!</strong><br />
In order to submit something, it has to be your very best work. That means, first, you need to finish it. Yes, finish it! Finish that short story or novel and then revise it until it’s your absolute best work at that time. Then, send it in. Don’t be afraid of rejection letters. They are merely stepping stones (or ladder rungs, whichever you prefer) on your road to publication. Celebrate each rejection because it means you finished something, polished it the best you could and sent it out into the world! That’s worth throwing a rejection letter party.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Filling Your Well</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/filling-your-well/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sandra Wickham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 17:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips for Writers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While wrestling with rewrites for my very first novel (which is now safely tucked away&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While wrestling with rewrites for my very first novel (which is now safely tucked away for no one to see, but was an excellent experience) I felt like giving up. I’d lost all motivation, I didn’t want to work on it anymore, and most of all, I’d lost all faith in myself as a writer.</p>
<p>I emailed my friend and mentor Diana Rowland, author of the Kara Gillian Demon series and White Trash Zombie series. As always, she had excellent advice for me and for anyone else experiencing the same struggle.</p>
<p>She told me to step away from the novel. Speaking in terms I’d understand as a fitness professional, she said, “you have overtrained and torn your write-isimus maximus.” She then forbade me to work on my book for one whole week.</p>
<p>During that time, she told me to fill my well back up. “Read, watch movies, torture your training clients. If you come up with brilliant ideas for your book, you can jot down notes, but that’s it.” It’s about doing things for you, things you enjoy doing, that give you renewed energy, peace and personal fulfillment.</p>
<p>She also let me know that every single writer she knows goes through the “meltdown phase, where the book is such a complete ****ing garbled mess that they’re convinced that there’s no possible way it can ever be salvaged. It can be. Really. But you have to get some distance from it first.”</p>
<p>I took her advice. I detoxed from my novel and attempted to fill my well. I spent a bit of time spoiling myself while I stayed away from working on the novel. I went back to it with renewed energy and finished my rewrites. That novel may never see the light of day, but it was an incredible accomplishment and taught me a lot about myself and my writing.</p>
<p>Filling our wells is important and we really don’t do it enough. Find what works for you, what re-energizes and refreshes you and don’t feel guilty about indulging in those things. In the long run, you writing will be all the better for it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
