<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>T.D. Walker &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/t-d-walker/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 16:49:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Celebrating US National Poetry Month While Sheltering in Place</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/celebrating-us-national-poetry-month-while-sheltering-in-place/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Speculative Poets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[April, in the US, is National Poetry Month, a time when poetry readings sprout up&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>April, in the US, is <a href="https://poets.org/national-poetry-month" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">National Poetry Month</a>, a time when poetry readings sprout up in bookstores, schools, and cafes like seedlings pushing up through soil…. I’ll admit, this isn’t a great metaphor, but like everyone else in <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17922 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/flowers-4765561_1280-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/flowers-4765561_1280-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/flowers-4765561_1280-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/flowers-4765561_1280-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/flowers-4765561_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />the US, I’ve been trying to stay at home as much as possible, which means I’ve turned my attention to turning my backyard into a gathering of sunflowers, marigolds, zinnias, and cosmos. Again, “gathering” doesn’t quite work as a metaphor, but to be honest, I haven’t felt much like writing of late.</p>
<p>Though it’s almost over, I don’t want to let the month of April pass without at least acknowledging the genre it celebrates. But how do we celebrate when we’re all supposed to be staying out of the places where poets tend to read their work? The Academy of American Poets suggests many activities at the link above, and here are a few more:</p>
<ul>
<li>This one is easy: go find an online journal that publishes poetry. Read a selection, and share what you love on social media.</li>
<li>Indie bookstores are suffering, so if you can, buy a book by a speculative poet from an independent bookseller. The site <a href="https://www.indiebound.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IndieBound</a> is a good place to start to find a local store—most places will ship to you. Need ideas for book titles? Most poets put their latest book titles in their bios, so if you found a poem you enjoyed in the previous item, there’s a place to start. Or go to the <a href="http://sfpoetry.com/elgin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Elgin Awards</a> page on the Science Fiction and Fantasy Poetry Association&#8217;s website and look through the past nominees—lots to choose from there.<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17921 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/book-4646735_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/book-4646735_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/book-4646735_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/book-4646735_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/book-4646735_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/book-4646735_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></li>
<li>A good number of poets are posting videos of their poems online. Watch and share.</li>
<li>National Poetry Month isn’t just about reading poetry. Try writing a poem yourself. You might write in the voice of a wronged character in a fairy tale, or consider how inhabitants of another planet might use imagery familiar to them to express love or sorrow or hope.</li>
</ul>
<p>How did you celebrate National Poetry Month? How might we keep celebrating even after the month has passed?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversations with Speculative Poets: F. J. Bergmann</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/conversations-with-speculative-poets-f-j-bergmann/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Speculative Poets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17541</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers of science fiction and fantasy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers </em><em>of</em><em> science fiction</em><em> and fantasy</em><em> poetry</em><em>. For the eleventh post in this series, I spoke with poet F. J. Bergmann about her collection, </em><a href="https://dornsife.usc.edu/goldlinepress/a-catalogue-of-the-further-suns/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="">A Catalogue of the Further Suns</span></a><em> (Gold Line Press 2017).<br />
</em><br />
<em>F. J. Bergmann lives in Madison, Wisconsin (for at least the fifth time), and imagines tragedies on or near exoplanets. She is the poetry editor for </em><a href="http://mobiusmagazine.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mobius: The Journal of Social Change</a><em>, the vice president of the <a href="http://sfpoetry.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Science Fiction &amp; Fantasy Poetry Association</a>, for which she edited </em>Star*Line<em>, its flagship quarterly, for five years, the managing editor of <a href="http://madhat-press.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MadHat Press</a>, and poetry editor for <a href="http://weirdhousepress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Weird House Press</a>. She freelances as a copy editor and book designer.</em><br class="" /><br class="" /><em>Her writing awards include SFPA Rhysling Awards for both long and short poems and SFPA Elgin Awards for two recent chapbooks:</em> Out of the Black Forest<em> (Centennial Press, 2012), a collection of conflated fairy tales, and </em>A Catalogue of the Further Suns<em>, first-contact reports from interstellar expeditions, winner of the 2017 Gold Line Press manuscript competition. She was a 2019 quarter-winner for Writers of the Future. Venues where her poems have appeared include </em>Asimov’s SF, Missouri Review, Polu Texni, Spectral Realms <em>and </em>Vastarien<em>; her speculative fiction has been published in </em>Abyss &amp; Apex, Little Blue Marble<em> (CA), </em>Pulp Literature<em> (CA), </em>Soft Cartel, WriteAhead/The Future Looms<em> (UK), and elsewhere.</em></p>
<p class=""><em><strong>T.D. Walker:</strong> First, a question about the structure of </em>A Catalogue of the Further Suns<em><span class="">: The collection begins with &#8220;Overtures,&#8221; a poem about literal and figurative wounds, which sets up a major theme of the book. We see the explorers unintentionally harming the inhabitants of the planets they visit, such as in &#8220;Cultural Exchange,&#8221; and the inhabitants of the visited planets harming themselves, such as in &#8220;Code of Ethics.&#8221; </span></em></p>
<p class=""><em><span class="">Did you initially envision the collection as a series of poems focused on this theme of harm? Or did the theme emerge as you wrote the poems? And why end the book with the poem &#8220;Duration,&#8221;</span><span class=""> in which the explorers and inhabitants were unable to communicate directly, but the speaker &#8220;wondered if they had a word for </span></em>bliss<em><span class="">&#8220;?</span></em></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17545 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ACatalogue-225x300.jpg" alt="Cover of A Catalogue of the Further Suns" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ACatalogue-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ACatalogue-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ACatalogue.jpg 799w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></p>
<div class=""><strong>F. J. Bergmann:</strong> &#8220;Overtures,&#8221; like many of the other poems in the collection, is about religion. I was brought up without any particular religious instruction, and the ridiculous belief systems that humans are willing to inflict upon themselves has always amazed and horrified me. Of course the destruction of the environment and the climate are also a major subtext.</div>
<div class=""></div>
<div class="">I had originally sequenced the poems from encounters intended as benevolent to the purely observational to those overtly exploitative, but another poet suggested opening with &#8220;Overtures,&#8221; as one of the most shocking/striking poems (as well as the most appropriately titled).</div>
<div class=""></div>
<div class="">&#8220;Duration&#8221; is not only a reference to colonialism, as are a number of the other poems (and perhaps to some extent the focus of the whole concept of voyages of &#8220;discovery&#8221; when it comes to meeting other sentient beings), but also, given how much trouble we have with interacting and communicating with other humans, how vastly more difficult those tasks will be when we do encounter aliens. I&#8217;ve explored the degree to which aliens, when we finally encounter them, are likely to be not only incomprehensible, but unrecognizable, in some poems not included here, notably &#8220;<a href="http://www.polutexni.com/?p=4574" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Envoy</a>&#8220;, which appeared in <em><span class="">Polu Texni</span> </em>and has been nominated for the 2020 Rhysling Award.</div>
<p class=""><em><span class=""><strong>TDW:</strong> The voices in the poems demonstrate curiosity and yet they also seem to distance themselves from their subject, as a reader might expect from the book&#8217;s subtitle: &#8220;Précis of Reports Compiled </span>by the Preliminary Survey Expeditions.&#8221; The objectivity creates a tension with the heartbreaking reality of the missions, some of which ended in the destruction of populations.</em></p>
<p class=""><em>For me, it was difficult not to read your book as both a work of science fiction poetry and as social commentary about the ways in which humans engage with each other, with the environment, and so on. What prompted you to use the voice you chose for these poems&#8211;with its invested objectivity, if I can call it that&#8211;and did that drive the particular details you chose to focus on for each poem? What questions were you aiming to raise in your readers after they engaged with your poems?</em></p>
<div class=""><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17544 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/FJBergmann-200x300.jpg" alt="Author photo of F.J. Bergmann" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/FJBergmann-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/FJBergmann-681x1024.jpg 681w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/FJBergmann-768x1154.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/FJBergmann-1022x1536.jpg 1022w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/FJBergmann-1363x2048.jpg 1363w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/FJBergmann-scaled.jpg 1703w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />FJB: </strong>My natural voice appears to be not only objective and elevated, but generally the first-person plural; however, the &#8220;we&#8221; in these poems is not necessarily the same &#8220;we&#8221;&#8211;and not necessarily humans. The expedition members narrating these interactions range from selfless rescuers to exploiters, from hapless scientists to agenda-driven bureaucrats&#8211;who are mirrored, not necessarily in the same poem, in those they encounter. Of course the &#8220;we&#8221; can also be used as a disclaimer of individual responsibility&#8211;nearly as useful as the passive voice!</div>
<div class=""></div>
<div class="">The questions I hoped to elicit were all the ones we ask ourselves today as we embroil ourselves in the social and physical aspects of this world. Most, if not all, people have an idea of what constitutes &#8220;greater good&#8221; as opposed to merely benefiting themselves in the short term, and most of them like to think that they are, in some way, working toward that goal, but there is a demonstrable difference in how they choose or hope to implement their efforts. Nearly all of these poems, I&#8217;m afraid, show the failure of well-meant efforts on the part of either the expeditions or their contactees, with the possible exception of &#8220;Xenoaesthetics&#8221; and &#8220;The Planet of Ideal Readers,&#8221; which are about encounters via the arts. And perhaps the arts are the vehicle with which the most progress can be made in reaching out to others with differing views.</div>
<p><em><span class=""><strong>TDW:</strong> </span>The poem that resonated with me most in this collection is &#8220;Exobiology II,&#8221; in which the inhabitants of a planet willingly kill themselves (or each other) with &#8220;war machines.&#8221; The speaker notes the survival of &#8220;their most ordinary / objects,&#8221; which are also poignantly human: &#8220;worn-out garden tools, old shoes / blankets, erasers&#8221; along with data about all the inhabitants&#8217; lives.</em></p>
<p class=""><em>Perhaps what was so compelling for me about this poem is that it takes Cold War-Era fears of nuclear annihilation and sets them against the age of social media, an age in which so many of us have, essentially, recordings of our lives spread out through various corporate servers. What, then, brought your speaker to note: &#8220;They left us / no instructions on how to proceed.&#8221;? And are we all complicit in whatever destruction we bring on ourselves in the same sense that the planet&#8217;s inhabitants &#8220;pass[ed] a comprehensive test / before turning on the war machines.&#8221;?</em></p>
<div class=""><strong>FJB: </strong>Certainly the poem stems from the fear of nuclear war, but also asks the question: In the face of extinction, what would you choose to leave as a message for posterity? In this case, of course, it&#8217;s global extinction via suicide, or possibly deliberate mutual fratricide (suicide-by-army as opposed to suicide-by-cop). And to some extent reiterates the final message of <span class=""><em>Citizen Kane</em>:</span> that what is held most dear by another may make absolutely no sense to an unfamiliar observer. I have other poems where doomed civilizations choose to booby-trap what they leave behind for a future discoverer.…</div>
<p class=""><em><strong>TDW:</strong></em><em> Are there speculative poetry collections that explore the same themes as </em>A Catalogue of the Further Suns<em> does that you&#8217;d like to recommend to readers of </em>Luna Station Quarterly<em>?</em></p>
<div class=""><strong>FJB: </strong>The only collection I know of that is purely first-contact is <a href="http://home.earthlink.net/~schwader/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ann K. Schwader</a>&#8216;s fabulous Chthulhu-Mythos sonnet sequence <em><span class="">In the Yaddith Time</span></em> (Mythos Books, 2007), which I unreservedly endorse. For formalist horror-poetry fans, Wade German&#8217;s <em><a href="https://www.hippocampuspress.com/mythos-and-other-authors/poetry/dreams-from-a-black-nebula-by-wade-german" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="">Dreams from a Black Nebula</span></a></em> (Hippocampus Press, 2014) is a rich compilation. I&#8217;m crazy about Wendy Rathbone&#8217;s poetry, in particular <em><a href="http://www.eyescrypublications.com/html/dead_starships.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="">Dead Starships</span></a></em> (Eye Scry Publications, 2016), and I enjoyed <em><a href="http://utampapress.org/product/space-traveler" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Space Traveler</a> </em>by Benjamin S. Grossberg (University of Tampa Press, 2014); not only an astronaut narrative, but also navigating a gay marriage. I&#8217;m certainly influenced by speculative poets of the caliber of Max Ingram, John Rinehart, Laura Madeline Wiseman, and countless others. And for humorous as well as horrific encounters with aliens, David C. Kopaska-Merkel is unsurpassed&#8211;especially in the title poem of his newest collection, <em><a href="https://books.google.com/books/about/The_Ambassador_Takes_One_for_the_Team.html?id=tuXOxgEACAAJ&amp;source=kp_book_description" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Ambassador Takes One for the Team</a></em> (Diminuendo Press, 2019). I should mention that I&#8217;m now the poetry editor for <a href="https://www.weirdhousepress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Weird House Press</a>, which will shortly release Robert Borski&#8217;s <span class=""><em>Carpe Noctem</em>,</span> followed by Ann K. Schwader&#8217;s <em><span class="">Unquiet Stars</span></em> later this year, both of which I adore.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversations with Speculative Poets: Bonnie Jo Stufflebeam</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/conversations-with-speculative-poets-bonnie-jo-stufflebeam/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 11:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Speculative Poets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17166</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers of science fiction and fantasy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers </em><em>of</em><em> science fiction</em><em> and fantasy</em><em> poetry</em><em>. For the tenth post in this series, I spoke with Bonnie Jo Stufflebeam about the <a href="https://bonniejostufflebeam.com/art-words-show/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Art &amp; Words Show</a>, which she curates.</em></p>
<p><em><a href="http://www.bonniejostufflebeam.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bonnie Jo Stufflebeam</a>&#8216;s fiction and poetry has appeared in over 50 publications such as </em>LeVar Burton Reads<em>, </em>Fairy Tale Review<em>, and </em>Year’s Best Dark Fantasy &amp; Horror<em> as well as in six languages. She has been a finalist for the Nebula Award and won the Grand Prize in the SyFy Channel&#8217;s Battle the Beast contest; SyFy made and released an animated short of her short story &#8220;Party Tricks,&#8221; set in the world of </em>The Magicians<em>. She is the curator of the Art &amp; Words Show in Fort Worth, Texas where she lives with four cats: Gamora, Junebug, Don Quixote, and Gimli.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>T.D. Walker: </strong> What prompted your development of the Art &amp; Words show? And what is your process for curating the works and responses? Has that evolved over the years?</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17169 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Reduced-Size-Photo-by-Tony-Najera-200x300.jpg" alt="Photo of author Bonnie Jo Stufflebeam" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Reduced-Size-Photo-by-Tony-Najera-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Reduced-Size-Photo-by-Tony-Najera-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Reduced-Size-Photo-by-Tony-Najera-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Reduced-Size-Photo-by-Tony-Najera-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Reduced-Size-Photo-by-Tony-Najera.jpg 1095w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><strong>Bonnie Jo Stufflebeam:</strong> I was prompted by a need to find a project to complete as a requirement of my MFA at the time, and I wanted to do something that allowed for engagement with the artistic community. My mom owns an art gallery in Fort Worth&#8211;the cooperative, <a href="https://artontheboulevard.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Art on the Boulevard</a>&#8211;and I thought it would be fun to do something that encompassed both art and literature. I&#8217;m glad I did, because it&#8217;s been wonderful working with my mom and also with all the artists and writers I&#8217;ve gotten to know as a result of the show.</p>
<p>To curate, I take open submissions in March. This year, I&#8217;ll be opening submissions from March 1 to the 15. I then go through and read all the work. Sometimes I hire an outside editor to make the final decisions, and sometimes I make them myself, depending on the year. But when I&#8217;m reading, I&#8217;m looking for work that moves me and work that invokes a sense of the strange and otherworldly, and I look for turns of phrase or images that I can&#8217;t get out of my head. When I&#8217;m winnowing it down to the final twenty or so participants, I have to put aside my love of the works, because I&#8217;ve usually fallen for more than I can take, and curate with an eye for balance of people who have participated before versus people who haven&#8217;t, locals versus people from outside Texas, diversity of perspectives, etc. I always want to make a space for LGBTQ writers, writers of color, women. I always want a good mix of genres, too.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s evolved a little over the years, absolutely. For one thing, I no longer accept visual art from outside Texas, as the process of shipping got to be too much. I also keep good track of how many times a writer has participated, because there are some people whose fiction or poetry I just adore, and they&#8217;ve done the show three or four times. I want to give other people a shot to participate.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> At the 2019 Art &amp; Words show, you expressed an interest in including written pieces with speculative elements. What is it about the science fictional, the fantastic, or the horrific that works particularly well for ekphrasis?</em></p>
<p><strong>BJS: </strong>It&#8217;s more about my love for the genre than about it working particularly well for ekphrasis. I love thinking outside present reality, and I love looking at art that explores worlds and concepts that don&#8217;t exist. I do hear from a lot of the visual artists who haven&#8217;t read a lot of speculative fiction; they often say that trying to make art from speculative fiction is challenging to their imaginations and also freeing in a way that they tend to appreciate.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW</strong><strong>: </strong>Which response works have surprised you most over the years? How so?</em></p>
<figure id="attachment_17168" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17168" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17168" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Alex-Sharp-Drowning-in-Nostalgia-300x225.jpg" alt="Alex Sharp's Drowning in Nostalgia" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Alex-Sharp-Drowning-in-Nostalgia-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Alex-Sharp-Drowning-in-Nostalgia-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Alex-Sharp-Drowning-in-Nostalgia-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Alex-Sharp-Drowning-in-Nostalgia-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Alex-Sharp-Drowning-in-Nostalgia-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17168" class="wp-caption-text">Alex Sharp&#8217;s Drowning in Nostalgia</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>BJS: </strong>I&#8217;m most in awe when a visual artist or a writer finds a new depth in their response. Last year, <a href="https://www.logencure.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Logen Cure</a> submitted a beautiful poem called &#8220;Flash Floods&#8221; about a woman in the first stages of new love, and how, in the first stages of love, you don&#8217;t yet understand what a person holds inside herself. The artist, Alex Sharp, did a breathtaking collage, drawing on themes of mental illness and drowning. In the poem, we got one woman&#8217;s perspective, and in the collage, we got the other woman&#8217;s perspective. I love that the show can do that, give two sides of the same poem.</p>
<figure id="attachment_17170" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17170" style="width: 225px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17170" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Stacy-Tompkins-Mourning-Cup-225x300.jpg" alt="Stacy Tompkins--Mourning Cup" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Stacy-Tompkins-Mourning-Cup-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Stacy-Tompkins-Mourning-Cup-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Stacy-Tompkins-Mourning-Cup-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Stacy-Tompkins-Mourning-Cup.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17170" class="wp-caption-text">Stacy Tompkins&#8217; Mourning Cup</figcaption></figure>
<p>There have been several elaborate sculptures or found art works that have appeared in the show that have delighted me to no end. I love when the artist goes all in, as happens every year with Stacy Tompkins&#8217; sculptures.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> </em> <em>Are there speculative poetry collections that engage in the same kinds of response to visual art that writers do in the show that you’d like to recommend to readers of</em> Luna Station Quarterly<em>?</em></p>
<p><strong>BJS: </strong>Bruce Bond and Aron Wiesenfeld&#8217;s <i><a href="https://etruscanpress.org/shop/the-other-sky/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Other Sky</a> </i>is a beautiful book of subtle horror that combines poetry and art.</p>
<p>Del Samatar and Sofia Samatar put together <a href="https://rosemetalpress.com/books/monster-portraits/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i>Monster Portraits</i></a>, a book that tackles themes of otherness through fiction, autobiography, and monster art. It&#8217;s a brilliant genre hybrid.</p>
<p>Laura Madeline Wiseman and Lauren Rinaldi, both previous Art &amp; Words participants, put out a book of short stories and art, <a href="http://lauramadelinewiseman.com/portfolio-view/the-hunger-of-the-cheeky-sisters-ten-tales/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i>The Hunger of the Cheeky Sisters</i></a>, about coming-of-age, filled with a dream-like logic.</p>
<p>And I&#8217;d be remiss if I didn&#8217;t mention Michael Cunningham and Yuko Shimizu&#8217;s <a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250097309" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>A Wild Swan</em></a>, an illustrated fairy tale collection that is one of my favorite books of all time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversations with Speculative Poets: Wendy Van Camp</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/conversations-with-speculative-poets-wendy-van-camp/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Speculative Poets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17047</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers of science fiction and fantasy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers </em><em>of</em><em> science fiction</em><em> and fantasy</em><em> poetry</em><em>. For the ninth post in this series, I spoke with poet Wendy Van Camp about her 2019 collection, </em>The Planets<em>.</em></p>
<p><em>Wendy Van Camp writes science fiction, regency romance, and poetry. Her writing blog &#8220;No Wasted Ink&#8221; features essays about the craft of writing, poetry, flash fiction, and author interviews. Wendy’s short stories and poems have appeared in science fiction magazines such as “Quantum Visions”, “Altered Reality Magazine”, “Scifaikuest”, and “Far Horizons”. Her first poetry book is &#8220;The Planets: a scifaiku poetry collection&#8221; and her Regency Historical is &#8220;The Curate&#8217;s Brother&#8221;, both can be found on all major online book outlets as either an ebook or a paperback. Find her at <a href="http://nowastedink.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://nowastedink.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1579054795878000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH9XMVkfi0_FpMcgOzrN7S8Hc51Mg">http://nowastedink.com/</a>.</em></p>
<p><em><b>T.D. Walker:</b> In your collection, </em>The Planets<em>, you explore the major bodies in our solar system using the scifaiku form, and you include a discussion of the form in your introduction. What was it about planets in particular that you wanted to explore in short form poetry? Did your writing process involve researching each planet as you wrote the poems?</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17049 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/The-planets-blog-200x300.jpg" alt="Cover Image of Wendy Van Camp's poetry collection The Planets" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/The-planets-blog-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/The-planets-blog.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><strong>Wendy Van Camp: </strong>I included a description of what scifaiku is because the poetry form is not well known. While it follows similar rules to traditional haiku poetry, there is leniency in the structure to allow for science fiction or scientific concepts. The concept for &#8220;The Planets&#8221; started as a struggle to find subjects to write about. Originally, I wanted to write the poems and draw simple line illustrations to highlight them. This was in order to have a short subject to post on my blog, &#8220;No Wasted Ink.&#8221; Since I have always had a fascination with the planets and follow their ongoing discoveries via NASA, writing about the planets was a natural subject for me.</p>
<p>I always intended to put together a poetry collection of my planetary poems, but at the rate I was going, I would not have finished for another ten years. In the summer of 2019, I decided to put my poetry as a priority and spent my summer months at the local coffeehouse with my notebook and fountain pen. I composed the majority of &#8220;The Planets&#8221; at this time, although around 10% of the poems in the book have been previously published in various magazines. I also illustrated the book with line drawings of each planet for the chapter heads. I used articles from NASA and other science journals to gain details about each of the planets. I wrote not only about their physical properties but some of the historical events that each planet caused among humans. Scattered in are also science fiction tropes or wry questions I have about our exploration of the solar system.</p>
<p><em><b>TDW:  </b>A number of poems give voice and emotion to the planets and other objects in the book, such as the first poem, &#8220;Layers,&#8221; in which Mercury observes, &#8220;I am the most dense.&#8221; Later Venus speaks of &#8220;my gently rolling plains&#8221; in &#8220;Volcanic Venus,&#8221; the &#8220;Rover&#8221; in the Mars section has &#8220;lonely wheels,&#8221; the eponymous character speaks of &#8220;my surface&#8221; in &#8220;Europa,&#8221; &#8220;Neptune&#8217;s Moons&#8221; notes &#8220;we circle Neptune,&#8221; and in &#8220;Pluto&#8217;s Five,&#8221; the moons tell us &#8220;we dance together.&#8221; Why use anthropomorphism in these poems? How did you want your readers to relate to the planets, moons, and spacecraft, given their distance from Earth?</em></p>
<figure id="attachment_17050" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17050" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-17050 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Wendy-Van-Camp-Poet-Headshot-2019-200x300.jpg" alt="Image of author Wendy Van Camp" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Wendy-Van-Camp-Poet-Headshot-2019-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Wendy-Van-Camp-Poet-Headshot-2019.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17050" class="wp-caption-text">Wendy Van Camp</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>WVC: </strong>Anthropomorphism is common enough in poetry. I use it in order to give resonance to the time and places in the poem.  Touching on our feelings and allowing the reader to be emotionally present in the poem is key to making it more memorable. Several of the poems have humor too. Creating laughter combined with emotion makes these objects more understandable to us as humans. I wanted the readers to learn more about the solar system as they read the poems, but in a way that might make them smile. One day, these distant places may become future homes to humanity. Poetry allows us to visit and wonder as our machine scouts continue to explore.</p>
<p><b><em>TDW: </em></b><em>There has been much debate about whether Pluto meets the criteria for classification as a planet. Do you side with one position or another in this argument? And why include a Pluto section in the book given the controversy?</em></p>
<p><strong>WVC:</strong> Considering that I created a section of Pluto-related poems, you can conclude that I consider it to be a planet. I&#8217;m of an age where we were taught that there were nine planets in our solar system and that is how I tend to view the heavens even though I know that Eris is almost as large as Pluto and that Charon could be considered a planet in its own right. There has been much debate over what is a &#8220;planet&#8221; or not. In my mind, Pluto meets those criteria and there are those in the astronomical community who agree with this idea.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> Are there collections that share the same themes as </em>The Planets<em> that you&#8217;d like to recommend to readers of </em>Luna Station Quarterly<em>?</em></p>
<p><strong>WVC:</strong> There are not a great many scifaiku poets on the planet so you need to look for us. My recommendation to readers of <em>LSQ</em> is to read magazines connected with the <a href="http://sfpoetry.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Science Fiction and Fantasy Poetry Association</a> (SFPA). Most scifaiku and astropoets can be found as members of the SFPA. The publications are <a href="http://eyetothetelescope.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Eye to the Telescope</em></a>, <a href="http://sfpoetry.com/starline.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Star*Line</em></a>, and <a href="https://albanlakepublishing.com/scifaikuest-online/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Scifaikuest</em></a>. I have recently read a collection of scifaiku that is based on the elements of the periodic table by <a href="http://www.marysoonlee.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mary Soon Lee</a>. It is called <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/605873/elemental-haiku-by-mary-soon-lee/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Elemental Haiku</em></a>.  I met Mary at World Fantasy Con in 2019 and we were both tickled to discover a fellow scifaiku author. I thought her reading and her book were excellent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversations with Speculative Poets: Shannon Connor Winward</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/conversations-with-speculative-poets-shannon-connor-winward/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Speculative Poets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16892</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers of science fiction and fantasy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers </em><em>of</em><em> science fiction</em><em> and fantasy</em><em> poetry</em><em>. For the eighth post in this series, I spoke with poet Shannon Connor Winward about her collection </em><a href="http://www.sycoraxpress.com/books/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>THE YEAR OF THE WITCH</em></a><em> (Sycorax Press 2018).</em></p>
<p><em>Shannon Connor Winward is an American editor and writer. She is the author of the <a href="http://sfpoetry.com/el/16elgin.html">Elgin-Award</a> winning chapbook </em><a href="http://www.shannonconnorwinward.com/?page_id=1147">UNDOING WINTER</a><em> and </em>THE YEAR OF THE WITCH<em>, a full-length collection of poetry published by <a href="http://www.sycoraxpress.com/">Sycorax Press</a> (Summer 2018). Her fiction has earned recognition in the <span id="yiv8966037294yui_3_16_0_1_1422617750119_6697" class="yiv8966037294">Writers of the Future Contest, the Odyssey Con Odd Contest, Postcard Poems &amp; Prose Flash Fiction Contest, and the Delaware Division of the Arts, for which she was awarded an emerging artist fellowship in fiction in 2018. Her stories and prose have</span> appeared in </em>Fantasy &amp; Science Fiction, Pseudopod’s Artemis Rising Series, Lunch Ticket, Shoreline of Infinity, The Wild Musette, Persistent Visions, Cast of Wonders, Gargoyle, Spinetingler Magazine, Flash Fiction Online, Plasma Frequency Magazine,The Vestal Review,<em> and </em>PANK <em>(among others), as well as in genre anthologies on both sides of the Atlantic (including </em>Heiresses of Russ: The Year’s Best Lesbian Speculative Fiction <em>2015).</em></p>
<p><em><strong>T.D. Walker: </strong></em><em>You begin </em>The Year of the Witch <em>with an introduction to the concepts of cyclical and linear years and an instructional guide for the reader, a &#8220;how to.&#8221; And yet, in giving the reader context for the poems, you also recognize the individual place where a reader enters your work: &#8220;Your measure of the Year is as needful, and needless, as mine,&#8221; and &#8220;There&#8217;s a story here, though it doesn&#8217;t matter, really, where it starts and where it ends.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>This led me to wonder how this cyclical nature of the year affected your process of crafting the poems in the book. Did you view writing the poems as a collection in this same way? And how do you view the necessary linearity of the individual poems&#8211;the flow of the poem from line to line, from beginning to end&#8211;in light of the overarching theme of returning?</em></p>
<p><strong>Shannon Connor Winward: </strong><i>The Year of the Witch</i> wasn&#8217;t written cover to cover. The poems were chosen from a body of work that spans almost two decades. Although my focus and voice has shifted over the years, I&#8217;ve long been interested in many of the same themes. Once I had decided on the structure of the book, that I wanted it to follow the wheel of the pagan year, with four main quarters—one for each season— it was just a matter of selecting poems that fit each seasonal axis.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16895 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Year-of-the-Witch-official-Cover-200x300.jpg" alt="Cover of The Year of the Witch" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Year-of-the-Witch-official-Cover-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/Year-of-the-Witch-official-Cover.jpg 333w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<div>Is a poem&#8217;s nature necessarily linear? A poem is much like a story—some dance closer to narrative than others, but usually they contain story elements, even if only the impression, the ghost of one. And stories are cyclical; we tell ourselves the same stories over and over and over yet again. They must often follow a script or pattern—certain things have to happen in order, the first line has to come before the ending, flowers have to bloom before they die, because otherwise the cadence sounds off. On the other hand, it is possible to tell a good story no matter where it begins or ends. It just depends on the dance between the storyteller and their listener or reader, and how much we are willing to let go of.</div>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> Your collection centers on the supernatural: astrology, tarot, gods and goddesses. Yet woven in the poems is a thread of referencing the scientific. For instance, &#8220;Ostara / Spring&#8221; acknowledged the spring equinox as &#8220;an astronomical event,&#8221; the epigraph of &#8220;Midsummer&#8221; notes the distance between Earth and Mars, and &#8220;Paradox of Return&#8221; begins with the lines &#8220;The tilt of the earth / is 23 1/2 degrees.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>How do you see scientific fact as engaging with the rituals and the sense of the unseen in your poems?</em></p>
<p><strong>SCW: </strong>Science was not anathema to pre-Christian cultures. A lot of the mythic and ritual traditions that inspire me come from early pagan groups who pioneered our observation of the natural world. Astronomy, in particular, was important to ancient peoples; it informed their economic and social systems as much as it did their religions. For me, as for folks throughout the ages, the marriage of observable, natural fact with a spiritual narrative makes for fabulous poetry. It helps us to understand our place as spiritual beings in a physical world.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW: </strong>Of the poems in the collection, the one I found most engaging is &#8220;Return.&#8221; The images of nature&#8211;the hyacinths&#8211;interplay with the mundane images of office work&#8211;the coffee cup and spreadsheets. Later, we follow the speaker back to her childhood home, then back to her childhood, which makes a frame given the reference to her son at the beginning of the poem.</em></p>
<p><em>In a book grounded in nature and mythology, the specific reference to hyacinths stands out. What sparked this poem for you? And what was it about the brief but brilliantly alive flowers of the hyacinth that drew you to them?</em></p>
<p><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16896 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/SCW19-200x300.jpg" alt="Poet Shannon Connor Winward" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/SCW19-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/SCW19-681x1024.jpg 681w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/SCW19-768x1154.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/SCW19.jpg 948w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />SCW: </strong>All of the poems in <i>The Year of the Witch</i> were chosen for their relationship to the seasons, either through direct imagery or else thematic kinships of a personal or poetic nature. &#8220;Return&#8221; is not only one of the first poems in the first quarter of the book (in the &#8220;Spring&#8221; quarter), it was also one of the first selections that I made for the book overall. To me it was a natural choice because of its references to hyacinths, the pungent annuals that herald spring, and because of the stream of spring-related associations that flower evokes for me (e.g., Easter, patent leather shoes, perfume on my mother&#8217;s wrist) that also &#8220;return&#8221; in the poem. They say smell is one of the most powerful ways to incite memory. One whiff of a hyacinth can transport me to the springtime of my own childhood. What scent can spark a sense-memory for you?</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> Are there collections that share the same themes as </em>The Year of the Witch<em> that you&#8217;d like to recommend to readers of </em>Luna Station Quarterly<em>?</em></p>
<p>There are many fantastic speculative poets out there who are exploring mythic narratives, nature love, and other themes similar to those in <i>The Year of the Witch</i>. As a whole, however, I&#8217;m not aware of a poetry collection that&#8217;s quite like this one, because it was intended as an homage not to other poetry but to a specific genre of non-fiction.</p>
<p>As a young person seeking new spiritual options in the early 90s, I cut my teeth on Neo-Pagan how-to books that sought to modernize ancient traditions for the new millennium&#8211;I read a lot of the kind of books that were shelved next to the crystals and tarot cards in the back corners of big box bookstores: glossy covers and user-friendly text focused on light and love, with varying degrees of actual scholarship to underscore their claims, but brimming with the new age-y spiritual romance that so many of us needed at the time.</p>
<p>A lot of the texts I enjoyed as a teen are still available through Amazon under searches like &#8220;wheel of the year&#8221;, so readers who enjoyed what I&#8217;ve done with <i>The Year of the Witch</i> and want to get more of that kind of content could start there. Another perennial favorite of mine is the <i>Llewellyn&#8217;s Witches&#8217; Calendar</i> series, which still comes out every year. Along with the calendar blocks they publish earnest lyrical essays reflecting on witchcraft and earth-based spirituality as well as the magical associations, astrological data, and overall seasonal celebration that I remember from those early books&#8211;all the things that I tried to invoke, poetically, with <i>The Year of the Witch</i>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversations with Speculative Poets: Deborah L. Davitt</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/conversations-with-speculative-poets-deborah-l-davitt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Speculative Poets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16546</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers of science fiction and fantasy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers </em><em>of</em><em> science fiction</em><em> and fantasy</em><em> poetry</em><em>. For the seventh post in this series, I spoke with poet <a href="http://www.edda-earth.com/">Deborah L. Davitt</a> about her book, </em><a href="https://www.finishinglinepress.com/product/the-gates-of-never-by-deborah-l-davitt/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Gates of Never</a><em> (Finishing Line Press 2019).  </em></p>
<p><em>Deborah L. Davitt was raised in Nevada, but currently lives in Houston, Texas, with her husband and son. Her poetry has received Rhysling, Dwarf Star, and Pushcart nominations; her short fiction has appeared in </em>Galaxy’s Edge, Intergalactic Medicine Show,<em> and </em>Pseudopod<em>. For more about her work, including her Edda-Earth novels and her poetry collection, </em>The Gates of Never<em>, please see <a href="http://www.edda-earth.com/">www.edda-earth.com</a>. You may contact her on Facebook at <a href="http://www.facebook.com/deborah.davitt.3">www.facebook.com/deborah.davitt.3</a> or Twitter @davittDL.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>T.D. Walker: </strong></em>The Gates of Never <em>is a collection that returns to desire again and again. We see the physical desire of lovers, as in &#8220;Blossom&#8221; and &#8220;The Gargoyle.&#8221; There&#8217;s a desire to live and create life as in &#8220;The Pyre&#8221; and &#8220;Creators.&#8221; And we even see celestial desire in &#8220;Enceladus.&#8221;</em><br />
<em>Was this a theme you saw in the poems early on in crafting the poems for the book? And since these poems connect your 21st century audience with mythic and ancient figures, did you view desire as a connection point between poem and reader?</em></p>
<div>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16547 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Davitt_Deborah_COV_EM-194x300.jpg" alt="Cover of The Gates of Never by Deborah L. Davitt" width="194" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Davitt_Deborah_COV_EM-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Davitt_Deborah_COV_EM-768x1187.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Davitt_Deborah_COV_EM-663x1024.jpg 663w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Davitt_Deborah_COV_EM.jpg 1650w" sizes="(max-width: 194px) 100vw, 194px" /><strong>Deborah L. Davitt:</strong> I assembled the book out of things I&#8217;d written separately, over the course of about two years&#8217; real time. One of my long-term interests is Eriksen&#8217;s Crises&#8211;a theory of human development within each of our lifetimes. At each stage, we&#8217;re faced with a crisis point, and failing to negotiate those crisis points in a positive fashion can lead to a sort of stunted existence. Folks can look up all the stages for themselves, but I do a lot of work in &#8220;intimacy vs. isolation&#8221; and &#8220;generativity vs. stagnation&#8221; so to say that the poems tend to talk about desire . . . yeah, they do. Quite a lot of them reflect the yearning for intimacy, the fear of isolation, yet also the fear of/desire to be subsumed or consumed by the object of that desire. The balancing point each individual has to strike between being part of a &#8220;we&#8221; yet also remaining an &#8220;I.&#8221;</p>
<p>As to the mythic stuff&#8211;mythology and history are ongoing pre-occupations of mine. But so are science and futurism. For me, time is all of one piece, and the more we understand the past, the more capable we are of shaping and understanding the present and the future. So &#8220;desire&#8221; wasn&#8217;t picked out as a way of understanding the past. It&#8217;s more like I . . . see commonalities between past and future, and try to illuminate them, partially to educate a modern audience, and partially in an effort to strike passion in that audience <i>for</i> that past (or that future).</p>
<p>Which is a long way of saying &#8220;no, but also yes.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> Each section of the book has as its title the name of a gate: &#8220;The Gate of Sandstone,&#8221; &#8220;The Gate of Marble,&#8221; &#8220;The Gate of Wood,&#8221; &#8220;The Gate of Steel,&#8221; and &#8220;The Gate of Stars.&#8221; What drew you to structuring the book as such? And does the idea of the gate as a passageway play a role in the way you&#8217;d like readers to progress through the book?</em></p>
<p><strong>DLD:</strong> I started with the concept out of Greek mythology that there are two gates through which dreams issue, the gate of horn and the gate of ivory. And it&#8217;s always struck me as surprising that the dreams that were true or prophetic came through the gate of horn, whereas the fanciful, fluff dreams came through the gate of ivory. (It turns out to have nothing to do with the value of the materials; it has to do with the word for &#8216;horn&#8217; being close in sound to the Greek word for &#8220;fulfill,&#8217; and the Greeks enjoyed a good pun.)</p>
<p>Once I established that dichotomy, I looked at the other poems I had available, and started sorting them. The Gate of Wood, for instance, is the category for poems that are closer to folktales and fairy tales. The ones that take us into the woods, where grandmothers might have betrayed their grandchildren to a wolf-spirit for a shot at immortality, or show us how fairy tales and magic die as industrialization leaves marks as black as coal on the white snow, and the queen no longer has a spindle to prick her fingers on, etc. The Gate of Steel is more about magic in modern contexts. Gate of the Stars is pure science and science fiction poetry&#8211;though I do like to lace in the mythological references there, too.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s inescapable in my stuff, because time is all one big piece, and literally everything connects.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> The poem I enjoyed most in the collection is &#8220;Once Human,&#8221; in which the two central figures from the present are reclaimed by gods from a distant past. She turns into a mermaid while he turns into a centaur. Both fail to adapt to the requirements of the lives they once led. Can we read this as a metaphor for what old stories can do for (and to) new readers?</em></p>
<p><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16548 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ddavitt-p17-small-1-240x300.jpg" alt="Image of poet Deborah L. Davitt" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ddavitt-p17-small-1-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ddavitt-p17-small-1-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ddavitt-p17-small-1-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/ddavitt-p17-small-1.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />DLD:</strong> I&#8217;m so glad you like that one! It&#8217;s one of the pieces that&#8217;s got a wry, sly sense of humor to it. It hearkens back to some of my Edda-Earth novels (alternate history, Rome never fell, all the gods are real, and whoops, at one point, humans start getting transformed into creatures out of mythology due to the deaths of several gods and the unleashed power that warps the world). I took that same concept, but applied it to <i>our</i> world, and what would happen to a modern relationship if yes, suddenly, and without anyone&#8217;s consent, two people were warped and changed physically in such a way that their lives together couldn&#8217;t continue in the same fashion.</p>
<p>If you want to read it as a metaphor, I can&#8217;t stop you! That&#8217;s the joy of poetry once it gets out in the wild, into other people&#8217;s minds. They find things in there that the author didn&#8217;t intend, because of their own experiences and connections. I&#8217;m definitely not in the &#8220;The Author is Dead&#8221; camp, but there&#8217;s an interesting place between Authorial Intention and Audience Interpretation that can be fruitful, lovely, and amazing.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> Are there collections that share the same themes as </em>The Gates of Never<em> that you&#8217;d like to recommend to readers of</em> Luna Station Quarterly<em>?</em></p>
<p><strong>DLD:</strong> I&#8217;m really not aware of anyone writing exactly what I&#8217;m writing. The field of speculative poetry is <i>huge</i>, so you&#8217;ve got people like <a href="http://www.hlwalrath.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Holly Lyn Walrath</a> writing feminist modern stuff with a speculative edge in <a href="https://www.finishinglinepress.com/product/glimmerglass-girl-by-holly-lyn-walrath/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i>Glimmerglass Girl</i></a>, and <a href="http://www.michellemuenzler.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Michelle Muenzler</a> writing horror-tinged poems that verge on the edible in her work, and <a href="https://sabarazvi.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Saba Razvi</a> exploring ancient manuscripts and Islamic meditations and magic and mythology in <i>her</i> works<i>, </i>so . . . look them up, get hold of their bibliographies, and try an assortment of what they&#8217;ve written for online venues. Then maybe go buy their books.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thirty Days, Thirty Reviews: Or What I&#8217;ve Learned from Interviewing Poets and Using that to Write Short Reviews in November</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/thirty-days-thirty-reviews-or-what-ive-learned-from-interviewing-poets-and-using-that-to-write-short-reviews-in-november/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Speculative Poets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If I know one thing about book reviews, it&#8217;s their importance to readers, writers, editors,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-16440 size-medium alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/kat-stokes-BoYnwJ8lM54-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/kat-stokes-BoYnwJ8lM54-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/kat-stokes-BoYnwJ8lM54-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/kat-stokes-BoYnwJ8lM54-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />If I know one thing about book reviews, it&#8217;s their importance to readers, writers, editors, publishers, book sellers, librarians, and, well, basically anyone who has any interest in finding good reads and avoiding those that don&#8217;t fit their interests. And I know that writing reviews is one of those things that authors should do to support both writers whose work they appreciate and readers whose experiences with those books they respect. Knowing all this, I&#8217;ve had that little voice that keeps telling me &#8220;You should write book reviews, you know&#8221; for years.</p>
<p>And yet, I haven&#8217;t. You see, the thought of writing reviews makes me rather anxious.</p>
<p>&#8220;Why?&#8221; I keep asking myself. As a former college writing instructor, I&#8217;ve taught students how to write reviews: pick your book, pick your criteria of what makes a good book in that genre, and then write about whether or not the book meets those criteria. And I&#8217;ve read a fair number of book reviews. In spite of knowing in the abstract how to construct a useful review and having solid models, I still couldn&#8217;t bring myself to write reviews.</p>
<p>Maybe it&#8217;s because of my grad school theory training. My previous attempts at reviews inevitably resulted in theory-laden messes. They were neither solid academic work nor useful reviews.</p>
<p>Maybe it&#8217;s because of my evolving sense of what I like to read. Coming out of an academic program, I didn&#8217;t have much experience with speculative literature and none at all with speculative poetry, if you don&#8217;t count <i>Beowulf</i> or medieval romances or Yeats&#8217; use of Irish folk tales in his poems. When I started reading science fiction again after grad school, I could easily shift between literary fiction and speculative fiction as a reader, but it took me reading more SF to formulate what I like about the different genres. And you do have to know what readers expect from a genre in order to write a useful review.</p>
<p>Or maybe it&#8217;s my fear of stars. One of the things that contributed to my burn out as a teacher was the need to assign grades. Grading is, after all, another form of evaluating work against a set of criteria, just like a review. And I enjoyed writing comments on student work, because I knew those comments were going to help them improve their writing, not the grades I assigned to their essays. (I know that reviews are not for writers, but still, I think the parallel is still relevant here.) Reviews on book seller sites or sites like Library Thing or GoodReads require star ratings. But how do you decide what&#8217;s a three-star or four-star or five-star book?</p>
<p>Which leaves me here, at the end of October, looking at what I&#8217;d like to do with November, which <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16441 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/nick-morrison-FHnnjk1Yj7Y-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/nick-morrison-FHnnjk1Yj7Y-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/nick-morrison-FHnnjk1Yj7Y-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/nick-morrison-FHnnjk1Yj7Y-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />for a lot of writers, means preparation for NaNoWriMo. As much as I appreciate what NaNo provides for novelists, I just can&#8217;t write at that pace, and the timing doesn&#8217;t work for me right now, as I&#8217;m trying to finish up a second poetry manuscript. What I am taking away from NaNo is the sense of community it fosters. And given that writing reviews works toward fostering community, I&#8217;ve decided to use November to that end. Over the course of the month, I&#8217;m writing reviews of thirty books I appreciate. These will be mostly reviews of speculative poetry collections, but there will be one book of essays, an academic work about women in early 20th century science fiction publishing, a memoir writing manual, and a manual to prepare for the US amateur radio license exam. (That last one? Research for a novel. Also five stars. I passed easily on the first try.)</p>
<p>These reviews will be around 100 words each, and I&#8217;ll post them to Library Thing, GoodReads, Amazon, and on my Instagram account (<a href="https://www.instagram.com/tdwalker_/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@tdwalker_</a>) with the tag #thirtydaysthirtyreviews. To be honest, I&#8217;ve written some of them already in preparation for November, and many of them will come out of notes I wrote to prepare for interviews I&#8217;ve conducted with poets.</p>
<p>Which brings us back to community building. I started interviewing poets as a way to promote the work of poets I admire. And, given my trepidation about review writing, I approached the poets directly and wrote interview questions instead. Those Q&amp;As have led to a number of wonderful things, chief among them is getting to chat with writers, of course. Pretty high up there too is that in writing questions for those interviews, I trained myself to get away from theory and think about books in terms of what a reader might be wondering about after reading them. Which means, I think, that I&#8217;m in a better, or at least more confident, place to write reviews.</p>
<p>Even if, of course, I&#8217;m still anxious about all those stars . . .</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversations with Speculative Poets: Christina Sng</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/conversations-with-speculative-poets-christina-sng/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Speculative Poets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers of science fiction and fantasy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers </em><em>of</em><em> science fiction</em><em> and fantasy</em><em> poetry</em><em>. For the sixth post in this series, I spoke with poet <a href="http://christinasng.com/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Christina Sng</a> about her book, </em><a href="http://store.albanlake.com/product/astropoetry/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Astropoetry</a><em> (Alban Lake Press, 2017)</em><em>, which placed second in the chapbook category of the 2018 Science Fiction &amp; Fantasy Poetry Association’s <a href="https://www.sfpoetry.com/el/18elgin.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Elgin Awards</a>.<br />
</em></p>
<p><em>Christina Sng is the Bram Stoker Award-winning author of A COLLECTION OF NIGHTMARES. Her poetry has appeared in numerous venues worldwide and received multiple nominations in the Rhysling Awards, the Dwarf Stars, the Elgin Awards, and honorable mentions in the Year’s Best Fantasy and Horror and the Best Horror of the Year. Her next book of poems A COLLECTION OF DREAMSCAPES is slated for 2020.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>T.D. Walker: </strong>Space is vast, but your poems are brief and compact. What drove your choice of short forms in writing about asteroids, moons, planets, stars, and even galaxies and human exploration of them? How did the traditions of the short forms you used speak to the way you approached your subjects?</em></p>
<p><strong>Christina Sng:</strong> Since I was a child, I’ve always wanted to be an astronaut, to go out there and see the universe. The vastness of space and all its magnificent objects gives us an infinite source of inspiration to write about.</p>
<p>Writing in short forms is an act of necessity rather than choice. Busy days of caregiving don’t afford me hours of immersive writing but instead offer shards of time where I carve out a tiny story in three or five lines, reminding me of the pulsed glimpses we see of celestial objects through our telescopes.</p>
<p>I’ve grown to love the brevity of short forms, how it reflects the little time we have on this world, how they’re like small puzzles we need to fit together like the mysteries of space, how each word means so much, and how we weigh one word over another to sculpt a poem to its final form.</p>
<p><em><strong>TW:</strong> The poems in your collection both give celestial objects the weight of their own stories, their own volition, and yet they also acknowledge that the observer must be a part of those stories. We see “The Sun is furious” (“ENCAPSULATED”) and “You collect dust like dolls” (“MERCURY”). And yet, later, in “THE TWIN LIGHTS ON CERES,” for example, the lights on the asteroid are “my eyes/ Looking back at yours.” As the collection progresses, humans begin to dominate the stars, planets, asteroids, and so forth, which become less anthropomorphized. Do you see the stories we tell about space as progressing as such? And do you see the stories we tell about space as part of the human exploration or domination of what is beyond Earth?</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16202 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/astropoetry.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="618" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/astropoetry.jpg 400w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/astropoetry-194x300.jpg 194w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" /><strong>CS: </strong>I see the journey through my collection as an expansion of our experience in the universe where it becomes less and less about us and more about how minute we are in the whole scheme of things, and most significantly, how amazing it is that we are around to observe it.</p>
<p>I’d like to think that our stories reflect the awe and wonder of how we feel when we look up into space yet at the same time also reflect our nature to conquer and destroy.</p>
<p><em><strong>TW:</strong> The poems at the end of the collection speak to a sort of absorption of its human explorers by the universe. I was particularly moved by “REMNANTS,” in which the speaker of the poem acknowledges that what will become of people is “Memory remnants/ Fragments of us.” Do you see the stories that we tell about space as consuming us in the same way? That we become part of the poetry we create about what we cannot (yet) reach?</em></p>
<p><strong>CS: </strong>Yes, I believe they do. Each story we tell is a fragment of our lives, our hopes, and our dreams. They become a remnant of us, immortalized in the things we create that endure after we are gone and in the memories of the people who remember us.</p>
<p><em><strong>TW:</strong> Are there any speculative poetry titles you’d like to recommend to the readers of</em> Luna Station Quarterly?<em> Or, more specifically, collections that work toward “celebrating the wonders and mysteries of space” as your poems do?</em></p>
<p><strong>CS: </strong>Perhaps not a title but two science fiction journals, <a href="https://www.sfpoetry.com/starline.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Star*Line</em></a> and <a href="https://www.albanlakepublishing.com/scifaikuest-online" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Scifaikuest</em></a>, curate some of the best space poems I’ve read.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversations with Speculative Poets: Holly Lyn Walrath</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/conversations-with-speculative-poets-holly-lyn-walrath/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Speculative Poets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers of science fiction and fantasy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers of science fiction and fantasy poetry. For the fifth post in the series, I spoke with poet Holly Lyn Walrath about her 2018 chapbook </em><a href="https://www.finishinglinepress.com/product/glimmerglass-girl-by-holly-lyn-walrath/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Glimmerglass Girl</a>, <em>published by Finishing Line Press.</em></p>
<p><em>Holly Lyn Walrath’s poetry and short fiction has appeared in </em>Strange Horizons, Fireside Fiction, Luna Station Quarterly, Liminality,<em> and elsewhere. Her chapbook of words and images, Glimmerglass Girl, will be published by Finishing Line Press in 2019. She holds a B.A. in English from The University of Texas and a Master’s in Creative Writing from the University of Denver. She is a freelance editor and host of </em>The Weird Circular<em>, an e-newsletter for writers containing submission calls and writing prompts. Find her on Twitter @<a href="https://twitter.com/HollyLynWalrath" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">HollyLynWalrath</a> or at <a href="http://www.hlwalrath.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.hlwalrath.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1533174749692000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGSQD2npWtbvaMj3zHOPhgdm3CdBw">www.hlwalrath.com</a>.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>T.D. Walker:</strong> In the introduction to </em>Glimmerglass Girl<em>, you note that the collection &#8220;is a fantastical account of womanhood [&#8230;.</em><em>] that draws upon my personal experience.&#8221; Readers encounter in the poems the mundane details of a present-day life, which are punctuated by references to other-worldly places and beings, such as in &#8220;Espejitos,&#8221; &#8220;Self-Portrait through an iPhone,&#8221; &#8220;I am Going to Find the Unicorn,&#8221; and others. Do you see womanhood as a sort of balancing the otherness of the fantastic with the ordinary of the mundane world?</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15810 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Front-Cover-Only_adjusted-194x300.jpg" alt="cover of Glimmerglass Girl by Holly Lyn Walrath" width="194" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Front-Cover-Only_adjusted-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Front-Cover-Only_adjusted-768x1187.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Front-Cover-Only_adjusted-663x1024.jpg 663w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Front-Cover-Only_adjusted.jpg 1650w" sizes="(max-width: 194px) 100vw, 194px" /></p>
<p><strong>Holly Lyn Walrath: </strong>I’m very interested in the speculative writing of contemporary women authors, which in my opinion re-evaluates how women approach our bodies. Historically, the woman-as-fantastic tradition in fairy tales and fiction has been written by men. We’ve only just begun to challenge the so-called ideals of what it means to be a woman. The fantastic is one way to do this—to embrace the othering of women’s bodies and make it our own language.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW: </strong>Many of the poems in this collection have references to or are evocative of Texas, such as &#8220;I Want to be a Grackle, I Want to Caw,&#8221; &#8220;Blue Cadillac,&#8221; and &#8220;Premise of the Heart.&#8221; How does this sense of place affect your creative process? And since Texas can be a complicated place for women, given its politics and culture, how do you see place as a part of your aim to depict womanhood?</em></p>
<p><strong>HLW: </strong>I was born in Texas and have lived here for most of my life. The beauty of Texas and its conglomeration of cultures are definitely a part of me. I currently live in southeast Houston near all the oil and gas refineries, so those landscapes get into my work unconsciously. As much as I acknowledge that I’m a southern girl who loves country music and fried chicken, I also struggle with the politics of Texas. The lack of access to healthcare and alarming rate of maternal mortality rates reinforce this idea of women’s bodies being othered. There’s still a lot of shame in this state about womanhood, gender, and mothering. I grew up Baptist and I see the harm that can come from the church in regards to women’s identities. But there’s a lot of strength in southern women. “Blue Cadillac,” is an homage to my grandmother, who wore white gloves to church and was as outspoken as a matriarch can get. I don’t think I’ll ever stop writing about this place I call home, because Texas is a complex, beautiful, gritty, difficult, and kaleidoscopic state.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW: </strong>In &#8220;I Swallowed the Moon,&#8221; personal details show the moon as an object re</em><em>adily consumed by the speaker of the poem as a medium for her imagination, then later as something &#8220;haunting&#8221; and outside the known. When the speaker at last consumes the moon whole, she has &#8220;doomed the world.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em>I read this poe</em><em>m first in a literal, speculative mode&#8211;a woman dooms the world by consuming this symbol of feminism when using it as a medium for creation no longer satisfies her appetite&#8211;and on rereading as a metaphorical exploration of the dangers of consuming myths and their implications. How do you approach myths and fairy tales, especially the &#8220;unfulfilled fairytales&#8221; of &#8220;Behind the Glass,&#8221; as both source material to be consumed and to be wary of?</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-15811" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_8359_large_cropped-245x300.jpg" alt="image of poet Holly Lyn Walrath" width="245" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_8359_large_cropped-245x300.jpg 245w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_8359_large_cropped-768x939.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_8359_large_cropped-837x1024.jpg 837w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/IMG_8359_large_cropped.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 245px) 100vw, 245px" /><strong>HLW:</strong> For me, fairy tales began with Disney. I grew up in the generation that knew the golden age of Disney as not just something to be consumed but as a kind of religion. We lived, breathed, and ate (in the form of kid’s cereal and snacks) Disney. However, as much as I love them, those stories are being reexamined today for their implications. Women were taught to be princesses, not queens—damsels in distress, not heroes. But when we grow up, we realize those stories set false expectations. I’m in love with the new Disney stories like <em>Moana, Rogue One, A Wrinkle in Time, Brave</em>, and <em>The Incredibles</em> because they give girls new options. We’re redefining what a fairy tale means and where women stand in the narrative.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> Can you recommend a couple speculative poetry collections that share the same themes as yours? And are there Texan poets you&#8217;d like to recommend to the readers of </em>Luna Station Quarterly<em>?</em></p>
<p><strong>HLW:</strong> I love the work of another Finishing Line Press poet and Houstonian, Saba Syed Razvi. Check out her 2017 book, <em><a href="https://www.finishinglinepress.com/product/heliophobia-by-saba-syed-razvi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Heliophobia</a></em>, nominated for an Elgin award. Other poets who inspire my work are Rose Lemberg (<a href="http://www.aqueductpress.com/books/978-1-61976-099-8.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Marginalia to Stone Bird</em></a>, Aqueduct Press, 2016) and Kayla Bashe (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/glitter-blood-chapbook-Kayla-Bashe-ebook/dp/B074MMPGVL" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Glitter Blood</em></a>, 2017).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conversations with Speculative Poets: Jeannine Hall Gailey</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/conversations-with-speculative-poets-jeannine-hall-gailey/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Speculative Poets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers of science fiction and fantasy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The Conversations with Speculative Poets Series features interviews with writers of science fiction and fantasy poetry. For the fourth post in the series, I spoke with poet <a href="http://webbish6.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jeannine Hall Gailey</a> about her 2015 collection, </em><a href="http://mayapplepress.com/the-robot-scientists-daughter-jeannine-hall-gailey/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Robot Scientist’s Daughter</a><em>, published by Mayapple Press.<br />
</em></p>
<p><em>Jeannine Hall Gailey served as the second Poet Laureate of Redmond, Washington. She is the author of five books of poetry: </em><a href="http://webbish6.com/about/becoming-the-villainess/">Becoming the Villainess</a>, <a href="http://webbish6.com/books/she-returns-to-the-floating-world/">She Returns to the Floating World</a><em>, which was a finalist for the 2012 Eric Hoffer Montaigne Medal and a winner of a Florida Publishers Association Presidential Award for Poetry</em>, <a title="Unexplained Fevers" href="http://webbish6.com/books/unexplained-fevers/">Unexplained Fevers</a>, <a href="http://webbish6.com/books/robot-scientists-daughter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Robot Scientist’s Daughter,</a><em> and her latest, winner of the Moon City Press Book Prize and SFPA’s Elgin Award,</em> <a href="http://webbish6.com/books/field-guide-to-the-end-of-the-world/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Field Guide to the End of the World</a>.<em> She’s also the author of </em><a href="http://webbish6.com/pr-for-poets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PR for Poets: A Guidebook to Publicity and Marketing.</a><em> She has a B.S. in Biology and an M.A. in English from the University of Cincinnati, as well as an M.F.A. in Creative Writing from Pacific University. Her poems have been featured on NPR’s The Writer’s Almanac and on Verse Daily; two were included in The Year’s Best Fantasy and Horror. In 2007 she received a Washington State Artist Trust GAP Grant and in 2007 and 2011 a </em><a href="http://www.dorothyprizes.org/index_DorothySargentRosenbergMemorialFund.htm"><em> Dorothy Sargent Rosenberg Poetry Prize. </em></a></p>
<p><em><strong>T.D. Walker:</strong> In the collection, we see the character of the Robot Scientist’s Daughter as both of the community and yet outside of it. How did you initially conceive of her in respect to your intentions for the poems? Did your concept of her change over the course of the collection, especially in light of your personal connections to Oak Ridge National Laboratories and that of the research you did for the poems? </em></p>
<p><strong>Jeannine Hall Gailey:</strong> The Robot Scientist’s Daughter is a mythological character who has a lot in common with me, but isn’t actually me. I’ve always enjoyed writing persona poetry, and in this book, which is much more personal (and actually has first-person autobiographical poems in it) I thought it provided a little bit of fun and more potential for sci-fi experimentation inside the historical story of Oak Ridge and my own history living there.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-15805" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/The-Robot-Scientists-Daughter-front-cover-LARGE-400x603-199x300.jpg" alt="cover of The Robot Scientist's Daughter by Jeannine Hall Gailey" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/The-Robot-Scientists-Daughter-front-cover-LARGE-400x603-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/The-Robot-Scientists-Daughter-front-cover-LARGE-400x603.jpg 400w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> I’m curious about the theme of the perilous nature of the parent/child relationship in the collection: the dangerous offspring elements created in “Radon Daughters,” the wasps and swallows building nests from radioactive mud in “Hot Wasp Nest,” “The Girls Next Door” and their daughters, and, of course, the Robot Scientist and his daughter.</em></p>
<p><strong>JHG:</strong> In this book, there is a definite sense of menace in terms of scientific “fathers” – I specifically reference some scientists who made what I consider unethical decisions when it came to their creations in nuclear science and of course, they carry the responsibility for the creation of the most devastating military weapon ever – the nuclear bomb. There’s a feeling that people in the nuclear era – and in Oak Ridge – trusted the government to tell them about the dangers nuclear experimentation exposed them to, and that trust was betrayed multiple times, in multiple ways, over the last fifty years. In environmental terms, the endangered babies of various animals raised in a toxic environment represented by own (and many other children from the area’s) damage from exposure to nuclear pollution – but I wanted to represent the damage this nuclear pollution does to the entire ecosystem, not just the human part of it.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> You note in your introduction to the book that one of your reasons for writing the collection was to draw attention to the potential harms of nuclear research, particularly “that the half-life of the pollution from nuclear sites is longer than most human life spans.” The presence of the children in the collection, affected as they are by the pollution, seems to work in tension to the danger, however, as we see the children as a kind of emblem of some better possible future. What drove your choice to place them both within and as narrator(s) of the poems?</em></p>
<p><strong>JHG:</strong> Children don’t have a choice about where they live, or what their parents do for a living, and yet, they are still exposed to dangers that they may or may not be aware of that can affect them for the rest of their lives, and even their children’s lives. Children can make decisions when they become adults about what they do about that exposure, whether they speak out against it, or keep their families (and their governments’) secrets for them. You can see the results of this now in young people in Japan who are much less tolerant of nuclear power and nuclear pollution after living through the disaster at Fukushima than perhaps previous generations have been. I hope this book raises some awareness about our own problems – still unfixed – in cities near the readers – not just Oak Ridge and Hanford, the sister “atomic cities,” but many secret cities around our country. Anyone who talks about how “clean” nuclear energy is needs to be educated about the real dangers and the effects already around many rural (and some not-so-rural) areas in America.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> Throughout the collection, you anchor the poems in the landscape around the ORNL with almost incantatory series of plants and animals, from “lilacs, daffodils, black bears and mockingbirds” in “Oak Ridge, Tennessee” to “wild onion, grass, green apples” in “Lessons in Poison” to “Pears and apples, asparagus and peanuts, rows and rows of lettuce” in “Oak Ridge National Laboratory: Unlock the Secrets of America’s Secret City!”</em></p>
<p><em>These groupings give us as readers a view of the wildlife affected by the ORNL, but they also seem to make of the land and landscape a sort of community, a spare and haunting gathering of its inhabitants. How did you view these groupings in your poems? How do you see them in relation to the same groupings of body parts affected by the radiation, such as the “bones, fingernail, brain” you group in the first poem of the book, “Cesium Burns Blue”?</em></p>
<p><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-15804" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/JHGKitsuneHeadshot.jpg" alt="picture of poet Jeannine Hall Gailey" width="133" height="200" />JHG:</strong> I would say it’s fair to say that as a child living in Tennessee I spent more time with the plants and animals there than I did with any fellow humans. I loved the woods and the animals we kept on our small farm and the wild things there. As a kid I pretended to be a horse and ate grass; I pretended to be a cat and climbed trees; I pretended to be a bird and built nests. There was no way those items would not become an important part of the book. I live in a beautiful part of the world now, but there’s no doubt, with every garden I plant, I’m in some way trying to recreate the beloved gardens of my childhood home.</p>
<p>Also, when I studied ecotoxicology and toxic botany in college, I learned about the way that plants take up poisons from their environments, and I read studies that showed that, say, children who drank milk from cows in the Oak Ridge area or ate fish from streams even miles away were exposed to high levels of radioactive cesium, for instance, so I became aware as an adult that the fruits and flowers I loved were actually poisonous, toxic.</p>
<p><em><strong>TDW:</strong> Are there any speculative poetry titles you’d like to recommend to the readers of</em> Luna Station Quarterly?<em> Or poetry collections that also touch on the same kind of environmental concerns that </em>The Robot Scientist’s Daughter<em> explores?</em></p>
<p><strong>JHG:</strong> As far as environmental concerns, the terrific <a href="http://www.washington.edu/uwpress/search/books/FLEPLU.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Plume</em></a> by Kathleen Flenniken explores similar themes to <em>The Robot Scientist’s Daughter</em> from the perspective of an actual former Hanford, WA engineer who was also the daughter of a Hanford engineer. Hanford has almost more terrible lessons than Oak Ridge, from an American nuclear perspective. (Plus: google ‘the Green Run.’)</p>
<p>Speculative poetry that I love? Margaret Rhee’s <a href="https://www.finishinglinepress.com/product/radio-heart-or-how-robots-fall-out-of-love-by-margaret-rhee/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Robot Love</em></a>; Matthea Harvey’s <a href="https://www.graywolfpress.org/books/modern-life" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Modern Life</em></a>; Tracy K. Smith’s <a href="https://www.graywolfpress.org/books/life-mars" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Life on Mars</em></a>; Dana Levin’s <a href="https://www.coppercanyonpress.org/pages/browse/book.asp?bg=%7B900E1D4B-0CC0-4A70-A4CD-51807E49172A%7D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Banana Palace</em></a>. More female speculative poets to check out: <a href="http://stephaniewytovich.blogspot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stephanie Wytovich</a>, <a href="https://lesleywheeler.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lesley Wheeler</a>, <a href="http://www.nancyhightower.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nancy Hightower</a>, <a href="http://www.sallyrosenkindred.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sally Rosen Kindred</a>, <a href="https://jennalewriting.com/about/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jenna Le</a>, <a href="http://www.shannonconnorwinward.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Shannon Connor Winward</a>, <a href="https://lanaayers.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lana Ayers</a>, and <a href="http://marymcmyne.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Mary McMyne</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
