<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Inked in the Clouds &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/inked-in-the-clouds/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 03:28:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Prime (or Tragedy) of Miss Jean Brodie</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-prime-or-tragedy-of-miss-jean-brodie/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Levin Solace]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inked in the Clouds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11244</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The book begins with an introduction to the &#8220;Brodie set”, who are “recognizable as Miss&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/brodie.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11252 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/brodie-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a>The book begins with an <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/517188.The_Prime_of_Miss_Jean_Brodie">introduction</a> to the &#8220;Brodie set”, who are “recognizable as Miss Brodie’s pupils”. Each of them, we are told, is famous in school. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">But before we get carried away with the impression that they are indeed the “creme de la creme”, as Miss Brodie describes, we discover that when they turn sixteen, they aren’t likable in school and are regarded with suspicion. Hence, their fame is of the infamous kind. So what has led the girls to gain such a notorious reputation? “Give me a girl at an impressionable age and she is mine for life,” says Jean Brodie, our eponymous character. We wonder if the outcome of girls’ lives and characters are indeed the work of Miss Brodie. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Miss Brodie seems to have effectively charmed and seduced her girls. She takes them into her confidence. These “special girls”, will be taken to her home for tea and bidden not to tell anyone. The girls understand the internal feud between the headmistress of the school and Miss Brodie. They have come to recognize that the allies of the headmistress are, therefore, their enemies. Miss Brodie and her girls seem unbreakable, their allegiance to each other is impenetrable. When Miss Mackey, the headmistress, plans a scheme to break up the Brodie set, it fails. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The Brodie set’s loyalty is forged in a single belief, and that is <a href="https://www.signature-reads.com/2016/06/why-the-prime-of-miss-jean-brodie-still-matters/">Miss Brodie</a>. They idolize her, almost as if she were a god. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Told in a series of flashbacks and flash-forwards, we are given clues that Miss Brodie’s prime will eventually come to an end. The story comes with a twist and her plan to dominate the minds of her girls comes to a bitter end. “You will receive the fruits of my prime”, says Miss Brodie and she promises that the fruits will “remain with (them) in all (their) days”. It is, however, a betrayal with which Miss Brodie will be paid back. She will be doomed to a loveless and lonely life. Her relationship with the girls proved to be fragile after all. It takes her many years later, when she is near death, that she will finally come to realize it was her favorite girl, Sandy, who has betrayed her. The heroine isn’t as formidable as we thought her to be. “Whatever possessed you?” says Miss Brodie to Sandy, at her moment of <a href="https://literarydevices.net/anagnorisis/">anagnorisis</a>. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dickens &#038; Orwell</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dickens-orwell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Levin Solace]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 10:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inked in the Clouds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the things that makes literature beautiful is its ability to bring out our multifaceted&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the things that makes literature beautiful is its ability to bring out our multifaceted humanity. It functions like a prism that reflects the many colors of the rainbow when a beam of white light passes through it.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/kiki-falconer-608549-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10658 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/kiki-falconer-608549-unsplash-300x198.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="198" /></a>However, this ‘rainbow’ is not all about beauty; neither is it infallible. It has its vulnerabilities, the little pockmarks that blemish an otherwise beautiful face. And I think that it is not only at its most vulnerable, but also at its most interesting stage, when the intricacies of human relationships and of humanity surface.</p>
<p>To my mind, Charles Dickens is a master at doing this: in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Expectations" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Great Expectations</em></a> Pip lays up in bed for days while in London. It was neither his guardian, Mr Jaggers, nor the supposed ‘fairy god-mother’, Miss Havisham, who tended to his needs, and nursed him back to health. It was his uncle Joe, the unassuming blacksmith, whom loved Pip without reservations. The irony is that the unappreciative Pip used to constantly spurn him. He was like a pebble in his shoe: bothersome and unwanted when Pip was walking his way up the road of the high society. Therefore, a reader’s indignation about Pip could not be appeased until Pip finally realized his mistakes. He headed back to Kent to look for Joe, hoping to redress the sullied relationship.</p>
<p>Recently, for some strange coincidence, I was re-reading George Orwell’s essay, <a href="http://theorwellprize.co.uk/george-orwell/by-orwell/essays-and-other-works/how-the-poor-die/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>How the Poor Die</em></a>. Although I read it once many years ago (and I liked it very much), I could not really recall the full details of it.</p>
<p>But as I read on, the words started turning on the many little bulbs in my head. One by one, a fuller light was formed and I could see what it was about the essay that I had liked so much. And I called it a coincidence because, just like Orwell, who was battling with an unrelenting illness, I was battling with a fluctuating fever for days in bed while reading it.</p>
<p>In that essay, Orwell talked about how common it was for medical students in the past to kill ‘free’ patients by conducting experiments on them. These were experiments that could not have been done on a ‘paid’ patient. Therefore, patients who did not have a penny to pay for their medical treatments, paid by being test specimens. The nurses often left these ‘free’ patients soiled and constipated on their beds simply out of sheer laziness. It was also not uncommon that the dead would not be discovered <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/annie-spratt-147610-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10659 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/annie-spratt-147610-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>until the nurses or doctors did their usual rounds in the morning. For the poor, it was a time when sufferings augmented as sickness struck.</p>
<p>There could not be a more suitable time to read the essay than the time when I was recuperating from a fever. I was able to connect with the sick and the poor in Orwell’s days without having to try too hard. I was immediately convinced of and converted to Orwell’s belief that it is better to die in one’s boots than in one’s bed: the violent death of war is much less painful than the slow and smelly way of dying on a hospital bed.</p>
<p>Charles Dickens and George Orwell―the canonical writers― have masterfully accentuated humanity through literature. They built a bridge that breaks through time, transporting us beyond the prism to discover colors to which we could have been blinded. That is what literature has never failed to do over centuries.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Going to a Play &#8211; The Curious Incident of the Dog in the Night-Time</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/going-to-a-play-the-curious-incident-of-the-dog-in-the-night-time/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Levin Solace]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inked in the Clouds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To my mind, people go to plays for different reasons. I&#8217;ve known of some who,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/kilyan-sockalingum-478724-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10187 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/kilyan-sockalingum-478724-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a>To my mind, people go to plays for different reasons. I&#8217;ve known of some who, having watched the movie version of it (such as <em>Rabbit Hole</em>), were curious how it could be performed and produced on a live stage. They wondered if the same kind of emotions, provoked in a cinema setting on screen, could stir the same when acted out live.</p>
<p>There are those who go to a play because of its star-studded cast, such as when Kevin Spacey was in town for <em><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2011/jun/29/richard-iii-review-kevin-spacey">Richard III</a> </em>many years ago.</p>
<p>And of course, there are those who go to a play simply because it is Shakespeare.</p>
<p>But when <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=O704ld5WQnk"><em>The Curious Incident of the Dog in the Night-Time</em></a> was in town, it seemed to draw a different crowd entirely: it managed to pique interest in everyone, even the non-theater goers. As far as I know, it was a full-house most of the time.</p>
<p>Playwright Simon Stephens says the production is &#8220;loyal” to the book, which I actually don&#8217;t agree with entirely.</p>
<p>In chapter 163 of the novel (the book is chaptered by prime numbers), Christopher narrates an exercise which he has had with his first teacher, Julie. It involves a tube of Smarties candies. Christopher is asked to guess what is inside the tube, which he has, of course, guessed that it is Smarties. Julie then revealed that it actually contains a red pencil.</p>
<p>Julie asked Christopher what his mother and father would guess, should they walk in at that moment. Christopher&#8217;s answer still is a red pencil. The purpose of this exercise reveals that Christopher has problems understanding things from another person&#8217;s point of view.</p>
<p>I find this insight into Christopher&#8217;s world interesting and crucial, as it sheds light on things concerning people who are autistic, such as Christopher&#8217;s reaction when he has found out that his dad is the murderer of the dog.</p>
<p>This, however, was a missing piece in the play. Stephens might have left it out due to time constraint; to have <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/jad-limcaco-254927-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10188 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/jad-limcaco-254927-unsplash-300x206.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="206" /></a>an entire novel played out in three hours is quite an extraordinary feat.</p>
<p>The novel was an enjoyable read; narrated in Christopher&#8217;s perspective, who was unreliable but honest. There were moments when I chuckled at his innocence and his fixation at certain things, such as not eating food that is brown or yellow in color. There were also scenes where I felt deeply sorry for him, where so many things are happening in his life yet he is completely oblivious because of his medical condition.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think art grows out of a place of discomfort,&#8221; says author Mark Haddon in his essay <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Light-Dark-Creativity-Inspiration-Artistic/dp/0143130846">Music for Misfits</a>. He thinks that the job of a writer is uphill most of the time, where &#8220;you get some fantastic views when you pause or when you get to the top, but the actual process can be tough.&#8221; It made me wonder how much discomfort Haddon had put himself through in order for Christopher Boone to tell his story.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Gluttony</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-gluttony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Levin Solace]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 21:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inked in the Clouds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dante, in his The Divine Comedy writes of a hell, where the three-headed hound Cerberus&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dante, in his <em>The Divine Comedy</em> writes of a hell, where the three-headed hound Cerberus guards the gluttons as they are condemned to “lie in the mire.” In Shakespeare’s <em>Antony and Cleopatra</em>, Cleopatra is said to “prorogue (Antony’s) honour” with “sleep and feeding.” Pompey sees an “amorous surfeiter” in Antony, and thinks that the insatiable appetite of his has now weakened his military prowess.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/heather-schwartz-493953-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9633 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/heather-schwartz-493953-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>Likewise, gluttony is a common theme in children’s literature. The “enormously fat” <a href="http://roalddahl.wikia.com/wiki/Augustus_Gloop">Augustus Gloop</a> in Roald Dahl’s <em>Charlie and the Chocolate Factory</em> is punished when, while gulping from the chocolate river, he falls into it and gets sucked through a pipe that links to the fudge room. Augustus’s fate is ruined by the same gluttonous habit that wins him the golden ticket.</p>
<p>On television, we aren’t spared from the dramatization of this excessive desire either. It is a subject of curiosity how something so horrifying could intrigue us at the same time. As much as feeling repulsed by the sight of someone gorging on a large quantity of food, there is this voyeuristic tendency that compels us to watch. This is probably why eating competitions are successful in attracting both the contestants and audiences alike. And how internet celebrity <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donna_Simpson_(internet_celebrity)">Donna Simpson</a> rises to stardom by maintaining a website where her fans pay to watch her eat.</p>
<p>One of the most graphic ways of portraying gluttony on television is Monty Python’s <a href="https://laughingsquid.com/terry-jones-talks-about-playing-the-enormous-mr-creosote-in-monty-pythons-the-meaning-of-life/">Mr. Creosote</a>, played by Terry Jones. In a classy French restaurant where patrons dine with the piano playing in the background, in walks a monstrously obese Mr. Creosote. His entrance to the scene puts the talking-fish in the aquarium in a frenzy and causes some discomfort among the patrons. It is, however, a French restaurant where customers are the epitome of polite society. Despite the presence of this bizarre guest who has just wobbled in, everything resumes and guests continue with their meals.</p>
<p>Alas, his presence soon proved to be more than just incongruous. As soon as Mr. Creosote is seated at his table, he starts vomiting buckets. He misses his aim at the bucket a few times and creates puddles of vomit on the floor. Some restaurant workers hurry to clean them up, but most efforts are in vain as Mr. Creosote continues with his vomiting, and this time, showering the poor workers with his murky stuff.</p>
<p>And, this is not the end of making the guests’ (also our) stomachs turn. At the end of his meal, where towers of plates and bowls now dominate his table, Mr. Creosote explodes, causing the restaurant to “rain” with his vomit. Guests start running for the exit, retching with disgust.</p>
<p>It is easy to recognize the cause of this disaster – Mr. Creosote’s insatiable appetite, his ballooned body, his vomiting, they all point to one reason: Mr. Creosote is a glutton. He overindulges and becomes a hazard not only to his own body, but also to the people around him.</p>
<p>As it is Monty Python, it is meant to entertain and for us to have a good laugh. Well, not quite. Quentin Tarantino is said to have found the scene nauseating and disturbing.</p>
<p>In contrast, in J.M. Coetzee’s <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/booksblog/2009/jun/16/booker-club-jm-coetzee"><em>The Life and Times of Michael K</em></a>, the protagonist’s appetite is intensified by desperation and exhaustion instead of greed. The story takes place in war-torn South Africa, where food is scarce and <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/alex-munsell-18753-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9635 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/alex-munsell-18753-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a>survival is a question of chance rather than will. Though weak and famished, K manages to talk himself into bare-hand hunting, followed by a messy butchering of a goat with the help of only a penknife.</p>
<p>Telling himself that he “must press through to the end” and he “must not relent,” K throws his entire weight upon a tribe of goats, with the aim to capture a slow and unlucky one among the many. The captive goat initially “bleated again and again in terror; its body jerked in spasms.” K, with his hands clenching around its neck and his knees gripping the goat’s body, presses its head under the mud until its snort and tremor finally cease.</p>
<p>What follows is more barbaric than the hunt, as Coetzee describes in vivid details how K butchers and cleans his kill: “He slits the belly and pushes his arm into the slit; he expects blood-heat but inside the goat encounters again the clammy wetness of marsh-mud [remember how he kills the goat by drowning it in mud; the goat must have swallowed the mud in its struggle, thus causing its stomach to now bloat with it].” With “his hands and sleeves full of gore” K then hangs the dismembered carcass from the ceiling, which soon attracts a swarm of flies. The goat begins to stink and K ends up burying the remains.</p>
<p>In his less hungry thus less delirious state, he learns that he should not have killed such large animals. Instead, he makes himself a sling-shot using a Y-shaped stick, the tongue of an old shoe, and strips of rubber, and learns to hunt for small birds in the trees – a much simpler and cleaner meal as compared to the earlier humongous feast that proved too much for him to handle. K’s bad judgment is, therefore, prompted by a natural need rather than hedonistic gratification.</p>
<p>Similarly, Roxane Gay’s memoir <em>Hunger</em> tells of a psychological trauma that manifests itself into an appetite. As a way of responding to her being gang-raped at the age of twelve, Gay seeks security from food. Her fatness becomes a solution, a safe place, where “no one can get you.” Overeating, ironically, grants Gay a sense of control, by losing herself in food.</p>
<p>Eating becomes a means of escapism for Gay. She eats in order to blot out the memory of her rape. By making her body repulsive, Gay thinks that she could keep men away. At her heaviest, Gay weighed 577lb.</p>
<p>Whether it is motivated by irresponsibility such as Mr. Creosote, insecurity like Roxane Gay, or hunger pangs such as Michael K, gluttony tells more of what lies within than without: it tells of an inner gulf that is too wide to fill.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/brooke-lark-275181-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9636 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/brooke-lark-275181-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>“Comedy too can sometimes discern what is right,” says Aristophanes’ Dicaepolis. Mr. Creosote fits into a stock character whose purpose is to satirize social follies – in this case, the habit of excessive eating. The ending of Mr. Creosote’s story is, without a doubt, an exaggeration. No human body will ever explode like how Mr. Creosote’s body does due to overeating. Hence, we are able to laugh at Mr. Creosote’s fate, but at the back of our minds we know that by exposing Mr. Creosote’s failings, there is a message behind it. Mr. Creosote behaves without calculating the consequences; he acts without regard to what is right for his body, thus he is wanting in conscientiousness.</p>
<p>Stories like <em>Hunger </em>and <em>The Life and Times of Michael K</em>, on the other hand, rely on their cathartic effect for their moralizing purpose. K’s fate in Coetzee’s novel is a consequence of a country at war. His obsession with hoarding food is, therefore, forgivable and appeals to our sympathy. It tells how our judgment is often susceptible to our bodily ailments. The practice of mind over body is often easier said than done. However, as the story progresses, K’s survival instinct becomes more adaptable. Besides the use of a sling-shot to hunt birds, K also learns to grow and harvest pumpkins. K’s ability to implement a makeshift tool such as the sling-shot and his cultivated patience to savor food that his “own labor has made the earth to yield;” K has finally triumphed and evolved. He is no longer the man of wild instincts but one who is analytical and patient. On the night as he held his first pumpkin in hand, moved by the fragrance of the first fruit of his labor, K begins to pray: “For what we are about to receive make us truly thankful.”</p>
<p>In<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2017/jul/30/hunger-by-roxane-gay-review-one-bodys-lessons-for-everybody"> <em>Hunger</em></a>, eating excessively proves to be a false means of solace for Gay. She eventually realizes that as she eats in order to forget, her body has in fact, become “a cage of my own making.” Her body has grown to the extent where “nearly everything physical is difficult,” and finally, her greatest fear is realized when she is told from an x-ray that her “ankle is very, very broken.” In an attempt to escape the entrapment of a bad memory, she falls into another. Through her broken ankle, Gay then comes to many realizations. She begins to see her body differently and tells herself “that one day I would stop feeling this quiet but abiding rage about the things I have been through at the hands of others.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>El, Magwitch, and All of Us</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/el-magwitch-and-all-of-us/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Levin Solace]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 12:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inked in the Clouds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Death and taxes – Benjamin Franklin said nothing in this world is as certain as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Death and taxes – Benjamin Franklin said nothing in this world is as certain as these. What about our mortality? Could we then say that nothing is really to be as certain as death and food?</p>
<p>The primal need of daily sustenance is what makes all things living and breathing, the same.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12ee1146-dc67-4090-b82d-e5894d1f5654.png.w960.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9029 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/12ee1146-dc67-4090-b82d-e5894d1f5654.png.w960.png" alt="" width="263" height="180" /></a>Hence, when Chief Hopper in <a href="http://strangerthings.wikia.com/wiki/Stranger_Things/Season_2">Stranger Things</a> is seen placing some Eggo&#8217;s and Christmas cookies in the forest box, we immediately recognize the hint – El (aka Eleven or Jane) is still somewhere out there alive.</p>
<p>How the protagonist is so connected with Eggo&#8217;s begins when she first escaped from the Hawkins Lab. While hiding in the basement in Mike’s house, Eggo&#8217;s is the first meal she is given. She soon grew very fond of not just the food, but also her benefactor, Mike.</p>
<p>Mike’s Eggo&#8217;s means more than just an act of hospitality or kindness to El. Besides tending to El’s biological needs, Mike has, in consequence, also filled her emotional need. Hunger reveals the most vulnerable part of us. When denied food, a gift of daily fuel, however minuscule, appeals to the humility of the receiver and accentuates the humanity in the giver.</p>
<p>Cicero said that gratitude is the greatest of virtues. When El is capable of reciprocating Mike’s Eggo&#8217;s with gratitude, we know that humanity lives within this strange and unknown girl. It tones down the peculiar, possibly even sinister image of hers, especially when she hurls Mike’s bully off the cliff, or when she breaks the necks of a Hawkins Lab guard without lifting a finger.</p>
<p>Mike’s gift of Eggo&#8217;s therefore grants El the need to belong. <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/science-choice/201609/5-reasons-why-we-crave-comfort-foods">Comfort food</a> provides us such solace just by reminiscing, and this is precisely what Eggo&#8217;s has given El. It fills the gap of wanting to belong&#8211;a place to anchor and a source of security.</p>
<p>The same effect food has is also reflected in Dickens’ <em>Great Expectations</em>. The first meal of the novel takes place in the wilderness, where <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abel_Magwitch">Magwitch</a> meets Pip for the first time. In his desperation for food, Magwitch threatens and demands Pip to bring him some “wittles” – referring to food. Magwitch then wolfs down his meal like a dog, with “strong, sharp sudden bites.&#8221; His wild manner of gobbling and snapping up food brings out the beastly image of Magwitch. It augments the already dubious image he already has, by his threatening Pip into stealing food for him.</p>
<p>We begin to grow skeptical of this unknown character, until Magwitch reveals that underneath his grotesque hunger is a man capable of gratitude and generosity.</p>
<p>In an attempt to protect Pip, Magwitch first lies about being the one who has stolen the food instead of Pip. Many years on, he then bequeaths Pip a large sum of money in order for him to advance in life as a “gentleman.”<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/dan-gold-105699.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9030 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/dan-gold-105699-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>The mere provision of food becomes instrumental in the fate of Pip. By satisfying Magwitch’s hunger for food, Pip has also warmed the humanity in him.</p>
<p>Magwitch repaying Pip’s act of kindness and hospitality, like El’s to Mike’s, highlights the understanding of the philosophy: to do unto others as you would have do unto you. This is marked by one significant meal in both instances – a meal given in times of dire helplessness.</p>
<p>By revealing the humane quality in both the unknowns, El and Magwitch, it diminishes the character’s hostility and unveils a certain accessibility in them. What food has done for both El and Magwitch in both stories, testifies to the common basic need in all of us, which is the dependence to sustain not just biologically but also through relationships.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two Helpful Books for Writers</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/two-helpful-books-for-writers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Levin Solace]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inked in the Clouds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[All of us have always had this problem with writing. We sit down at the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>All of us have always had this problem with writing. We sit down at the desk, knowing that we ought to write something, anything; even if it turns out lousy and unappetizing, we just got to get something written.</p>
<p>“A word after a word after a word is power,” a popular and well-known quote of Atwood. It works like chant, actually. And, I’m guessing that probably was Atwood’s idea as she wrote it. A word after a word… after a word… it might have the effect of coaxing the writer’s mind into writing. Who knows?</p>
<p>Recently, I have rediscovered two much treasured books I used to use, to help get some writing done.  The titles themselves lend a tinge of hope and inspiration: <a href="http://www.writersdigest.com/qp7-migration-books/3am-epiphany"><em>The 3A.M. Epiphany</em></a> and <a href="https://www.writersstore.com/the-4-am-breakthrough-brian-kiteley/"><em>The 4A.M. Breakthrough</em></a> by Brian Kiteley.</p>
<p><em>The 3A.M. Epiphany</em> is a book of short writing exercises that are “uncommon” with the result of “transforming your fiction”. The exercises range between 300-600 words each. And don’t be fooled by the number of words required, because the fewer number of words actually mean the tougher the exercise is.</p>
<p>How exactly “uncommon” are these exercises? How do they differ from other books on writing exercises? The exercises in this book are designed to work backwards; by “teaching writers how to read themselves and read for themselves”.</p>
<p>A companion to the first book,<em> The 4A.M. Breakthrough</em> is slightly advanced, where Kiteley jumps right into addressing problems and processes through the writing exercises.</p>
<p>Of course, it isn’t necessary to use the first book before the second. Although both books work in tandem, we can read either book on its own.</p>
<p>I don’t have a systematic approach in using these books. Whenever I recognised the moment of being stuck in a piece of writing, and my mind is crying out for a break, I select an exercise in random from one of these two books. This way, even though I am taking a break from my fiction writing, the work will not “feel” disrupted, especially when the rhythm has already picked up its pace.</p>
<p>Here’s what happened for my writing last week. I wrote an exercise with an ox or a cow as the significant role; a 500 words exercise that was supposed to be based on the letter “A”. I was to make the one word title of the piece with “A”, and write 20 words that began with it. My 20 words included verbs like “assumed”, “assail”, “approved”, nouns like “attitude”, “audience”, “apricot”, and the list goes on, with a variety of verbs, nouns, adjectives, etc.</p>
<p>The next step to this exercise was to write a sentence or two or even three, around each word. I was supposed to let these group of sentences stand for a moment before I could see an order to them. However, as I was in the process of making these sentences, I could already see the connection and order in them. Somehow, they all surrounded one of the characters of the story I am currently working on; these 20 words helped to give me an idea of the next scene, or a future scene to develop.</p>
<p>I guess how this book helps in fictional writing is by giving us a portal to the inner mind, an access to the materials we encounter in our day-to-day activities, “Fiction is made of all sorts of other bits of language and image, knowingly borrowed some of the time but most of the time unconsciously stolen”, explains Kiteley. Many of the exercises in the books urge the readers to “explore your own personal consciousness as well as the collective unconscious and the many written and spoken resources that can inspire and create our fiction”.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>For The Love of Bookstores</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/for-the-love-of-bookstores/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Levin Solace]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 17:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inked in the Clouds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Someone once told me that bookshops are sacred. And, I couldn&#8217;t agree more. The year&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Someone once told me that bookshops are sacred. And, I couldn&#8217;t agree more. The year was 2011, when the news of Borders&#8217; closure shook the book industry. I was working in Page One then, a chain bookstore and publisher founded in Singapore. It shared the same fate as Borders; augmenting the bleak outlook of the book industry. Perhaps it was an act of defiance, perhaps it was an act of hope or optimism, but I got myself a job in another bookstore after Page One, an independent one on a much smaller scale. Alas, neither my defiance nor optimism yielded a better outcome.<br />
Within a few years, bookstores were closing all over the world, like dominoes. It was like curse, a chain effect that couldn&#8217;t be broken.</p>
<p>People started the finger-pointing game; some blamed the ebook or the online bookstores, some claimed that humans were just not reading anymore, a fatalistic view which I was glad to soon discover that it wasn&#8217;t true.</p>
<p>In this age of the Internet, where distractions abound, people are probably reading less, but I believe it has definitely not come to a complete halt. There is, however, another thing that can never be broken too. And that is the affinity between book lovers. It is something that a fellow book lover could understand, the solace and the contentment we get from a good book.</p>
<p>Good literature sets us into contemplation, into introspection, and somehow it seems to enhance our individuality. It gives us an opportunity to reflect.</p>
<p>During my days in the bookstores, whenever I saw a customer returning the next day, I knew that they had discovered a good book which they couldn&#8217;t let go. They were hooked. Such was the joy I got from working in a bookstore; to know that some strangers out there cherished the same thing as I did, that we shared the same love.</p>
<p>My experience of working in the bookstore was short lived, but it was one of the best memories I ever had. Yes, bookstores are indeed sacred and I would still say yes to an opportunity of working in one again.</p>
<p>Find your closest independent bookstore <a href="http://www.indiebound.org/indie-bookstore-finder">here</a>.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t miss out on <a href="http://www.indiebookstoreday.com/">Independent Bookstore Day</a> Saturday April 29th 2017.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reading Diversely</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reading-diversely/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Levin Solace]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inked in the Clouds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Being an Asian, with parents who do not speak a word of English, and living&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Being an Asian, with parents who do not speak a word of English, and living in a country that is predominantly Chinese, I actually grew up reading <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enid_Blyton">Enid Blyton</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roald_Dahl">Roald Dahl</a>, and I speak and write English more than I do for my mother tongue. Strange as it may seem, the fact is, most of us Singaporeans are such.</p>
<p>I am not going to lie by saying that I have always been reading diversely. Anyone who takes a look at my bookshelf would know&#8211;while Caucasian authors occupy most of my shelves&#8211;only a quarter of those shelves belongs to books by Asian authors. And, to tell the truth, these Asian authors made it to my shelf only recently.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/maxresdefault.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-7712 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/maxresdefault-300x170.jpg" alt="maxresdefault" width="300" height="170" /></a>It only occurred to me how important and also interesting it would be to read diversely, when I started studying Postcolonial Literature. It was about the same time that booktubers started a week of #diverseathon in September.</p>
<p>My reading of diverse books is still growing and I have promised myself to expand it further come 2017. I started by picking up Tash Aw’s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26071616-the-face"><em>Strangers on A Pier</em></a> from <em>The Face</em> series by <em>Restless Books</em>. Aw’s anecdotes of his grandparents’ experiences as the first-generation immigrant and his own experiences as the third-generation immigrant, are at once moving and humorous. In this tiny book of 78 pages, Aw paints a vivid picture of having to leave one’s homeland, of diaspora and of displacement. In his words, “to drop their cultural baggage entirely in order to assimilate successfully into their new environment”&#8211;to be uprooted from a place born in&#8211;is always the first big struggle an immigrant has to overcome. To my mind, this book adequately represents the voice of a third-generation Chinese immigrant of postcolonial Southeast Asia.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/5439.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7713 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/5439-189x300.jpg" alt="5439" width="189" height="300" /></a>Books by Indian writers is another category I wish to explore in my expedition of diversity reading. Jhumpa Lahiri’s <em><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5439.Interpreter_of_Maladies">Interpreter of Maladies</a>, </em>is a short story collection that touches on the lives of Indian-Americans. These stories tell the challenges and confusion of exiles, who are torn between their rich and strict tradition, and the unfamiliar culture of a foreign land. From the story of an estranged Pakistani husband living in America, to a second-generation Indian-American visiting their native land for the first time, Lahiri gives an intimate view of immigrants’ deep longing for acceptance into the New World and also the struggle to shed or preserve their roots.</p>
<p>While Aw’s <em>Strangers on A Pier</em> and Lahiri’s <em>Interpreter of Maladies</em> share the experiences of Asian migrants, Jean Rhys’ <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25622780-wide-sargasso-sea?from_search=true"><em>Wide Sargasso Sea</em></a> tells the story of a Creole heiress, Antoinette Cosway. Fans of <em>Jane Eyre</em> will take to this book instantly, as it is a prequel Charlotte Bronte’s acclaimed novel. Who exactly is Rochester’s madwoman in the attic? How did this Creole woman, famous for her beauty, become the “savage” looking “vampire”Jane describes? Being a native of Dominica herself, Jean Rhys seems to speak the exact sentiments of a displaced and lonely heiress, who fits in neither with the Europeans nor the Africans.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Florence Foster Jenkins in Us</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-florence-foster-jenkins-in-us/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Levin Solace]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 16:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inked in the Clouds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I walked into the cinema for Florence Foster Jenkins one evening, without any expectations. I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/MV5BMjA0Mzc4MjMxMl5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTgwODIwNTQxODE@._V1_SY1000_CR006831000_AL_.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7509 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/MV5BMjA0Mzc4MjMxMl5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTgwODIwNTQxODE@._V1_SY1000_CR006831000_AL_-205x300.jpg" alt="mv5bmja0mzc4mjmxml5bml5banbnxkftztgwodiwntqxode-_v1_sy1000_cr006831000_al_" width="205" height="300" /></a>I walked into the cinema for <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4136084/"><em>Florence Foster Jenkins</em></a> one evening, without any expectations. I was there purely for a movie; an evening of entertainment, to unwind and get things off my mind.</p>
<p>Little did I realise how wrong I was. My mind was far from getting rid of the one thing that preoccupied me regularly. I left the cinema thinking more intently of the craft of writing. In fact, I walked out of the theatre that day, believing that I had seen a Florence Foster Jenkins, the world’s worst opera singer, in every writer.</p>
<p>Florence Foster Jenkins is best known for her vocals, a recognition any singer would have desired. Except, the soprano’s performance at the Carnegie Hall in 1944 was described as being awful from the beginning to the end. While most of her audience doubled over from laughing, some of her most loyal and sensitive friends tried as best as they could to save her from the embarrassment. Such was the reaction of her performance back then, and it was mirrored in the cinema that I was in – the entire hall was reverberating with laughter from Florence Foster Jenkins’ (Meryl Streep) performance.</p>
<p>I laughed, in fact I laughed very hard. I laughed at a woman, an ailing 76 year-old woman at that, who mistook her screaming and shrilling as a mark of vocal talent. There was no doubt that I was amused. I supposed that would have served the purpose for my wanting catch a movie that evening. Well, not quite.</p>
<p>There is no doubt that Florence Foster Jenkins is a reflection of every writer; from the unpublished one who plods on silently, to the award-winning and widely-acclaimed writer who basks in glory. Jenkins’ desire was to be recognised for the one thing that she was passionate about.</p>
<p>To be successful, in the pursuit of music, is ambiguous. The same applies to writing – or for that matter, any form of art. We practise, we dive deep and lose ourselves unreservedly, all for the desire of perfecting the craft. However, quite unlike any other profession, the success of an artist (musicians, writers or painters alike), to my mind, is something quite intangible.</p>
<p>While an athlete, for example, could measure her success by the number of medals won – gold, silver and bronze, how do writers measure success? Do we base our success by the number of books sold? Should our sense of accomplishment comes from winning one of the many writing prizes? Are the rejected writers from the slush pile all losers, then? Well, whether <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Gaskell">Elizabeth Gaskell</a> is a good writer or not remains a much debatable topic to this day. That certainly says a lot about how successful a writer could be.</p>
<p>When all the tickets to her performance at the Carnegie Hall were sold out, that perhaps, was an accomplishment for Jenkins. People wanted to hear her voice. Her happiness however, was short-lived. She received the most scathing reviews from the following morning’s newspapers. Jenkins, who was being lifted to the height of great pride for a moment, was plunged deep into the abyss of devastation and failure.</p>
<p>The story of Jenkins, therefore, seems very much like any writer’s. The fate of our long and hard pursuit is very much dependent on a second party’s opinion. At times, we feel that we have finally honed our skills, just like how Jenkins felt that she sounded right in her head. Her art, whether or not it is an object of beauty, is influenced by another person’s taste. It gives a sense of vulnerability: to offer a piece of us, something which we cherish endearingly, to someone else to be judged.</p>
<p>Jenkins’ accomplishment, to my mind, takes on a different form that is much more pure and divine. She possessed one superior quality, which every dream pursuer should have.</p>
<p>Jenkins took delight in her art; you could feel her love in it. It was undeniably distinct. “You can feel her,” said Meryl Streep during an interview for her role as Jenkins. Listen to the soprano’s singing, and no one will miss the conviction and bravado in her voice. Florence Foster Jenkins believed in herself. Eventually, she did what every artist should hope to do – to remain true to one’s dreams. And because of her belief, Jenkins ultimately achieved what every artist desires – she touched people by her unrelenting love of the art. That, indeed, is what every artists could aspire to accomplish.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: We Should All Be Feminists</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-we-should-all-be-feminists/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Levin Solace]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 16:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inked in the Clouds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have a confession to make before this review begins. I had never given much&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have a confession to make before this review begins. I had never given much thought about Feminism: all the things about women’s rights. I knew that it mattered; I knew that it should matter; but I just did not grasp how much it should matter.</p>
<p>About four years ago, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2012_Delhi_gang_rape">2012 Delhi gang rape case </a>thrust me into this world I had been ignorant of. The stark contrast between Jyoti Singh’s world and mine was appalling. It left me with this deep revulsion of how she became a victim of a heinous crime, simply because she was a woman. Following this was the public outcry of how women in India have always been victims of rape, and the government of India has never done enough to ensure the safety of women. I began to see that in today’s twenty-first century, although the problem of gender might seem to have been alleviated, women in certain parts of the world are still very much choked and bullied by oppression. Deciding to cast the parochial me aside (shamefaced and sorry), I started to diversify my reading, by looking at books concerning women’s issues; books that will make me a better woman, or for that matter, a better human.</p>
<p><em><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/index-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7344 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/index-2.jpg" alt="index" width="188" height="268" /></a>We Should All Be Feminists</em>, by <a href="http://www.cerep.ulg.ac.be/adichie/index.html">Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie</a>, is one of such books that I have picked up. In this tiny book of 52 pages long, Adichie talks about her experiences in both Africa and America. Some of them that she had had in Africa bewildered me, such as the one when she tipped a man for helping her to park her car, and the man, in turn, thanked her male friend instead. His assumption was that the money should have come from the man and not her.</p>
<p>Similarly bewildering is Adichie’s revelation concerning the concept of marriage in African society. A successful woman, such as Adichie, is believed to intimidate man, leaving her with the difficulty of getting married.</p>
<p>Adichie gives an eye-opening view of what marriage is in her society: “Because I am female, I’m expected to aspire to marriage. I am expected to make my life choices always keeping in mind that marriage is the most important.”</p>
<p>And she goes on to tell why a Nigerian woman, whom she knows, decided to sell her house, so that she would not intimidate any potential suitors. Another unmarried woman in Nigeria poses as a married woman by putting on a wedding ring before she goes to conferences, because the ring is deemed to “give her respect”. The demarcation could not be clearer; a married woman is successful, she is to be respected, while an unmarried woman is a failure.</p>
<p>While I am bewildered and astounded by such episodes, because they are things that I do not see happening in my society, Adichie raised an issue that is subtle yet resonating. How do we judge if a woman is likeable?</p>
<p>She relates an experience of an American woman: having being unfairly treated by her boss at a meeting because of her gender, she eventually convinced herself that she should not speak up because aggression in woman is not a “likeable” quality. “What struck me with her and with many other female American friends I have is how invested they are in being ‘liked’ ”, says Adichie. Adichie then continues to illustrate this idea of a “likeable” woman – she is someone who is not “…showing anger or being aggressive or disagreeing too loudly”.</p>
<p>Now, that strikes a chord. This perception of a “likeable” woman is universal, indeed.</p>
<p>My late grandmother used a Hokkien word, to describe a woman who is not just aggressive, but a rather unlikeable woman, in her opinion. In fact, “aggressive” is too mild a word for her. Hence, whenever my grandmother called a woman “<em>chia zhar bo</em>”, we automatically took it to mean that her presence was unwelcome, and any interactions with her should be avoided.</p>
<p>People’s definition of the term, “<em>chia zhar bo</em>”, is actually quite divided in my society. To some, such a woman has a strong character, and who has no qualms about doing or saying things that obliging women will not. I also realised that to others, especially to men, a “<em>chia zhar bo</em>” also connotes a woman who is difficult to handle and, above all, one who will be a difficult wife.</p>
<p>This view of a “likeable” woman transcends all countries, languages and cultures. In order for a woman to be liked, she has to be demure, pleasant and agreeable. A woman who speaks her mind in meetings, just like the American friend of Adichie, is not “likeable”, so is a woman who is intractable or even rebellious, in my grandmother’s context. Therefore, if woman openly expresses her disagreement or anger, she could be seen as not likeable. In point of fact, such a woman is one who only wants to open up and voice her view; this, perhaps, is deemed too strong a character for a woman.</p>
<p>Would I have realised this perception of a “likeable” woman, without having read Adichie’s essay? I doubt it. Neither would I have realised the sexual politics masked in today’s society.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
