<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Dungeons &amp; Discourse &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/dungeons-discourse/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 01:25:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What Your DnD Character&#8217;s Class Says About You</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-your-dnd-characters-class-says-about-you/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 18:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dungeons & Discourse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28015</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back, players! We&#8217;ve talked about character creation at length here on this blog column&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back, players! We&#8217;ve talked about <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/who-am-i-what-am-i-creating-your-character/">character creation</a> at length here on this blog column of mine, and today, we&#8217;re going to put that knowledge (*insert dramatic <em>dun-dun-dun</em> sound effect here*) TO THE TEST&#8211;</p>
<p>&#8211;Okay, not really. We&#8217;re not in a campaign. I have no inspiration points to give and I&#8217;m not your DM (only in spirit). But what I <em>can </em>give you is a fun little personality quiz. There&#8217;s no greater joy than someone on the internet telling you what kind of person you are based on some non-consequential fact. Let&#8217;s get started!</p>
<p>If you don&#8217;t have a current character you&#8217;re playing right now, drum up an old one from your archives, or make someone up! If you&#8217;ve never played DnD before, maybe you can use this list as inspiration for what class you&#8217;d like to play in the future <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> No, this list isn&#8217;t biased at all based on my favorites.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cxdw96oy-yw.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28016 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cxdw96oy-yw-300x200.jpg" alt="assorted-color Ninjago plastic figures" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cxdw96oy-yw-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cxdw96oy-yw-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cxdw96oy-yw-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cxdw96oy-yw-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/cxdw96oy-yw.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Barbarian &#8211; </strong>Those jock villagers in <em>Animal Crossing </em>are based off you. You do 5000 push-ups a day and launder the party&#8217;s clothes on your washboard abs. You&#8217;re always thinking about balancing your macros and what your next meal is going to be. It&#8217;s not unusual for you to charge headfirst into combat with your axe held high, bellowing your battle cry as your party stares at you in horror. You&#8217;re the best at spreading cheer and incredibly incapable of speaking in a low voice&#8211;and your team wouldn&#8217;t have it any other way. And don&#8217;t forget: when you&#8217;re a team of one, you always get to be the captain!<br />
<em>A word of advice:</em> Don&#8217;t go on any stealth missions.<br />
<em>Example</em>: Leeroy Jenkins</p>
<p><strong>Bard &#8211; </strong>Your typical Saturday night involves sitting around, playing a half-assed rendition of <em>Wonderwall </em>by Oasis on the lyre. Much to everyone&#8217;s chagrin, your lazy strumming attracts the barmaids and patrons alike, your syrupy tone drawing them to you like flies. A life of the party, you always have a good anecdote to share, and your easygoing attitude means you&#8217;re always on the guest list. A blessing and a curse, you fit in with every social group quite easily, but never feel at home one place in particular. When they say, &#8220;a friend to all is a friend to none&#8221; they were talking about you.<br />
<em>A word of advice:</em> Don&#8217;t be afraid to be vulnerable. Also, please pick another song.<br />
<em>See: </em>Jack Black, probably</p>
<p><strong>Cleric &#8211; </strong>Deathly afraid of confrontation, you prefer to assist from the sidelines. You&#8217;re always there to lend an ear to a friend in need, but you refuse to get involved&#8211;no matter the stakes. Some people think you&#8217;re a fuddy duddy because your bedtime is 9PM, but that&#8217;s only because they&#8217;re cranky and unrested. Under no circumstances will you take sides, or at least not until you&#8217;ve heard the full story. When someone needs a tissue or a Band-Aid, it is your time to shine. At the end of the day, everyone needs a Cleric.<br />
<em>A word of advice: </em>Sometimes the best things in life happen after midnight.<br />
<em>Example: </em>The Pope, I guess</p>
<p><strong>Druid &#8211; </strong>You&#8217;ve always preferred animals to people; they&#8217;re cute and furry and make funny noises when you talk to them. Nothing pleases you more than being one with nature, taking a peaceful stroll to listen to the trees. When people have trouble keeping their plants alive, you&#8217;re the one they plead to bring them back to good health. You have actually never done anything wrong in your whole life, and we love you.<br />
<em>A word of advice: </em>You&#8217;re perfect. Never change.<br />
<em>Example: </em>Steve Irwin, r.i.p.</p>
<p><strong>Paladin &#8211; </strong>You are <em>determined </em>to be that girl&#8217;s Prince Charming, even if you only met her five minutes ago and she&#8217;s clearly uninterested! Raised on chivalry and good vibes, you don&#8217;t have a Chaotic or Evil bone in your body. You&#8217;re often found in the training grounds, whacking into a practice dummy as hard as you can in hopes that when it really counts, you&#8217;ll succeed. There is nothing more important than protecting the people you love&#8211;and the ones who don&#8217;t love you back.<br />
<em>A word of advice: </em>Stop texting her, dude. She&#8217;s just not that into you.<br />
<em>Example: </em>Prince Charming</p>
<p><strong>Rogue &#8211; </strong>Social interaction? Never met him. You much prefer to hide in the shadows; there is nothing you fear more than the spotlight. If someone gives you attention, you might die on the spot from sheer embarrassment. You have trouble trusting people after your hard upbringing, but in time you will learn. Sometimes your humor can come off too sarcastic, but it&#8217;s a defense mechanism and you&#8217;re working on it. Still, your determination and relentlessness proceed you; you are a force to be reckoned with.<br />
A word of advice: stop rebelling against the people who love you!<br />
<em>Example</em>: Rogue (from<em> X-Men</em>)</p>
<p><strong>Wizard: </strong>Oh, you just <em>love </em>to stir the pot. You always have time to chat about to the latest drama with your friends&#8211;as long as it&#8217;s not yours. The book you carry around is called a &#8220;burn book,&#8221; but not for the fire spells it contains. When you&#8217;re not on a mission, you concoct and sell psychedelic brews from your tower.<br />
<em>A word of advice: </em>Put the book down, nerd.<br />
<em>Example: </em>Merlin, Gandalf, Dumbledore &#8212; any skinny old guy with a white beard, you name &#8217;em</p>
<p>Did I leave your class out? Tell us what it is in the comments below!</p>
<p>Until next time, players. Let the good dice roll! ⚀⚁⚂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Little Cubes of Chance: Let the Good Dice Roll</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/little-cubes-of-chance-let-the-good-dice-roll/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 10:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dungeons & Discourse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I know what you&#8217;re thinking. I could hear it when you clicked on this post.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/m4sgyahyn5o.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-27350" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/m4sgyahyn5o-300x226.jpg" alt="closeup photo of dices" width="398" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/m4sgyahyn5o-300x226.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/m4sgyahyn5o-1024x770.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/m4sgyahyn5o-768x578.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/m4sgyahyn5o-1536x1156.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/m4sgyahyn5o.jpg 1595w" sizes="(max-width: 398px) 100vw, 398px" /></a></p>
<p>I know what you&#8217;re thinking.</p>
<p>I could hear it when you clicked on this post. <em>I know what dice are, </em>you scoffed. <em>I&#8217;ve played Yahtzee. </em></p>
<p>Well, you&#8217;re not wrong. So many board games &#8212; from the most complex &#8220;Euro&#8221; strategy games to the simplest of childhood pastimes &#8212; utilize dice. They&#8217;re one of the simplest, easy-to-use random number generators. Remember how we talked about <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/roll-the-dice-storytelling-in-real-time/">RNG</a>? Well, here it is in real time. An introduction to gambling; the first lesson in statistics. The game of chance.</p>
<p>Didn&#8217;t think you&#8217;d have to do <em>math </em>to play this game, did &#8216;ya? I hate to tell you this, but as much as D&amp;D is about storytelling, sometimes it takes a few simple calculations to get there.</p>
<p>Here are the basic dice you should expect to see around the campaign table.</p>
<p><strong>D20: </strong>The icosahedron, aka the 20-sided die. Twenty sides gives each number a 5% chance (or 100 divided by 20). This is the one you&#8217;ll be using for the majority of the time, whether it be to infamously roll for initiative, see if your attack lands, do an ability check, you name it.</p>
<p><strong>D12: </strong>The dodecahedron, or 12-sided die. You&#8217;ll only use this sometimes to attack, most likely if you&#8217;re a barbarian wielding a big weapon that does heavy damage.</p>
<p><strong>D10: </strong>The decahedron<em> (or is it a trapezohedron?)&#8211;</em>whatever<em>, </em>it&#8217;s the 10-sided die. In a standard 7-dice D&amp;D set, you&#8217;ll actually get two of these. No, it&#8217;s not a baker&#8217;s half-dozen. Sometimes your DM will make you use these to make a percentile throw, or get a number out of 100. For example, if you roll a 6 first and then roll a 4, that gives you a 64%. It&#8217;s important to note that there&#8217;s a 0 and also a 00, and they&#8217;re not the same. Two 00&#8217;s gives you a 100%!</p>
<p><strong>D8: </strong>The octahedron, or 8-sided die. Another damage die. Another day.</p>
<p><strong>D6: </strong>The cube we all know and love from every board game ever. I feel like I use these during character creation time to get my stats and then never again.</p>
<p><strong>D4: </strong>The tetrahedron. This 4-sided die is a pyramid, or 3D triangle, and might look a little confusing at first. When you roll it, you should only be going by the number that&#8217;s right side up. If you look at all sides of the die, you&#8217;ll realize that top number is the same going all the way around. Don&#8217;t sweat it if it&#8217;s a little awkward at first; you&#8217;re only going to use this for small weapon damage and heal spells, so it won&#8217;t get used terribly often. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/v3qzwmy2ak0.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-27351 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/v3qzwmy2ak0-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="459" height="344" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/v3qzwmy2ak0-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/v3qzwmy2ak0-1024x769.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/v3qzwmy2ak0-768x577.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/v3qzwmy2ak0-1536x1153.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/v3qzwmy2ak0.jpg 1598w" sizes="(max-width: 459px) 100vw, 459px" /></a></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a new recruit in the world of DnD and find yourself diceless, fear not &#8212; I guarantee at least one person at your table has already purchased more dice than they need. Why? Because they&#8217;re pretty and come in a lot of fun colors. They can be rainbow, neon, glow in the dark; some even have little objects suspended in the resin. And, as I&#8217;ve said before, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/players-the-pavlovian-response/">people are just like dragons</a>; we like to hoard cool, shiny things.</p>
<p>Something to note: like all things in life, nothing is perfect&#8211;not even pretty dice. If you ever hear somebody mumble about dice being cursed, they&#8217;re not just being salty. Imperfections happen.  Sometimes one side is just a little bit heavier than the rest, making it land on a certain number more often. It really depends on the manufacturer, but if you&#8217;re factoring other things like human error, if it&#8217;s a full moon, etc, I&#8217;m not sure how much it matters. If you find a die is giving you bad luck one day, switch it up for a bit! That gives you a reason to buy more dice <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>It&#8217;s said that the most accurate dice are in Las Vegas and other large, famous casinos. Real casino dice are much more expensive than your average $10-ish D&amp;D set. They&#8217;re the most precise, most evenly balanced, and least likely to screw you over (though casinos will screw you out of your money in other ways, I&#8217;m sure). If only casinos used D20s, we&#8217;d be in business with some pretty kickass dice.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re playing online, most platforms have simple add-ons or features that will do the dice rolls for you. These are technically more accurate, since they don&#8217;t have to deal with any external factors like weight and balance. I still like the tactical experience of playing with real dice, but it&#8217;s certainly a convenient option &#8212; and it&#8217;s free. Discord in particular has some &#8220;bots&#8221; that come with a bunch of features that ensure you never have to do math again. It&#8217;s a beautiful thing, though less climactic than watching a crit fail (roll of 1) or nat 20 (20 without any additional bonuses) happen in real time.</p>
<p>What say you? Do you have a shiny dice hoard? Come on, be honest!</p>
<p>Until next time, players. Let the good dice roll! ⚀⚁⚂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Players &#038; The Pavlovian Response</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/players-the-pavlovian-response/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 10:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dungeons & Discourse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Players, DMs, countrymen. Before we go into full on Dungeons &#38; Dragons mode, I&#8217;d like&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27146 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/p-dij5ljkc-254x300.jpg" alt="black puppy looking at cupcakes" width="254" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/p-dij5ljkc-254x300.jpg 254w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/p-dij5ljkc-868x1024.jpg 868w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/p-dij5ljkc-768x906.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/p-dij5ljkc.jpg 1017w" sizes="(max-width: 254px) 100vw, 254px" />Players, DMs, countrymen. Before we go into full on Dungeons &amp; Dragons mode, I&#8217;d like to start today&#8217;s post by going a bit into psychology. Don&#8217;t worry&#8211;you didn&#8217;t click on the wrong blog column. There is a method to my madness.</p>
<p>Do you know a guy named<strong> Ivan Pavlov</strong>? Probably not personally, since he hasn&#8217;t been alive for centuries, but you&#8217;ve probably heard of the phrase<strong> <em>Pavlov&#8217;s dogs</em></strong>. To keep it brief, Pavlov was a Russian scientist who studied and performed experiments on something called the &#8220;conditional response,&#8221; which is basically a fancy way of saying that a reaction becomes directly associated with or being caused something else that is seemingly neutral and unrelated. In this case, Pavlov would ring a bell every time he fed his dogs, and so his dogs came to associate the sound of the bell with food. Eventually, their mouths started to water at the sound of the bell (before they were even presented with the food) because they knew what the bell meant. You might recognize this kind of conditioning from literature (ex. the &#8220;aversion therapy&#8221; in <em>A Clockwork Orange), </em>or even every day life. When a random, seemingly inconsequential detail continually produces an unrelated but consistent reward, that&#8217;s what Pavlov was all about.</p>
<p>Why am I talking about psychology? Has <em>Dungeons &amp; Discourse </em>changed ownership? Nope, still me! But it&#8217;s more relevant to our favorite tabletop game than you might think.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/vhwoa_flio8.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-27141 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/vhwoa_flio8-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="335" height="223" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/vhwoa_flio8-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/vhwoa_flio8-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/vhwoa_flio8-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/vhwoa_flio8-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/vhwoa_flio8.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 335px) 100vw, 335px" /></a></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t want to call our lovely players dogs, so let&#8217;s call them<strong> Pavlov&#8217;s Dragons.</strong> It&#8217;s popular lore that dragons love gold and shiny objects; they like adding to their hoards, just like real players. While at times campaigns can fly off the handle, your party is more likely to aim for the objective if there is an incentive to do so. And what is that incentive? Why, gold and XP, of course! While for more experienced players, that motivation might also stem from established character traits and backstories, you really can&#8217;t go wrong with dangling loot in front of them. Think about it: why <em>else </em>would your players want to search <em>every single room in the dungeon </em>for treasure? They want m-o-n-e-y and shiny objects. We are all just dragons (real dragons?).</p>
<p>Your players will most likely be developing their characters as they go, so don&#8217;t expect them to have a firm handle on their motivations early on. While they&#8217;re working on that, they need something to keep them going. This mechanic is built into the game for a reason. It&#8217;s the launchpad for a bunch of scraggly travelers from all over the world to team up and form a party. They know if they go into a cave, they&#8217;ll probably be able to search dead bodies for loot, find hidden passageways, stumble upon hidden scrolls and gems. It&#8217;s a Pavlovian response at its core: a quest comes up and they&#8217;re already salivating for gold, even if a monetary reward doesn&#8217;t come up in the conversation. They&#8217;ll see dollar signs in their eyes the minute the request is presented to them. That&#8217;s how games (both tabletop and video alike) have taught us to respond time and time again.</p>
<p>Though now that I&#8217;m saying this, how funny would it be for a DM to make players go on a quest, only to <em>not </em>reward them in money and loot? Is that cruel? I think it would be hilarious.</p>
<p>Until next time, players. Let the good dice roll! ⚀⚁⚂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s Our Strategy?: Why You Should Roleplay in Video Games</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/whats-our-strategy-why-you-should-roleplay-in-video-games/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 11:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dungeons & Discourse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last time in our D&#38;D safe space, we talked about narrative rpgs.  Games like Dragon&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-26654 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/xc3fq-ffxri-300x200.jpg" alt="black laptop computer beside controller on brown wooden surface" width="404" height="269" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/xc3fq-ffxri-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/xc3fq-ffxri-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/xc3fq-ffxri-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/xc3fq-ffxri-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/xc3fq-ffxri-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 404px) 100vw, 404px" /></p>
<p>Last time in our D&amp;D safe space, we talked about <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/clementine-will-remember-that-aka-narrative-rpgs/">narrative rpgs.</a>  Games like <em>Dragon Age </em>and <em>Fable,</em> narrative RPGs that combine strategy and combat with decision-making, used to bore me. They would start off fun, but that excitement would begin to taper soon after the first 10 or so hours of gameplay. I always thought those kinds of games were too long, too convoluted, and way too repetitive. Granted, all of those things are all still true, but around the 40-hour mark in <em>Dragon Age: Inquisition</em>, something suddenly clicked for me.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t worry; I don&#8217;t plan on boring you with the complex plot of the <em>Dragon Age </em>series. Let me just set the stage so you. This is a game by BioWare, which&#8211;similarly to their most-famous <em>Mass Effect </em>trilogy<em>&#8212;</em>involves starting off a fresh playthrough with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/who-am-i-what-am-i-creating-your-character/">creating your own protagonist</a>. As technology progresses, this creative process continues to take longer and longer, with each developer offering more options than the previous iteration in a series. For example, <em>Cyberpunk 2077 </em>in all of its buggy, infamous glory, went so far as to offer genitals customization for your protagonist.</p>
<p>As the author of this cozy little D&amp;D column, you&#8217;d probably expect me to put two hours of design time into my protagonist. On the contrary, I didn&#8217;t think too much about creating my <em>Dragon Age </em>character. I decided to make a female elf named <em>Evelyn </em>who could use magic, simply because I thought it would be cute. Little did I know, there is a ridiculous amount of lore in this series, the developers having given reasons and stories for every bit of classism, racism, and societal hierarchy. Much of the dialogue, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-dash-of-flavor-text-dd-umami/">flavor text</a>, and events relate to the surrounding world and the war occuring within its walls. There&#8217;s fighting between the soldiers (Templars) and the mages, scorn towards the elves and the dwarves for one reason or another. One could argue what you choose for your protagonist doesn&#8217;t change that much of the game, since you can still choose to support either side of the war despite your lineage, but I&#8217;ve grown to think that this choice goes beyond the decisions made at a glance.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/by-tzimt0ms-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26656 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/by-tzimt0ms-300x225.jpg" alt="black digital device at 0 00" width="393" height="295" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/by-tzimt0ms-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/by-tzimt0ms-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/by-tzimt0ms-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/by-tzimt0ms-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/by-tzimt0ms-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 393px) 100vw, 393px" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;m about to real boil down (read: butcher) this next part of the story, but stay with me. After a certain plot-heavy quest about 30-40 hours into my game, I (or rather, <em>Evelyn, </em>my elf), was able to capture an apostate mage. He was working with his father on the opposite (read: villainous) side of the war, working as a no-good very-bad fellow. Normally in these types of video game situations, the choices are 1) let him live or 2) make him die, but not in this series! Since I had chosen a mage protagonist, I was also given him the option to come back to my castle as a prisoner, yet crucial advisor on dark magic in exchange for his life. It got me thinking, not just what I would do, but what would <em>Evelyn </em>do? My sweet little elf mage. Would she want to see one of her own killed, even if he was on the bad side of the tracks? Considering the outcome from not just a gameplay perspective, but also a storytelling perspective, made my choice that much more involved, and frankly, way more interesting.</p>
<p>Although we talked <em>about</em> narrative rpgs, it took me way too long to think about putting the &#8220;narrative<em>&#8221; </em>in <em>narrative rpg. </em>Narrative rpgs are not just for the game to tell <em>you </em>a story; they allow you to craft your <em>own </em>storyline. In many games like <em>Dragon Age</em>, your protagonist is starts as blank slate, with no personality and no appearance set in stone. This allows infinite playthroughs&#8211;and ones that are way more fun, at that.</p>
<p>With all of these possibilities, why choose to have no qualities? Why not make some choices? Just who <em>is </em>your protagonist? What are their strengths and weaknesses? What character(s) would you like to see them romantically involved with? If they were a real person, how would they react to the dialogue spoken to you throughout the game? Rather than roleplaying as a version of yourself as a default, try someone completely different! Do you always try to do the &#8220;good&#8221; thing? Play a villain! Kill innocent chickens! (And I&#8217;m not saying you should cheat on your in-game spouse, but it certainly has less consequences than doing it in real life.)</p>
<p>Use this time to be someone new, someone different. You know yourself why enough; why would you spend another 100+ in-game hours on replay?</p>
<p>Until next time, players. Let the good dice roll! ⚀⚁⚂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Clementine Will Remember That&#8230;&#8221; aka Narrative RPGs</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/clementine-will-remember-that-aka-narrative-rpgs/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/clementine-will-remember-that-aka-narrative-rpgs/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 10:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dungeons & Discourse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26128</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Forget everything I&#8217;ve been telling you about DnD for the past year&#8211;about dice rolls and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/f7nnokm1yeu-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26129 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/f7nnokm1yeu-300x199.jpg" alt="grayscale photo of female zombie" width="425" height="282" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/f7nnokm1yeu-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/f7nnokm1yeu-1024x680.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/f7nnokm1yeu-768x510.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/f7nnokm1yeu-1536x1020.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/f7nnokm1yeu-2048x1360.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 425px) 100vw, 425px" /></a></p>
<p>Forget everything I&#8217;ve been telling you about DnD for the past year&#8211;about <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/roll-the-dice-storytelling-in-real-time/">dice rolls</a> and <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/from-tabletop-to-tv-dnd-rpgs/">RNGs</a>. Let all that talk of attack strength and weapons fade from your mind. Release the brain cells that are reserved for sorcery and magic spells&#8230;.</p>
<p style="text-align: center">&#8230;Okay, now this is starting to sound like a meditation, so I&#8217;ll get to the point.</p>
<p>Last month, we talked about how tabletop games like DnD inspired many video games, including the RPG (role-playing game) genre. It was easy to track how elements transferred over, from HP and stats, to backstories and motivations. We defined RPGs as games that prioritize battling, whether it be via a menu or using real-time attack, and place importance on &#8220;leveling up&#8221; and gaining new skills.</p>
<p>What if I told you that there is a subgenre of RPGs where none of that matters?</p>
<p style="text-align: center">Enter: the narrative RPG.</p>
<p><em>What is that? </em>You might ask. <em>Aren&#8217;t all RPGs narrative</em><em>? </em>Well, more of less to varying degrees, but Narrative RPGs in particular make <strong>storytelling </strong>the priority. Lay down your swords, because you won&#8217;t be needing them here. These RPGs are <em>all </em>about the story, and let you&#8211;the player&#8211;be the one to tell it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26131 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/nmk1vggt2hg-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="374" height="249" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/nmk1vggt2hg-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/nmk1vggt2hg-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/nmk1vggt2hg-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/nmk1vggt2hg-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/nmk1vggt2hg-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 374px) 100vw, 374px" /></p>
<p>One of these most popular franchises is <em>The Walking Dead</em>. TellTale Games, albeit a questionable game company for their <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/3/20/17130056/telltale-games-developer-layoffs-toxic-video-game-industry">unhealthy labor practices</a>, really cemented the genre with this narrative series. Your main interaction in the game isn&#8217;t physically fighting off zombies; instead, it&#8217;s choosing your words wisely to your fellow humans (NPCs), because they will always come back to bite you (pun intended). Despite their non-playability, their memories of the things you tell these non-playable characters and the actions you take with them play quite the role in the realm of the plot. It&#8217;s very much a choose-your-own-adventure game, in the way you won&#8217;t know which direction a choice takes you in until it&#8217;s too late.</p>
<p>Take a look at <a href="https://i0.wp.com/venturebeat.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/the-walking-dead-graph-by-gamesbeat.jpg?strip=all">this flow chart</a> of the order of events available in the first <em>Walking Dead</em> game. Though some of your choices might seem inconsequential, its development really paved the way for this new world of video game storytelling. You&#8217;re not quite the Dungeon Master of the game, because you don&#8217;t have omniscient foresight of the plot, but you&#8217;re also more powerful than one single party member of a campaign. Your actions are the sole progressor of the story, even if you don&#8217;t always know where they&#8217;ll next you next.</p>
<p>Other games you might have heard of in this genre have similar linearities, like the <em>Life is Strange </em>series and, the very-fitting-for-Halloween <em>Until Dawn</em>. Each one has their own twist to make it special; <em>Until Dawn </em>utilizes Quick Time Events to test your reflexes, and gives you very little time to make your decisions, while <em>Life is Strange </em>has a &#8220;rewind&#8221; feature that allows you to see multiple outcomes without committing. It&#8217;s the perfect genre for those who are new to video games, who was to see the story unfold without having to &#8220;grind&#8221; in battle through standard RPG combat. Much like DnD, Narrative RPGs aren&#8217;t about how deftly your thumbs can press buttons on a controller, but how quickly you can consider your options and think on your feet. It&#8217;s like virtual improv!</p>
<p>Of course, some games toe the line of this subgenre. Series like <em>Dragon Age and Mass Effect </em>combine exciting combat with decision-making. You have dialogue options that will gravely affect the plot, but you can also swing your sword around as much as you want if you&#8217;d rather focus on that. For those who <em>want it all</em>, these types of RPGs have the best of both worlds so you never get bored, like a video game buffet. Just like DnD campaigns, these games can go in whatever direction you wish&#8211;you just might not know where you&#8217;re headed until you&#8217;re already there.</p>
<p>Until then, players, let the good dice roll! ⚀⚁⚂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/clementine-will-remember-that-aka-narrative-rpgs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From Tabletop to TV: DnD &#038; RPGs</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/from-tabletop-to-tv-dnd-rpgs/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/from-tabletop-to-tv-dnd-rpgs/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dungeons & Discourse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you a fan of video games? Do you regularly enjoy franchises like Final Fantasy,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you a <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/are-ya-winning-son">fan of video games</a>? Do you regularly enjoy franchises like <em>Final Fantasy, Kingdom Hearts,</em> or the <em>Mana</em> series? If so, even if you&#8217;ve never played Dungeons and Dragons, you probably know more about it than you think! Many classic video games, especially role-playing games (or RPGs), find their roots from tabletop gaming.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever seen the term RNG but didn&#8217;t know what it meant, it stands for Random Number Generator, and is essentially the computer equivalent to a dice roll (<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/roll-the-dice-storytelling-in-real-time/"><em>sound familiar?)</em></a>. In this case, game developers input a possible number range (for example, the number of damage your level four fighter can do to an enemy with his sword) and the computer &#8220;rolls the dice&#8221; in real time when you attack.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25947 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/xiisv6ashjy-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="413" height="275" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/xiisv6ashjy-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/xiisv6ashjy-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/xiisv6ashjy-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/xiisv6ashjy-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/xiisv6ashjy-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 413px) 100vw, 413px" /></p>
<p>I&#8217;m no historian, but I played a lot of video games growing up. In my younger years, games like early installations of the<em> Final Fantasy</em> series had a blank canvas when it came to characters and personalities. This, like D&amp;D, allowed you to fill in the blanks and make up your character&#8217;s &#8220;role&#8221; when playing the game. Even when there were less customization options in the early days of gaming, it was still something you could make your own&#8211;because there wasn&#8217;t as much specifically laid out for you. Decades later, webcomics like <a href="https://www.nuklearpower.com/2001/03/14/episode-005-run-heroes-run/">8-Bit Theater</a> still use this open world of possibilities like a playground, because it allowed for so much freedom and interpretation.</p>
<p>A groundbreaking difference between D&amp;D and<em> Final Fantasy </em>and other RPGs is that instead of just your main character, you have control over the <em>whole party</em>. In that sense,<em> Final Fantasy</em> makes you the DM of your own story. How <em>cool </em>is that? Although you don&#8217;t have as much control over the plot as a DM might, the ability to pick the classes and concentrations of the whole cast is such a wild possibility.</p>
<p>In 1992, five years after the original, <em>Final Fantasy V</em> introduced a massive &#8220;job&#8221; system that allowed you to make your party whatever classes you could possibly want, branching out as the story progressed from typical D&amp;D classes like thieves and barbarians into jobs like gladiators, necromancers, and dancers. To be both the protagonist and the Dungeon Master in a game is a really interesting twist that doesn&#8217;t get nearly enough credit!</p>
<p>On the other side of the coin, <em>Final Fantasy IV, VI, </em>and <em>VII</em> began concentrating on defining your protagonist&#8217;s role in the story. Rather than naming your voiceless character in the beginning of the game, you were given a pre-made protagonist who already had a distinct personality and a major role to play in the plot. Essentially you are given a <em>role </em>to play, which really gives the term <em>role-playing game </em>its name. Characters were also given more dialogue, more intense storylines, and plots with unforeseeable twists, just like in film. Video games today can be mistaken for movies at times, and this is where it all began!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25946 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/71vdy9v_wfk-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="413" height="275" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/71vdy9v_wfk-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/71vdy9v_wfk-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/71vdy9v_wfk-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/71vdy9v_wfk-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/71vdy9v_wfk-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 413px) 100vw, 413px" /></p>
<p>Fast forward to today, where series like <em>Dragon Age, Fable</em>, and <em>Mass Effect </em>advance the world of character personalization by leaps and bounds. Nowadays, you have more control over your character than ever before. You can make critical decisions in the storyline that have severe impacts on not only the plot, but how other characters view your protagonist. Did you decide to kill that captured renegade, or did you give him a second chance to turn a new leaf? (Most importantly, did you kick a lot of innocent chickens in <em>Fable</em>?). These choices often affect your <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/beyond-good-and-evil-morality-part-one/">moral alignment</a>, and can have other effects such as what quests are available, down to what armor your character is allowed to wear.</p>
<p>Not only is your moral alignment at your fingertips, but these games also give you significantly more control when it comes to your character&#8217;s appearance and physical features. You might think you&#8217;re playing a lifestyle simulator, like The Sims, rather than an RPG when you start. Just when you think we&#8217;ve reached the pinnacle of game design, and that the most recent game can&#8217;t possibly be more detailed, another game is one-up&#8217;ed by the next. <em>Cyberpunk 2077</em> might have gotten flack for being a little glitchy upon release, but it can&#8217;t be argued that the character creator is absolutely insane with the amount of details you have control over, from scars and tattoos, to even more &#8220;sensitive areas&#8221; that might not ever see the light of day. (You might have seen the meme about how in <em>Red Dead Redemption 2, </em>Rockstar Games really <a href="https://www.pcgamesn.com/red-dead-redemption-2/red-dead-redemption-2-horse-testicles">outdid themselves with the realism.</a>) And I for, one, couldn&#8217;t be more excited to see where video games take us next.</p>
<p>Until then, players, let the good dice roll! ⚀⚁⚂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/from-tabletop-to-tv-dnd-rpgs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Dash of Flavor Text: D&#038;D Umami</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-dash-of-flavor-text-dd-umami/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 10:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dungeons & Discourse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tabletop gaming is a lot like cooking: there are different flavors you can utilize to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25535 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/aas9mblcer0-225x300.jpg" alt="happy birthday to you neon light signage" width="300" height="400" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/aas9mblcer0-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/aas9mblcer0-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/aas9mblcer0-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/aas9mblcer0-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/aas9mblcer0-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Tabletop gaming is a lot like cooking: there are different flavors you can utilize to make your dish tasty and unique. Not every flavor is going to be used in every recipe, because that would be disgusting, but you can punch up a few to make a recipe go from good to great. Of course, not everyone likes the same thing&#8211;as they say <em>different strokes for different folks</em> (or, a better alternative, <em>different games for different dames), </em>but they&#8217;re all tools at your DM Disposal.</p>
<p>We have covered so many basic DnD components in this little blog column here on LSQ, from creative character building to stellar setting creation. Now that we all have a general understanding of what it takes to make a DnD campaign, we can move on to the <em>really </em>fun stuff. That&#8217;s right, I&#8217;m talking about the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qRStS3xtXU4"><em>creme de la creme</em></a><i>: </i>the special little ornaments that make a game memorable, that set it apart in your mind from all the rest. These are the campaigns that come to the forefront mind when you think about how much you love this game, the ones that overwrite all of the boring or dull ones you&#8217;ve been begrudgingly a part of. It truly is the little things in life, and DnD life is no exception!</p>
<p>As we go more in-depth, there are sadly less specifics I can share with you. This is where we start deviating from the <a href="https://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/dungeon-masters-guide">Dungeon Master&#8217;s Guide</a> and start really making the game your own. Although DnD is the most popular and well-known tabletop game, there are dozens to choose from, and many use DnD simply as a gateway drug to more freestyle gaming titles. Unlike expensive board games, sometimes all tabletop games require is a pencil and an idea, making them pretty accessible to anyone who wants to try it out. (That being said, you will probably find yourself spending money on it anyway. They don&#8217;t make <a href="https://www.redbubble.com/i/pouch/Yes-I-Really-Do-Need-All-These-Dice-Tabletop-RPG-by-pixeptional/32999471.440R3">dice bags this big</a> because people <em>need </em>all those dice).</p>
<p>Without further ado, here are a few flavors that stepped campaigns I was a part of (either as a player or DM) up a notch.</p>
<h3><strong>Add Spice to Combat </strong></h3>
<p>It&#8217;s so easy, especially for newer players, to get bored with combat quickly. This is especially true with physical attackers, whose characters can get into a rut with repeatedly swinging their club/axe/pointy-stabby weapon around. There can be a few reasons for this, but to force your players to think more creatively, you&#8217;ll have to <strong>give them a place to start. </strong>Set your expectations. Make sure they keep it focused on the storytelling, using the dice as a tool rather than a crystal ball. Tell them to think first and act second, to picture it cinematically. What would be cool or interesting to watch if this campaign was a movie? Whether the end result is comical or devastating is for the dice to decide, but the initial plan for action is on the player.</p>
<h3><strong>Confiscate Ingredients</strong></h3>
<p>Just like in Alton Brown&#8217;s diabolical show,<em> Cutthroat Kitchen</em>, <strong>put limitations in play </strong>to narrow the scope of the player&#8217;s actions. How cool would a battle be where the floor is lava, literally, so<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25696 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/qup5rl_e5oe-300x200.jpg" alt="candy pack lot" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/qup5rl_e5oe-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/qup5rl_e5oe-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/qup5rl_e5oe-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/qup5rl_e5oe-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/qup5rl_e5oe-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> they can&#8217;t set foot on the ground? What tools can you give them to make this battle possible? How <em>will </em>he make that tomato sauce taste good without any garlic? (<em>spoilers: he can&#8217;t)</em>. Taking options away and making them work with a smaller purview could call for some pretty creative problem solving!</p>
<h3><strong>Consider the Senses</strong></h3>
<p>Experts say you &#8220;eat with your eyes first,&#8221; and they&#8217;re not wrong! It&#8217;s not just about how the dish tastes, but it also has to <em>look </em>appetizing. Although writers say to use all the five senses when writing, it&#8217;s easy to forget a couple along the way. In DnD, it might be easiest to describe things visually, but what does it feel like? Does the air smell funny? I stumbled upon <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DnDBehindTheScreen/comments/458epf/dungeon_dressing/">this table</a> on &#8220;adding set dressing&#8221; on Reddit that works for some last-minute inspiration to get those writer juices flowing. Try rolling a die and just seeing where it lands! Having to incorporate a quality that might not have easily fit prior is a good opportunity for you to add something unexpected to the scene!</p>
<h3><strong>Incorporate a Side Dish</strong></h3>
<p>Who doesn&#8217;t love a good side quest? Having a main goal for the party is essential to any DnD campaign, but sprinkling in other opportunities for NPC interaction, reward-seeking, and miscellaneous events can keep players on their toes. One time, I had the town my players were staying in be the host of a community fishing tournament. It was just a one-off line said by an NPC to create a colorful environment, but every player was immediately intrigued by this idea and <em>they all wanted to participate. </em>Naturally, it turned into a 20-30 minute detour, but it was a lot of spontaneous fun!. Naturally, I had to make up a bunch of information on the fly, but it was worth it. Don&#8217;t be afraid to add details that might not &#8220;mean anything&#8221; to the main quest, for there is always a side quest just waiting to be explored!</p>
<p>These are only a few suggestions of the many, many things you could do to <em>season your campaign</em>, so to speak. All this talk about food is making me hungry. Whose turn was it to bring the snacks this week?</p>
<p>Until next time, players. Let the good dice roll! ⚀⚁⚂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tabletop Tunes: Selecting a DnD Soundtrack</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/tabletop-tunes-selecting-a-dnd-soundtrack/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 11:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dungeons & Discourse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When you think of Dungeons &#38; Dragons, what comes to mind first? Whimsical adventure? Medieval-style fantasy plots?&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jahdphmoaea-scaled.jpg"><br />
</a><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-25315 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jahdphmoaea-300x200.jpg" alt="woman standing watching LED light musical instrument" width="485" height="323" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jahdphmoaea-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jahdphmoaea-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jahdphmoaea-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jahdphmoaea-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jahdphmoaea-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 485px) 100vw, 485px" /></p>
<p>When you think of <em>Dungeons &amp; Dragons, </em>what comes to mind first? Whimsical adventure? Medieval-style fantasy plots? Elves running amok? Whatever it is, it&#8217;s likely that <strong>music</strong> is not the first thought. Why would it be? This isn&#8217;t a concert; it&#8217;s a tabletop game!</p>
<p>Ever notice in a horror movie when the music cuts out and everything starts to go eerily silent? Subconsciously, even if we don&#8217;t know it yet, we&#8217;re preparing ourselves for something bad or scary to happen. Not just in the horror genre, though&#8211;music is extremely useful when it comes to setting the tone in all kinds of media. When the rain starts to fall and the character cries over their lost loved one, a soft piano can be often heard lilting in the distance. When the characters are grinding at a club, you hear the bumping beat that they&#8217;re dancing to, and sometimes it makes you want to dance, too. If it is has the power to make us feel things so strongly in movies, why <em>shouldn&#8217;t</em> we use it in D&amp;D? Like in movies, music can help your players know what the vibe of the scene is, what kind of story they&#8217;re telling right now, and help them get into character.</p>
<p>Every DM has their own approach to how to they add music and soundtracks to their campaign. Personally, I prefer songs without words, softly playing in the background, just to fill the empty silence. If it gets too distracting, it might actually do the opposite and take your players <em>out </em>of the game. Before your players start acting OOC (out-of-character), try to strike a balance between setting the scene and stealing the show!</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve never put your campaign to music before, don&#8217;t worry&#8211;I&#8217;ve got you covered! Here&#8217;s some Soundtrack &#8216;Spo to get you started:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Your favorite action RPG soundtracks</strong>. Nothing gets a session going like some video game music! I have really good luck with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VZ4ZOsBovyc">Dragon Age: Inquisition</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4r_5A6K7gu0">Witcher 3</a>, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dd10InDdvJE&amp;t=1896s">Skyrim</a> for general mood music. Try searching for your video game OST of the moment on YouTube and see what you can find!</li>
<li><strong>Bardcore. </strong>I&#8217;m obsessed with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ne8fzMxX2Ps&amp;t=18s">Dungeon Synth</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FnOEGvEKFSQ">Medieval Style</a> song covers. You can find <em>so </em>many wonderful artists on just YouTube alone doing crazy-genius things with popular, pre-existing songs. This cover of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ugqQlB5fpuc"><em>Jolene </em></a>is awesome for some <em>ye olde towne</em> music!</li>
<li><strong>Tabletop Audio. </strong><a href="https://tabletopaudio.com/">This site</a> is 100% free and has an <em>insane </em>selection. It beats Netflix for most obscure categories, including <em>Mysterious Grotto</em>, <em>Oregon Trail,</em> and <em>Nordic Noir.</em> And they all <em>slap</em>.</li>
<li><strong>Reddit: </strong>Somehow I&#8217;m always surprised, but yes, there&#8217;s a <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/DnDPlaylist/">subreddit</a> for this.</li>
<li><strong>Check Amazon Music: </strong>If you have an Amazon membership, you can find some really cool music on there for free! <a href="https://smile.amazon.com/Chronicle-Black-Sword-Hawkwind/dp/B002C6EQR8/ref=sr_1_1?s=dmusic&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1493043683&amp;sr=1-1-mp3-albums-bar-strip-0&amp;keywords=Hawkwind+Chronicle+of+the+Black+Sword">Hawkwind</a> is a little more attention-grabbing than most of this list, but if not played too loudly, I think they could provide some sweet battle tunes.</li>
<li><strong>Select from My Favorites: </strong>If you&#8217;re looking for something more grab-and-go, here are a few playlists already curated for your listening pleasure: <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/0ajFLRP6joCaqfLkVYKnkq">nature sounds</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/40H1Drwhd8O0FT8uz7tSh9">town and tavern songs</a><a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/1Uz8FLQzXY2mtnXKvF7exJ">, and battle music </a>(credit: Janna Chapman)</li>
<li><strong>And, if all else fails,</strong> there&#8217;s always <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wl-HPIu5kcs">ten hours of sea shanties</a>.</li>
</ul>
<div class="entry-content">
<div>Until next time, players. Let the good dice roll! ⚀⚁⚂</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Are You Sure You Want To Do That?&#8221; &#038; Other Warnings</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/are-you-sure-you-want-to-do-that-other-warnings/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 10:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dungeons & Discourse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[  Have you ever watched a video so aggravating that you couldn&#8217;t wait to force&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25098 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/do1i_fwbbcw-300x225.jpg" alt="green and brown concrete wall" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/do1i_fwbbcw-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/do1i_fwbbcw-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/do1i_fwbbcw-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/do1i_fwbbcw-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/do1i_fwbbcw-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div><i> </i></div>
<div>Have you ever watched a video so aggravating that you couldn&#8217;t <i>wait </i>to force your friend to see it? Not that it was particularly enjoyable on your first viewing, but making someone else share in your misery allows the second viewing to be far more fun (I&#8217;m looking at you, <i><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QrGrOK8oZG8">Too Many Cooks</a></i>). Sometimes, that&#8217;s what being a DM is like. You know what&#8217;s coming, and you&#8217;re just watching with all-knowing eyes as your surprise unfolds. It&#8217;s not unlike the sensation of buying someone a Christmas present and dangling clues above their head all month long. (Oh, does no one else do that? Just me? Oops).</div>
<div></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div>DMs are not all ambivalent creatures, however! We will not make you suffer without blinking an eye. If you are going to make a stupid decision, chances are we will try to warn you. As citizens living in the world we created, we care about you. We want you to succeed. We don&#8217;t want you to die (also because integrating a new character to replace one that died can be a pain in the donkey&#8217;s heinie).</div>
<div></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="text-align: center"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-25105" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/eehbs1punxk-300x181.jpg" alt="Mind The Step signage" width="300" height="181" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/eehbs1punxk-300x181.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/eehbs1punxk-1024x616.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/eehbs1punxk-768x462.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/eehbs1punxk-1536x924.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/eehbs1punxk-2048x1232.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div>When you hear the DM say any of the phrases below, take it as a word of caution. These are the words to watch out for. Heed my words, players. Don&#8217;t take these sentences lightly!</div>
<div></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div>When the DM says: <b>&#8220;You hear the whole dungeon tremble around you.&#8221;</b></div>
<div><u>What you should do</u>: detect magic, listen for monsters, find traps, search for threats&#8230;<br />
Most balanced parties will have at least one member who has some sort of detection or search skill. Keep your guard up and try not to get ambushed! (If they don&#8217;t, it&#8217;s possible you made a party of five barbarians, <i>again, </i>failing the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/session-0-the-game-before-the-game/">character creation session</a> once more.) (<i>&#8220;But they&#8217;re just so powerful!&#8221;</i> you say, as your barbarian falls to one hit of a magic missile.) (But I digress.)</div>
<div></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div>When you roll a perception check and ask if you found anything, to which the DM replies, &#8220;<b>Maybe!&#8221;</b><br />
<u>What you should do</u>: Tear that room apart!</div>
<div>Unless your DM is a sadist (it happens) or simply has a dark sense of humor (this also happens), chances are there <i>is </i>something in that area, and it&#8217;s up to you to find it. Maybe it&#8217;s an entrance to a secret room. Maybe it&#8217;s a hidden treasure. Maybe the DM is just messing with you, but think outside the box and don&#8217;t give up until you find out!</div>
<div></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div>When you ask for advice on how to proceed and the DM says, <b>&#8220;You have people you can ask&#8230;&#8221;</b><br />
<u>What you should do</u>: Talk to nearby NPC(s)!</div>
<div>NPCs are a great tool DMs use to deliver important information without feeling like they&#8217;re overstepping or backseat driving. Oftentimes, they&#8217;re there to serve as your guide. If you get stuck or don&#8217;t know what to do, take advantage of them! They were created <i>for </i>you! An added bonus is getting to know the NPC more as a fleshed-out character. Who knows? You might even be able to recruit them to your party!</div>
<div></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div>When the DM says: <b>&#8220;Are you sure you want to do that?&#8221;</b><br />
The session comes to a halt. The phrase that makes every player in the room look up. All side conversations are immediately silenced as everyone waits with bated breath. When the DM asks this, you should say, <i>Just kidding! No, I don&#8217;t!!!<br />
</i><u>What you should do</u>: NOT THAT. <i>Anything </i>but that.<br />
Also sounds like: <b>&#8220;You <i>could </i>do that, but <u>so-and-so/NPC</u> might not like it.&#8221;</b></div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div>Don&#8217;t say I didn&#8217;t warn you!</div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div>Until next time, players. Let the good dice roll! ⚀⚁⚂</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Session #0: The Game Before the Game</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/session-0-the-game-before-the-game/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/session-0-the-game-before-the-game/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 10:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Dungeons & Discourse]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You might be thinking, &#8220;Session 0? That doesn&#8217;t make any sense! The first number in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-24791 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/um5_ng2ssc-300x169.jpg" alt="pink Star Here text" width="509" height="287" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/um5_ng2ssc-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/um5_ng2ssc-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/um5_ng2ssc-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/um5_ng2ssc-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/um5_ng2ssc-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 509px) 100vw, 509px" /></p>
<p>You might be thinking, &#8220;Session 0? That doesn&#8217;t make any sense! The first number in a series should be one!&#8221; And you&#8217;re half correct. Although the first game <em>session </em>should be #1, there&#8217;s always some prep work to do before you start the campaign, and this is popularly dubbed in the DnD community as &#8220;session zero.&#8221;</p>
<p>Since every GM (Game Master) runs their game a little differently, everyone has different things they like to cover in this precursor session. Today, I&#8217;m going to cover my personal Session 0 Essentials.</p>
<p><strong>HOUSE RULES<br />
</strong>In March&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/because-i-said-so-rules-regulations/">blog post</a>, we talked about laying the laws of your land&#8211;not just the DnD game rules, but the general guidelines to follow in your particular campaign. Are there any uncommon changes that you&#8217;ve made to the base game that players might not know off the bat? Is your DM style more of player-driven sandbox, letting them explore as they see fit, or more like a subway, confined to the tracks going in a specific direction? (My preference is a mixture of both, but that&#8217;s a story for another day&#8211;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/improvisation-vs-preparation-finding-the-balance/">this day</a>, in fact).</p>
<p><em>Other things to think about: How will experience work? Will there be leveling up in this campaign? How many sessions will the plot cover? Do you award inspiration points? </em>In a previous game I played in, the DM gave an inspiration point to whoever recalled the most about our last session and could explain to the rest of us what happened in case we forgot. I loved this feature! It made everyone more likely to pay attention and be present, even if they weren&#8217;t the one acting at that moment. I was never that person, because I have the memory of a pea (even with note-taking), but that person was the true MVP! You could also assign a person to be the scribe of the group, for their own goodwill or for a reward of some kind. The world is your oyster&#8211;that is, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/using-foils-in-dnd-shining-a-literary-spotlight/">if your world has oysters</a>. <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">I have to say this every time now, it&#8217;s a meme at this point.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-24798 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zni0zgb3bkq-300x201.jpg" alt="black marker on notebook" width="331" height="222" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zni0zgb3bkq-300x201.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zni0zgb3bkq-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zni0zgb3bkq-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zni0zgb3bkq-1536x1027.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/zni0zgb3bkq-2048x1369.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 331px) 100vw, 331px" /></p>
<p><strong>PLAYING SCHEDULE</strong><br />
I don&#8217;t know why more DnD blogs don&#8217;t cover this, because it&#8217;s super important! How often will you all be meeting to play? Once a week? Once every two weeks? If you are all set to play every Tuesday at 7pm, and one member works every Tuesday night, you&#8217;ll know early on that either you need to change the meeting time, or that player is not a good fit for the campaign. If you don&#8217;t establish a gaming schedule early on, the campaign is bound to dwindle off. The players will only be as enthused about it as you are, so be upfront about availability early on.</p>
<p>In the same vein, be upfront about duration. How long do you think your sessions will be? This can be flexible, but do you have a ballpark in mind? Personally, when sessions go longer than two hours, I know my creativity&#8211;and overall brain function&#8211;begin to decline. My friends know that I am a grandma in essence, so we to start around 7-8PM and finish by around 10PM, so any longer than that and my roleplaying will suffer. If a player says they&#8217;re available Tuesday at 7, but have to be somewhere by 8, that might not make for a very long or intense session. If your sessions only take an hour, however (I envy you; it can sometimes take 30-45 minutes for us to start), then you know that will be fine. What are your expectations?</p>
<p><em>Other things to think about: Will you be playing in-person or virtually (using Discord or another program). If playing in-person, will you rotate houses, or will it always be at the same location? And most importantly: who is in charge of the DnD snacks? </em>Salty, crunchy snacks are my favorite!</p>
<p><strong>CHARACTER CREATION<br />
</strong>Arguably the most important goal of Session #0: creating your characters! Although this could be done by everyone on their own time, there are so many benefits to doing it as a group. Such as:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Group bonding! </strong>If this is a new DnD group, even if you&#8217;re all already friends outside of playing, you will quickly discover the dynamics of how you all might interact in-game! The more you know about each other in real life, the better partners you will be (even if your <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/who-am-i-what-am-i-creating-your-character/">characters</a> hate each other in-game).</li>
<li><strong>Broadening Skill Sets:</strong> In one campaign I played, we all accidentally picked magic classes, leaving us at a high disadvantage when it came to physical attacks and defense. Our one (1) paladin was not enough to protect us. It was a war zone. Convincing your players to cover a bunch of bases skill-wise will make things more varied and interesting for them, <em>and </em>easier for you, since you won&#8217;t have to worry about a random battle featuring one (1) goblin accidentally killing the whole party.</li>
<li><b>Insider Knowledge: </b>As the DM, it&#8217;s essential you know everyone&#8217;s characters inside-and-out so you can prepare, but it&#8217;s wonderful to have the players be in-the-know, too! Not that you should give away all of your secret plans, but the players don&#8217;t have to be limited to things only their characters would know. It can be a great way to get characters to bond. In one game I played, two players realized their characters were the only ones who could speak a certain language, so they would occasionally have their characters whisper to each other and gossip. Even if the rest of our characters couldn&#8217;t tell what they were saying, it was hilarious to hear their dialogue out loud (in plain English, for us humans). Little colorful moments like that really make a game memorable and fun.</li>
</ol>
<p>A productive Session #0 can make for a smooth-sailing campaign. It&#8217;s all about front-loading prepwork so you can have twice as much fun later!</p>
<p>Until next time, players. Let the good dice roll! ⚀⚁⚂</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/session-0-the-game-before-the-game/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
