<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Fearless Thoughts &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/fearless-thoughts/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 14:04:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Just a Single Dollar Bill</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/just-a-single-dollar-bill/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 14:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fearless Thoughts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Can we make a change in someone else’s life just by sending good thoughts, prayers,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17726 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ben-white-gEKMstKfZ6w-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ben-white-gEKMstKfZ6w-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ben-white-gEKMstKfZ6w-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ben-white-gEKMstKfZ6w-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ben-white-gEKMstKfZ6w-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ben-white-gEKMstKfZ6w-unsplash-2048x1367.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Can we make a change in someone else’s life just by sending good thoughts, prayers, energy?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Holding someone in the center of our thoughts to such an extent that a shift can happen in their lives?</p>
<p dir="ltr">The online encyclopedia Britannica has this to say about the definition of energy:</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;Energy is the process of transfer from one body to another.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr">So according to science, we are indeed capable of transferring energy to another. Personally, I have been growing in this awareness for several years to amazing results.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This transference is not always for the good. The mass hysteria that has swept through the world over the coronavirus is a blaring example of how energy can be spread from one person to another. I am not talking about the virus itself. I am talking about how, as humans, we have a tendency to hook our energy to others, merge together, and create a mob mentality. This is never more apparent than during what gets classified as a global crisis. I think the fear of this virus will cause more problems than the actual virus will. Leave humanity to sort this out, and at some point, this current frenzy will play itself out. My energy can be spent in more positive ways.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Looking at someone we don’t know in the checkout line, passing on the street, in another car, or next to someone in an elevator, we are drawn to compassion. We don’t know why. Often the moment passes quickly as our minds move on to more important things. What if we take a second once we realize we&#8217;re in that moment and send thoughts of healing for that person? Can that make a difference to them? Does it cost us anything personally if we do?</p>
<p dir="ltr">I believe we can make such a difference. Although we will never know what the outcome of that person’s worries might be, we can see them whole, well, and loved in our minds. It takes only a second in the doing. It also takes some training our minds to have this be the reaction to the compassion we feel toward another. But it can happen; in fact, it often does.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Recently I had such an encounter that was so extraordinary and a perfect example of how my energy can affect those around me. That like-minded people’s energy can connect with mine to create an awesome result while waiting for a traffic light to change.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As I left work yesterday I was sitting at a very busy light. Often people who are homeless panhandle there. I was maybe fifth in line and watched an older man in rough physical shape begging for money as the rain just poured off him. I couldn&#8217;t easily reach him, but I had a dollar sitting on the passenger seat leftover from coffee I just purchased that I wanted to give him.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I said out loud: &#8220;Someone is going to offer you money.&#8221; Up to that point no one ahead of me had <img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17728 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/annie-spratt-BJ3g2Ck2WfE-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/annie-spratt-BJ3g2Ck2WfE-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/annie-spratt-BJ3g2Ck2WfE-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/annie-spratt-BJ3g2Ck2WfE-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/annie-spratt-BJ3g2Ck2WfE-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/annie-spratt-BJ3g2Ck2WfE-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />so much as rolled a window down; the rain was in sheets, pelted down sideways in the wind. But I persisted in seeing a hand reach out and give a dollar to him.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I imagined a ribbon of energy flowing from me and connecting with the other drivers. I knew human compassion meant someone else would also want to help.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The light finally turned green, but the guy at the head of the line of cars jumped out of his truck, ignoring the signal, and ran back to the man and handed him a dollar bill. Then hands came out of every car window and started to offer the man money. People behind me were rolling down their windows with dollar bills in them! The man, hampered by a bad limp and aided by a cane, was hobbling to each car as fast as he could with a look of total bewilderment.</p>
<p dir="ltr">We had to all wait through another round of light changes, as more hands offered dollar bills. Only afterward did I realize that not one person HONKED when we missed the first green light. That alone is an amazing act.</p>
<p dir="ltr">When it was my turn to pass, I was grinning like a fool as I handed him my dollar and said I hoped he was having a good day! He said in reply, “I don&#8217;t know what the hell just happened.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">But I did. People sharing energy, finding a common outlet for their energy, sharing compassion for another human being. Not because our mothers told us to be kind to others, not because we learned in Sunday school to take care of those less fortunate than ourselves.</p>
<p dir="ltr">No, this was about the Universal love that runs through every cell in our bodies. This was about my energy, being sent out, growing as it gravitated toward others whose energy was searching to connect.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Yes, I do believe we can send our good thoughts, well wishes, our energy to others and make a difference for them and for ourselves. Those of us who freely give our energy to another never feel a lack. We are never drained by the gift we give. Energy is never-ending and infinite, and it is in every living thing on this planet and beyond. We are all connected by it. At some point, I will feel that energy come back to me, fuller and brighter and filling every broken part of me.</p>
<p dir="ltr">If you don’t believe me, try it for yourself. Experience the feeling that will radiate through your body when you simply offer your considerable healing energy toward someone. That feeling of total oneness with the Universe is your gift. A gift I know will carry you through your whole day.</p>
<p dir="ltr">With love and light,</p>
<p dir="ltr">Anna O’Keefe</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Little Magic</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/little-magic/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/little-magic/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 11:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fearless Thoughts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17056</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Does magic exist? Do miracles happen? And what exactly do we call a miracle or&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Does magic exist? Do miracles happen? And what exactly do we call a miracle or magic anyway?</p>
<p dir="ltr">A topic much better schooled scholars and mystics alike have debated through the ages.</p>
<p dir="ltr">From my small corner of the Universe, I can only share my own experiences and what has become my truth, my story.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So here I am in the deep of winter’s darkness pondering these questions. For me, the answer is yes to both questions and magic <em>does</em> exist and miracles <em>do</em> happen in small incredible ways when I least expect it. I had such a magical moment on Christmas Day.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I sat at the little table where I used to put make-up on and do my hair, and a little ladybug dropped into my hand. Where she came from, I could not say but she was crawling all over my fingers and would open her wings and flit to the mirror and back again. My little spotted visitor <img decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-17244 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vincent-van-zalinge-oBL5QRAxZzo-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vincent-van-zalinge-oBL5QRAxZzo-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vincent-van-zalinge-oBL5QRAxZzo-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vincent-van-zalinge-oBL5QRAxZzo-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vincent-van-zalinge-oBL5QRAxZzo-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vincent-van-zalinge-oBL5QRAxZzo-unsplash-2048x1367.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />was very lively, landing on my shirt and in my hair. It was bitterly cold outside and not ladybug season. I knew at once that magic was happening right in the palm of my hand. I have learned that in moments like this I do not try to analyze the hows and whys of things. Just let them be and enjoy them fully.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And I knew with certainty that this little visitor was my mom, having died when I was twelve, coming to show me love and send me Christmas greetings.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I had been thinking of my mom for weeks. Christmas was her favorite season, loving every part of the preparations and celebration. The day after Thanksgiving through the end of the year she was in her happy place. She baked and decorated and shopped for presents. We set up the manger under the tree, placing the animals and shepherds in odd places around the little bit of straw we had out. The tree was decorated with ornaments she had collected over our many travels throughout the world, tagging along with our military dad. I can remember coming in from the cold and being greeting with not just warmth but surrounded by the smell of spices and sugar from the baking she had done that day. So seeing her show up in the form of this sweet little ladybug was not a surprise. It made me smile and brought tears to my eyes.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I believe that the way to have magic in our lives is to be open to it. To keep our hearts openly vigilant to the possibility. That way we allow the Universe to delight us in remarkable ways. Being willing to be open is the miracle. Humans are not wired to accept things that we can not explain. If we get to that place where we are saying ‘yes!’ to the Universe, our worlds begin to embrace mysteries others can not even perceive.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This morning as I was driving to The Common Market in Frederick, Maryland, to write my blog, the moon was huge and bright in the sky at 8 am, still high but reluctantly making her descent into the west. I had to stop and watch her glory. It was amazing to me and a moment of pure magic. What a splendid way to start the day. But I know I would not have even seen her hanging brightly in the morning sky if my heart was not open to it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Watching the ladybug crawl over me, tickling the fine hairs on my arms, I could do nothing more than be thankful for such a gift.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Merry Christmas, Mom,” I said as she opened her wings and took off behind the drapes.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Magic and miracles. How have they shown up in your life? I would love to have you share.</p>
<p dir="ltr">With love &amp; magic,</p>
<p dir="ltr">Anna O’Keefe</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/little-magic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Library Shame: Part 2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/my-library-shame-part-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fearless Thoughts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17024</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Part 1 of this two-part series appeared on the LSQ blog on Monday. &#8211;Blog Ed.]&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17115 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-768x1151.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-1025x1536.jpg 1025w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-1367x2048.jpg 1367w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1709w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />[<em>Part 1 of this two-part series appeared on the LSQ blog on Monday. &#8211;Blog Ed.</em>]</p>
<p dir="ltr">“You know it doesn’t work that way. This is a library, not a book store. If you lost it you could pay to have it replaced. But we do not sell books here.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Well, I want to pay for the copy of <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> that I took out. I know I also have late fees to pay.” I smiled at her bewildered face, thick lines of confusion crossing her brow.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Can you wait a second?” She disappeared behind the circulation desk. As I have put a few years between myself and this encounter, I often wonder if she was thinking, “I don&#8217;t get paid enough for this shit.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">She returned a few minutes later with another woman in tow. Her name tag said she was the Head Librarian: Ms. Shelley Percey. She was sporting the same painful expression the first librarian had on her face.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Hello, young lady, how may I help you?” This was a fair greeting since I was young enough to be her grandchild. Ms. Percy was very polite as all librarians take training to be. But the look down her nose and over the top of her glasses told me she was not in any mood for foolishness. I, of course, was just as polite back.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“I am here to pay for the copy of <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> I took out a couple of months ago. I want to pay for the book and any late charges I have on it, please.” I nodded as if that should clear up any problems of understanding my purpose.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“You lost the book?” She asked as if she had not already heard from Librarian #1 that I had not misplaced the property of the county.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“No, I have the book at home. I just love it so much, I want to buy it.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">“We are always glad to hear when one of our patrons enjoys our books, but these books are for everyone. What kind of library would we have if we allowed everyone who wanted to buy a book to do so?”</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Do a lot of people ask to buy the books they take out?” I was honestly confused. If this was a normal everyday thing I wasn’t sure why the Head Librarian had gotten involved.</p>
<p dir="ltr">She started to respond to me but thought better of it. Clearly, she was working something out. I held my breath.</p>
<p dir="ltr">She looked at my library card and tapped it on the countertop. One tap followed by three short taps, all the while scrutinizing me like I had not seen since my second-grade teacher who happen to be a nun. Our Ms. Percy had not gotten to the rank of Head Librarian without understanding what battles to fight and which ones to walk away from. She turned to Librarian #1.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Take her money.” Her eyes never left my face. Then to me, she said, “The cost for replacing this book is <span class="yiv8435612716money">$25.00</span>, plus of course your late charges.” My eyes grew huge and wild.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“But it says <span class="yiv8435612716money">$7.99</span> inside the cover,” I croaked. Silence fell between us for a very long half minute that felt like a year of my life had just been sliced off.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And then she shrugged. A shrug that clearly said, ‘I don&#8217;t get paid enough for this shit.’ She and Librarian #1 gave each other THE LOOK.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Charge her the cover price, plus the late fees.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">With that, she turned to go back through the door behind the desk still holding onto my library card. When she realized she was still holding it, she placed it down on the counter in front of me. I reached for it but she had not let it go. Her fingers pulled the card and me closer. In a low voice she whispered to me:</p>
<p dir="ltr">“I don&#8217;t want to see you in my library again. There are lots of other branches in our system, please make someone else’s life interesting.” I nodded and the card was released to me. The transaction was completed without another word spoken. Good thing I was shaking so badly that I don&#8217;t think I could have said anything. I never did visit that branch again.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Over the many years that have spanned the time from my encounter with Ms. Percy, I have been a much better patron. I have taken many classes in a variety of libraries across several states. I have happily participated in demonstrations when I was a Master Gardener at a number of <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17116 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jessica-ruscello-OQSCtabGkSY-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jessica-ruscello-OQSCtabGkSY-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jessica-ruscello-OQSCtabGkSY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jessica-ruscello-OQSCtabGkSY-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jessica-ruscello-OQSCtabGkSY-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jessica-ruscello-OQSCtabGkSY-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />branches. I have taken hundreds of books out and promptly returned them, paying whatever nominal late fees I might have incurred. I have even talked to librarians without my palms sweating. I felt that this troubled episode in my life was well behind me.</p>
<p dir="ltr">My beloved, furball-stained copy of <em>Atlas Shrugged</em> is still with me. It has managed to stick around when so many other books have made their way to other hands to enjoy, or charity sales. Dagny and I have grown to be best buds, BFFs. Would she approve of my forthright way of dealing with a book I had loved? I would like to think so. The years have allowed me a softer remembering of all of this. Being older, wiser, and all that.</p>
<p dir="ltr">However, standing in the parking garage with Frederick, Maryland’s own version of The Apple Dumpling Gang surrounding me, Ms. Percy came rushing back to me. She could scare the bejesus out of me even all these years later.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I excused myself and went to my car, placed my library card in the cup holder and firmly locked the door behind me. I wasn’t going to take any chances that this new library system would have any reason to call their own version of Ms. Percy out to greet me.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Then, with my parking ticket in hand, I opened the car door and marched right through the front doors of the library and up to the front desk were the validating machine sits. I proceeded to validate the crap out of that ticket, just like any normal person would. No fish eye looks from the librarians. None of them acted as if they cared. I felt I had dodged a bullet. My picture must have been taken down many years ago.</p>
<p dir="ltr">When I returned to my car, the gang was gone, moving on to liberate some other driver from the tyranny of a <span class="yiv8435612716money">$4.00</span> parking fee. I put my card back into my wallet and smiled. I just let Ms. Percy affect my behavior. Something I felt sure she would have completely approved of.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Light &amp; Love,</p>
<p dir="ltr">Anna O&#8217;Keefe</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Library Shame: Part 1</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/my-library-shame-part-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 11:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fearless Thoughts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Note: This is the first in a two-part series. Part 2 will appear this Friday.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">[<em>Note: This is the first in a two-part series. Part 2 will appear this Friday. &#8212; Blog Ed.</em>]</p>
<p dir="ltr">On a recent visit to <a href="https://www.serendipitymm.com/">Serendipity</a>, a cafe in Frederick, Maryland where I live, I parked in a garage that was close by. There, I drank coffee, had a nosh and wrote for several hours. Upon leaving I headed back to the garage to pay my parking fee when I was stopped by a gang of elderly retirees. I was pummeled with all kinds of questions about my parking choice for the day:  Where was I parked? How long had I been gone? What was I going to do next? Didn’t I have a need to go into the library?</p>
<p dir="ltr">I was always taught to be polite to everyone but most assuredly to anyone older than myself.</p>
<p dir="ltr">&#8220;<em>Can I help you? Yes or no Ma’am/Sir, Please and thank you, That is very kind of you.</em>&#8221; I had <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-17111 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/susan-yin-2JIvboGLeho-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/susan-yin-2JIvboGLeho-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/susan-yin-2JIvboGLeho-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/susan-yin-2JIvboGLeho-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/susan-yin-2JIvboGLeho-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/susan-yin-2JIvboGLeho-unsplash-2048x1367.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />been trained from the time I understood words the importantance of showing respect. I am glad to report my training kicked in as I answered all the questions posed to me.</p>
<p dir="ltr">My response: &#8220;Second level, a bit over four hours, going home after stopping at the food store for cat litter, no, I had no need to go to the library and thank you for your kindness in asking.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr">There was a moment of total silence save for the amplified car noises as people came and went.</p>
<p dir="ltr">One of the gang turned to another one and nodded. In unison, they all said, “The library validates parking!” Aha, now I understood the reason this group of rouge seniors were barring the way to the pay station.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“You’ll say <span class="yiv8435612716money">$2.00</span>! That’s two cups of coffee at Common Market if you use their mugs.” How could I refuse their earnest demand? So with my thanks for their diligence in helping my finances I started to march toward the library entrance.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Suddenly my insides were pulling at every step my feet took, my hands began to sweat and that little voice, so rarely followed in my younger years, was pleading for me to run the other way. An image of me fleeing down East Patrick Street with this group of cane and walker users in lukewarm pursuit filled my field of vision. I glanced back once to see their smiling faces beaming their pleasure at imparted deep wisdom to a younger generation and cheering me on to take frugal action. Go get that parking ticket validated!</p>
<p dir="ltr">You see, I have a problem with libraries and have my whole life. Every since I got my first library card in elementary school.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Words can make me giddy and I love books. I also adore libraries. They have always been a happy and safe place for me. The smell of books, God how I love the smell of books. The older the better. And books would take me to other worlds, other lives and it was the first place I started connecting to my desire to write. The library has always held magic for me. In my rough childhood there was a connection with so many other people in those pages that soothed me. So what’s the problem, you might be asking?</p>
<p dir="ltr">In every new county or state I have moved to in my life, one of the first things I always have done after getting a local driver&#8217;s license was locating all the branches in the library system and get my card. After spending countless hours reviewing their collections I would happily take out as many books as they would let me. As I grew, that included cassette tapes, CDs, books on tape. I would find an author whose work I really enjoyed and would rush forward to read everything they had ever written.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The problem is I don’t always get around to returning the borrowed items to the library. I start out with the best intentions with a new library card in my hand and for a while, it all goes smoothly. I get books back on time, returning the ones I am done with early even. If I was late by a day or two I would march right up to the desk, like any normal person ready to pay my ten-cent fine. This always made me secretly feel very adult. I have gotten a lot better with this issue over time.  Years of therapy might have helped; hard to say.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But back then, given time I would start to slip and library books would bump along in my car with me turning the volume up on the tap deck to block out the sound of their judgement  At some point, I would drop them all in the overnight drop slot and wait for the bill to come. When it did I would pay it. It was never very much. I would feel so ashamed it would take months before I would go back into the library, usually visiting a different branch. Regardless of my chronic bad behavior in regard to library etiquette, loaned items were always returned at some point, and late fees were always paid. Even though I was certain my picture was on a notice board under a list of bad patrons, I seem to have come through most of this without affecting that all-important permanent record, a threat we all lived under during our tender school years.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17112 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/zaini-izzuddin-55btQzyDiO8-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/zaini-izzuddin-55btQzyDiO8-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/zaini-izzuddin-55btQzyDiO8-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/zaini-izzuddin-55btQzyDiO8-unsplash-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/zaini-izzuddin-55btQzyDiO8-unsplash-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/zaini-izzuddin-55btQzyDiO8-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />All of that changed however when I first read Ayn Rand’s novel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atlas_Shrugged"><em>Atlas Shrugged</em></a>. I fell in love with this book in my late teens. I had never read a more powerful protagonist than Dagny Taggart. She was kick-ass <em>and</em> a girl! A Kick Ass Girl! Wooo! I had never come across one in print before. I read and re-read the loaned book several times, not a small feat since the book is 1,168 pages. It was the largest book I had read up to that point. I renewed it the allotted three times until I had lost total track of the days and months I had that book. At some point, it dawned on me that I needed to just take it back. Face the music. Take control of my own destiny. Had I not learned anything from Dagny? But how could I part with it?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Regardless, I would indeed return it and face the consequences of whatever they might be. Lining the book up with my money on the coffee table for the return the next day, I was ready.</p>
<p dir="ltr">At some point in the night, my cat threw up a massive furball all over the book’s cover. As I wiped the cover off the best I could I wondered if this was fate interceding. Was I meant to keep this book? What else could I do? Well, actually it appears I could have done several things but none of them made their selves known at the time.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I did something I have been told just doesn&#8217;t get done. Leaving the book drying in the dish drainer, I marched into the library with my card in hand and said I wanted to speak to someone about an overdue book I had out. I wanted to pay for it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“You lost the book?” I was asked.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“No, I just want to purchase it.” The Librarian just stood there blinking at me.</p>
<p dir="ltr">
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Small Voice Part 2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-small-voice-part-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 11:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fearless Thoughts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Editor&#8217;s note: For Part 1, see yesterday&#8217;s post.] Just as I got to the gas&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<em>Editor&#8217;s note: For Part 1, see yesterday&#8217;s post</em>.]</p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16527 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/wolfgang-hasselmann-_kTvNCb7gZA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/wolfgang-hasselmann-_kTvNCb7gZA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/wolfgang-hasselmann-_kTvNCb7gZA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/wolfgang-hasselmann-_kTvNCb7gZA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />Just as I got to the gas station, the rain stopped and I went into the convenience store to pay for my five gallons of gas. That&#8217;s when I remembered that my wallet was nice and dry inside my purse on the front seat of the car. I started rooting around in my pockets wondering how much change I might have. I had no purse, so no driver’s license, no money, no credit cards, but all I could think about was that tiny snail. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">I then recognized the voice of the dad from the station wagon. He stood next to me smiling with one of the little people from the back seat holding his hand. Another boy, a bit older, stood on the other side. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">“Peg said we needed to make sure you got some help.” He smiled broader. And I smiled back! He nodded to the older boy and the gas can was taken from me as he disappeared out the door. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">“Come on,” the dad said. “Let&#8217;s get some gas in that car of yours.” I stood there stunned as I watched the dad hold the door open for me. A little hand reached up and grabbed my hand and out the door we went. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">I sat in the back seat of their wagon as we pulled back on the road heading in the direction of my car. The mom asked me what happened that morning.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">“I was being stupid,” I simply answered. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">“Well,” she mused, “it happens to all of us. The important thing is to learn from those moments.” She peered over her glasses at me in question. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">“I talked to a snail.” The words slipped from my lips. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">“Wonderful! That wasn’t the stupid thing was it?” she asked.</span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><i>Wonderful? Who are these people? </i>I just shook my head no. I couldn&#8217;t do anything else.</p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">The dad nodded his head in agreement that snails were awesome creatures to talk to. I handed my keys over in complete befuddlement. In return, he told me to sit tight and stay warm. The now full gas can was pulled from the trunk. The boy and dad made their way to my car to get it ‘humming along’. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">The mom offered me her cell phone to call my boss. The dog had come over and gave me a sloppy kiss on my cheek and placed a paw on my lap. The little hand holder climbed into my lap and checked out my earrings. I could hardly put my head around it all. In this day in age were their people like this still around? I had proof in front of me, but I was still totally stunned. Again, I <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16528 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/john-towner-3Kv48NS4WUU-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/john-towner-3Kv48NS4WUU-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/john-towner-3Kv48NS4WUU-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/john-towner-3Kv48NS4WUU-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />asked myself, </span><i>Honestly, who were these people?</i></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">It wasn&#8217;t long before I was ushered back to my now running car and told to drive safe and be well. As I sat there, trying to get my bearings, the station wagon pulled off to the toot of the horn, and a chorus of goodbyes.</span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">For years I held that little snail in my heart. I think about him and that morning from time to time, always with warmth in my heart. But I wasn’t sure what the point was or if I had missed some message I was supposed to receive from it all. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">Years went by and I found myself sitting on a folding chair in the basement of a church with my husband, who was a member of a 12-step program. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> “God talks loudest in the tiniest of voices. You just have to listen for it,” the speaker said as part of her own story she was sharing. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">And just like that, I knew, after all that time, that I had held God in my hand that day. Woo. I teared up. I couldn’t help it. It took a long time to get the message of that little living creature. But I finally got it. I did have help that day, so much help but never recognized it. And sitting in that church basement I was finally grateful for it.</span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">As I write about that day, I find I tear up a little bit. I have learned that the Universal Spirit is the most amazing thing! Even when we least expect it, we are handed a gift. It might take years to see it, but I&#8217;m not sure that even matters. Right this moment I can still feel that little snail in my hand.</span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">How has that Universal Spirit spoken to you? I would love to hear your story. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;"> </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">With love and light, </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in; margin-bottom: .0001pt;"><span style="font-family: Arial;">Anna O’Keefe</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Small Voice: Part 1</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-small-voice-part-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 11:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fearless Thoughts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was my own fault. I had pushed it beyond reason and here I was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16532 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/inge-maria-pv2ZlDfstXc-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/inge-maria-pv2ZlDfstXc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/inge-maria-pv2ZlDfstXc-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/inge-maria-pv2ZlDfstXc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />It was my own fault. I had pushed it beyond reason and here I was on a country road, in heels, rain pouring down on me as if the angels were tossing buckets on top of my head. I was going to miss an important meeting and my cell phone was dead.</p>
<p>With the car’s last fumes of gas, the engine sputtered and quietly glided to a stop on the shoulder of the road.</p>
<p>I had known I needed gas when I got into the car, of course. The needle was sitting on empty and had been for quite a while. I knew it the previous night when I drove home. But I was tired and thought I had enough to make it out in the morning to fill up. I had even prayed to a God I was not sure I believed in. Praying was not something that typically happened, but this seemed like a desperate situation. I wasn&#8217;t sure how far I had gone since I had noticed the needle flat-lining in the red zone on the meter. I tried my best to ignore it. How much gas did it really take to make it out to the main road?</p>
<p>Now I knew exactly how far the car would go without gas. Just to be sure, I closed my eyes and said another prayer. “Please, please, please!” I pleaded as the engine refused to crank over.</p>
<p>“Oh, come on,” I shouted. “Would it kill you to do this one little thing?” God and I have not been on good terms for most of my life. Still, occasionally, something would happen, and I would turn my eyes to the clouds and throw pleading words towards the heavens.</p>
<p>In my fit of anger, I slammed my fist on the steering wheel, threw the door open, and sloshed myself on the wet gravel to the hatch at the rear of the car, heels sinking into the soft shoulder of the roadway. I was hoping that the umbrella I saw on the kitchen counter that morning had somehow magically made it into the car. I shook my head in disgust at the all-loving Creator of the Universe, as the rain flew off the now soaked ends of my hair, smacking me in the face. Of course, no umbrella. Why did I think there would be?</p>
<p>I grabbed the bright red gas can I kept in the trunk. I rooted around until I found a crumpled-up plastic shopping bag and slid my embarrassment along with the gas can inside the very transparent bag. Anyone who saw it would have known what it was, and knew I belonged to that car sitting on the side of the road with its hazards cheerfully blinking.</p>
<p>I was fuming, if not at myself then at a God who cared so little about me that He couldn’t leave a few ounces of gas in the tank. I had a good two miles to walk to get to the nearest gas station.  Cars passed by me, spraying water from the soaked roadway up over my head and down over my body. I kept marching, sputtering curses at the heavens. I could have made my own rain clouds. <em>Couldn&#8217;t God at least send a girl a little help?</em></p>
<p>A beat-up station wagon going the opposite direction slowed down. The driver&#8217;s window rolled down and a cacophony of kids laughing, a dog barking, and music playing on the radio met my ears.</p>
<p>“You need help?” the man asked. He looked like the dad to me.</p>
<p>“No, thank you, I&#8217;m OK,” I said, as if I wasn’t standing in a downpour with a gas can hidden in a plastic grocery bag in my hands.</p>
<p>“You sure?” A concerned look sat on his face. The back window rolled down and three little faces peered out, soon to be joined by a large shaggy head. “Hi,” a little person chirped, waving his little hand at me. I tried to smile but wasn’t sure if it was coming across as creepy. The woman sitting next to him, the mom, I was guessing, said something and the dad turned to her. “She says she doesn&#8217;t need any help, Peg.”</p>
<p>“She clearly needs help. Maybe we can give her a ride,” Peg said in her best mom voice. Dad started to relay the message when I cut in.</p>
<p>“Thank you for asking. But really I am good.” I forced a smile I hardly felt.</p>
<p>“OK. If you are certain. God bless you.” He rolled the window up and the car pulled back onto the road and disappeared around a bend. His God had a very strange sense of humor. God bless me indeed!<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16533 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/krzysztof-niewolny-6-pcQrF0doI-unsplash-300x195.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="195" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/krzysztof-niewolny-6-pcQrF0doI-unsplash-300x195.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/krzysztof-niewolny-6-pcQrF0doI-unsplash-768x499.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/krzysztof-niewolny-6-pcQrF0doI-unsplash-1024x666.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Finally, I made it to the crossroads. When traffic allowed, I started to step out into the intersection and something on the gravel right where my foot was about to land caught my eye. I stopped and bent over, placing the gas can down on the ground.</p>
<p>It was the smallest snail! The same color as the pebbles and stones that had been crunching under my feet. How I even saw such a small thing I do not know. When I picked it up, all my anger had drained from me, the gas can forgotten. It was perfect in all ways. The rings on the tiny translucent shell, the small snail body—even the antennas were moving back and forth but in the opposite direction of each other. On its head above, little eyes. This awesome little creature with such a tiny little life, and yet so complete. I was struck by how I could have crushed it under my feet and not even known. I stood in the rain with this tiny life in my hands, a life I didn&#8217;t even know existed moments before, a life I could have easily passed by if not crushed under my heel.</p>
<p>I smiled. I couldn’t help myself. The whole situation: running out of gas, the rain, no umbrella; all of it struck me as funny. I must have been quite a sight, standing in the rain laughing out loud. I placed the snail onto the grass out of any other feet that might travel the shoulder. I wished it well, telling it not to get back on the stones.</p>
<p>[<em>Editor&#8217;s note: Stay tuned for Part 2 tomorrow</em>.]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Daughter of Amphitrite</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-daughter-of-amphitrite/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fearless Thoughts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sitting on the balcony of our cabin watching the night sky, seeing the moon growing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="page" title="Page 1">
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16289 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/giga-khurtsilava-5kwVYW8ZIHo-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/giga-khurtsilava-5kwVYW8ZIHo-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/giga-khurtsilava-5kwVYW8ZIHo-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />Sitting on the balcony of our cabin watching the night sky, seeing the moon growing into fullness, and listening to the waves crash against the starboard side of the ship was mesmerizing. As the rest of the 2,000 guests partied, gambled, drank and were entertained, I sat in the lovely calm of the ocean.</p>
<p>I spent my evenings this way every night of the cruise. I took a shower, then, wrapped in a bathrobe, would sit in a deck chair for hours allowing myself to be taken away by the splendor of the sea, watching as nature played out in front of me.</p>
<p>The fifth night on board would be different. The Captain had announced earlier that a storm was in our path and he was going to take the ship through it to get us further out to sea to calmer waters. It would be a bit rough as we passed through the storm but nothing for anyone to worry about.</p>
<p>I had turned the lights off in the cabin and watched the massive, clear, blue-black sky, filled with stars, roll slowly over my head, pass the top deck full of partiers, over the bridge and the smokestacks, giving way to the approaching storm.</p>
<p>The gray rolling clouds pushed in, covering every inch of the sky and all the way down to the surface of the water and collided with the ship&#8217;s hull, churning in a display of power I have not experienced before. More intense, a storm at sea is very different from a storm on land. I knew I was exactly where I was meant to be.</p>
<p>The transformation playing out in front of me felt epic! The warm breeze had grown stronger and blew the curtains straight into the cabin.T he rain came down in sheets, changing direction with each wind gust. The thunder and lightning were right in front of me, and coming at the exact same time. The ship swayed just slightly.</p>
<p>In that darkness, I stood up, dropped my robe, and spreading my arms wide, let the full force of Mother Nature smash right into me. I closed my eyes as the energy of the storm soaked into my skin, into every pore, right into my soul. It was the most exquisite feeling. There was nothing but the raw power of the storm. As the rain pelted my body, I ceased to exist. I was taken by a power so ancient it reached back to the beginning of time. I felt no fear as I got pulled into the moment.</p>
<p>It only lasted a few minutes, but it could have been hours; time felt like it had stopped. The ship, leaving the storm behind her, once again pushed into calm seas and clear skies. Our ship slid through the water with hardly a break in the waves, just as the good Captain had promised.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="page" title="Page 2">
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>I wasn’t sure how long I stood there. Every nerve in my body was snapping, my heart was pounding, and though I felt my bones had turned to rubber I could not move. Every inch of my being was soaked with seawater. Her brininess was in my nose, and in my ears. My eyelashes had small salt crystals on them, and my hair smelled like seaweed. When I touched my skin a<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16290 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/marcis-berzins-KyuvxYkR36Q-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/marcis-berzins-KyuvxYkR36Q-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/marcis-berzins-KyuvxYkR36Q-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/marcis-berzins-KyuvxYkR36Q-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> fine layer of salt covered it. I had been embraced deeply by the magnificent Atlantic Ocean and she claimed me as her own.</p>
<p>I finally lowered my arms and flopped down into the deck chair. I kept my eyes closed and tried to pull myself back from the storm. I was reluctant to let go, wishing instead to stay within the storm and flow into her power forever.</p>
<p>I finally managed to get dressed and resume my human existence. I made my way to a tiny alcove I had been using for writing over the past five nights. My body was still humming and felt I was floating right above the floor. The power of the sea was still vibrating inside of me.</p>
<p>The energy began to flow out of me and onto the pages. I wrote without thought, as I filled up page after page. The inspiration was bursting out of me. Later, and several times since, I have gone back to read what I had written but have never understood a single word; it was written in some language I simply do not recognize. Perhaps a language no one could.</p>
<p>Now and again, when the rain is coming down I will step out into it, lift my face up, close my eyes and remember the night a great storm took me into her.</p>
<p>Next time it rains, let it pour on your head. Invite the storm in. There is magic in there.</p>
<p>Love and Life,<br />
Anna O’Keefe</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ronnie B, Musings on a Muse: Part 2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ronnie-b-musings-on-a-muse-part-2/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ronnie-b-musings-on-a-muse-part-2/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fearless Thoughts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15867</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Editor&#8217;s note: this is the last in a two-part series which began yesterday.] I have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_15885" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15885" style="width: 730px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-15885 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Ruin-in-Winter-1024x543.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="387" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Ruin-in-Winter-1024x543.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Ruin-in-Winter-300x159.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Ruin-in-Winter-768x407.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Ruin-in-Winter.jpg 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15885" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Ruin in Winter&#8221; by Ronnie Goodwin</figcaption></figure>
<p>[<em>Editor&#8217;s note: this is the last in a two-part series which began yesterday.</em>]</p>
<p>I have written many stories using Ronnie’s images as a starting point. One of the most fun has been an ongoing journal written by a character named Ruth, who goes on a journey to find the locations of many of Ronnie’s pictures. The journal has been so much fun to write, and the progress of this main character amuses and amazes me.</p>
<p>Another story I am still working on comes from Ronnie’s work, &#8220;Ruin in Winter,&#8221; a nearly all white image with just the faintest outline of a house, a tree, and the road that goes between and disappears. The viewer is caught between the snow on the ground and the fog and mist in the air, a near total white out.</p>
<p>I call my story <em>The Disappearing Season</em>. All that whiteness was such a wealth of inspiration. This story centers around the inhabitants of a small town on a little island in Scotland. Every year people wait until the very conditions shown in the photo occur in late February, what is locally known as The Disappearing Season<strong>. </strong></p>
<p>The ill, or old, or deeply depressed terminally ill decide it is time to leave this world and walk down the road and just disappear. They choose when they are ready and simply walk through the mist and snow down the endless road. No one who wants to cross over ever walks through the other side of the road. Teenage boys are always trying to jump through but are promptly spit back out on the other side of the road, no memory of the drive. To my surprise and delight many characters have come forward, filling out, and becoming an important part of the fabric. I can no longer look at this image without seeing the ghosts of those who have already disappeared. I just love this story and equally love the image that brought this story forward.</p>
<p>Would I have found something else to inspire me? I am not sure. But I do think that this awesome universe often arranges things in a wonderful chaotic order, bringing people and situations into our lives exactly when we need them most. I am grateful to Ronnie for his talent and vision and the way he allows himself to be accessible. I am thankful for Stephen Walker for posting that little tweet. I am sure Stephen has no idea what those few words unleashed. But that is how it often works. We never know what we say or do that can affect someone else.</p>
<p>Ronnie’s work is the pebble being dropped into the pond and I am constantly amazed at the ripples created for me.</p>
<p>I have written many things over the past few of years: stories about fairies and trinket keepers and poems about a famous beard, my love of a Jaguar car, things that go bump in the night, of love and loss, heart break, and redemption. But if I find myself lacking inspiration I will go back to Ronnie’s work. It seems only right I should say this now: T<em>hank you, Ronnie, for your gift and all it has meant to me. Your work was the lifeline when I needed to remember how to be a writer</em>.</p>
<p>Is Ronnie my muse? His work certainly is and of course since he is the artist of these magnificent works of art, he must be as well. But not the kind of muse to be held on a pedestal.</p>
<p>Ronnie’s work is alive and always changing. That movement and flow is astonishing.</p>
<p>Over the past couple of years, I have had a chance to get to know Ronnie at bit. He is a lovely man, very open and available to his fans. His talent is wider and deeper than photography. Ronnie is also an award-winning filmmaker. I am very grateful to call him my friend.</p>
<p>I am now a butterfly, learning to fly, and trusting my words will just be there when I am inspired to create. I see the world as a writer does. Always seeing questions, always seeking an answer, and creating worlds with words.</p>
<p><a href="https://us-email-isolation.prod.fire.glass/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fronniebgoodwin.com%2F">Here</a> is the link to Ronnie’s work. Take a look. I will be surprised if you don&#8217;t find something to amaze you.</p>
<p>How are you inspired? I would love for you to share.</p>
<p>With love and light,</p>
<p>Anna O’Keefe</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ronnie-b-musings-on-a-muse-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ronnie B, Musings on a Muse: Part 1</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ronnie-b-musings-on-a-muse-part-1/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ronnie-b-musings-on-a-muse-part-1/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 10:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fearless Thoughts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Editor&#8217;s note: this is the first in a two-part series, to be concluded tomorrow.] I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<em>Editor&#8217;s note: this is the first in a two-part series, to be concluded tomorrow.</em>]</p>
<p>I had been in the darkness for so many years I was not sure if I could find my footing again; finding who I was and embracing her, letting her heal. Learning to start living all over again by picking up pieces of my shattered self. Depression is a killer of dreams, of the spirit, of hope, of love and of life. The pain of staying in the dark had been overtaken by fears of living. Out of that pain came a deep desire to grab at life again. I had made it out alive, coming back from the blackness, from the very edge, but at what cost?</p>
<p>In what seemed unthinkable, I found in my recovery that I had lost my voice as a writer. In those early days and weeks of breathing again I had not been able to write one single creative thing. I had always thought of myself as a writer, even when I had not written for more than a decade. Now, I was faced with the possibility that I had waited too long to get my words back, to create worlds inside my heart and let them seep out my fingers onto the paper or keyboard. The image that I was a newly emerged butterfly, testing my wings, seemed fanciful considering this new and extremely heartbreaking discovery. If I could not create, I couldn&#8217;t be a writer. My mind was having trouble grasping the idea. If I couldn’t write, who was I?</p>
<p>The fledgling me had branched out in all areas, taking in the world of things I had missed during my depression. I jumped into social media and spent a few months feeling like I was so out of my element. Facebook was moderately okay, but Twitter was a world I didn’t understand. I kept trying, thinking I could find other creative souls like myself. Each time I visited my Twitter account I was left feeling confused and frustrated. It didn’t help that in those early days I followed everybody.</p>
<figure id="attachment_15882" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-15882" style="width: 730px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-15882 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/In-the-middle-of-nowhere-1024x682.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="486" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/In-the-middle-of-nowhere-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/In-the-middle-of-nowhere-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/In-the-middle-of-nowhere-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/In-the-middle-of-nowhere.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-15882" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;In the middle of nowhere&#8221; by Ronnie Goodwin</figcaption></figure>
<p>In my growing frustration with what seemed to be the most childish and unrelatable posts I had seen, I was about to log off and delete my account. I was done! Clearly whatever I needed I was not going to find on Twitter.</p>
<p>My finger sat poised to exit when at the last second, a post by Stephen Walters, the incredibly talented actor, most notably for his role in the <em>Outlander</em> series popped up. A short little post, saying, &#8220;<em>Everyone needs to go check out my good friend, Ronnie B Goodwin’s artwork. He is incredibly talented.&#8221; </em>If not the exact words, these are very close.</p>
<p>Even though I have watched the <em>Outlander</em> series, I didn’t know who any of the actors were. Stephen’s name didn’t mean anything to me, a simple post from one friend praising another friend’s work. I paused and reread the post. I wondered, would it be worth looking at this artist&#8217;s link and seeing his work before leaving Twitter? Sometimes it is the big things that hallmark important moments in our lives. Other times it is a second&#8217;s hesitation before looking at a link or logging off. I had no idea what was about to happen in my life.</p>
<p>With that one simple click I found myself immersed in a most captivating world! Photographs yes, to be sure, but much much more. This work was art. I was drawn in and viewed the whole gallery a couple of times. Brilliant color images, haunting black and whites. Animals, nature, buildings, people. Stephen was not wrong; Ronnie B. Goodwin is an incredible talent. He uses his camera to sculpt out images, to paint stories. I was captivated. Without realizing it, something inside of me was shifting.</p>
<p>I went from image to image, moved by the depth of feeling they evoked in me. But it was one image that kept drawing me back. Over the next few days I would click on the link to Ronnie&#8217;s gallery and return to the image titled, &#8220;In the Middle of Nowhere.&#8221;</p>
<p>The photo was a stunningly stark black and white of an old abandoned shack. The whole front face has sheared off the building, landing on the ground still upright. In front of the fallen facade is a bicycle propped against the steps. The backdrop is sparse landscape, a mountain in the distance, scrub and a few trees in the middle ground. So yes, it is in the middle of nowhere. It was also how I had been feeling. It would be a couple of years before I realized the connection between where I was personally and the emotions this photograph brought forth in me.</p>
<p>Who left the bike? How did they get home from the middle of nowhere otherwise? I rolled the questions over in my mind so many times. Just like the oyster with a grain of sand, the questions were an irritant. I would go to sleep with it on my mind, I would sit at green traffic lights lost in the possibilities until cars behind began to honk. I jotted down random thoughts on envelopes, advertisements, and once on the back of a check. Without realizing it, a story began to emerge. So, drawn into its creation I had not even realized my words had come back until I sat down in front of my laptop one Saturday afternoon wanting nothing more than to get my thoughts out of my head. To make order out of them. The story came out of me in a rush and when I looked up two hours had passed and a story was looking back at me from the screen.</p>
<p>The poetic prose that came into being that day is named after Ronnie’s work: <em>In the Middle of Nowhere</em>. To my surprise the story that emerged was not about the bike. Instead the story is from the collapsing shack&#8217;s perspective. Telling how it came to be, what kind of life it once held, and how in the end it met the fate the photograph brings to us. By the end I had answered the question of how the bike was left in that spot so many years ago. Writing a story from an object&#8217;s point of view was very strange and foreign to me, but also seemed perfectly natural.</p>
<p>When I finally sat back in my chair that day I smiled, my eyes filling with tears. I was writing again! Relief rushed over me. Thinking about that moment now can still bring tears to my eyes. I was flying, fluttering off the ground, if not soaring high; these new wings appeared so fragile yet incredibly strong.</p>
<p>Inspiration is a funny thing. We never know where or when it will find us. The more we look for it, the more elusive it becomes. I have been writing since that experience with Ronnie’s work. I am not a prolific writer. It has come little by little, but it is writing nevertheless. Being a writer is who I am, how I see the world, and how I process events. It is my healing, my reclaiming myself so far beyond where I thought was even possible. All because I clicked on one little link. Followed one small post from someone I did not even know. Life is indeed awesome.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ronnie-b-musings-on-a-muse-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Giver of Trinkets: Part 2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/giver-of-trinkets-part-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fearless Thoughts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14894</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Editor&#8217;s note: Part 1 of this story appeared on yesterday&#8217;s blog.] A waitress, Rose was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="page" title="Page 2">
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>[<em>Editor&#8217;s note: Part 1 of this story appeared on yesterday&#8217;s blog.</em>]</p>
<p>A waitress, Rose was on her name tag, said, “How did you know?”</p>
<p>“How did I know what?” I asked. Her hands shook as she accepted the little mason jar full of buttons. I purchased them at a yard sale a week before with a handful of change. All I had on me at the time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14895 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/dmitry-mashkin-288168-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/dmitry-mashkin-288168-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/dmitry-mashkin-288168-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/dmitry-mashkin-288168-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />“This is just like a jar of buttons my grandmother had when I was a kid. I use to dump them out on her kitchen table and count them. Stack them in similar colors. Thread string through them in a long chain. Make up stories about them.” She had clutched the jar to her apron. “I have been thinking about her. I miss her sometimes until it hurts. She raised me.&#8221; I just smiled and touched her hand briefly.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="page" title="Page 3">
<div class="section">
<div class="layoutArea">
<div class="column">
<p>The thing is I don&#8217;t know about these trinkets. I don&#8217;t ever know. I had no answers for her. Why I was drawn to that jar of buttons? Why am I drawn to any trinket I find?</p>
<p>I patted her hand one last time and told her to enjoy them. I left her standing in the middle of the cafe as I hiked my backpack high on my shoulder and swung out the door. Much later that night I realized I never paid for my coffee and pie. Perhaps she thought that was a fair trade.</p>
<p>This is how it always happens. And it is really that simple. I can&#8217;t take requests, please don&#8217;t ask. It does not work that way. I don&#8217;t want the focus on me or my part anyway. I am just delivering what I have been given. I usually hot foot it out the door as soon as I can.</p>
<p>I keep thinking there have to be others like me. The universe would not have hired just one of me. The hungry raw need for people to be connected to something deeper than themselves is massive. My life long efforts can only be a very small drop in the vastness of humanity. I hang on <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14896 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/krissia-cruz-353941-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/krissia-cruz-353941-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/krissia-cruz-353941-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/krissia-cruz-353941-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />to the hope that someday I will meet another Giver of Trinkets. But so far I am the Lone Ranger without a white horse or sidekick. In the meantime, I delight in the variety of items I find and the waiting for the inspiration for who they belong to.</p>
<p>If by chance you are a Giver of Trinkets, let me know. It would be wonderful to think there are many of us out in the world, doing these small little deeds that make someone’s life a bit better. But until that time I will keep receiving and giving Trinkets as I have always done.</p>
<p>With love and light, Anna O’Keefe</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
