<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 039 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-039/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:34:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 039 Author Interview: Nadia Attia and &#8220;Flower, Feather, Hare, and Snow&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-039-author-interview-nadia-attia-and-flower-feather-hare-and-snow/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 039]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we wrap up another successful issue of Luna Station Quarterly and prepare to publish&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16568 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/samsommer-vddccTqwal8-unsplash-1024x685.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="488" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/samsommer-vddccTqwal8-unsplash-1024x685.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/samsommer-vddccTqwal8-unsplash-300x201.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/samsommer-vddccTqwal8-unsplash-768x514.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/samsommer-vddccTqwal8-unsplash-1536x1028.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/samsommer-vddccTqwal8-unsplash-2048x1371.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />As we wrap up another successful issue of <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> and prepare to publish a new one, we took the opportunity to chat with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-039/">Issue 039</a> author Nadia Attia about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/flower-feather-hare-and-snow/">Flower, Feather, Hare, and Snow</a>.&#8221; Check out her behind-the-scenes insight below.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: </strong><span class="im"><strong>The danger and beauty of mountains is deftly portrayed in your story. What is it about this geological feature that keeps Liath there? How does the mountain&#8217;s spell on Liath differ from how others (both fortunate and unfortunate) are drawn to it? Or perhaps the lure of mountains is the same for everyone?</strong> </span></em></p>
<p>Nadia: I actually imagined Liath not as a literal person but as a local myth, as the very spirit of the mountain itself, who appears in human form at certain liminal times of day or weather. Over thousands of years she&#8217;s grown old and changed with the geology (her hair was &#8216;mud brown&#8217; once) and that&#8217;s why she comes across as detached from humankind and a little aloof. If anything, she&#8217;s actually worried that the &#8216;spell&#8217; of the mountain is waning, and that it – and she – will be changed by time and return to dust, just like the unfortunate adventurers on her slopes.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Your story seems timeless &#8212; it could take place on a summit today or in centuries past. In what time frame did you imagine your story, or did you at all? Does it even matter?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Nadia: I wanted <i>Flower Feather Hare and Snow</i> to come across as timeless, so this is a huge complement! I wanted it to feel believable as a folk tale that might have been told through many generations, a tale that still holds weight today, perhaps as a warning to those foolhardy wanderers who ignore Mother Nature. I almost imagined the story being told around open fires in Scotland, perhaps in the very bothies I mention in the text.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">A respect of nature&#8217;s forces seems to be a source of Liath&#8217;s knowledge of the mountain. In what ways does she approach the mountain differently than other hikers and what does this say about her character? </span></strong></em></p>
<p>Nadia: Liath is a part of nature herself so that&#8217;s why she&#8217;s amused to see all the tools and trinkets that humans use to navigate the mountain, whereas she&#8217;d only ever rely on natural signs, even <img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16569 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/alberto-restifo-cFplR9ZGnAk-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/alberto-restifo-cFplR9ZGnAk-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/alberto-restifo-cFplR9ZGnAk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/alberto-restifo-cFplR9ZGnAk-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/alberto-restifo-cFplR9ZGnAk-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/alberto-restifo-cFplR9ZGnAk-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />other animals (such as the mountain hare – often associated with witchcraft and transformation), to determine what&#8217;s coming or how to react. I guess I&#8217;m commenting on our reliance on modern technology to such an extent that we might become blind to what&#8217;s around us, what the world&#8217;s telling us. I&#8217;m not suggesting that hikers and climbers don&#8217;t respect nature: in Liath I created a character who has grown to resent our impact through sheer proliferation, since she literally has to clean up our mess.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: And what about you, Nadia? Are you a lover of mountains? Where did the inspiration for this story come from?</strong></em></p>
<p>Nadia: I love mountains, from a distance! I&#8217;d never climb one if it needed ropes or picks. With this story I&#8217;m asking why humans feel this deep need to conquer, to make their mark on everything and shape and change what has been perfectly beautiful for millennia. I&#8217;ve never understood that drive to reach impossible summits, to be the first, the quickest, the best – nature will always win in the end. I was inspired to write this short story after reading Nan Shepherd&#8217;s wonderful book <i>The Living Mountain</i>, and thinking about how perfectly she captured the spirit of the Cairngorms; I&#8217;ve never been, but I felt like I was there with her.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us about them?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Nadia: I&#8217;m working on my third novel (I&#8217;m as yet unpublished), which is currently called <i>Verge</i>. It&#8217;s a rural road trip <span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;"><span lang="EN-US">across an alternative Britain where county borders are hard, people are harder, and there’s a return to ‘the old ways’. It&#8217;s a good excuse for me to research folklore, superstitions and country life and weave these elements into a coming-of-age story with plenty of dark humor and folk horror. I&#8217;ve managed to secure a place on a nine-month writing scheme (can&#8217;t announce which one yet), so I&#8217;ll be busy writing this book well into 2020.</span></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 039 Author Interview: Erin McNelis and &#8220;The Fire Wife&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-039-author-interview-erin-mcnelis-and-the-fire-wife/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 039]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our current Issue 039 is up! Today we chat with Issue 039 author Erin McNelis&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16514 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/martin-adams-D9MDpAjlJ6k-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/martin-adams-D9MDpAjlJ6k-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/martin-adams-D9MDpAjlJ6k-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/martin-adams-D9MDpAjlJ6k-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Our current <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-039/">Issue 039</a> is up! Today we chat with Issue 039 author Erin McNelis about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-fire-wife/">The Fire Wife</a>&#8220;. Check it out!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">One of the most wrenching aspects of this story is seeing a woman with so much power being stripped down to nothing. What were the challenges in writing this?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Erin: In the fantasy genre, and in literature in general, we read so many stories in which women have little or no power. In the case of fantasy, too many times they are hunted, their children are taken away, and then the main male character swoops in and saves them. While that is changing, we rarely get to experience the story from the woman’s point of view.</p>
<p>In the case of my character, Aruna, she has lost her magic, her freedom, her people, and her social status. It was challenging to take away her power. It felt wrong. We want to see female characters gaining power, not losing it. I took what women experience every day, a cutting down with a word or a look, and I tried to make sure that she wasn’t just a victim and that she wasn’t pitiful. Words are powerful, and when Aruna loses her ability to speak, she loses her power. Women get spoken over or misrepresented, and not heard, just as whole groups of people on a global level are silenced. Plus, she doesn’t win. It is difficult as the writer not to make things better for the characters you love. But that wasn’t the story I was telling.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Stories aren’t required to have happy endings, and this one certainly doesn’t. Can you talk about what non-happy endings bring to a story?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Erin: Happy endings offer the reader answers to questions, and non-happy endings encourage readers to arrive at their own answers. The happy ending brings closure, and the story ends. Not many people wonder what happens to Cinderella after the big wedding. Non-happy endings allow readers to inhabit the story longer, leave readers with more questions, and create a capacity for empathy.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Are there any writers who have influenced your work?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Erin: Everyone I read does, but that is too easy an answer, so I will try to be specific. Margaret Atwood is one of my writer heroes. She straddles the line of literary and science fiction, and she tackles subjects that are uncomfortable and edgy and gritty. Indira Ganesan was my professor in <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16515 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/gui-avelar-aA7VnDn1ysI-unsplash-201x300.jpg" alt="" width="201" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/gui-avelar-aA7VnDn1ysI-unsplash-201x300.jpg 201w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/gui-avelar-aA7VnDn1ysI-unsplash-768x1145.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/gui-avelar-aA7VnDn1ysI-unsplash-687x1024.jpg 687w" sizes="(max-width: 201px) 100vw, 201px" />graduate school, and she taught me that a soft voice and subtle writing is not a detriment. We don’t all have to yell or be shocking to tell a good story.</p>
<p>I have read a lot of fantasy writers, like Robert Jordan, George R.R. Martin, and Brandon Sanderson, but they are predominantly men. That doesn’t mean that they haven’t influenced me. They have in many ways, but probably the biggest way they have is to encourage me that more female voices are needed in the genre. There are female main characters with tremendous power, but they are written largely by men, though that is changing. I wanted to speak for myself and tell the story my way, not necessarily taking the path laid by those who came before me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 039 author interview: Katherine Kendig and &#8220;The Wiser Move, The Better Choice&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-039-author-interview-katherine-kendig-and-the-wiser-move-the-better-choice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 11:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 039]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16457</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear readers! This week we chatted with Issue 039 author Katherine Kendig about her short&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-16458" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/aron-visuals-_l4yffWjgt4-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/aron-visuals-_l4yffWjgt4-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/aron-visuals-_l4yffWjgt4-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/aron-visuals-_l4yffWjgt4-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Dear readers! This week we chatted with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-039/">Issue 039</a> author Katherine Kendig about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-wiser-move-the-better-choice/">The Wiser Move, the Better Choice</a>.&#8221; Go read her story and enjoy the interview below!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Stories about prophecies and such can always be tricky, but I like your interpretation of the Universe merely making suggestions. Where did this idea come from?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Katherine: I think it’s natural to see direct orders as antagonistic, and a lot of people resist that automatically. But it’s harder to see the influence that something has if it’s mild and indirect. I think the idea comes from the constant suggestions we get from society and advertising and culture. When someone says “Buy this product” or “Act this way” we get prickly, but we’re not always as tuned to see the power in “You’ll be so happy when you buy this product” or “This is the way people act.” We’re more likely to think we’ve made those choices completely on our own.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">The plot twist with the Governor was so well done! Do you have any tips for writing effective plot twists that aren’t just made for shock value?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Katherine: I had a student in a creative writing class one time say, matter-of-factly, that she knew every short story had to have a plot twist. That’s not how I feel about short stories at all (and I kind of wonder what she’d been reading), but I do think sometimes it’s nice when two story lines that seem to be running in parallel, separate, suddenly converge. I think writers do best with plot twists when they don’t guard the secret too jealously – it’s so satisfying as a reader to realize that you failed to notice the signs, and so unsatisfying to realize the author just never gave you any.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Would you like to be Prophecy-touched, or not?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Katherine: Not like Rien is, but I do love fortune cookies – they provide the same sense of mysterious prediction with absolutely zero stakes. (Plus they come with food!)</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">What was the most challenging part of this story to write and why? What was the most enjoyable and why? </span></strong></em></p>
<p>Katherine: It was challenging to write the ending, and I rewrote it over and over. I always struggle <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-16459" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/antoine-beauvillain-0Kw44ElHN3A-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/antoine-beauvillain-0Kw44ElHN3A-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/antoine-beauvillain-0Kw44ElHN3A-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/antoine-beauvillain-0Kw44ElHN3A-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />to keep things natural at the finish line, when I’m so close to being done and I just-want-everything-to-wrap-<wbr />up-as-planned so I’m trying to force things that may or may not be working. In this case, I also vacillated between having Rien overcome the Prophecies, or not. I originally had the opposite ending, and when I changed it, it didn&#8217;t work until I went back and sharpened her character in earlier parts of the story.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the scenes with Tia were fun. I usually like writing dialogue, especially in scenes where wary people sort of poke at each other’s boundaries until they’re having a real conversation. There&#8217;s something very appealing to me as well about situations where characters are stuck together for long periods of time, because it forces them to engage or not engage very deliberately. You can&#8217;t just accidentally not talk to someone who&#8217;s sitting next to you in a boxcar for days on end.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 039 Author Interview: Jerica Taylor and &#8220;The Pet Owner&#8217;s Guide . . . &#8220;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-039-author-interview-jerica-taylor-and-the-pet-owners-guide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 039]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 039 is full of amazing stories by women-identifying authors. Jerica Taylor is one of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16417 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/lisa-risager-9CWKfMwIGfo-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/lisa-risager-9CWKfMwIGfo-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/lisa-risager-9CWKfMwIGfo-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/lisa-risager-9CWKfMwIGfo-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Issue 039 is full of amazing stories by women-identifying authors. Jerica Taylor is one of them and today we chat with her about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-pet-owners-guide-to-reptilian-hauntings/">The Pet Owner&#8217;s Guide to Reptilian Hauntings</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><span class="im"><em><strong>LSQ: The opening of this story really makes the reader feel how hectic Maggie’s life is. Do you have any advice on writing effective openings?</strong></em></span></p>
<p>Jerica: I almost never write beginnings first. I&#8217;m definitely a “write the story to know what it&#8217;s about” type of writer, so I remember writing Maggie finding Howard first. A good beginning can hook you into the character and their situation right away, and so I considered what would make everything worse for her. I&#8217;ve been where she is – you&#8217;re struggling to keep a handle on the basics, and something happens that you normally would respond to with grace and empathy, but it&#8217;s just too much, it&#8217;s just one more hassle you have to deal with.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: So I have to ask: where did the ghost gecko idea come from?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jerica: Agatha actually came first, the odd collector of lost spirits. I had recently lost one of my senior cats, and I was idly thinking about whether or not pets could be ghosts the way we see ghosts in speculative fiction. It would have been too hard for me to write about a ghost cat, that close to losing my kitty, and I also expect a ghost cat would be easier to have an emotional, empathetic response to, even if you weren&#8217;t a cat person. But a gecko was just a little less emotive. Not that people can&#8217;t love and mourn any animal in their care. It&#8217;s not exactly grief Maggie feels over the loss of her son&#8217;s pet. It&#8217;s an annoyance, and so when Howard&#8217;s ghost appears, she&#8217;s not comforted by his visitation, she&#8217;s flummoxed.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any writers who have influenced your work?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jerica: I read Douglas Adams at an impressionable age and have a great fondness for the wacky <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16418 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ben-berwers-CLFun8jLZLQ-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ben-berwers-CLFun8jLZLQ-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ben-berwers-CLFun8jLZLQ-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/ben-berwers-CLFun8jLZLQ-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />trying to disguise itself as normal. Contemporary romance taught me the importance of side characters and their intersections with the main characters in making a story&#8217;s world feel real. I&#8217;m incredibly inspired by <a href="https://kellysue.tumblr.com/FAQ">Kelly Sue DeConnick</a>, and her Bitches Get Shit Done text reminders have gotten me out of a rut more than once.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jerica: Right now, I&#8217;m working on a draft of a story that&#8217;s like <em>Pacific Rim x Ocean&#8217;s 8</em>. An accident with alien technology tangles two cryptographers up in mind-sharing, and they collect a team of other awesome ladies to help them steal a spaceship to escape their corrupt research organization. I&#8217;ve never written a heist, but it&#8217;s a lot of fun to imagine the mischief this team gets up to. I&#8217;m also writing a short story about a psychopomp who plays in the band whose songs carry spirits to the next world.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m almost finished a queer romance novel about a trash fire exorcist who crashes into the stable, controlled life of a single dad witch. Incidentally, it&#8217;s sort of set in the same universe as this story. There&#8217;s a community whose purpose is to mend various magical problems, large and small, and it&#8217;s where I imagine Agatha would live and use as her base of spirit-collecting operations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 039 Author Interview: Koji A. Dae and &#8220;The Artist&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-039-author-interview-koji-a-dae-and-the-artist/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 10:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 039]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 039 is rocking and we&#8217;re here today to share a chat we recently had&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-039/">Issue 039</a> is rocking and we&#8217;re here today to share a chat we recently had with Issue 039 author Koji A. Dae about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-artist/">The Artist</a>.&#8221; Enjoy!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16399 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/markus-spiske-k0rVudBoB4c-unsplash-722x1024.jpg" alt="" width="722" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/markus-spiske-k0rVudBoB4c-unsplash-722x1024.jpg 722w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/markus-spiske-k0rVudBoB4c-unsplash-212x300.jpg 212w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/markus-spiske-k0rVudBoB4c-unsplash-768x1089.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 722px) 100vw, 722px" />LSQ: This story touches a bit on art for art’s sake versus what can be profited from it. Why is it so important for someone like Karla to pursue her art even when her society thinks it’s worthless?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Koji: I strongly believe that art allows humans to explore complex ideas on a subconscious level and ultimately expand our consciousness. It allows us to take a leap of faith beyond logic and potentially learn new ways of understanding others and the world around us. This is more important than ever now that we live in a global world where people constantly interact with people who do not share the same culture or language as them.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: There’s a huge difference in social interaction between the people of New and Old Ironwood. How do you think this came to be?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Koji: In this world, the rich moved underground after a minor nuclear war. The poor stayed on the surface. From what I&#8217;ve seen in the world (from the perspective of someone who has never had much wealth), wealthier people tend to have a bit stiffer, formal style of interaction in public whereas, for poor people, the public and private spheres tend to blur. Over time, this caused the underground culture to take on a more formal feel while the people who lived above ground were known for being more open and warmer.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: What was your inspiration for this story?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Koji: This story came from the novel I am working on. I kept adding in too much backstory about the crystal city so I decided writing this would allow me to move on in my book. Parts of the crystal architecture were inspired by the Tok&#8217;ra crystals in <em>Stargate SG-1</em> and the ending&#8211;which is where the idea for the story started&#8211;was inspired by <em>Blindness</em> by José Saramago.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Koji: I always have several short stories in progress. Many of my shorts are based on the same world as this piece. In particular, I am working on a companion short to this piece that explores what happens in New Ironwood after Karla&#8217;s final act.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I also have a novel set in this world that is on its final round of revisions. It is called <em>Casual</em> and is about a pregnant woman with anxiety who depends on a neural implant to stabilize her moods.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 039 Author Interview: Lucy Stone and &#8220;The Gold Chain&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-039-author-interview-lucy-stone-and-the-gold-chain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 039]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 039! Have you read it yet? If not, what are you waiting for? If&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16334 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/alex-chambers-TxCbfMc854c-unsplash-683x1024.jpg" alt="" width="683" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/alex-chambers-TxCbfMc854c-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/alex-chambers-TxCbfMc854c-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/alex-chambers-TxCbfMc854c-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-039/">Issue 039</a>! Have you read it yet? If not, what are you waiting for? If you have, go read it again! Today we chat with Issue 039 author Lucy Stone about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-gold-chain/">The Gold Chain</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><span class="im"><em><strong>LSQ: Khane is what we call a “strong female character,” although not in the stereotypical way. Would you talk a bit about how her character came to be?</strong></em><br />
</span></p>
<div>Lucy: I feel like Khane sprang ready-formed from the Yiddish folktales I’d been reading. There are bits of her that are based on personal experience&#8211;my love of stories, the horrible morning-sickness I had when I was pregnant with my son&#8211;but then, in lots of ways, she’s not like me at all. What I love about her is that she is helpless, and she knows she’s helpless, but she’ll never allow anyone <i>else</i> to know it. She’s proud as well as pragmatic. She’s not the sort of character I usually write&#8211;most of my female characters are shy and neurotic like me, because it’s a mind-set I can perfectly understand&#8211;but her pride and pragmatism seemed perfectly in-keeping with the folktales I’d been reading as research for this piece.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Story plays a big role in this piece. What does story mean to you, personally?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Lucy: Very pleased to hear you say that story plays an important role in this piece! I am usually one of those writers who prioritizes her characters at the expense of all plot (although my excuse&#8211;which I’m sure makes editors roll their eyes&#8211;is that I use the characters to develop the plot, as I feel like I can’t get a good idea for what’s going to happen without first getting a feel for my characters and what they will do). My favorite quote about writing is from Henry James’ <i>Art of Fiction</i>:</div>
<div></div>
<blockquote>
<div>“What is character but the determination of incident? What is incident but the illustration of character?”</div>
</blockquote>
<div></div>
<div>With this piece, though, I’d been reading so many tales of Jewish folklore before I started writing that I suppose the story had to take center-stage. But Khane is a character who defines and empowers herself through stories, so even when story takes center-stage, it’s still, in a way, serving the needs of character. And, at the end, she uses stories to take control of her life&#8211;<i>she knew a lot of stories, and could always find a way to thrive within them</i>&#8211;which is what I am trying to do all the time!</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story and why?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Lucy: I remember being very pleased with the description of Khane’s unborn child as her little, ship-wrecked mariner (especially as I had a ship-wrecked mariner of my own not so long ago), <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16335 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/click-and-learn-photography-NGB9oBtOUM8-unsplash-1024x697.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="497" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/click-and-learn-photography-NGB9oBtOUM8-unsplash-1024x697.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/click-and-learn-photography-NGB9oBtOUM8-unsplash-300x204.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/click-and-learn-photography-NGB9oBtOUM8-unsplash-768x523.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />and I enjoyed the verbal sparring between her and Moyshele. But I think, mostly, I remember what a visual story this was for me&#8211;how I could see the glint of the gold chain, the snow feathering down between the boards of the roof, the image of Khane picking up Velvl’s legs and dragging him home through the snow. Writing it didn’t feel like work, instead it felt like watching a movie in my head.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: You use Jewish mythology in this piece, which I really enjoyed. Do you plan to draw on it again in future works? Which tales are your favorite?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Lucy: Yes, I would love to write more about Jewish mythology. It’s a passion of mine anyway, but I’m also writing a short story collection of feminist folklore&#8211;sort of myth-inspired fantasy stories that feature female characters (as you can see, I haven’t thought of a snappy title yet, and would be totally open to suggestions!).</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>As you can tell from &#8220;The Gold Chain&#8221;, I like stories about golems and dibbuks. My favorite tale (from <i>Yiddish Folklore</i> by Beatrice Silverman Weinreich) is called &#8220;The Dibbuk Melody of Tolne&#8221;. It features an old cantor in the synagogue being replaced by a younger model, dying of bitterness and grief, possessing the younger cantor in the middle of a service, and then being exorcised by a rabbi who teaches both ghost and victim a sweet melody in which to sing the blessing. It’s such a humane ghost story, and though there are terrifying elements, nobody is really evil. That’s the kind of tale I admire (and find it very hard to write, because let’s face it, evil characters are fun!).</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 039 Author Interview: Linda Codega and &#8220;Tonghai&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-039-author-interview-linda-codega-and-tonghai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 039]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you checked out our Issue 039 yet? What are you waiting for? Today we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16304 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/geran-de-klerk-AXSoVgLaHmc-unsplash-1024x671.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="478" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/geran-de-klerk-AXSoVgLaHmc-unsplash-1024x671.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/geran-de-klerk-AXSoVgLaHmc-unsplash-300x197.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/geran-de-klerk-AXSoVgLaHmc-unsplash-768x503.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />Have you checked out our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-039/">Issue 039</a> yet? What are you waiting for? Today we chat with one of our Issue 039 authors (and editors of the <em>Quarterly</em>!) Linda Codega about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/tonghai/">Tonghai</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span id="m_-3399083531008578530gmail-docs-internal-guid-899d98c8-7fff-fe40-20d5-b0a0c4c21b57"><span class="im">You take your readers on a trip navigating the Tonghai, with all its dangers and adventures of life at sea. Added to the danger is the world of toxic oceans. Tell us a bit more about the time and place you&#8217;ve set this story, since the Tonghai is, after all, one of the main characters</span></span>.</strong></em></p>
<p>Linda: This story is set in a speculative far-future Earth. I don’t think that the prospect of a fully aquatic Earth is scientifically possible, but I saw <em>Water World</em> at an early age and it made an impression. I imagined the Tonghai as a desert, wide-reaching and impossible to truly navigate from the landscape itself, an ever-changing and tumultuous environment caused by human hubris.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The setting is unfortunately hard to pin down. On one hand, any ocean can be the Tonghai, and on the other, this story is centered around Chinese mythology and space. The constellations and navigation that happens is a simplified and extravagant version of the South China Sea. I wanted to make sure that the descriptions of the entire world would be applicable to any ocean and tried to avoid using specific markers or species, opting for fauna that could have been from anywhere.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The Tonghai in this story is an ocean poisoned by all the causes of the environmental crises we find ourselves in. Fracking, oil, plastics, pollutants, and chemicals have combined into a gloopy, heavier-than-water, toxic sludge that is carried along by currents as the world turns. This is inspired by the ways in which the world often turns and adapts to correct itself, much like a living organism seeks to eject poison and infection.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span id="m_-3399083531008578530gmail-docs-internal-guid-899d98c8-7fff-fe40-20d5-b0a0c4c21b57"><span class="im">Do you have experience or an interest in open sea sailing? Jian proves more than adept on the Green Moon and your descriptions of both classic and futuristic boating make this story very rich and plausible, so that the reader feels she is alongside Jian the whole time. Where did you get your inspiration for the solar sails and other technologies onboard the Green Moon?</span></span></strong></em></p>
<p>Linda: I have been a sailor almost my entire life, and have been on a handful of open sea voyages myself. My entire family has a keen interest in boats, sailing, fishing, and the ocean, so I grew up on the water and on deck. I’m lucky that I have the right kind of sailing experience to translate sailing-speak to a clear story! I love boats and it’s great to see that come through in my writing.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Much of the inspiration for the technology on the Green Moon comes from inventions and <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16305 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bobby-burch-7ghPaPLdmTY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bobby-burch-7ghPaPLdmTY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bobby-burch-7ghPaPLdmTY-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/bobby-burch-7ghPaPLdmTY-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />advancements that are either being tested or are considered speculative futures for sailing. Many long-distance boats are already outfitted with solar panels for the deck, so it was just another step to move the panes upward. I thought about what I would want on a long journey, and I thought about the ways in which one could sustainably survive on a boat with limited resources.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: J<span id="m_-3399083531008578530gmail-docs-internal-guid-899d98c8-7fff-fe40-20d5-b0a0c4c21b57"><span class="im">ian&#8217;s interactions with ocean life are fascinating &#8212; for example, the giant sea turtle and the nudibranches. What do her interactions with each of these animals tell us about her character? </span></span></strong></em></p>
<p>Linda: Jian is, at her core, a romantic. She believes in life, and in stories, and in the future. Her search for Clean Water and her interactions with the world around her can be read as naive, but I wanted to emphasize that she is deeply empathetic, caring, and hopeful. There are plenty of opportunities for her to give up, to take the easy way out, or to even stop caring altogether, but she survives.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I wanted a character who was built on hope, who saw herself reflected in the world around her. She is enchanted by the Earth, and she loves it dearly. Each interaction with the animals that survive alongside her is based on a deep love and respect for their resistance and strength. I really wanted to emphasize the duality of self-interest and empathy.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span id="m_-3399083531008578530gmail-docs-internal-guid-899d98c8-7fff-fe40-20d5-b0a0c4c21b57"><span class="im">It could be argued that the tellerites are the unknown in this story. Can you comment on this? At the end, has Jian found what she was looking for all along? Why or why not? </span></span></strong></em></p>
<p>Linda: I wanted to have something in the story that indicated either a secondary civilization or another world outside of the struggles of life on the Tonghai. I don’t have a clear idea about what the tellerites were made for, or who created them, but the core of it was that there is hope out there for a different life. I didn’t want to imply the presence of alien life in this story any more than I wanted to imply human survivors. The tellerites could be space stations created in the late 22nd century. They could be aliens. They could be satellites that simply dipped too low in orbit to revolve above the atmosphere. The takeaway from their presence is the idea that things could be different.</p>
<p dir="ltr">At the end, I don’t know if Jian found what she wanted or not. She thought she had found something different, and I don’t want to confirm an ending outside of what was written. I think that Jian has embarked on a new journey, even if she’s still on the Tonghai.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span id="m_-3399083531008578530gmail-docs-internal-guid-899d98c8-7fff-fe40-20d5-b0a0c4c21b57"><span class="im">What other writing projects are you working on right now?</span></span></strong></em></p>
<p>Linda: I’m always working on a couple of short stories and I’m currently working on a larger novel with my best friend. I’ve become more interested recently in horror and fantasy, and I’m trying to find a way to bring those things together without being too corny, cliche, or reliant on exploitative horror tropes to make a point.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I’m also working on a few role-playing games and projects. I hope to have more to announce on this soon, but you can always follow my narrative games and adventures <a href="https://lhcodega.itch.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://lhcodega.itch.io/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1570269815058000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFrvSXjk0MiEbuyHeCWBu6AmWe0gA">here, on my itch.io page!</a></p>
<p dir="ltr">Otherwise, that’s about it! Twitter is the best place to keep abreast of my writing, so give me a follow for nerd content, writing tweets, and sad lamentations at @_linfinn</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 039 Author Interview: Lisa Fox and &#8220;Seeing Utopia&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-039-author-interview-lisa-fox-and-seeing-utopia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 10:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 039]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16273</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear readers! Hope you&#8217;re enjoying our Issue 039 as much as we are! Today we&#8217;re&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16274 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ashton-mullins-j1HU-Oll7KI-unsplash-1024x678.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="483" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ashton-mullins-j1HU-Oll7KI-unsplash-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ashton-mullins-j1HU-Oll7KI-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ashton-mullins-j1HU-Oll7KI-unsplash-768x509.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />Dear readers! Hope you&#8217;re enjoying our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-039/">Issue 039</a> as much as we are! Today we&#8217;re chatting with one of the thirteen awesome authors featured in our current issue &#8212; here&#8217;s Lisa Fox to tell us about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/seeing-utopia/">Seeing Utopia</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: T<span class="im">he story starts with a queen completely fooled by her suitor, a tragic mistake for herself and her kingdom. Tell us more about Queen Aclara. How were you able to create this character who was incredibly vulnerable and yet still strong?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Lisa: Queen Aclara is someone we probably can all relate to. Everyone thinks they&#8217;re a good judge of character, yet everyone in their lives has been burned at least once, twice, by someone who pretended to be something they weren&#8217;t. In Aclara&#8217;s case, and in her position, being deceived as she was had much higher stakes. She is a leader, a ruler with responsibilities that still exist even with the mistakes she made and with the guilt that weighs upon her. But as good leaders do, they seek advise and counsel from others around them. They allow you to see their human side &#8211; shortcomings and all &#8211; while maintaining a resolve that engenders trust. I suppose I painted her after the best leaders/managers I&#8217;ve had, my own experience as a manager of people in the corporate world, and my experience &#8220;managing&#8221; my two sons. You&#8217;re going to make mistakes. Things are going to go wrong. It&#8217;s how you handle yourself in the difficult times that defines your character. And your effectiveness as a leader.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">The dichotomy of the sister witches, Myth and Janin, is endearing and enjoyable and really the crux of the story itself. Are these two characters based on individuals you know or perhaps based on pieces of yourself? What was it like to create these too almost opposing yet benevolent forces? </span></strong></em></p>
<p>Lisa: Definitely based on two sides of me! And a little of the whole left brain/right brain thing, too. Sometimes I think it&#8217;s easier to be Myth and harder to be Janin, but as we see in the end, both sides coming together are really critical. I had a lot of fun creating these two &#8211; their quirks, nuances, and most of all their interactions.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The loss of the queen&#8217;s sight is both literal and metaphorical. Did you know how this story would end when you started writing it or did it figure itself out as you went along? </strong></em></p>
<p>Lisa: This was one that I definitely wrote from end to beginning. I knew how it would end from the moment I started writing it. Aclara&#8217;s journey and key question is &#8220;what is a leader without vision?&#8221; She consults the sisters (who had the vision to defeat the king) to help be her &#8220;eyes&#8221; as she looks to rebuild. The &#8220;friendly competition&#8221; Aclara establishes to bring the people back out again <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16275 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/jonny-caspari-A7ol2HfnycY-unsplash-683x1024.jpg" alt="" width="683" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/jonny-caspari-A7ol2HfnycY-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/jonny-caspari-A7ol2HfnycY-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/jonny-caspari-A7ol2HfnycY-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" />is an example of Aclara still maintaining her vision as a leader even though she doubts herself. It&#8217;s funny, the more I think about it, that Aclara&#8217;s journey is a little bit like in <em>The Wizard of Oz</em>, when Dorothy realizes she had the power within her the entire time &#8211; she didn&#8217;t need shoes, just the help of others to give her the confidence she needed to find her way. I think the same can be said of Aclara.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">What was the most difficult part of this story to write and why? </span></strong></em></p>
<p>Lisa: Bringing in three distinct points of view, three distinct voices, in a short space without it feeling disjointed. And getting around the potential for infodump with all the backstory. The story itself was the easy part. The mechanics took a while to get where I needed them to be.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us about them? </strong></em></p>
<p>Lisa: Right now I&#8217;m focused on short stories, so there&#8217;s a lot of ideation for new pieces and revision of pieces that have been drafted. I do have a few that are begging to become novels, so we&#8217;ll see where that goes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 039 Author Interview: Kate Sheeran Swed and &#8220;Recovery&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-039-author-interview-kate-sheeran-swed-and-recovery/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 10:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 039]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The weeks fly by and so do the pages of LSQ&#8216;s current issue. Please enjoy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16230 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ruben-bagues-WUTkYbM3SeM-unsplash-1024x640.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="456" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ruben-bagues-WUTkYbM3SeM-unsplash-1024x640.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ruben-bagues-WUTkYbM3SeM-unsplash-300x188.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ruben-bagues-WUTkYbM3SeM-unsplash-768x480.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />The weeks fly by and so do the pages of <em>LSQ</em>&#8216;s current issue. Please enjoy our chat with Issue 039 author Kate Sheeran Swed about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/recovery/">Recovery</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I</strong><span class="im"><strong>n the world you&#8217;ve created, everyone has a card that, when used, gives them back four minutes of their life. This raises so many interesting societal questions. What inspired this idea and what made you specifically settle on four minutes?</strong> </span></em></p>
<p>Kate: In most cases, it&#8217;s hard for me to pinpoint a precise inspiration for a story. But this one actually does have a very specific origin. I was heading to a write-in at my local library, where I get together with other authors a few times a month for focused writing time, and I stopped at Starbucks to grab coffee. Something happened with my drink&#8211;I don&#8217;t even remember what it was, but some minor customer service mishap occurred. I don&#8217;t tend to get bothered about these things since I&#8217;ve worked in customer service and I know mistakes happen. So I was surprised when the barista handed me what she called a recovery card, with four dollars of store credit on it to use toward a future purchase. I thought four dollars was a funny amount (not enough for a latte at the &#8216;bucks, right?) and I spent the writing session exploring what exactly they thought I was supposed to be recovering.</p>
<p>I settled on time and Penny appeared in my mind to share her opinion on the concept. Since then I&#8217;ve Googled the recovery card system to find out that they mean customer service recovery, whatever that means. Such is the brain of a writer, taking me on the oddest possible tangent! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">The main protagonist, Penny, refers occasionally to the time travel paradox. Did you know how you were going to navigate that before you wrote the story, or did Penny&#8217;s voice sort of naturally decide on the work around?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Kate: I dealt with it by deciding what story I wanted to tell&#8211;and Penny&#8217;s voice absolutely played a part in that. I&#8217;ll admit I&#8217;m still a <em>Lost</em> fan at heart, and I always appreciated the way they acknowledged the paradox of time travel without letting it get in the way of the core story. Same with the latest <em>Avengers</em> films. I didn&#8217;t want to go too much into it, but I couldn&#8217;t ignore it, either. The ripple effects that would happen if we really each had a chance to go back and change four minutes of our lives? It would be complete chaos. That wasn&#8217;t the story I wanted to tell, so I let Penny acknowledge the question right away so I could move on with her story.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: </strong><span class="im"><strong>Is this the first time travel story you&#8217;re written? Are there any other time travel stories out there you admire?</strong> </span></em></p>
<p>Kate: Yes, I&#8217;m pretty sure it is. I haven&#8217;t read too many. My husband adores Connie Willis, but I&#8217;ll admit I haven&#8217;t picked up her books yet, though I have enjoyed some of her short stories.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Penny and Molly are a delightful pair and ultimately, this is an uplifting story about empathy and selflessness. Are Penny and/or Molly modeled after anyone you know? Or do you identify more closely with one over the other? </span></strong></em></p>
<p>Kate: They&#8217;re not modeled after anyone I know specifically, mostly because that doesn&#8217;t tend to <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16231 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/jack-sharp-d_eoQs4NvDM-unsplash-768x1024.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="973" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/jack-sharp-d_eoQs4NvDM-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/jack-sharp-d_eoQs4NvDM-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />work for me. Whenever I start with a premise like this, I can&#8217;t begin the actual story unless I know who the story should belong to&#8211;which character will tell it. I&#8217;ve been wanting to write about a couple of old ladies on an adventure, and the premise matched that pretty perfectly. I love writing cranky characters, but even so I&#8217;d say Penny&#8217;s probably one of the crankiest I&#8217;ve ever written. I&#8217;m probably more of a Molly myself, in that I&#8217;m a little more optimistic in general. I like to write people who are really different from me, though. If this happened to me I&#8217;d probably pull the blankets up over my head and go back to sleep!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect of this story to write and why? Can you contrast this with what was the easiest aspect to write?</strong> </em></p>
<p>Kate: The easiest part was Penny&#8217;s voice for sure&#8211;if something like that lands, it&#8217;s like walking straight into another person&#8217;s head. I knew exactly what she&#8217;d say, from page one. For me, the challenge is usually figuring out exactly how the action will play out on the page. Sometimes it just comes together in the moment, and other times I need to sit and consider it for a while. In this case, that was the final confrontation with the Well Dressed Man. I think it came together pretty well in the end.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us about them?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Kate: Yes! I&#8217;m in the middle of releasing my sci fi novella trilogy, with the final book due out at the end of October. The first book, <em>Parting Shadows</em>, came out in July. It&#8217;s a sci fi imagining of <em>Great Expectations</em>, only it centers on Estella&#8217;s character, with a vengeful AI playing the part of Miss Havisham (or, as my mother-in-law puts it, &#8220;kind of like the Dickens novel, only the bride is Alexa). The second book came out in August, and that one plays on the story of <em>The Phantom of the Opera</em>. I&#8217;m working on the third now. It was originally supposed to be a take on <em>Treasure Island</em>, but it&#8217;s veered away from that story pretty spectacularly. Still, I think it might be my favorite! If folks want to know more about the series, they can visit my website: <a href="http://katesheeranswed.com/toccata-system-trilogy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://katesheeranswed.com/toccata-system-trilogy/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1569107274936000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFHTYbUQei-EGcMtmaOgo_vZxYciQ">http://katesheeranswed.com/<wbr />toccata-system-trilogy/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 039 Author Interview: Raluca Balasa and &#8220;Keep Moving&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-039-author-interview-raluca-balasa-and-keep-moving/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 10:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 039]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 039 came out two weeks ago and it&#8217;s filled with great speculative fiction short&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16185 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ryk-naves-b_-KVgWg_YM-unsplash-1024x946.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="674" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ryk-naves-b_-KVgWg_YM-unsplash-1024x946.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ryk-naves-b_-KVgWg_YM-unsplash-300x277.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ryk-naves-b_-KVgWg_YM-unsplash-768x710.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-039/">Issue 039</a> came out two weeks ago and it&#8217;s filled with great speculative fiction short stories by women-identifying authors. Today, we chat with Issue 039 author Raluca Balasa about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/keep-moving/">Keep Moving</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The world you&#8217;ve created is afraid of voices, human connections, seemingly anything that might inspire feeling. Where did this idea come from? Can you tell us more about this world and how the society&#8217;s rules influence those in charge?</strong></em></p>
<p>Raluca: This story was written as a prequel to an epic fantasy novel that I have in the works. The idea for the world came from my desire to write a fantasy around a complex magic system focused on music. In this world, legend has it that the goddess Arasu descended from the heavens to share her music with humanity, but humans were callous and ignorant of her gift, and so she cursed them. Music now has the ability to hurt people not only emotionally, but physically and magically. Only &#8220;royals&#8221; are immune &#8212; but even they aren&#8217;t foolproof. Musicians like Sarrai are thought to be Arasu&#8217;s Chosen: demons chosen specifically to inflict pain on those the devil-goddess hates.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us more about Sarrai. She moves from being led to think she&#8217;s royal to accepting fate as a monster. What does this confusion tell us about her character?</strong></em></p>
<p>Raluca: While Sarrai is a caring and selfless character, she&#8217;s not particularly good at empathizing. She always knew she was different, yet being unable to understand most people&#8217;s fear of emotional and physical stimuli, she didn&#8217;t imagine she would be hated for that difference. So it was easy for her to imagine she was a royal, or some Chosen One, or both. Learning she&#8217;s considered a monster taught her that others can&#8217;t be trusted because of their limited understanding of the world, and that she must take her survival into her own hands.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Children are taken away from their parents soon after birth but at the end, Sarrai chooses to raise a child by herself. What is her plan for the future? Are her plans benevolent or malevolent?</strong></em></p>
<p>Raluca: Sarrai&#8217;s really not thinking about what she&#8217;ll feed the child, how she&#8217;ll clothe it, or how she&#8217;ll cope if it dies after she takes it. Unlike many of my characters, she&#8217;s very impulsive. Her intentions are good, and she genuinely wants to save the baby from an upbringing like hers, but <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16186 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/priscilla-du-preez-FgNAw7qniIk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/priscilla-du-preez-FgNAw7qniIk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/priscilla-du-preez-FgNAw7qniIk-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/priscilla-du-preez-FgNAw7qniIk-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />the first year with it will be extremely difficult. That being said, she does develop a strong bond with her brother.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect of this story to write and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Raluca: The most challenging aspect of this story was figuring out how the magic works (and why). This story only touches on a sliver of what I hope to include in the novel.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about them? </strong></em></p>
<p>Raluca: Other than the music magic novel? Yes! I&#8217;m working on publishing &#8220;Blood State,&#8221; a character-driven science fiction novel that combines culture clash with noble family rivalries, extreme environments, and genetic experimentation. The novel will be coming out in 2020 from Renaissance Press!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
