<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Icy Sedgwick &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/icy-sedgwick/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 22:55:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Learn from the Horror Masters</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/learn-from-the-horror-masters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Icy Sedgwick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 15:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Monsters and Madmen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the past few months, I&#8217;ve suggested a few ways you can go about writing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the past few months, I&#8217;ve suggested a few ways you can go about writing your own horror work, including looking at monsters, and locations. However I&#8217;ve purposefully left the best until last &#8211; learning from how the professionals do it! Naturally there are some authors more synonymous with horror than others, and I&#8217;ve purposefully left out HP Lovecraft, Bram Stoker, Mary Shelley, and Edgar Allan Poe because they&#8217;re so well known, but here are five authors I think you should definitely check out, although there are many, many more that you can discover!</p>
<p><strong>MR James</strong></p>
<p>Montague Rhodes James died in 1936, and left behind a whole host of creepy stories, particularly those starring ghosts. Many earlier writers used familiar Gothic tropes, and James put his own stamp on the genre by taking those tropes and placing them into contemporary settings, although he&#8217;s often criticised for a somewhat formulaic approach to his writing, since many of his protagonists are professors (so was he, so he was &#8216;writing what he knew&#8217;). Obviously these stories read as &#8216;outdated&#8217; now, as we look back on them from the twenty-first century, but you can learn a lot from his pacing and characterisation, as skeptics become believers following horrible experiences. He&#8217;s perhaps best known for &#8220;The Mezzotint&#8221;, &#8220;Oh, Whistle, and I&#8217;ll Come to You, My Lad&#8221; and &#8220;Lost Hearts&#8221;, and both the BBC and ITV made adaptations of his stories. &#8220;Casting the Runes&#8221; was the inspiration for <em> Night of the Demon </em>(1957), starring Dana Andrews, which later inspired Sam Raimi&#8217;s godawful <em>Drag Me To Hell </em>(2009). Most recently, Mark Gatiss directed a new version of &#8220;The Tractate Middoth&#8221; for the BBC in 2013. You can download <em>Ghost Stories of an Antiquary Part 2: More Ghost Stories</em> <a href="https://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/9629">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Shirley Jackson</strong></p>
<p>Born in 1916, Shirley Jackson is perhaps most famous for her short story of 1948, called &#8220;The Lottery&#8221; (which you can read <a href="http://sites.middlebury.edu/individualandthesociety/files/2010/09/jackson_lottery.pdf">here</a>), and <em>The Haunting of Hill House</em> (1959), which was adapted in 1963 as <em>The Haunting</em>, directed by Robert Wise. I highly recommend the film as a study in how to generate tension without showing a monster, but the novel is equally instructive. Just 48 when she died, Jackson left behind a huge legacy in Hill House, and its redefinition of the haunted house. Previous houses were haunted by spectral entities, but for Jackson, the house WAS the ghost. Even if you read nothing else by her, make sure you check out &#8220;The Lottery&#8221; (the publication of which earned her hate mail) and <em>The Haunting of Hill House</em>. There&#8217;s an air of psychological vulnerability in <i>Hill House</i> which sets it apart from other haunted house novels, and this air of &#8216;otherness&#8217; also appears in <i>We Have Always Lived in the Castle</i> (1962).</p>
<p><strong>Stephen King</strong></p>
<p>You can&#8217;t write a list about influential horror novelists and not include Stephen King. Born in 1947, King has published over fifty novels since 1973. His horror novels encompass such a wide range of subgenres, from vampires (<em>Salem&#8217;s Lot</em>) to the Devil (<em>Needful Things</em>), via stalkers (<em>Misery</em>), aliens (<em>IT</em> and <em>The Tommyknockers</em>), psychokinesis (<em>Carrie</em>) and other psychic gifts (<em>The Shining</em>).  In <em>The Shining</em>, King also investigated the haunted house genre, setting up his story on an epic scale, with his &#8216;haunted house&#8217;, the Overlook Hotel, becoming an extra character in the story. Some of his ideas are better than others, but even in his terrible books, his characterisation sets him apart. These are people you want to follow, who could live next door to you. While his narratives occasionally venture into absurdity (<em>Rose Madder</em>), his short stories are instructive exercises for anyone wanting to get started in writing horror shorts.</p>
<p><strong>Richard Matheson</strong></p>
<p>Many know the name, if not his work, but Matheson, born in 1926, has written plenty of material that&#8217;s worth a look. He&#8217;s perhaps best known as the author of <em>I Am Legend</em>, published in 1954, but he also wrote short stories, as well as episodes of <em>The Twilight Zone. </em>You know the famous one where William Shatner sees a monster on the wing of the aeroplane in which he&#8217;s flying? Yep, that was Matheson. He also wrote <em>A Stir of Echoes</em> (1958), <em>Hell House</em> (1971), and <em>What Dreams May Come</em> (1978), all of which have been adapted by Hollywood. He didn&#8217;t just write horror, and has plenty of genres to his name, and that&#8217;s why he&#8217;s worth a look &#8211; you might see elements of your own genre within his work, and you can see how you might turn that towards the direction of horror.</p>
<p><strong>Clive Barker</strong></p>
<p>Bringing horror back to Britain, Barker was born in Liverpool in 1952, and is an author, film director, video game designer and visual artist. Perhaps best known for <em>Hellraiser</em> and <em>Candyman</em>, it&#8217;s his <em>Books of Blood</em> anthologies that I want to highlight here. The short story format is an excellent training ground for new horror writers, and its within these stories that you can really see Barker explore his ideas around other worlds existing alongside our own. He doesn&#8217;t shy away from visceral body horror, and his work can often be more gruesome than the other writers I&#8217;ve mentioned here. Still, I think his visual style, even within his short stories, bears examination, and seeing the way that he indulges his rampant imagination can be a great &#8216;unblocker&#8217; for creativity. He describes his style as being &#8220;dark fantasy&#8221; but he easily belongs in the horror camp.</p>
<p><strong>Have you read any of these authors?</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who&#8217;s afraid of the Big Bad Wolf?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/whos-afraid-of-the-big-bad-wolf/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Icy Sedgwick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 14:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Monsters and Madmen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last month we talked about the importance of location in horror, and this time I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last month we talked about the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-location-in-horror/">importance of location in horror</a>, and this time I want to talk about characters. Not ALL characters &#8211; horror has a certain set of &#8216;rules&#8217; about its characters, so I want to break it down to talk about a very specific type of character; The Antagonist.</p>
<p>There are different types of antagonist within horror. You have some, like Buffalo Bill in <em>The Silence of the Lambs</em>, who are the antagonist within the crime to be solved, but the true &#8216;monster&#8217; of the piece is Hannibal Lecter. Then there&#8217;s Patrick Bateman, the narrator who is both protagonist AND antagonist in <em>American Psycho</em>. Obviously the type of antagonist is in some ways dictated by the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/horror-101/">type of horror</a>, but these are some of the villains you might like to pit your hero against.</p>
<p><strong>The Monster &#8211; Bad to the Bone</strong></p>
<p>The good old-fashioned monster. Dracula. Mr Hyde. Jason Voorhees. Freddie Krueger. These are the monsters who are either bad and they know it (but they don&#8217;t care), or they&#8217;re just plain out to get you. There can be no sympathizing with these monsters &#8211; we might think they&#8217;re cool, but we can&#8217;t justify what they do, or understand them on any level. They&#8217;ll either kill or be killed, and your plot will arise out of a) how the body count rises while the hero evades them and b) how the hero discovers how to destroy them. In some cases your hero will just simply contain them, rather than outright destroy them, but either way your hero will save the day, albeit temporarily. Be careful that your monster isn&#8217;t cooler than your hero &#8211; while it&#8217;s difficult to root for the Woman in Black compared to Arthur Kipps, the kids in the <em>Nightmare on Elm Street</em> films were so nondescript that it was easy to prefer wise-cracking Freddie.</p>
<p><strong>The Monster &#8211; Misunderstood</strong></p>
<p>You&#8217;ve always got the other type of monster &#8211; the one who&#8217;s monstrous, but through no fault of their own. Think Frankenstein&#8217;s Creature, or Karloff&#8217;s Imhotep from <em>The Mummy</em>. There&#8217;s something oddly appealing about these characters, who are both deadly, but desperate to be loved or understood. There is a lot more pathos in their stories, as the plot may see the hero destroy them (while not really wanting to), and we often end up rooting for them because they&#8217;re in such a horrid situation. Take Imhotep &#8211; he simply wants to be reunited with his love, and he&#8217;s a far more interesting character than the wet &#8216;hero&#8217; who is set up to save her. These monsters often do generate sympathy, which is what makes their end more tragic than triumphant.</p>
<p><strong>The Serial Killer</strong></p>
<p>Serial killers are considered a form of monster, but the distinction usually arises from the fact that while monsters may have once been human, they are now monstrous in their form, while serial killers are humans who are monstrous through their deeds. Cinema in particular is full of interesting, complicated and utterly chilling serial killers, and horror fiction is much the same. Just make sure you give your serial killer some kind of reason or justification beyond general madness, otherwise the randomness of their acts turns them into little more than zombies, driven only by bloodlust. Serial killers also let you play with the conventions of the police procedural, as there has to be some form of investigation to uncover exactly who they are, and what they want.</p>
<p><strong>The Ghost/Supernatural Presence</strong></p>
<p>Ghosts are wonderful antagonists because they tick so many boxes. Like the room in <em>1408</em>, they can be simply evil for the sake of it, or like the Woman in Black, they can be driven to dark deeds through a need for revenge, or because they become trapped in an eternal cycle of killing and re-enactment of the original crime. Ghost narratives also require an investigation by the hero into the past of the story&#8217;s location in order to explain the ghost&#8217;s motivations, and possible weaknesses, but because ghosts are already dead, they hold a lot more cards than your vulnerable, human hero. Fire is usually a good way to make a point.</p>
<p><strong>Nature</strong></p>
<p>Survival horror continues, and you can easily pit your unwary humans against bees, wolves, zombies, or even killer frogs. Revenge-of-nature films pit nature itself in the role of the monster &#8211; look at Jaws &#8211; but if you look again, you&#8217;ll often find that the problem occurs as a result of human intervention in the first place. Still, with nature&#8217;s arsenal at your disposal, you can come up with some interesting secondary antagonists along the way, particularly those humans who want to blast in with firepower or nukes, where simple containment or appeasement will do. In these cases, the &#8216;good&#8217; humans need &#8216;bad&#8217; humans to fight while trying to subdue nature, since nature can never truly be conquered.</p>
<p><strong>Can you think of any others?</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Location in Horror</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-location-in-horror/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-location-in-horror/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Icy Sedgwick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 15:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Monsters and Madmen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;ve previously talked about types of horror, and the basic process to actually write a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;ve previously talked about types of horror, and the basic process to actually write a horror story, but I thought we might spend the next few posts looking at the elements of a successful horror story. You can have all of the gory bits you like, but without some building blocks, your story might not be as rounded as it could be. So this month we&#8217;re going to look at my own personal favourite, location!</p>
<p>You&#8217;ll often hear the phrase &#8216;location, location, location&#8217;, and in horror, it&#8217;s just as important. Without somewhere for your story to take place, it&#8217;s still just an idea. Of course, horror is very closely allied with one of the most famous settings of all, the haunted house. In the case of these stories, the space itself IS the story. Think of the Overlook hotel in <em>The Shining</em>, or Hill House in <em>The Haunting</em>.</p>
<p>You essentially have a choice between three basic ideas when devising locations.</p>
<p><strong>The Ordinary</strong></p>
<p>Think of the ordinary, mundane, normal spaces into which horror erupts. Look at the identikit house of <em>Poltergeist</em>, or the thoroughly nondescript houses of <em>Insidious</em>. These could be any house in any neighbourhood &#8211; they could be next door to your house, or worse still, they could BE your house.</p>
<p>Sigmund Freud wrote an incredibly influential essay in 1919 entitled &#8216;The Uncanny&#8217;, and while the uncanny covers many areas that are beyond the scope of this post, a fundamental point is that around familiarity. Uncanny feelings are provoked when something familiar becomes unfamiliar &#8211; and few things are as unfamiliar as your house becoming the conduit to the afterlife, or a battleground between you and a rampaigning psychopath. This, in particular, helps to generate the horror for readers because this house is so familiar because it&#8217;s so like their own. If ghosts can move in, or a serial killer can enter freely, then who&#8217;s to say it couldn&#8217;t happen to them?</p>
<p><strong>The Not-Quite-Right</strong></p>
<p>These are the locations which just aren&#8217;t normal. They aren&#8217;t bad, but there is something &#8216;off&#8217; about them from the start. We know when Rosemary first views the flat in the Bramford building in <em>Rosemary&#8217;s Baby</em> that this is not a happy place. Still, the place in itself isn&#8217;t inherently bad, it just isn&#8217;t a comforting space, and it merely bears witness to the horror. These spaces unsettle the characters, and with them the readers, and you can play on their &#8216;not-quite-rightness&#8217; to generate suspense, since the readers can tell something is off about the place, and they&#8217;re waiting on tenterhooks to see what will go wrong. These are spaces that could be cured though &#8211; the slightly dated Rhode Island house of <em>The Conjuring</em> just needs its resident evil presence to be evicted (presumably along with the hideous furniture).</p>
<p><strong>The &#8216;Bad&#8217; Place</strong></p>
<p>In her landmark horror text, <em>Men, Women and Chainsaws</em>, Carol Clover talks about the concept of the &#8216;bad&#8217; place. These are those places that are just bad to the bone, baby. They&#8217;re the Overlook hotels, the Hill Houses, the 1408 hotel rooms, the Castle Draculas, the houses at 112 Ocean Avenue. While they occasionally may look alright to start with &#8211; in fact, Mike Enslin is downright surprised at just how unthreatening and boring room 1408 appears when he first enters &#8211; they are evil through and through.</p>
<p>These places are a lot of fun to write because you don&#8217;t even necessarily need an actual antagonist because the space itself becomes the antagonist. The space holds all the cards, and can change the rules whenever it wants, and the characters simply have to hold on and hope they can survive long enough to escape. There is always a tension between &#8220;inside&#8221; and &#8220;outside&#8221;, and getting out, and ultimately away, is the biggest goal. The characters aren&#8217;t trying to defeat evil, or vanquish a villain, they just don&#8217;t want to die.</p>
<p>The beauty of these spaces is that you don&#8217;t even need to explain why the space is evil &#8211; it just is. No one knows why room 1408 kills its occupants, or why the mysterious tunnel in the Paris catacombs is so keen to claim the urban explorers in <em>As Above, So Below</em>. The only important fact is that they simply do these things, irrespective of why. The lack of reasoning makes them illogical and therefore completely outside of anything we can truly understand.</p>
<p>Personally, I find the bad place the more interesting to write because it gives a wider arena of locations to play with. Look at haunted theme parks, or demon-infested nightclubs. They do tend to be more spectral in nature, and if your inclinations run to more body-based horror, then you might want to concentrate on evil entering an otherwise ordinary home, but why not try mixing and matching? Could your serial killer survive in a space like room 1408?</p>
<p><strong>What types of settings do you like in your horror stories, and do you find that a good setting can redeem a mediocre story, or do you feel that sometimes story is sacrified for the sake of an interesting setting?</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-location-in-horror/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Steps to Writing Horror</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/5-steps-to-writing-horror/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Icy Sedgwick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 15:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Monsters and Madmen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2228</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So last month we talked about the three &#8216;umbrella&#8217; terms for horror &#8211; Visceral, Psychological,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/horror-101/">last month</a> we talked about the three &#8216;umbrella&#8217; terms for horror &#8211; Visceral, Psychological, and Supernatural. Remember that a horror story can encompass one or more of those areas and still be horror.</p>
<p>But how do you go about writing a horror story? This post is essentially for those of you who have never written a horror story, or wanted to and weren&#8217;t sure where to start. If you have written horror before, then maybe try this five point program and try writing a story that sits under a different umbrella.</p>
<p><strong>1) Read horror &#8211; and lots of it!</strong></p>
<p>This should be a no-brainer, but it&#8217;s amazing how many people try to write a genre without reading it first. Don&#8217;t worry that you&#8217;ll end up copying someone else&#8217;s ideas &#8211; your concepts might be similar, but your execution will be entirely yours as only you will view your idea in your particular way. Decide which of the umbrellas you might want to sit under and read within that sub-genre. Watch horror films, too. Films and literature are not the same, but you can learn a lot about pacing and structure from films. Treat this as &#8216;research&#8217;. Check out Goodreads for recommendations for where to start. Hell, ask me, and I&#8217;ll give you a homework list of films to watch!</p>
<p><strong>2) Brainstorm.</strong></p>
<p>Now you&#8217;ve done your research, you&#8217;ll be much better placed to know how your chosen sub-genre works. Generic conventions are not a straitjacket &#8211; they&#8217;re more like set dressing. Humans like the comfort of familiarity, and are often drawn to &#8216;more of the same&#8217;. You just give them that, but with your own unique twist!</p>
<p>That said, you don&#8217;t just want to write about the same stuff as everyone else. If you&#8217;ve read a novel about a cannibal who lives in the basement of a creepy house then you probably aren&#8217;t going to write a novel about the same thing. But you might want to write about something else that lives in a basement &#8211; only this one might be the basement of a shiny, upmarket New York apartment building. What is it? How did it get there? This is what you&#8217;ll put in your brainstorm &#8211; settings, time periods, characters, anything that really caught your attention. You need a pool of ideas in which to go fishing.</p>
<p><strong>3) Get scared.</strong></p>
<p>Unlike film noir or the Western, which are genres bound by iconography and themes, horror and comedy are two of the rare genres that rely on the emotion they produce. Clearly horror&#8217;s goal is to horrify (there is a subset of horror, called terror, which is obviously meant to terrify &#8211; this road will lead you towards Psychological horror and the world of the thriller). So add more things to your brainstorm &#8211; this time, add things that scare you. Phobias are fine, too. Would <em>IT</em> have worked if Pennywise wasn&#8217;t a clown?</p>
<p>True, some things might scare you that don&#8217;t scare other people &#8211; I know someone who&#8217;s terrified of cotton wool &#8211; but put them down anyway. Your brainstorm is essentially a mind dump, and you&#8217;ll pick through for gems when you&#8217;re done. You can even add sensations &#8211; loneliness is a popular one, and &#8216;not fitting in&#8217; gave us <em>Carrie</em>!</p>
<p><strong>4) Mix and match!</strong></p>
<p>Put your brainstorm aside for a few days and come back to it with fresh eyes. Look at what you&#8217;ve added. Are there any common themes? Does anything leap out? Underline those words, or highlight them in some way. Once you&#8217;ve picked out a few things, write them on a new sheet of paper, with plenty of space around them. Now you can see them more clearly, really think about what words you&#8217;ve got. What connections can you make between them? Maybe you&#8217;ve got &#8216;roadside diner&#8217;, &#8216;poltergeist&#8217;, and &#8216;dark places&#8217;. You might immediately think about a poltergeist who terrorises the patrons of a roadside diner, one which is already struggling for business as it competes with McDonalds. So who is afraid of the dark? Could it be your protagonist? From this point, you&#8217;re then working up a plot, all from what you added to your brainstorm.</p>
<p><strong>5) Now get writing.</strong></p>
<p>This process might sound dreadfully formulaic, but the brainstorm is essentially just a catalyst, something to get you going. Once you know who and what your story will be about, your creative juices will take over and the story will unspool just the way it needs to. Things will crop up in the writing that you never would have imagined during the brainstorm &#8211; and that&#8217;s where the beauty of it lies. Your mind will have taken all of that raw data from your reading/viewing, and all of the thinking you did while you made the brainstorm, and turned it into something real. That in itself should be scary enough!</p>
<p>Next time I&#8217;ll talk about familiar tropes and characters that you might want to reinvent, but I hope this post has given you some food for thought about getting started writing horror. Good luck &#8211; and do let me know how you get on!</p>
<p><strong>Have you ever written a horror story, and if not, do you think you&#8217;ll give it a go?</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Horror 101</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/horror-101/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/horror-101/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Icy Sedgwick]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 15:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Monsters and Madmen]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=1989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As this is the first post for this horror-themed column, I thought we&#8217;d take some&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As this is the first post for this horror-themed column, I thought we&#8217;d take some time out to have a look at the main areas of horror &#8211; after all, it&#8217;s a wide-ranging genre whose content includes both <em>Poltergeist</em> and <em>Saw</em>. Some people will say they don&#8217;t like gory films, but they like ghost stories, while others find demonic activity boring when compared with thrillers &#8211; but they&#8217;re all horror! One really good way to learn to write horror fiction is to read horror novels, but you&#8217;ll also learn a lot by watching horror films.</p>
<p>I do think that if you boil horror down to its constituent parts, you can see there are three broad areas &#8211; Supernatural, Visceral, and Psychological. Some stories remain solely in one area (<em>Saw</em> is very much visceral and never strays beyond that), while others occupy two positions (where <em>The Shining</em> explores Jack&#8217;s psychological breakdown against a background of supernatural occurrences), but few flirt with all three. If you want to write horror, it&#8217;s probably best to decide which &#8216;type&#8217; you want to produce, and consider how your story will work with the elements of that type. Bear in mind that there are other types of horror, such as comedy horror, but they still come under one of these three umbrellas.</p>
<p><strong>Supernatural Horror</strong></p>
<p>Think ghosts, demons, cosmic forces beyond our ken &#8211; if it isn&#8217;t defined by physical laws, and has a foot in a realm other than that of the living, then it&#8217;s Supernatural. Remember horror doesn&#8217;t have to have monsters &#8211; it has to horrify, and being confronted by your own mortality is exactly that. MR James was a master of the supernatural tale, although perhaps the most famous ghost story of them all is Dickens&#8217; <em>A Christmas Carol</em>.</p>
<p>Humans are fascinated with ideas of what happens to the soul after death, and religious horror also comes under the umbrella of &#8216;supernatural&#8217; due to its engagement with life after death, miracles, and other unexplained phenomena. There is a subset of &#8216;cosmic horror&#8217;, which includes the likes of H.P. Lovecraft and deals with notions of ancient gods, or beings in other dimensions seeking to punch their way through to ours, but I think this ultimately comes under the heading of Supernatural as these are things &#8216;not of this earth&#8217;.</p>
<p>Haunted houses are a perennial favourite, as is demonic activity or possession. There&#8217;s a general assumption, at least in horror films, that whatever the viewer doesn&#8217;t see will always be more frightening than what they do, since the imagination is such a powerful thing. Bear this is mind when writing Supernatural horror.</p>
<p><strong>Visceral Horror</strong></p>
<p>Gore, gore, and more gore &#8211; this is the stock in trade of Visceral horror. <em>The Texas Chainsaw Massacre</em>, <em>The Hills Have Eyes</em>, and <em>Hostel</em> would all be good examples of visceral horror. This particular subset explores the darker side of humanity, although supernatural monsters are equally welcome here &#8211; <em>A Nightmare on Elm Street</em> and <em>Suspiria</em> are a good examples of the combining of Visceral and Supernatural.</p>
<p>Body parts are rendered, blood spatters, cannibalistic families live in isolated houses, ready to prey on unsuspecting visitors, and people uncover abbatoirs and killing rooms hidden below seemingly normal houses. I&#8217;d also argue that while a lot of monsters are Supernatural by their nature, some monsters, such as vampires, also come under Visceral due to the manner in which they kill.</p>
<p>Visceral horror is not for the squeamish, and while its film variant relies heavily upon special effects makeup and a liberal application of fake blood, its literary equivalent must be extremely descriptive to conjure up these images in the imagination of the reader.</p>
<p><strong>Psychological Horror</strong></p>
<p>A lot of psychological horror stories also masquerade as thrillers, since they often deal with the exploration of a disturbed mind. <em>The Silence of the Lambs</em> is a good example &#8211; possibly the only horror film ever to win an Oscar, it&#8217;s largely considered to be a thriller so that critics feel they&#8217;re allowed to like it. It&#8217;s also an example of blending horror types, mixing Psychological with Visceral.</p>
<p>But psychological horror isn&#8217;t just about getting into the mind of a killer &#8211; it can also be about the mindset of the victim. Roman Polanski&#8217;s <em>Repulsion</em> explored the mental breakdown of a young woman living in 1960s London, and the &#8216;horror&#8217; comes from the things she does as a result. If you want to combine subsets, then Psychological works well with Supernatural. <em>The Haunting</em> by Shirley Jackson is a famous example, exploring the mental unravelling of Eleanor while staying at the haunted Hill House. Is the house really haunted &#8211; or is everything just inside Eleanor&#8217;s head? The novel is well worth a read, and if you decide to watch the film make sure it&#8217;s the 1963 Robert Wise version, and not the 1999 Jan de Bont remake.</p>
<p>Psychological horror depends upon tension, and a level of sympathy with the afflicted victim, or fascination with the afflicted villain.</p>
<p><strong>What do you think? What type of horror do you prefer?</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/horror-101/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
