<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Health and Fitness for Creative People &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/health-and-fitness-for-creative-people/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 02:27:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Buyer Beware!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/buyer-beware/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sandra Wickham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 18:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health and Fitness for Creative People]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4675</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is no quick fix, magic formula or miracle pill when it comes to health&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is no quick fix, magic formula or miracle pill when it comes to health and fitness, yet you can’t surf the net without being bombarded by ads for food that fight fat, the ultimate diet or quick fix workout program. I’m here to tell you, nothing works for everyone. Don’t buy into it, literally. Save your money.</p>
<p>I cringe every time I see a quick fix workout pasted on Pinterest or any other website. This is what happens. Someone with the best intentions does the 10 minute workout diligently for a month, maybe more. They begin to get discouraged because they’re not looking like the model in the picture and inevitably they end up quitting. Go ahead, browse those workouts, but be aware of what’s behind them. Those Pinterest pictures and other promotions link to websites that are trying to take your money. Of course they’re going to make it look enticing and promote it as a quick and easy way to get results.</p>
<p>Writers need to be wary of agents who approach them and say if they pay them x amount of dollars, the agent will get them published and make them famous. The same thing applies to anyone trying to take your money in exchange for a shortcut to health and fitness results. These people are salespeople whose aim is to take your money. I think because it’s the health and fitness industry, people believe what they see. How could anyone possibly steer someone wrong about their health? There are always people ready to take advantage of others for a quick buck.</p>
<p>Any time you are looking at hiring a trainer, purchasing a program, or anything else you need to pull out your wallet for, make sure you know what you’re getting. Like anything else you’d buy, research the person, website or program as much as you can. Look for reviews, ask questions and don’t spend your money until you’re comfortable with it. Finally, remember, no matter how much money you spend on a nutrition plan or workout program, it’s not going to help unless you put in the time. There is no quick fix, but there are results to be had from diligent effort.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Water, water everywhere!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/water-water-everywhere/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sandra Wickham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2015 20:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health and Fitness for Creative People]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If I could convince people of one thing to change their level of health and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">If I could convince people of one thing to change their level of health and fitness, it would be to drink more water. Headaches, fatigue and bloating can all be a result of not drinking enough water and could easily be alleviated by more intake of the straight up stuff.</p>
<p class="p4"><span class="s1">Most people are walking around in a constant state of dehydration and don’t even know it. Dehydration to even small levels can cause headaches and extreme fatigue. Tired, cranky, not feeling your best during the day? Drink more water! </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">When you don’t eat enough food, the body thinks it is starving and will hold onto all the calories it can. Similarly, if the body doesn’t get enough water, it will hold onto every drop and holds it in the outside cells, causing a bloated appearance. Reduce water retention by drinking <i>more</i> water!</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">As an added bonus, water helps metabolize stored body fat! Increasing your water intake can help reduce fat deposits. Your entire body needs water to function properly, including your kidneys and liver. If the kidneys do not have enough water to function properly, part of their job is put onto the liver. Metabolizing stored fat into usable energy for the body is one of the liver’s primary functions. If the liver is doing the job of the kidneys, it cannot do its job of metabolizing fat properly. </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">Drinking water also helps the body get rid of waste. TMI? Perhaps, but it’s important. To function normally, your body needs water to help flush out the waste. While losing weight, this increases and drinking plenty of water will help flush out that waste. </span></p>
<p class="p4"><span class="s1">You can drink other things besides water (though I don’t recommend high calorie drinks, myself, I’d rather eat my calories) but make sure you also get the water in. Drinking diet pop, or other flavoured drinks are a poor replacement for actual water. Most people know tea and coffee are diuretics, so the water in your coffee and tea doesn’t count.</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">So how much water is enough? The average recommendation of eight 8 ounce glasses a day is only a minimum. That amount should increase:</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">&#8211; If you have excess body fat to lose (additional glass for every 25lbs of excess weight)</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">&#8211; If you exercise-before, during and after!</span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">&#8211; On hot and dry days </span></p>
<p class="p7"><span class="s1">The easiest way to monitor how much water you drink is to fill a bottle with a measured amount, carry it with you and use it to drink from or pour glasses of water from. A one litre bottle (33.8 ounces for USA readers) is a great way to start. I drink 4L (about a gallon) of water on an average day. Using a 1L bottle makes that easy to track.</span></p>
<p class="p4"><span class="s1">So, let’s drink to a healthier, happier body, with a fresh, clear class of water!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Health and Fitness for Creative People &#8211; Yes, It’s Important</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/health-and-fitness-for-creative-people-yes-its-important/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sandra Wickham]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 16:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Health and Fitness for Creative People]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First, I want to address a stereotype that intelligent, creative type people (dare I say,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First, I want to address a stereotype that intelligent, creative type people (dare I say, nerds) cannot also be fit people. If you’re a writer, artist, or creative person, it doesn’t mean you can’t also be athletic and healthy. Conversely, just because you become more athletic, lean out, gain some muscle or improve your cardiovascular health, does not mean your IQ is going to drop. It’s just the opposite.</p>
<p>Strong in body really does mean stronger in mind. If your body is not functioning at its very best, how can you expect your brain to? If you’re not getting enough sleep, if you’re supplying your body with the wrong type of fuel, it’s going to affect your brain function, which relates to the quantity and quality of the art you will be able to produce.</p>
<p>Let’s face it. If someone is strong, no amount of strength is going to make them smart. However, if you’re smart, you can get strong.</p>
<p>Many of your friends might be inactive and don’t care to change. That doesn’t mean you have to follow the same pattern. Do you think they’ll respect you less if you decide to focus on living a long, healthy and functional life? If they do, it’s time to ditch those friends. More than likely, they’ll cheer you on in your efforts and they might even be inspired by your example to do the same.</p>
<p>Do you want to live long enough to write a five book series? Do you want to have the energy to finish your projects to your utmost potential? All it takes a brief amount of time, where you get away from your desk and get active. Go for a walk and let your creative side run free, you’ll be amazed at what it can come up with while you exercise. Don’t buy into the flawed thinking that you can’t be smart AND fit. Remember, brains and brawn should go together!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
