<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Spaceships and Notebooks &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/spaceships-and-notebooks/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 04:22:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Some M/M Books to Add To Your TBR</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/some-m-m-books-to-add-to-your-tbr/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KT Howard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 11:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spaceships and Notebooks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A few months ago, I asked where are all the M/M queer books? Since then,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few months ago, I asked <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/where-are-all-the-multi-level-market-i-mean-men-loving-men/">where are all the M/M queer books</a>? Since then, I discovered where: fanfiction and indie publishers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26346 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AO3.png" alt="" width="225" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AO3.png 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/AO3-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />Earlier this year, Archive of Our Own user centeroftheselights compiled a list of the <a href="https://archiveofourown.org/works/32940190?view_full_work=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">top 100 ships of all time</a>. The vast majority of the ships on that list are men loving men. In fact, it’s 12 places until a M/F pair appears (Rey/Kylo Ren from Star Wars), 23 until a Gen pair appears (Peter Parker &amp; Tony Stark from the Marvel Cinematic Universe), and 32 until a F/F pairing appears (Kara/Lena from Supergirl). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the indie publisher side, my conclusion is mostly based on anecdotal evidence gathered by me on my pseudo-regular hunt for more queer contemporary romance. If you browse the selections available at <a href="https://www.carinapress.com/shop/index.html">Carina Press</a>, for instance, you’ll notice that the numbers for M/M titles are much higher than the F/F ones. The same is true for <a href="https://riptidepublishing.com/">Riptide Publishing</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I believe the question still stands for where the M/M love is with regards to traditional publishing. And while I continue to look into that, with what I hope to be verifiable evidence and researched conclusions, here is a list of M/M books currently in my TBR pile that I believe are also worth adding to yours. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Summer Sons by Lee Mandelo </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It seems everyone is talking about this book lately. From the discussions I’ve been seeing, it is very gay but it is also very Southern. It’s also little more than gothic, atmospheric vibes until you get over halfway through the book, and then you can’t put it down. A great book if you are looking for something spooky where a lot of meaning comes from the subtext.  </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Route of Ice and Salt by Jose Luis Zarate, translated by David Bowles</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I had this book on me with the intention of reading it for Halloween (and then I did very little reading in October). I did read the introduction, which explained that this story was originally written in the 1990s and made a big wave in Mexico’s queer scene. This new translation was recently released and worth a read if you’re into lyrical prose singing the music of being a gay man stuck with other men on a ship. History aside, this tells the story of the sailor transporting Dracula’s coffin from Transylvania to England. Vampire gay shenanigans ensue, I’m told. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Extraordinaries by TJ Klune </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-26347 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/52380340._SX318_SY475_-195x300.jpg" alt="" width="195" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/52380340._SX318_SY475_-195x300.jpg 195w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/52380340._SX318_SY475_.jpg 308w" sizes="(max-width: 195px) 100vw, 195px" /></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve mentioned TJ Klune before when I recommended his novel <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/get-cozy-with-these-queer-comfort-reads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>The House in the Cerulean Sea</em></a>. He also has another novel out (<a href="http://www.tjklunebooks.com/under-the-whispering-door"><em>Under the Whispering Door</em></a>) which is also on my list. But I want to talk about The Extraordinaries, which is the first book of his young adult trilogy. The story follows a teenaged fan who writes fanfiction, and then meets the object of his affection which completely turns his life around. Come for the fandom meta, stay for the endearing characters. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Protectorate Series by Megan E. O’Keefe </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a completed series that starts with Velocity Weapon, continues with Chaos Vector, and concludes with Catalyst Gate. As the series grows, the cast becomes more an ensemble cast and less focused on Sanda and her brother, and that ensemble cast includes their gay fathers, a gay criminal that happens to be one of their father’s exes, and NAME himself who starts a romance with another man in the second book. Very queer-friendly series, and despite the physical books being absolute bricks, I got through them pretty quickly. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Winter’s Orbit by Everina Maxwell</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I actually read this one and enjoyed it a lot. Two political figures are brought together through an arranged marriage, and somehow their marriage is the center plot of a conspiracy that they are trying to uncover before an intergalactic war can break out of a . . . you know what, that&#8217;s not important. What&#8217;s important is two people are shoved together with very little choice in the matter. BUT WAIT, for political reasons, they have to look like they’re a happy couple! There are a lot of things I like in this book. Yearning? Yep. Fake relationship? Check. Arranged marriage? Love it. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">There was only one bed?</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Be still my heart. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I totally missed something. Tweet me your M/M book recommendations @CallMeKT_91! I would love to hear from you.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Some Non-Speculative WLW Books I’ve Enjoyed</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/some-non-speculative-wlw-books-ive-enjoyed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KT Howard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spaceships and Notebooks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Y’all, reading science fiction has been hard lately. I don’t know what it is. Something&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26102 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/becca-tapert-8_wjL7l5tik-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/becca-tapert-8_wjL7l5tik-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/becca-tapert-8_wjL7l5tik-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/becca-tapert-8_wjL7l5tik-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/becca-tapert-8_wjL7l5tik-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/becca-tapert-8_wjL7l5tik-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Y’all, reading science fiction has been hard lately. I don’t know what it is. Something in the air? Unfulfilled innate desires? The need to find hope in something more down-to-earth (hur hur) than a ship flying through space? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am not really worried about it, though. I am mostly concerned that I will not finish this novella before the library reminds me that it’s due back (again). I am mildly amused that it’s taken me more than a week to read the first book in a trilogy I had on my list for YEARS. Sometime soon I will sit down with these books and power through them. Just take an evening and sit and read and read and read. Despite my love for DNF’ing books that do not jive with me, I do believe in following through on my emotional commitments. And I am committed to these books! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In any case, this—what do you call this, a slump? A wave?—is something I am embracing (what else am I going to do?). And I have been embracing it for quite a while. As a result, here is a handful of non-speculative books I’ve enjoyed featuring a queer cast or queer main characters. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em><a href="https://www.morgwrites.com/books">Honey Girl</a></em> by Morgan Rogers</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am a sucker for good prose, and this book has it. The prose treats the main character like she’s a glass paperweight, tough when it needs to be but fragile when push comes to shove. I went into this book thinking it would lean more heavily on the romance end of things, but it’s really about our main character Grace Porter learning to take care of herself and redefine what it means to be the “best.” I read it all in a day, and I was crying through most of it. No, I am not sorry to admit that. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.kellyquindlen.com/she-drives-me-crazy"><em>She Drives Me Crazy</em></a> by Kelly Quindlen</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am also a sucker for girls being dicks to each other, but only in fiction. This is the high school, fake dating, enemies-to-lovers book of my dreams. I loved that our main character was just as “toxic” as her ex-girlfriend that she wanted to make jealous, and part of her arc was learning to be more sympathetic to other people and more compassionate to the people she cared about. My preferences veer towards adult literature, so I do not know how this novel compares to other queer YA. In my limited experience, however, I would recommend this to others. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.jenniedavids.com/books.html"><em>New Ink on Life</em></a> by Jennie Davids </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the first in a series that I hope expands beyond its current two novels. I have the second<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26103 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/briana-tozour-hkkQbPa49UA-unsplash-214x300.jpg" alt="" width="214" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/briana-tozour-hkkQbPa49UA-unsplash-214x300.jpg 214w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/briana-tozour-hkkQbPa49UA-unsplash-730x1024.jpg 730w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/briana-tozour-hkkQbPa49UA-unsplash-768x1077.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/briana-tozour-hkkQbPa49UA-unsplash-1095x1536.jpg 1095w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/briana-tozour-hkkQbPa49UA-unsplash-1461x2048.jpg 1461w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/briana-tozour-hkkQbPa49UA-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1826w" sizes="(max-width: 214px) 100vw, 214px" /> book on my shelf, ready to be read at any moment! For this book, I also really like the characters and how they came together. I liked how they both were challenged to grow because of the other. One had to learn to be true to herself in a way that I could relate so much to, and the other had to learn to cast aside her insecurities to be less of an asshole. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am realizing, as I write this article, that I love reading about assholes turning into nice people. Before writing this article, I knew that I love people who appear to be assholes but are really misunderstood creatures with hearts of gold. There is value in both stories! And I love them all. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="http://loreliebrown.com/books/belladonna-ink/far-from-home/"><em>Far From Home</em></a> by Lorelie Brown </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think I read the words “demisexual main character” and “marriage of convenience” and “contemporary” in the same paragraph in describing this book and then got it from the library as soon as I could. This book for me came with all the feels and treated its subject matter with such compassion and tenderness that I had to wrap myself in a blanket burrito for a bit. Our demisexual main character is also dealing with an eating disorder, and she is marrying a friend of a friend who needs a visa to stay in the United States. Naturally, they fall in love, but they are not without their problems. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honorable Mention &#8211; <a href="https://caseymcquiston.com/books"><em>One Last Stop</em></a> by Casey McQuiston </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>One Last Stop</em> has a big speculative element driving the main plot of the book. Marketing terms are created to categorize where and how a book should be sold (and thus are fake but fake in the sense Wall Street is fake in that somehow a large chunk of the industry is managed by it). Which is to say, I consider <em>One Last Stop</em> a romance before I consider it a work of speculative fiction despite being both. I had a great time reading this book, so much so that I live-tweeted my thoughts on it, so I recommend it to others who are also looking for a great time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have some non-speculative queer books that you’ve enjoyed, please send the titles my way on <a href="https://twitter.com/callmekt_91" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Twitter</a>! </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Completed Queer Book Series to Distract You During The Big Wait</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/completed-queer-book-series-to-distract-you-during-the-big-wait/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KT Howard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 11:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spaceships and Notebooks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you one of the queers who is obsessed with the Locked Tomb series? Did&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left image alignleft wp-image-25665 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/58662507._SY475_-189x300.jpg" alt="" width="189" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/58662507._SY475_-189x300.jpg 189w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/58662507._SY475_.jpg 299w" sizes="(max-width: 189px) 100vw, 189px" />Are you one of the queers who is obsessed with the Locked Tomb series? Did you spend a weekend   f r e a k i n g   o u t   about the </span><a href="https://www.tor.com/2021/07/30/announcing-nona-the-ninth-a-new-addition-to-the-locked-tomb-series-from-tamsyn-muir/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">series’ big news</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">? Are you simultaneously jumping for joy at a release date and bemoaning the wait of a whole ‘nother year (and change)? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Join me, and together, we will distract ourselves! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a veteran of long waits between installments in a beloved series, I know what it’s like to wait a long time for the next season, the next the book, the next game, the next </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">anything</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One strategy to tide you over is to participate in the fandom and its various events—fic exchanges, big bangs, etc. But there’s a downfall to that. I speak only for myself, but I am sure other people can relate: you can only play around in the fandom for so long before you burn yourself out. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best, and I mean THE best way to manage the waiting period is to engage with other media, other fandoms. Since this is a literary journal all about the written word, and since this column is all about queer books of the speculative kind, here is a nice big list of recommendations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The majority of these recommendations are completed series that were pulled from my own bookshelf and <a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/profile/callmekt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">reading log</a>. If you have recommendations of completed series that are also queer (and maybe feature necromancers, space travel, and/or other cool stuff), hit me up on </span><a href="https://twitter.com/CallMeKT_91" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Twitter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">! I’d love to hear what you enjoyed! </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Series I’ve Read Entirely: </span></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Imperial Radch trilogy by Ann Leckie</strong> || The AI of a space station-sized ship is <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right image alignright wp-image-25667 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/17333324._SY475_-195x300.jpg" alt="" width="195" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/17333324._SY475_-195x300.jpg 195w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/17333324._SY475_.jpg 309w" sizes="(max-width: 195px) 100vw, 195px" />reduced to a single body, and now seeks revenge for this violent act. Along the way she will make friends, drink tea, and get confused by languages that have more than one gender identifier. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>The Indranan War trilogy by K.B. Wagers</strong> || Gunrunner Hail Bristol survived an assassination attempt. Unfortunately, her sisters weren’t so lucky. Now she is called back to the empire she left behind to hunt down the mastermind behind the attack on her family. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Wayfarers series by Becky Chambers</strong> || Stories of compassion and wonder set in the Galactic Commons, a universe-spanning civilization where humans are the underdogs. Each novel focuses on a different set of characters, so these can totally be read out-of-order. </span></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Series I’ve Read at Least Two Books For:  </span></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Broken Earth trilogy by N.K. Jemisin</strong> || Essun searches for her husband and daughter during an apocalyptic event that spans the entire planet. But there’s more at <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right image alignright wp-image-25668 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/19161852-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/19161852-198x300.jpg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/19161852.jpg 314w" sizes="(max-width: 198px) 100vw, 198px" />play as she learns the cause of the event and the reasons why. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Noumenon trilogy by Marina J. Lostetter</strong> || Vignettes from an interstellar convoy mission that was sent to investigate the irregular flickering of a distant star. You will fall in love with the ship’s AI.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Teixcalaan duology by Arkady Martine</strong> || The only thing standing between a galaxy expanding empire and an alien force is a lone space station with secret technology they want to keep from the empire at all costs. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>The Protectorate trilogy by Megan E. O’Keefe</strong> || Sanda Greeve wakes up alone on an enemy spaceship two hundred years in the future. It goes downhill from there, but not without some twists, some somersaults, and maybe a barrel roll or two. </span></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Series On my TBR pile: </span></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Machineries of Empire trilogy by Yoon Ha Lee</strong> || Look, I just know that there’s body sharing without romance and it’s kind of a transgender narrative? I recently got all <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right image alignright wp-image-25669 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/26118426._SY475_-196x300.jpg" alt="" width="196" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/26118426._SY475_-196x300.jpg 196w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/26118426._SY475_.jpg 310w" sizes="(max-width: 196px) 100vw, 196px" />three books from the library and will devour them sometime this month. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>The King Cycle series by C.L. Polk</strong> || This is a queer historical romance fantasy with gorgeous book covers. This is all I know about it. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>The Poppy War series by R.F. Kuang</strong> || A hella dark re-telling of a bloody war that defined modern day China. I think. I’ve seen the author re-Tweet fanfiction of her trilogy and I think that’s just the sweetest. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Simon Snow trilogy by Rainbow Rowell</strong> || Rowell’s response and/or celebration of the Harry Potter fandom or franchise, featuring barely concealed Drarry. </span></li>
</ul>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honorable Mentions, Incomplete Series Too Good Not to Share: </span></h2>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>The Murderbot Diaries by Martha Wells</strong> || The most relatable security construct just <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right image alignright wp-image-25670 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/32758901._SY475_-188x300.jpg" alt="" width="188" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/32758901._SY475_-188x300.jpg 188w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/32758901._SY475_.jpg 297w" sizes="(max-width: 188px) 100vw, 188px" />wants to slack on the job and watch some TV. Those damn humans keep getting in danger. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Wayward Children series by Seanan McGuire</strong> || Set in a school for children who returned from a portal fantasy world, and all the shenanigans that entails. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>The Masquerade by Seth Dickinson</strong> || Baru Cormorant uses her intelligence and wits to rise to prominence within an empire she seeks to destroy. Check the content warnings as this book series plays with the dark effects of colonialism. </span></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where Are All the Multi-Level-Market—I mean, Men Loving Men?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/where-are-all-the-multi-level-market-i-mean-men-loving-men/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/where-are-all-the-multi-level-market-i-mean-men-loving-men/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KT Howard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 12:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spaceships and Notebooks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s something I’ve been keeping in the back of my mind regarding queer speculative fiction:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s something I’ve been keeping in the back of my mind regarding queer speculative fiction: there is an overwhelming amount of women loving women (wlw). At first, I thought this was just me—in reading, I prefer to read about women loving other women and so the amorphous algorithm that runs my internet feed (and thus my life) veers towards that direction. As a result, I don’t see a lot of men loving other men. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And then I came across this Tweet on Twitter, and it gave me pause. So I QRT’d it and decided to change up my topic for this month’s column at the eleventh hour.  </span></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/CallMeKT_91/status/1410636010694840321?s=20">https://twitter.com/CallMeKT_91/status/1410636010694840321?s=20</a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This month, I’m taking a look at some data points to answer the question: “does adult queer speculative fiction veer towards f/f or is it just me?” I am answering this question with SCIENCE. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">About the Data and Its Collection</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the purposes of this article, I looked exclusively at <a href="https://kadoore.com/2021/05/01/2021-queer-adult-science-fiction-fantasy-books/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">K. A. Doore’s lists of adult, queer speculative fiction</a>. They are a nice one-stop-shop and list relevant information about the book in question without having to click through or do any serious digging. Please note that these lists do not list every adult queer speculative book coming out in a given year. In fact, the list for 2021 has more books on it than the list for 2019; I am assuming this is because the list is getting more well-known and people are submitting their books to it for marketing purposes. This is one way the data in this set is skewed. I’ll explain the other ways in a minute. </span></p>
<p>(SIDE NOTE: K. A. Doore is a fantastic human being and you should send them love for maintaining this list in the first place. The data collected and conclusions drawn in this post are not meant to attack Doore in any way, shape, or form. This writer does not support any action that does not involve an expression of eternal gratitude.)</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each title on these lists had two tallies: the type of romantic relationship presented therein, and the gender of the lead; each with four sub-categories. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Romantic Relationships</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The four romantic relationships I collected were: m/m (what I’m looking for), f/f (what I see a lot of), other (these are the bi m/f, polyamorous, m/nb, f/nb, and any other combination of relationship), and unspecified. As I did not do a thorough digging, “unspecified” simply means that the type of relationship was not present on the information in the list. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is another way the data below might be skewed—some m/m titles may be overlooked because the data was not present at the time of collection. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Main Character Gender</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The four genders I collected are: male, female, bisexual, and other. I included bisexual as its own gender because the data often said whether the MC was bi or not without other specifications. Additionally, look to your bisexual friends and tell me they aren’t a (fabulous, stupendous, show-stopping) gender all on their own. A lot of the data points did not specify whether a transgender character was a transgender man or a transgender woman, so quite a few of them went to the “other” bucket. They’re too cool for the gender binary anyway. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I do not mean to be exclusionary. As you will see from the data below, the number of unspecified relationships and other characters outnumber the number of m/m relationships and male leads by a great amount. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Without further ado . . . </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Disastrous Data </span></h2>
<h3>Table of Main Characters and Their Genders</h3>
<table style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>2019</td>
<td>2020</td>
<td>2021</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Titles with Male MC</td>
<td>5</td>
<td>10</td>
<td>12</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Titles with Female MC</td>
<td>23</td>
<td>27</td>
<td>27</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Titles with Bisexual MC</td>
<td>5</td>
<td>13</td>
<td>19</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Titles with Unspecified MC</td>
<td>12</td>
<td>16</td>
<td>20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total Titles</td>
<td>45</td>
<td>66</td>
<td>78</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Titles with Main Queer Romance</h3>
<table style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>2019</td>
<td>2020</td>
<td>2021</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Titles with Main m/m</td>
<td>6</td>
<td>7</td>
<td>15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Titles with Main f/f</td>
<td>17</td>
<td>26</td>
<td>27</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Titles with Main Other</td>
<td>2</td>
<td>4</td>
<td>8</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Titles with Main Unspecified</td>
<td>18</td>
<td>29</td>
<td>28</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total Titles</td>
<td>43</td>
<td>66</td>
<td>78</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Look! Graphs for the Queer Romance Table!</h3>
<figure id="attachment_25368" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25368" style="width: 1046px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-25368" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/men-loving-men-through-years-graphs.png" alt="" width="1046" height="215" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/men-loving-men-through-years-graphs.png 1046w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/men-loving-men-through-years-graphs-300x62.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/men-loving-men-through-years-graphs-1024x210.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/men-loving-men-through-years-graphs-768x158.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1046px) 100vw, 1046px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25368" class="wp-caption-text">Graphs collected by screenshotting Excel, a very scientific process. Apologies for all the zooming and squinting and overall horrendous quality.</figcaption></figure>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Very Scientific Analysis</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2019, 14% of the books on the list were mlm; that percentage dropped to 11% in 2020 and increased to 19% in 2021. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Compare this to the wlw relationships, which went from 39% in 2019 and 2020 to 35% in 2021. Over a third of the titles on the list are women loving women, where the number of mlm books are less than a fifth for all three years. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I find it worth pointing out that the number of Other relationships (polyamorous, multiple relationships, etc) increased from 5% in 2019 to 6% in 2020 to 10% in 2021. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The decrease in wlw books made room for more diverse relationships overall. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conclusions</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let me reiterate that this is a very incomplete set of data and the conclusion therein is barely more than an rudimentary assumption with some numbers behind it. I would feel a lot better about the data and conclusions drawn if I had 10 years’ worth of data and a more robust means of collection that records the sexualities, genders, and romantic relationships of secondary characters. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alas, I do not live in that world (I have a day job, you know). So we must sit with the knowledge that we do not have a lot of mlm relationships in speculative fiction from the past two years when compared to the number of wlw relationships seen in speculative fiction. Whether this is a good or a bad thing is entirely up to personal interpretation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My personal conclusion is that wlw speculative fiction has been selling more books, so publishers are buying those books. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to see more mlm in speculative fiction? Go out and buy it! Preferably from your local indie bookstore. In the meantime, please <a href="https://twitter.com/CallMeKT_91" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tweet me</a> your favorite mlm speculative fiction book. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/where-are-all-the-multi-level-market-i-mean-men-loving-men/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Places to Find Queer Literature</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/3-places-to-find-queer-literature/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KT Howard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 12:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spaceships and Notebooks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sometime around late summer 2020, I suddenly lost all interest in reading anything that was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometime around late summer 2020, I suddenly lost all interest in reading anything that was not queer in some way. I can only rely on Tor Books and Tor.com Publishing to provide me the queer speculative content that I require for so long. This is nothing against them—I love a lot of the things that Tor Books and Tor.com Publishing releases. But there is more to reading than queer speculative fiction, and as I disclosed in a previous column, sometimes I want to read a contemporary romance. So I set out to find more queer fiction.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In my search, I managed to compile a small list of reliable resources that could be shared with others. The magic of the internet* brings me to a lot of organically-found recommendations that suit my own tastes. The lists presented here are meant to be for queer literature in general; you may wade through the piles at your own leisure. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Go forth, fellow seeker of queer literature, and be gay (do crime)! </span></p>
<p><a href="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1533669955142-6a73332af4db?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=839&amp;q=80"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1533669955142-6a73332af4db?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=839&amp;q=80" width="839" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">*you know how if you sing a song to your phone and then put your music on shuffle, the song you were singing somehow gets played first? Yeah, the data collection of your <del>tracking device</del> smartphone or tablet definitely has your best interest at heart. <del>This isn&#8217;t my anti-capitalism showing.</del> </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Everyone: </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lambda Literary is an organization that seeks to boost the voices of queer individuals. Lambda uses the term LGBTQ, I use the term queer. To me, they mean the same thing. </span><a href="https://www.lambdaliterary.org/awards/current-finalists/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Lambda Awards</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are given to the best queer books released in a given year, and it’s been going since 1989! </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Adult Queer Speculative Fiction: </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since 2019, author K. A. Doore has kept a </span><a href="https://kadoore.com/2021/05/01/2021-queer-adult-science-fiction-fantasy-books/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">running tally</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of new fiction in a given year that is a) queer b) adult and c) speculative. The important bit for me is that the list is for adult fiction. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I see a lot of queer books popping up on my <a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/profile/callmekt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Storygraph</a> recommendations, but they almost always have a Young Adult tag on them. I have nothing against young adult fiction—I used to read it almost exclusively when I was in college—and I can only handle the stories of teenagers figuring out their lives for so long. Honestly, sometimes I want to know what an adult would do in a given situation. How does an adult handle parenting a teenager during an alien invasion? This could be my age showing, but I have moved on from relating to teenagers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which is why I love this list. The books here are written for an adult audience in mind. I can relate to that. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">For The Aro/Ace Niche: </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1607316484934-713e23cf5074?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=378&amp;q=80"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1607316484934-713e23cf5074?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=378&amp;q=80" width="378" height="501" /></a>The </span><a href="https://www.aroacedatabase.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aro/Ace Database</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is something I stumbled upon once upon a Twitter browse. And then I spent at least three days just perusing the archive for anything that features an asexual main character. I made a small list, and then I set out to hunt down these books for my pleasure. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This niche is near and dear to my heart because I am an asexual woman seeking more mainstream representation than Murderbot. I love Murderbot with all my heart, and I also love seeing books and short stories that use the word asexual on the page. Seeing that word in a story to a character that I can otherwise relate to makes me feel </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">seen</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a way I haven’t been before. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am sharing this database to you in the hopes that you will also feel seen. </span></p>
<hr />
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now I am opening the floor to you. Where are places you go to find queer literature recommendations? Share them in the comments below! </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Topple Empires With These Anti-Colonial Sapphics</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/topple-empires-with-these-anti-colonial-sapphics/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/topple-empires-with-these-anti-colonial-sapphics/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KT Howard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 11:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spaceships and Notebooks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve been noticing a pattern in some big name publications. This pattern is: anti-colonial sapphics.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve been noticing a pattern in some big name publications. This pattern is: anti-colonial sapphics. Hear me out. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/Marceline2174/status/1352097388861640705?s=20" target="_blank" rel="noopener">some awesome fanart</a> by artist Marceline, there is now a pipeline between fans of the Locked Tomb Trilogy and the Masquerade. The Locked Tomb Trilogy is the infamous “lesbian necromancers in space” books. The Masquerade is one (1) sapphic woman tearing down an unstoppable empire from the inside. They have a handful of things in common: a swordlesbian with a crooked smile, a main character who breaks herself in sacrifice to an Ultimate Goal, a visceral depiction of mental health. The biggest thing they have in common though: </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">anti-colonial sapphics.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best part? </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">They’re not the only ones!</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Let me share with you some series of various levels of completion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Note #1:</strong> I have not finished each of the series I am writing about in this post. For most, it’s because they’re not finished. For the one series that is complete, it’s because I haven’t gotten around to it yet (yet!). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Note #2:</strong> Most of the series in this list can get really dark really quick. I do not list specific content warnings here, so please check the content warnings before you read if you are uncomfortable with anything in particular. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Masquerade by Seth Dickinson</span></h2>
<p><a href="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1601723897234-327147304013?ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=729&amp;q=80"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1601723897234-327147304013?ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=729&amp;q=80" width="729" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">3 out of 4 books available, incomplete. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Masquerade follows the plight of Baru Cormorant. As a young girl, her homeland is invaded by the Empire of Masks and breaks her family. For revenge, she enrolls in an empire’s school with the intent of dismantling the empire from the inside. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the time of this writing, I have read the first book, which I am told is the roughest—this series gets </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">dark</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. From book one, there is talk about eugenics, which only furthers the racism and homophobia of the empire. There is plague and secrecy and the economics of war. There is a lot that goes into running an empire, and The Traitor Baru Cormorant highlighted each of the individual parts as Baru leads a foreign nation as its accountant. She makes policy changes and manipulates the will of the people and calculates her next move at every step of the way. Baru is one determined motherfucker, and I cannot wait to see her make the empire burn. (You can track my progress on my Storygraph). </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Teixcalaan Duology by Arkady Martine</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://images.macmillan.com/folio-assets/macmillan_us_frontbookcovers_350W/9781250186430.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium" src="https://images.macmillan.com/folio-assets/macmillan_us_frontbookcovers_350W/9781250186430.jpg" width="350" height="541" /></a>2 out of 2 books available, complete. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Teixcalaan Duology follows Mahit Dzmare, an ambassador from a tiny, tiny space station holding its own against a galaxy-expanding empire. Her predecessor has been murdered and it’s up to her to find out why. Political intrigue and maneuvering ensues. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The thing that blew me away about the first book was its worldbuilding. It took me a chapter to get into it because the first chapter is written as though you already understand the world and how it runs, so it doesn’t spend any time trying to catch you up. You either catch up yourself or get lost in the shuffle. Luckily, I caught on pretty quick, and I loved everything about it. From the snark and shenanigans of Yskandr to the mutual pining between Three Seagrass and Mahit, there is a lot to love about this series. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also has a lot to say about empire and imperialism. The Teixcalaan Empire is based on the Byzantine Empire with a little Maya/Aztec thrown in for good measure. Our main character loves the Teixcalaans, even though she will never be considered civilized in the eyes of its citizens, even though its culture is swallowing hers whole. It’s a fine line to walk, and Martine walks it with intelligence, balance, and grace. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Locked Tomb Trilogy by Tamsyn Muir</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2 out of 3 books available, incomplete</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Childhood rivals Gideon Nav and Harrowhark Nonagesimus must team up to compete in the Lyctoral trials. If Harrowhark ascends, she can rebuild her dying House. If Gideon does her job, which she is unwilling to do, she can earn her freedom. What could go wrong? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The anti-colonialism in this series is more subtle than the others on this list. All the characters already exist within a larger framework of empire and child soldiers and dying planets—and our main characters pay more attention to each other than the larger implications of their government. Of course, there’s also the murder and the mystery and the intrigue and, later on in book two, the murder attempts and the dissociation and Ianthe Tridentarius. The one thing that everyone can agree on? The Nine Houses must go. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Magic of the Lost series by C.L. Clark</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9780316542678.jpg?fit=441%2C675"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium" src="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9780316542678.jpg?fit=441%2C675" width="441" height="675" /></a>1 out of 3 (?) books available, incomplete </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am assuming this will be a trilogy. Please double-check this information against other sources. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Unbroken (book 1) follows two women from two completely different classes. Touraine is a soldier, raised in the military, and returning to the land she was stolen from as a toddler. Luca is a princess, heir to an empire if she can wrestle it away from her uncle. Touraine saves Luca from an assassination attempt, and it all goes wrong from there. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is another book that gets dark. It confronts ideas that are hard to reconcile, and our characters have to live through them, make hard decisions (sometimes on the fly), and predict the next moves of their opponents. They almost always get it wrong. I love the naivete of these two women and the lessons they learn along the way. I love how nothing goes right and the only thing you can count on is unpredictability. I love these two sapphics, hopelessly in love but unacknowledged by the other the entire book. (The! Entire! Book! It’s such a long book too!) </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Book 1 ended too cleanly for me. More things have to go wrong. More yearning must happen. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Jasmine Throne by Tasha Suri </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Book 1 will be available in June </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I know very little about this new series other than there is a servant with forbidden magic and the princess is locked in a temple? Either way, it’s an Indian-inspired empire and our main characters are in love. I am definitely reading this as soon as I am able. Here is a <a href="https://twitter.com/tashadrinkstea/status/1395316354505449474?s=19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">video of the author</a> unboxing a shipment of her books. Please note, this book may not be anti-colonial; it is featured here because I saw Tasha Suri and C.L. Clarke in <a href="https://www.crowdcast.io/e/clark-suri-feb2021" target="_blank" rel="noopener">conversation with each other</a>. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/topple-empires-with-these-anti-colonial-sapphics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Unintended Effect of Reading Fanfiction</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-unintended-effect-of-reading-fanfiction/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-unintended-effect-of-reading-fanfiction/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KT Howard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spaceships and Notebooks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24546</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve never been a fan of the romance genre. My attentions were always attracted to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1566244373908-15be37645de4?ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=560&amp;q=80"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1566244373908-15be37645de4?ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=560&amp;q=80" alt="Close up of a pinkish-white flower with a lot of petals. Photo by Sabine Ojeil on Unsplash" width="560" height="501" /></a>I&#8217;ve never been a fan of the romance genre. My attentions were always attracted to the action-adventure: giant robots, spaceships, big swords, and other similar things. Wizards and warriors and witches. As soon as I entered a new bookstore, I would make a beeline for the science fiction/fantasy section. This was my norm until quite recently. Recently being the pandemic.</p>
<p>Prior to the pandemic, romance was something I would scoff at. Despite knowing one or two romance writers in my real life, I would only read their books out of obligation. Somewhere between the start of the pandemic and the day I am writing this (April 2021), I realized that I have been a fool. Romance is a wonderful genre. In this post, I&#8217;m documenting that journey.</p>
<h2>A Fan&#8217;s Introduction</h2>
<p>The moment I finished reading <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/harrow-the-ninth/9781250313225" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Harrow the Ninth</em></a> last August, my first thought was, &#8220;There must be fanart about this. I know this in my bones.&#8221; During my search, I found a Discord server for the fandom, which led me to the wonderful world of fanfiction.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been on the periphery of fanfiction since my introduction to <em>Gundam Wing</em> in elementary school. It&#8217;s never been something I actively engaged with until I got deeper into a fandom than just reblogging posts on Tumblr. On the Discord, I had the opportunity to discuss a book series that I love with other people from around the world. We passed around theories and hunted down descriptions of characters and, eventually, started tossing out ideas for fics. <a href="https://archiveofourown.org/users/Morike91/works" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Some of them I&#8217;ve written</a>. Naturally, I also read the fanfiction of my newfound peers.</p>
<p><a href="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1604609982530-486775a3cf07?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=889&amp;q=80"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1604609982530-486775a3cf07?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=889&amp;q=80" alt="Close up photo of a bright pink flower with many petals. Photo by David White on Unsplash" width="889" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>The more I read, the more I realized that my favorite fics were ones that did not rely on canon material, in particular the Modern Setting Alternate Universes. After reading a couple, I started to wonder about the contemporary romance landscape. Not really seeking it out, just wondering how it exists and how prevalent queer representation is in it. (I may have outlined a business plan for a queer romance magazine that may never see the light of day.)</p>
<p>And then a member of the fandom promoted their <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/night-life-9781626498891/9781626498891" target="_blank" rel="noopener">debut novel</a> published by an indie press. And it featured a f/f romance! I got it, because it&#8217;s nice to support a friend, and I read it. I loved it. That&#8217;s when I figured out what romance was missing for me.</p>
<h2>The Missing Piece</h2>
<p><a href="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1602293781324-8bad7528f3e1?ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=334&amp;q=80"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1602293781324-8bad7528f3e1?ixid=MnwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=334&amp;q=80" alt="Close up photo of a blooming orange flower with many petals. Photo by Jason Leung on Unsplash" width="334" height="501" /></a>As it turns out, the biggest reason I wasn&#8217;t super into romance was because I couldn&#8217;t relate to any of it. Fanfiction introduced me to a collection of stories about women loving other women; it filled a hole within me that I didn&#8217;t realize needed filling. When I read a heterosexual romance, I had to be persuaded to like one of the leads, usually the man, before I could get on board with it. That was a smaller barrier for my friend&#8217;s f/f contemporary romance I purchased, and it&#8217;s an even smaller hurdle with fanfiction, where I am already familiar with the characters and rooting for their eventual union.</p>
<p>Since this realization, I started to seek out more queer romance. I joined the <a href="https://sapphicbookclub.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sapphic Book Club</a>, which aims to promote queer romance through reviews on Goodreads (or <a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/profile/callmekt" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Storygraph</a> in my case). I am contemplating taking one of my fics and converting it into an original piece despite not knowing where I would try to sell it. I did some research into the plot beats of the romance genre with the intention of one day writing more of my own.</p>
<p>This is a new avenue of fiction for me, and I am excited to further explore it. If you have recommendations for cozy queer romances, please drop them in the comments!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-unintended-effect-of-reading-fanfiction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get Cozy with these Queer Comfort Reads</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/get-cozy-with-these-queer-comfort-reads/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/get-cozy-with-these-queer-comfort-reads/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KT Howard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spaceships and Notebooks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=23026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[February has arrived. For the world, it is approximately one year since the start of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">February has arrived. For the world, it is approximately one year since the start of a global pandemic. As an individual who has miraculously been able to work throughout the pandemic and found ways to stay busy, February is also the Month of the Wall. Meaning, I feel like I hit a wall with everything in my life&#8211;my day job, my volunteer projects, creative writing, etc. None of this is helped along by winter weather. The snow is practically two feet high where I am and, as I write this, it is below zero in temperature. Cabin fever plus quarantine fever plus, if I’m going to be honest, a bit of relief related to the switch in American presidents. All I want to do right now is curl up with a book and get lost in some words I didn’t write. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re feeling the same, here are my suggestions for comfort-like reads that will tuck your queer heart into a soft bed with softer blankets. Let’s get ready to hygge! </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1414124488080-0188dcbb8834?ixid=MXwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHw%3D&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1500&amp;q=80" width="1500" height="1000" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">ON A SUNBEAM by Tillie Walden</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I always think graphic novels are going to take me less time to read than a novel because I don’t have to spend one or two minutes looking at the illustrations. But that does a disservice to graphic novels because part of the marvel about them is the illustration. The illustrations for <em>On a Sunbeam</em> are not to be passed over from a quick scan. Following the story of heartbreak and healing, <em>On a Sunbeam</em> is lush with atmospheric lineart and soft colors I wouldn’t expect in a space opera. You can purchase the book or <a href="https://www.onasunbeam.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">read it online</a>. This was my introduction to Tillie Walden as a graphic novelist and artist, and I have <a href="https://www.tilliewalden.com/books" target="_blank" rel="noopener">her other books</a> on by TBR pile. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">THE PRINCE AND THE DRESSMAKER by Jen Wang</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.jenwang.net/prince"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright " src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5dfae0f42c0f63527ba24ff8/1576794348452-Z3CXE25SG7GDVXMTFMDQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kGNweA9yp8kse9jkqvIwQYt7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmG94TGNuzCcCPVStE9JyN8Df5xvxKOBFYklIfNm0UjD1EZ4UVyG8vtUm4WbGwSj4E/C_Y8Nr3XUAAP6fN.jpg?format=500w" width="300" height="425" /></a>Continuing this, <a href="https://www.jenwang.net/prince" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>The Prince and the Dressmaker</em></a> is another graphic novel, but this time in a much more romantic period. Prince Sebastian is a lover of fashion, particularly women’s fashion, and he befriends dressmaker Frances with an amazing sense of style to make him lush dresses, which he uses in his disguise as a fashionista in Paris’s nightlife. This is a sweet graphic novel about learning to accept yourself, and the ending may or may not have had me in tears. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">THE HOUSE IN THE CERULEAN SEA by TJ Klune</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I finished this earlier this month for my book club. <em>THitCS</em> follows a government caseworker as he investigates an orphanage for magical children, all of whom are considered “extreme cases” but found a place of love and support under the tutelage of a man named Arthur Parnassus. While the book club agreed that the plot is a little flimsy, what made us fall for it was the characters and especially the children (I will die for Lucy). My friend described this book as a big, warm hug and that description is very on-the-nose. If you want to get metaphorically hugged by the wholesomeness presented here, <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/the-house-in-the-cerulean-sea/9781250217288" target="_blank" rel="noopener">read <em>THitCS</em></a>. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">SILK AND STEEL: A QUEER SPECULATIVE ADVENTURE ANTHOLOGY edited by Janine A. Southard </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://bookshop.org/books/silk-steel-a-queer-speculative-adventure-anthology/9781633270268"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright " src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/I/51csgoXC3bL.SX316.SY480.jpg" width="299" height="477" /></a>I recently purchased this <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/silk-steel-a-queer-speculative-adventure-anthology/9781633270268" target="_blank" rel="noopener">for myself</a> because I am in love with ladies who wield swords, especially if they also woo other ladies. This is an anthology that caters specifically to me (but I am not alone in my love). The stories in this anthology are fantastical and adventurous; some are humorous, some are serious, and all feature diverse characters. At least one story features two transgender women, and it would not surprise me if more did the same (as of this writing, I have only read a handful of the tales). This is the book I pull out when I want a feel-good story before I fall asleep at night; it&#8217;s the perfect hygge book for a cold winter’s night. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">CARRY ON / WAYWARD SON by Rainbow Rowell</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A small digression: the book <em>Fangirl</em> by Rainbow Rowell is about a fanfiction writer as she adjusts to her first year of college, while at the same time writing a multi-chapter fanfiction for that world&#8217;s version of Harry Potter. The name of that fanfiction is <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/carry-on-9781250135025/9781250135025" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Carry On</em></a>. Did Rainbow Rowell publish the fake fanfiction for her book? Yes, yes she did. <em>Carry On</em> follows Simon Snow in his final year at a magical school in England, where tensions in the magical world have come to a head and the final battle looms on the horizon. Full disclosure, I was not blown away by <em>Carry On</em>, but I have friends who were. For my friends, and for people looking for the comfort of fanfiction in a traditionally published novel, I present to you <em>Carry On</em> and its sequel <em>Wayward Son</em>. The third and final book of the series comes out <a href="https://www.rainbowrowell.com/any-way-the-wind-blows" target="_blank" rel="noopener">July 2021</a>. </span></p>
<hr />
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What’s a book that has been a comfort for you this winter? Let me know in the comments! </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/get-cozy-with-these-queer-comfort-reads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing Exercises for Fun and Profit</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-exercises-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KT Howard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spaceships and Notebooks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22638</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well, maybe less profit. These are just exercises, after all. If you want to buff&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" alignright" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1585152968992-851c3a8e1678?ixid=MXwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHw%3D&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=334&amp;q=80" width="301" height="452" />Well, maybe less profit. These are just exercises, after all. If you want to buff up the results and submit them to literary magazines, I am the last person that will stop you. But I am getting ahead of myself. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">January is a month of reflection and goal-setting. This post, right here, is not going to talk about how to schedule writing into your life or the importance of transforming your New Year’s Resolutions into SMART goals. (Get your writerly pep talk <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/it-is-2021-and-the-future-is-now-so-lets-start-writing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>!) Instead, I am assuming that one of your resolutions is to do some more writing throughout the year. Therefore, I am sharing some of my favorite creative writing exercises for you to adopt, adapt, and incorporate into your writing practice. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So if you find yourself between projects, if you find yourself bored with one project, if you need an injection of creativity in the form of writing something for the sake of writing something, or if you are in need of a guideline before you set out to write, here are some exercises to try out. </span></p>
<h2>Write a Flash or Poem Based on a Prompt</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a bunch of social media accounts that offer <a href="https://writing-prompt-s.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">writing prompts</a> for people to respond to or use for inspiration. I’ll link to a few on <a href="https://awesomewritingprompts.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Tumblr</a> that I found in this paragraph, but I encourage you to seek out others on Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, and <a href="https://unblockingwritersblock.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">other places</a> you hang out. </span></p>
<p>In case you need a refresher, when I say &#8220;flash&#8221; I mean a work of prose less than 1,500 words. The word count for flash fiction (or micro-fiction) varies depending on who is speaking, but everyone seems to agree that the stories are short and easily consumable in under five minutes by most readers.</p>
<h2>Write a Tabloid News Story Based on a Headline</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Head over to this <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=b-8DAAAAMBAJ" target="_blank" rel="noopener">archive of Weekly World News issues</a> and pick a headline at random (you don’t have to purchase an issue; just page through the front pages). Write down the headline, then write a fictional news story based on it, no more than 400 words. Keep in mind this is meant to be a newspaper article, so stick to reporting the &#8220;facts.&#8221; </span></p>
<p>If you want to take this a step further, you can write a story based on the events of your article.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1541534741688-6078c6bfb5c5?ixid=MXwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHw%3D&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=749&amp;q=80" width="749" height="500" /></p>
<h2>Writing About Place and Setting</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a notebook (or wherever you usually write), make two lists. For the first list, write a list of experiences that bring joy or would put you in a good mood. In the second list, write a list of experiences that would bring disappointment or put you in a bad mood. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Underneath, write down the following:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Place:</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taste:<br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sight:<br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Touch:<br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Smell:<br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hear: </span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Place, write down your favorite room in your current place of residence. In the other places, write the sensory experiences of that place. </span>For example, my favorite room is the front porch, which isn&#8217;t really a room but it&#8217;s attached to my home so it counts. For some sensory experiences, I&#8217;ll list the salty flavor of a snack for taste, the sight of a giant oak tree in a tiny, tiny yard for sight, etc.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally, for the actual exercise, you’re writing two paragraphs describing your setting: one for being in a good mood, one for being in a mad mood. Pay attention to your word choice and try to convey the mood without outright stating what the mood is. Let it come out in the imagery and sensory details. For example, sunlight may be welcoming if you&#8217;re in a good mood and blinding if you&#8217;re in a bad mood. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This exercise is meant to make you think about your word choice in relation to setting and character mood. Repeat at will for other places and moods as you desire. </span>You can also adapt this exercise for a longer work you are writing, replacing your story&#8217;s events for the experiences and a fictional setting for the room!</p>
<h2>Opening Paragraph Mad Libs</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Write a list of nouns, no more than 10. In case you need a refresher, a noun is a person, place, thing, or idea. (An example list of nouns: clock, nap, stocking, the bank, a teacher.) </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now pick a random story from either the internet or your bookshelf. If that&#8217;s too overwhelming, pick up the first book you reach for. Copy down the opening sentence (or paragraph if it&#8217;s short), then highlight and delete all the nouns in it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use the list of nouns you wrote down to replace the nouns you deleted from the opening paragraph. Change around a few more words so things make sense. You should have a new sentence/paragraph as a result. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you so desire, continue the story based on this brand new opening paragraph. </span></p>
<h2>Freewrite for 10 Minutes</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" alignleft" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1594381898411-846e7d193883?ixid=MXwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHw%3D&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=334&amp;q=80" width="301" height="452" />Set a timer for 10 minutes. As soon as you start it, start writing. Don’t stop to think about what you’re going to write next. If you’re writing by hand, don’t pick up the tip of your writing instrument. If you’re typing, your fingers should not stop typing. Keep going at this pace for the full 10 minutes. It is very important that you do not stop typing/writing to think; let the words flow as they come to you. Only stop when the timer goes off. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is meant to turn off your inner editor. You are not writing for quality, you are writing to get something down on the page, which is the whole point of a rough draft, or a draft zero. This is also a good exercise if you have very limited time and need to get a word count. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you so desire, work your way up by 5 minute intervals so you can write continuously for 30 minutes without stopping! </span></p>
<hr />
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The majority of these exercises are based off an online class I took through One Story. <a href="https://www.one-story.com/index.php?page=online_class" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Check them out</a>! Then s</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">hare some of your favorite writing exercises in the comments.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>All I Want This Holiday Season Are Queer Giant Robots</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/all-i-want-this-holiday-season-is-queer-giant-robots/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[KT Howard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 11:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Spaceships and Notebooks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The thing that got me interested in science fiction as a kid was giant robots.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The thing that got me interested in science fiction as a kid was giant robots. <em>Robotech</em> was my first foray into the magic of giant robots, but <em>Gundam Wing</em> left a bigger impression overall. Say what you will about the quality of these shows, but when you are barely nine years old and you see some effeminate male characters you identify with kick some ass in a big humanoid machine, that&#8217;s inspiring.</p>
<p><a href="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2020/08/05/14/41/robot-5465656_960_720.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2020/08/05/14/41/robot-5465656_960_720.jpg" width="960" height="607" /></a></p>
<p>As an adult, it&#8217;s hard to find a good giant robot anything that both caters to my queer sensibilities and inspires me in the same way <em>Gundam Wing</em> did twenty years earlier. Part of this is because my tastes evolved as I got older. I majored in creative writing at college, which meant learning to break apart stories and admiring those that hold up to scrutiny. Another part is, upon learning of my queerness, I started flocking to stories of other queer individuals for the chance to see <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/asexual-main-characters-in-speculative-fiction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reflections of myself</a> in the media I consume.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, this is a recipe for disappointment. Giant robots are typically marketed towards cisgendered, heterosexual men. And that makes everything. so. very. <em>straight</em>. (Trowa/Quatre was never explicitly canon but <a href="https://archiveofourown.org/works?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;commit=Sort+and+Filter&amp;work_search%5Bsort_column%5D=revised_at&amp;include_work_search%5Brelationship_ids%5D%5B%5D=108473&amp;work_search%5Bother_tag_names%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bexcluded_tag_names%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bcrossover%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bcomplete%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bwords_from%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bwords_to%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bdate_from%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bdate_to%5D=&amp;work_search%5Bquery%5D=&amp;work_search%5Blanguage_id%5D=&amp;tag_id=Gundam+Wing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">that&#8217;s what fanfiction is for</a>.)</p>
<p>For a while I abandoned the idea that I could ever fully enjoy a giant robot story. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, it is still super fun to watch two robots duke it out in the middle of space with ridiculous weapons, unreasonable speed, and unreal mechanical efficiency. But wouldn&#8217;t it be nice if someone was explicitly queer too?</p>
<p>Which is why I bring you the two stories that made me ridiculously happy this year. These two stories feature giant robots alongside queer characters. If you follow along with this column, you already know <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/authors-to-read-that-dont-conform-to-the-gender-binary/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one of them</a>. These stories are my winter holiday gift to you. Please take them, read them, treasure them if you want. I hope you enjoy them regardless.</p>
<h2>Gift One</h2>
<p>&#8220;Texts from the Ghost War&#8221; by Alex Yuschik I found via EscapePod. It is an epistolary story told through text messages, making the relationship between the characters intimate despite their physical and socioeconomic distance. The romance here is subtle. And I choose to see it as a romance because the things these characters do for each other show how much the other means to them. Also, that first interaction is prime shipping material. Fight me.</p>
<p><a href="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/11/04/11/46/robot-1797548_960_720.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/11/04/11/46/robot-1797548_960_720.png" width="960" height="540" /></a></p>
<p>What makes this story queer? The gender of one of the characters is never confirmed. EscapePod hired a male actor to portray them in the audio. If you don&#8217;t listen to the audio, the gender of that character is whatever. They could be cisgendered male, but they could just as easily be transgender, nonbinary, cisgendered female, intersex, or anything else.</p>
<p>I stumbled upon &#8220;Texts from the Ghost War&#8221; randomly on Twitter. <a href="https://escapepod.org/2017/06/09/ep579-texts-from-the-ghost-war/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">You can just click here</a>.</p>
<h2>Gift Two</h2>
<p>I have written about &#8220;A Stick of Clay, In the Hands of God, Is Infinite Potential&#8221; by Neon Yang before, and I am not sorry to bring it up again. I first read this story on my porch mattress (I have a porch mattress) during the summer and a little part of me will always be lying there, staring at spiderwebs, thinking about this story. If you haven&#8217;t read it already, <a href="http://clarkesworldmagazine.com/yang_05_20/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">what are you waiting for</a>?</p>
<p>There is a gift two-point-zero here, and that&#8217;s the announcement last September of Yang&#8217;s debut novel called <a href="https://www.tor.com/2020/09/28/announcing-a-new-sf-trilogy-from-author-neon-yang/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The Genesis of Misery</em></a>. Tor Books bills it as a space opera re-telling of Joan of Arc with a giant robot twist.</p>
<p><a href="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/04/01/17/26/robot-1301183_960_720.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/04/01/17/26/robot-1301183_960_720.jpg" width="960" height="596" /></a></p>
<h2>Some Stocking Stuffers</h2>
<p>A while ago, I found another book acquisition announcement featuring giant robots called Wind-Ups (I think) and a mechanic main character in a gaslamp fantasy setting. Unfortunately, I lost the link to this announcement and can&#8217;t remember much more. The author might be Korean or Korean-American? Please help me find this book because I want it. The announcement for it was made last September, so I&#8217;m guessing it has a 2021 or 2022 release.</p>
<p>In my search for the above announcement, I stumbled upon a light novel/video game called Heaven Will Be Mine. Gayming Magazine has a <a href="https://gaymingmag.com/2019/09/worst-girl-games-on-giant-robots-contradictions-and-queer-futures/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">nice article about it</a>. This I also want.</p>
<p><a href="http://xiranjayzhao.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Iron Widow</em></a> by Xiran Jay Zhao is another upcoming book featuring giant robots. No word on if it&#8217;s queer, but the author is in a cow onesie for her official photo, which means I trust her without question.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
