<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Shana DuBois &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/shana-dubois/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 04:05:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Beyond the Front Tables</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/beyond-the-front-tables/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shana DuBois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 17:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Front Tables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Greetings and salutations lovely readers! First, I want to announce I will be shifting this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Books-8.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5770"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5770 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Books-8-292x300.jpg" alt="" width="292" height="300" /></a>Greetings and salutations lovely readers!</p>
<p>First, I want to announce I will be shifting this column to quarterly versus monthly. It will be a longer column with more presses highlighted and will allow me more time with school/writing/work/life balance to make sure I don’t neglect one too much. That just means each post will pack more bang for your reading buck!</p>
<p>Without further ado, here we go…</p>
<p><strong>Small Press</strong>: Big Mouth House an imprint of <a href="http://smallbeerpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Small Beer Press</a></p>
<p>I can’t recall when or how I stumbled across Small Beer Press but I have been obsessed for some time and slowly collecting nearly every single title they’ve ever published. A recent <a href="http://blog.pshares.org/index.php/indie-spotlight-small-beer-press/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">interview</a> with <em>Ploughshares</em> described Small Beer Press and its books as:</p>
<p>&#8220;defy[ing] genre while also celebrating it; their titles are wondrous and fantastical, blurring the line between the speculative and the concrete in ways that are sometimes dark, sometimes delightful, and altogether original.&#8221;</p>
<p>Small Beer Press focuses on quality over quantity. They would rather publish a few highly honed and developed titles each year than a slew of rushed out drivel. Which is why I will be a devoted lifetime reader.</p>
<p><strong>Title I read and loved</strong>: <em><a href="http://smallbeerpress.com/books/2015/05/05/archivist-wasp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Archivist Wasp</a></em> by Nicole Korner-Stace</p>
<p><strong>Format</strong>: Physical book I purchased direct from publisher</p>
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 256 pages</p>
<p><strong>Description (from the book’s website)</strong>: “Wasp’s job is simple. Hunt ghosts. And every year she has to fight to remain Archivist. Desperate and alone, she strikes a bargain with the ghost of a supersoldier. She will go with him on his underworld hunt for the long-lost ghost of his partner and in exchange she will find out more about his pre-apocalyptic world than any Archivist before her. And there is much to know. After all, Archivists are marked from birth to do the holy work of a goddess. They’re chosen. They’re special. Or so they’ve been told for four hundred years.”</p>
<p><strong>Why I loved it</strong>: <em>Archivist Wasp</em> is a book that sticks with you. It is a YA novel with a protagonist you will find yourself rooting for time and again. She buckles down and fights for a life and change. I loved the way Korner-Stace weaves mythology into the narrative and how people have adapted to their post-apocalyptic society.</p>
<p><strong>Title I am looking forward to next</strong>:<em> <a href="http://smallbeerpress.com/books/2015/11/24/you-have-never-been-here/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">You Have Never Been Here</a> </em>by Mary Rickert</p>
<p><strong>Format</strong>: Physical book I purchased direct from publisher</p>
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 320 pages</p>
<p><strong>Description (from the book’s website)</strong>: &#8220;Open this book to any page and find yourself enspelled by these lush, alchemical stories. Faced with the uncanny and the impossible, Rickert’s protagonists are as painfully, shockingly, complexly human as the readers who will encounter them. Mothers, daughters, witches, artists, strangers, winged babies, and others grapple with deception, loss, and moments of extraordinary joy.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Why I’m looking forward to it</strong>: I love short story collections in general but when it is an author who I haven&#8217;t encountered, I find them a particularly delicious entry point into their writing. This collection has been getting amazing reviews and I’ve been purchasing her other works in anticipation of digging through her backlist.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p><strong>Small Press</strong>: <a href="http://subterraneanpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Subterranean Press</a></p>
<p>I discovered Subterranean Press via a podcast years ago and have been slowly collecting titles ever since.</p>
<blockquote><p>Subterranean Press is widely considered to be among the finest specialty publishers in the science fiction, fantasy, and horror genres, and has published Stephen King, Carlos Ruiz Zafon, Harlan Ellison, Joe Hill, and Peter Straub.</p></blockquote>
<p>Each book is holding art in your hands. A luscious testament to print lasting the ages and each book is a treat to have on my shelves.</p>
<p><strong>Title I read and loved</strong>:<em> <a href="http://subterraneanpress.com/store/product_detail/the_end_of_the_sentence" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The End of the Sentence</a> </em>by Maria Dahvana Headley &amp; Kat Howard</p>
<p><strong>Format</strong>: Physical book I purchased direct from publisher</p>
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 176 pages</p>
<p><strong>Description (from the book’s website)</strong>: “It begins with a letter from a prisoner…</p>
<p>As he attempts to rebuild his life in rural Oregon after a tragic accident, Malcolm Mays finds himself corresponding with Dusha Chuchonnyhoof, a mysterious entity who claims to be the owner of Malcolm&#8217;s house, jailed unjustly for 117 years. The prisoner demands that Malcolm perform a gory, bewildering task for him.”</p>
<p><strong>Why I loved it</strong>: This book was a delicious blend of horror, mythology, and fantasy. It also includes epistolary elements, something I love in my fiction. Despite its short length, it packs a powerful punch making each word count and not wasting time dragging the narrative down with unnecessary exposition. Headley and Howard managed to create a work that is a flawless weave of both their styles making me want to seek out all they have written as individuals.</p>
<p><strong>Title I am looking forward to next</strong>:<em> <a href="http://subterraneanpress.com/store/product_detail/the_best_of_nancy_kress" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Best of Nancy Kress</a></em> by Nancy Kress</p>
<p><strong>Format</strong>: Physical book I purchased direct from publisher</p>
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 560 pages</p>
<p><strong>Description (from the book’s website)</strong>: “Nancy Kress, winner of multiple awards for her science fiction and fantasy, ranges through space and time in this stunning collection.”</p>
<p><strong>Why I am looking forward to it</strong>: I have been hearing so many wonderful things about Kress in every length of fiction. I thought this dedicated collection would be a wonderful entry point before moving onto some of her novellas, etc.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p><strong>Small Press</strong>: <a href="http://www.valancourtbooks.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Valancourt Books</a></p>
<p>I came across Valancourt Books thanks to Twitter of all places. They describe themselves as: “an independent small press specializing in the rediscovery of rare, neglected, and out-of-print fiction. Despite the valiant efforts of a few small presses and the availability of new technology that can make books available to readers all over the world, far too many great books remain out-of-print and inaccessible; we founded Valancourt Books in 2005 to restore many of these works to new generations of readers.”</p>
<p>They focus on Gothic, horror, supernatural fiction, gay interest, and neglected authors and works. I adore what they are doing and publishing and have been slowly buying up their catalog and discovering so many wonderful books.</p>
<p><strong>Title I read and loved</strong>: <em><a href="http://www.valancourtbooks.com/store/p10/The_Elementals_by_Michael_McDowell_%28Paperback%29.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Elementals</a></em> by Michael McDowell</p>
<p><strong>Format</strong>: Physical book I purchased direct from publisher</p>
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 218 pages</p>
<p><strong>Description (from the book’s website)</strong>: &#8220;After a bizarre and disturbing incident at the funeral of matriarch Marian Savage, the McCray and Savage families look forward to a restful and relaxing summer at Beldame, on Alabama’s Gulf Coast, where three Victorian houses loom over the shimmering beach. Two of the houses are habitable, while the third is slowly and mysteriously being buried beneath an enormous dune of blindingly white sand. But though long uninhabited, the third house is not empty. Inside, something deadly lies in wait. Something that has terrified Dauphin Savage and Luker McCray since they were boys and which still haunts their nightmares. Something horrific that may be responsible for several terrible and unexplained deaths years earlier — and is now ready to kill again . . .&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Why I loved it</strong>: I read this book in one sitting! It was incredibly engrossing and one of the better haunted house stories I’ve come across and couldn’t put it down. I really loved the depth to the characters that drew me into what they were experiencing on each page. I am thrilled Valancourt is bringing such titles back into the world.</p>
<p><strong>Title I am looking forward to next</strong>: <em><a href="http://www.valancourtbooks.com/harriet-1934.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Harriet</a></em> by Elizabeth Jenkins</p>
<p><strong>Format</strong>: Physical book I purchased direct from publisher</p>
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 193 pages</p>
<p><strong>Description (from the book’s website)</strong>: Harriet Ogilvy is a young woman with a small fortune and a mental disability, making her the ideal target for the handsome and scheming Lewis Oman. After winning Harriet’s love, Lewis, with the help of his brother and mistress, sets in motion a plan of unspeakable cruelty and evil to get his hands on her money. With consummate artistry, Elizabeth Jenkins transforms the bare facts of this case from the annals of Victorian England’s Old Bailey into an absolutely spine-chilling exploration of the depths of human depravity.</p>
<p><strong>Why I’m looking forward to it</strong>: This is a story based on an actual case from 1877. Published originally in 1934, winning the Prix Femina Vie Heureuse, Harriet is a true-crime based novel that sounds incredibly intriguing. I am also keen to read neglected female authors and support efforts to bring them back!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p>I hope you have as much as I did browsing the catalogs of the above small/indie presses above! Until next quarter, happy reading!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond the Front Tables: Curbside Splendor Publishing</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/beyond-front-tables-curbside-splendor-publishing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shana DuBois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 16:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Front Tables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome, my beloved fellow readers! How has your reading shaped up over the past month?&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome, my beloved fellow readers!</p>
<p>How has your reading shaped up over the past month? I know I have built quite the scary reads TBR thanks to Halloween recommendation lists! I also spent some time exploring some of my favorite presses and I have another wonderful one to share with you today.</p>
<p><strong>Small Press</strong>: <a href="http://www.curbsidesplendor.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Curbside Splendor Publishing</a></p>
<p>I stumbled across Curbside Splendor in one of my favorite places to find presses: The Twitterverse. After browsing their catalog and making a large list of books to order, I finally settled on a few titles by Amber Sparks to dip my toes into the Curbside pool of awesome.</p>
<p>One thing I love about Curbside Splendor is their origin story, shared within their mission statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>Curbside Splendor was conceived as a punk rock band in the early 1990s in an apartment in Urbana, Illinois. The band never really went anywhere, but Curbside was re-founded as an independent press in the fall of 2009. We&#8217;re located in the Humboldt Park neighborhood of Chicago, Illinois.  We publish fiction, creative non-fiction, and poetry that celebrates extraordinary voices and work that is deeply rooted in the Midwest.</p></blockquote>
<p>I was born and raised in the Midwest so this publisher already has a spot in my heart and they are putting out some amazing fiction, especially women.</p>
<p><strong>Title I read and loved</strong>: <em><a href="http://www.curbsidesplendor.com/books/may-we-shed-these-human-bodies" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">May We Shed These Human Bodies</a></em> by Amber Sparks</p>
<p><strong>Format</strong>: Physical book I purchased.</p>
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 153 pages</p>
<p><strong>Book description</strong> (from the publisher’s website): &#8220;<em>May We Shed These Human Bodies</em> peers through vast spaces and skies with the world&#8217;s most powerful telescope to find humanity: wild and bright and hard as diamonds.&#8221;</p>
<p>It is no secret I am a huge fan of short story collections. For me, collections are my gateway drug into an author. If I love what they can do with a short story, I am willing to give any length they write a try. After reading this collection, Amber Sparks has a new fan for life (I have her newest collection on pre-order). These stories were varied in style and content so I never knew what a page turn might bring. I loved the fable type stories and her writing style managed to carry a different narrative voice into each piece. Pure joy.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/DesertPlacesCover.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5437 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/DesertPlacesCover-188x300.jpg" alt="DesertPlacesCover" width="188" height="300" /></a>Title I am looking forward to next</strong>: <a href="http://www.curbsidesplendor.com/books/the-desert-places" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Desert Places</a> by Amber Sparks &amp; Robert Kloss, illustrated by Matt Kish</p>
<p><strong>Format</strong>: Physical book I purchased.</p>
<p><strong>Length</strong>: 87 pages</p>
<p><strong>Book description</strong> (from the publisher’s website): &#8220;<em>The Desert Places</em> is a pocket-sized edition of a hybrid text by Amber Sparks and Robert Kloss that explores the evolution of evil in worlds both seen and unseen and features full-color illustrations by Matt Kish, illustrator of the critically acclaimed <em>Moby-Dick in Pictures: One Drawing for Every Page.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>I am all in on anything Amber Sparks now, but add exploring evil and I am sold! This book is small but it looks mighty. The illustrations are incredible and I look forward to inhaling this little gem very soon.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*   *   *</p>
<p>I hope you find something juicy to enjoy from Curbside Splendor Publishing! Until next time happy readers, go forth and always remember to search Beyond the Front Tables.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond the Front Tables: Aqueduct Press</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/beyond-front-tables-aqueduct-press/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shana DuBois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 16:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Front Tables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Greetings my cherished fellow readers! Have you come across any new books lately? I have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Greetings my cherished fellow readers!</p>
<p>Have you come across any new books lately? I have purchased WAY too many books in the past few months but every time I convince myself I will cut back I find more awesome books I want on my shelf ready to be read.</p>
<p><strong>Small Press</strong>: <a href="http://www.aqueductpress.com/index.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Aqueduct Press</a></p>
<p>This month I want to chat with you about Aqueduct Press. I am slowly purchasing their entire catalog because of all the amazing fiction, poetry, and non-fiction they offer. They have a focus on producing quality books containing mind-bending and thought-provoking prose. From their Mission Statement page:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Aqueduct Press dedicates itself to publishing challenging, feminist science fiction. We promise to bring our readers work that will stretch the imagination and stimulate thought.”</p></blockquote>
<p>A mission I intend to fully support by spreading the word and putting my buying dollars in their pocket.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/th.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5297 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/th-197x300.jpg" alt="th" width="197" height="300" /></a>Title I read and loved:</strong> <a href="http://www.aqueductpress.com/books/978-1-61976-053-0.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Elysium</a> by Jennifer Marie Brissett</p>
<p>Format: Physical book I purchased.</p>
<p>Length: 208 pages</p>
<p>Book description (from the publisher’s website): A computer program etched into the atmosphere has a story to tell, the story of two people, of a city lost to chaos, of survival and love. The program’s data, however, has been corrupted. As the novel&#8217;s characters struggle to survive apocalypse, they are sustained and challenged by the demands of love in a shattered world both haunted and dangerous.</p>
<p>I sat down to read this book one afternoon with the intention of just reading a few chapters. Instead I polished it off in one sitting and immediately turned back to page one to start again. This book sticks with you long after you finish as you consider the magnitude of what Brissett has put forth in her novel. The fluidity of gender and relation between two people is handled with incredibly finesse and never once caused a break in the story or world for me.</p>
<p><strong>Title I am looking forward to next:</strong> <a href="http://www.aqueductpress.com/books/978-1-61976-027-1.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Stone Boatmen</a> by Sarah Tolmie</p>
<p>Format: Physical book sitting on my shelf (purchased by me)</p>
<p>Length: 312 pages</p>
<p>Book description (from publisher’s website): Tolmie tells a tale of three cities, separated by oceans, lost to one another long ago: the first, the city of rituals, of ceremonies; the second, the city of words, of poetry; and the third, the city of the golden birds, of dreams. In their harbors stand the stone boatmen, pointing outward toward the unknown. Now the birds are fostering a new-found relationship of the three cities of the ancestors, and the voyages of the ship Aphelion and its crew are beginning to rebuild the links.</p>
<p>This book has received wonderful reviews from Ursula K. Le Guin, Nancy Hightower <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/entertainment/books/notes-from-the-internet-apocalypse-the-tropic-of-serpents-and-the-stone-boatmen/2014/03/18/bcfb869c-a9e0-11e3-b61e-8051b8b52d06_story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">with <em>The Washington Post</em></a>, and a<a href="http://www.publishersweekly.com/978-1-61976-027-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> starred review from <em>Publisher’s Weekly</em></a>. The premise is incredibly intriguing and I find myself wondering what these cities have in store for me.</p>
<p>* * *</p>
<p>I hope you check out the above titles and more from Aqueduct Press, I know you won’t be disappointed! Until next time happy readers, go forth and remember to keep searching Beyond the Front Tables.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond the Front Tables: Twelfth Planet Press</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/beyond-the-front-tables-twelfth-planet-press/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shana DuBois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 15:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Front Tables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Greetings my fellow readers! Welcome back. I hope you&#8217;ve been enjoying some great stories from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Greetings my fellow readers!</p>
<p>Welcome back. I hope you&#8217;ve been enjoying some great stories from around the world. I&#8217;m here to add a few more titles to your TBR pile.</p>
<p><strong>Independent Press:</strong> <a href="http://www.twelfthplanetpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twelfth Planet Press</a>.</p>
<p>They are putting out some truly captivating stories and working to bring us some truly fresh ideas/concepts from an elite group of authors. Per their mission outline, the following objectives from their website are at the forefront of their publishing goals:</p>
<blockquote><p>• to publish fresh, original, well-written work that seeks to interrogate, commentate, inspire or provoke thought;<br />
• to provide opportunities for female writers by publishing and showcasing new work;<br />
• to advocate for fiction written for, by and about women;<br />
• to raise the awareness of women’s voices in science fiction, fantasy, horror and recently, crime; and<br />
• to showcase and demonstrate the depth and breadth of Australian fiction to a broader audience.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Title I read and LOVED:</strong> <em><a href="http://www.twelfthplanetpress.com/products/ebooks/femalefactory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Female Factory</a></em> by: Lisa L. Hannett and Angela Slatter</p>
<p><em>Note: All the stories in the collection were co-written by both authors.</em></p>
<p>Format: e-book</p>
<p>Book description (from the Twelfth Plant Press website): &#8220;From Australia’s near-future all the way back in time to its convict past, these stories spin and sever the ties between parents and children.&#8221;</p>
<p>I learned about this collection from the amazing <a href="https://twitter.com/tithenai" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Amal El-Mohtar </a>on Twitter, she also wrote the introduction to the collection. Anything Amal recommends I take seriously so I bought this straight away and once again she nailed it. Each story was stunning and I found myself pausing after each one lost in thought about what I just read. Hannett and Slatter created some mind-bending possible futures that sent shivers through me.</p>
<p><strong>Title I am looking forward to next:</strong> <em><a href="http://www.twelfthplanetpress.com/products/ebooks/bad-power" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bad Power</a></em> by Deborah Biancotti</p>
<p>Book description (from the Twelfth Plant Press website): &#8220;From Crawford Award nominee Deborah Biancotti comes this sinister short story suite, a pocketbook police procedural, set in a world where the victories are only relative, and the defeats are absolute. <em>Bad Power</em> celebrates the worst kind of powers both supernatural and otherwise, in the interlinked tales of five people &#8211; and how far they&#8217;ll go.&#8221;</p>
<p>I am intrigued by story collections where the stories are linked, as though I am reading a shorter novel of sorts. Trying to find the links in plots and/or characters as I read each story adds an element of depth I don&#8217;t normally find in a standard story collection. This collection from Biancotti has a fascinating premise and I am excited to see how she weaves in her connections.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">* * *</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Until next time, happy book hunting my fine bibliophile friends!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond the Front Tables: Crossed Genres</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/beyond-the-front-tables-crossed-genres/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shana DuBois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 16:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Front Tables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Greetings and salutations fellow readers! Before I jumped into chatting about the amazing Crossed Genres&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/read-652384_640.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-4143" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/read-652384_640-300x225.jpg" alt="read-652384_640" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Greetings and salutations fellow readers!</p>
<p>Before I jumped into chatting about the amazing Crossed Genres press, I wanted to welcome you to &#8220;Beyond the Front Tables,&#8221; a column dedicated to highlighting small and independent presses and some of the titles I have loved from these presses. But first, allow me to introduce myself&#8230;</p>
<p>My name is Shana and I am an <em>extreme</em> bibliophile. If there were a book event at the X Games I would be all over it! And, as a former Marine I do love some competition. Currently, I am pursuing my MA in English with a concentration in Literary Studies.  And I also work full-time at an insurance company, but it is utterly boring as I deal with numbers all day (&#8230;zzz). But enough about me, let us get back to why we are all here: BOOKS!</p>
<p>A few years ago I realized I was limiting my reading to what the bookstore put in front of me and I decided I wanted to change things. I started seeking out titles I hadn&#8217;t heard about a hundred times over. The joy of finding a new-to-me author is infectious and something I started sharing with friends and family. And now, Luna Station Quarterly is going to let me share my passion here as well!</p>
<p>Each column will feature a small or independent press, some information about what they publish, where you can find their books, etc. I will also share a title I personally enjoyed as well as what I plan on reading next from the press. As a note, every book I read is picked out and purchased by me and the endorsement of any title is a reflection of the enjoyment I had upon reading.</p>
<p>I look forward to having many chats about books with all of you, my amazing fellow readers, so without further delay&#8230; LET&#8217;S GET THIS PARTY STARTED!</p>
<p><strong>Small Press</strong>: <a title="Crossed Genres" href="http://crossedgenres.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Crossed Genres</a></p>
<p>Crossed Genres is a small press I only recently discovered. The press focuses on &#8220;progressive speculative fiction&#8221; and is comprised of two branches, the Crossed Genres Magazine and Crossed Genres Publications. One of the many reasons I adore this press is their mission statement (from their website):</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;It&#8217;s the mission of Crossed Genres Publications to give voice to people often ignored or marginalized in SFF, which has led us to publish titles focused on older women, overweight women, immigration, skilled laborers, QUILTBAG families, and people marginalized throughout history.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>That is a mission I can embrace and support with all my heart and purchasing power.</p>
<p>When I started subscribing to their monthly SF/F magazine (something you can do <a href="http://crossedgenres.com/magazine/subscribe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>) I had not been aware of the book publishing side of the press. I fell in love with the stories in the magazine from the first issue I read. Then, when I was putting the book <a href="http://crossedgenres.com/titles/long-hidden/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Long Hidden: Speculative Fiction from the Margins of History</a> on my shelf, I noticed &#8220;Crossed Genres&#8221; on the spine and boom! one of my &#8220;light bulb&#8221; moments.</p>
<p><strong>Title I read and loved</strong>: <a title="Ink" href="http://inknovel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ink</a> by Sabrina Vourvoulias</p>
<p>Format: e-book</p>
<p>Length: 236 pages</p>
<p>Book description (from the book&#8217;s website): &#8220;The near-future, dark speculative novel INK opens as a biometric tattoo is approved for use to mark temporary workers, permanent residents and citizens with recent immigration history &#8211; collectively known as inks.&#8221;</p>
<p>This is a gut-punch of a book. The short length does mean things move quickly and for me that made it all the more powerful of a read. Seeing how quickly society allowed a system of institutionalized population control to become the status quo was alarming. And yet, I could see how it could happen even today, which was even more alarming.</p>
<p>A book that makes you think, sticks with you long after reading, and is one of the first things you want to recommend to people is a book full of win. Seriously, go read this book, right now, go!</p>
<p><strong>Title I am looking forward to next</strong>: <a href="http://crossedgenres.com/titles/menial/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MENIAL: Skilled Labor in Science Fiction</a> edited by Kelly Jennings and Shay Darrach</p>
<p>Format: Patiently waiting in my kindle app</p>
<p>Length: 150 pages / 17 stories</p>
<p>Book description (from the publisher website): &#8220;Miner. Harvester. Mechanic. Sanitation Worker. These are not the typical career of your average science fiction protagonist. Until now.&#8221;</p>
<p>I am so excited to read this book. You always read about the exciting hero, the mysterious traveler, or the amazing warrior rushing into battle, but what about the people that make those worlds go round? Here is a collection that focuses on those often ignored group of people, in literature and our own society.</p>
<p>Another reason I am particularly anxious to dig into this collection is because many of the authors are new-to-me and I will be reading them for the first time. That is one of the reasons I love anthologies; they offer the opportunity to discover some wonderful new voices. I hope you will join me in reading this collection!</p>
<p>Happy reading and until next time, remember to read Beyond the Front Tables!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anne McCaffrey, a Happy Birthday and remembrance</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/anne-mccaffrey-a-happy-birthday-and-remembrance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shana DuBois]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 15:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Because we build the worlds we wouldn&#8217;t mind living in. They contain scary things, problems,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone" src="http://cdn.inquisitr.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Dragonriders-Of-Pern-Movie-Release-Date-Will-Have-Anne-McCaffreys-Books-Flying-To-The-Big-Screen-665x385.jpg" alt="" width="665" height="385" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Because we build the worlds we wouldn&#8217;t mind living in. They contain scary things, problems, but also a sense of rightness that makes them alive and makes us want to live there.&#8221; ~ Anne McCaffrey</p></blockquote>
<p>Anne Inez McCaffrey was born April 1, 1926 in Cambridge, MA.  Ms. McCaffrey began publishing short fiction, of the speculative nature, in 1953 and her first novel, &#8220;Restoree,&#8221; was published in 1967. She went on to write dozens of novels with many set in the world of Pern as part of her most beloved series Dragonriders.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;A good story is a good story no matter who wrote it.&#8221; ~ Anne McCaffrey</p></blockquote>
<p>Ms. McCaffrey was the <em>first</em> woman to win a Hugo for fiction and the <em>first</em> woman to win a Nebula <em>both</em> in 1968, in 2005 she received the SFWA Grand Master Award and in 2006 was inducted into the Science Fiction Hall of Fame.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;That&#8217;s what writing is all about, after all, making others see what you have put down on the page and believing that is does, or could, exist and you want to go there.&#8221; ~ Anne McCaffrey</p></blockquote>
<p>On November 21, 2011 Anne McCaffrey passed away at the age of 85 at her home in Ireland. She was an amazing writer adept at combining science-fiction with elements of fantasy. Her love of books knew no bounds and her works inspired millions of young adults to develop a cherished connection with reading.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I have a shelf of comfort books, which I read when the world closes in on me or something untoward happens.&#8221; ~ Anne McCaffrey</p></blockquote>
<p>You can find Ms. McCaffrey&#8217;s obituary <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/books/2011/nov/23/anne-mccaffrey-obituary" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p>
<p>Ms. McCaffrey&#8217;s entry in The Encyclopedia of Science Fiction can be found <a href="http://www.sf-encyclopedia.com/entry/mccaffrey_anne" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
