<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 038 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-038/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:27:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 038 Author Interview: T.D. Walker and &#8220;Into Nothingness&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-author-interview-t-d-walker-and-into-nothingness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 038]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to our Tuesday interview with an author of the current issue of LSQ! Today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16058 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/kelley-bozarth-n6vS3xlnsCc-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/kelley-bozarth-n6vS3xlnsCc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/kelley-bozarth-n6vS3xlnsCc-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/kelley-bozarth-n6vS3xlnsCc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Welcome to our Tuesday interview with an author of the current issue of <em>LSQ</em>! Today we chat with author T.D. Walker about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/into-nothingness/">Into Nothingness</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">You use a lot of repetition in the syntax of this story. Since you’re also a poet, I wondered if this was intentional, accidentally influenced by poetry, or a combination of both. Do you find that poetry and prose play off each other in your writing?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>TD: The repetition is intentional, and it&#8217;s there for a few reasons. First, since the story is set on New Year&#8217;s Eve, I tried to evoke through the language a sense of music, the kind you might hear at such an event. Second, there&#8217;s the repetition we experience on New Year&#8217;s Eve, remembering the past year as well as engaging in the traditions of the evening, like the countdown, singing <em>Auld Lang Syne</em>, and perhaps a kiss. But on a deeper level, I wanted to show the characters ruminating, going over and over in their minds what the past year brought them. They&#8217;re spending their evening repeating their mistakes of the past years, and that, to me, is what made them interesting to write about.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Fitting multiple characters’ perspectives in a short story is no simple feat, but you’ve given us a good look at everyone’s thoughts and feelings. Do you have any tips for successfully juggling perspectives?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>TD: I think this goes back to being a poet. A poem is delivered to the reader through the voice of a character, the speaker created by the poet. One of the challenges of writing speculative poems that I especially appreciate is that I have to write with economy to create a character who is fully-formed enough to bring the reader into the world of the poem for the duration of the piece. So I&#8217;m constantly asking myself as I write, &#8220;Is this detail telling enough? Does this detail carry enough weight to drive the poem forward?&#8221; It&#8217;s the same for this story, which I originally envisioned as a series of four flash pieces.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Everybody seems pretty casual about aliens in the year 2038-going-on-2039. How do you think you would react in their shoes?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>TD: Well, at this point in their world, few people know about the aliens, so it&#8217;s rumor for just about everyone else. This is part of the reason why I added the &#8220;Tim&#8221; section&#8211;he&#8217;s heard about the aliens and Mia&#8217;s new body, but doesn&#8217;t believe it. I&#8217;d think most people would be in this state, that it&#8217;s too much to believe. Even if news of the aliens and the new bodies did become widespread, would that really change the ways we live our lives? Wouldn&#8217;t we make the same mistakes as we&#8217;d made before?</p>
<p>To answer your question more directly, I don&#8217;t know how I&#8217;d react. I&#8217;m a skeptic, so if this were <img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16059 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/brian-mcmahon-vPoKUPztOZM-unsplash-300x187.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="187" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/brian-mcmahon-vPoKUPztOZM-unsplash-300x187.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/brian-mcmahon-vPoKUPztOZM-unsplash-768x478.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/brian-mcmahon-vPoKUPztOZM-unsplash-1024x637.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />just a rumor, I&#8217;d be likely to dismiss it. But if, say, the news were announced that a mining company happened to encounter alien technology, and that company were to be the only entity controlling access to it, I think I&#8217;d be in line with the other protesters voicing a need for more transparency around such a discovery.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>TD: Too many projects! I&#8217;m working on a chapbook-length manuscript of poems that explore the voices of people aboard a generation ship. I&#8217;m also writing a novella&#8211;still!&#8211;that follows Alice from my previous story in <i>Luna Station Quarterly, </i>&#8220;All the Songs the Little Birds Sing.&#8221; When I started it years ago, it felt far-fetched, but the kinds of restrictions on women&#8217;s choices that drive the story are falling into place in too many states here in the US. So even though it&#8217;s been the single most difficult thing I&#8217;ve written (and rewritten), it feels urgent and necessary. Then there&#8217;s the novel about adoption and AI that I have outlined and partially drafted that I&#8217;ll come back to after I finally finish the novella. And I&#8217;m discovering after the publication of my first full-length poetry collection in May that book marketing could easily fill up all my writing time if I let it. But it&#8217;s a wonderful problem to have, so no complaints, if course.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 038 Author Interview: Celia Neri and &#8220;Vincent Coriolis, Father of the Nation&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-author-interview-celia-neri-and-vincent-coriolis-father-of-the-nation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 038]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16020</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do we have a treat for you, dear readers! Here, look over our shoulder as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16021 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/hasan-almasi-OwqLxCvoVxI-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/hasan-almasi-OwqLxCvoVxI-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/hasan-almasi-OwqLxCvoVxI-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/hasan-almasi-OwqLxCvoVxI-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Do we have a treat for you, dear readers! Here, look over our shoulder as we sit down and have a chat with Issue 038 author Celia Neri about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/vincent-coriolis-father-of-the-nation/">Vincent Coriolis, Father of the Nation</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The interwoven settings–a leisurely tour on a sunny day, and a grisly battlefield–are very jarring. Can you tell us why you used this method, rather than a straightforward timeline?</strong></em></p>
<p>Celia: From the beginning, you know that it&#8217;s not actually the revolution that fails. Rather than building up a sense of suspense&#8211;will this revolution succeed or not?&#8211;I was more interested in the reveal of the fact that it is the <em>ideals</em> that will fail. This let me play with the sense of tragedy, that beneath the happy, sunny day, something still isn&#8217;t right. The tragedy of it and the iconoclasm were what I wanted to explore rather than an action-oriented story that would make you believe in a dashing hero.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What were the challenges in writing the past and present scenes together?</strong></em></p>
<p>Celia: The most challenging part was getting the voice right. When Marina talks about the past, it&#8217;s with a lot of sadness. When she talks about the present, there&#8217;s cynicism and anger. I had to work so that both voices weren&#8217;t too dissimilar despite the different tones, otherwise it would&#8217;ve felt like two different characters. At the same time, I had to keep them dissimilar enough so that a reader could follow where they are in time.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: They say history is written by the victors. It’s clear that Marina doesn’t consider <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16022 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/valentin-salja-9kbaq1xoIr0-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/valentin-salja-9kbaq1xoIr0-unsplash-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/valentin-salja-9kbaq1xoIr0-unsplash-768x1158.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/valentin-salja-9kbaq1xoIr0-unsplash-679x1024.jpg 679w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/valentin-salja-9kbaq1xoIr0-unsplash.jpg 1990w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" />herself a victor even though she technically won her battle. Can you comment on this? </strong></em></p>
<p>Celia: Marina&#8217;s world is ready for a socio-economic change. Yet, despite the bloodshed, despite the readiness, nothing changes. They get some rights, but it&#8217;s nothing more than what we already have in the past in some countries. A revolution should lead forward, should mean progress. The fact is that many revolutions just consolidate old systems under new guises. So Marina isn&#8217;t a victor: her personal situation isn&#8217;t better and her society remains unequal, with an added cult of personality that blinds everyone to the reality.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any writers who have influenced your work?</strong></em></p>
<p>Celia: I started creative writing at 39. Before that, I was (I still am!) an avid reader. So it&#8217;s difficult for me to disentangle which writers, which stories influence my work, because there are so many. Any list would go on and on and on. But I would say that my four &#8220;pillars&#8221; are Terry Pratchett, Octavia Butler, Iain M. Banks, and Ursula Le Guin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 038 Author Interview: Johanna Levene and &#8220;Grork Dentist&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-author-interview-johanna-levene-and-grork-dentist/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 038]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Terrific Tuesday &#8212; we&#8217;re here to present an interview with one of our fabulous Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15899 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/jon-tyson-kpLEaeScdHY-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/jon-tyson-kpLEaeScdHY-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/jon-tyson-kpLEaeScdHY-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />Terrific Tuesday &#8212; we&#8217;re here to present an interview with one of our fabulous Issue 038 authors. This time we sat down with Johanna Levene and chatted about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/grork-dentist/">Grork Dentist</a>.&#8221; So pull up a chair and read along, won&#8217;t you?</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im"> Even though I don’t have a dentist phobia, I felt super nervous while reading this story! What is it about dentists that makes them perfect nightmare fodder</span>?</strong></em></p>
<p>Johanna: I’ve hated the dentist since I was eleven years old and got my first crown. At the end of that appointment, I got out of the dentist chair and fainted – autobiographical tie to my story there. For me, the lack of control, the pain, and the torturous instruments are a horror show. In some ways, I think Grork dentistry is less scary than human dentistry. The pain and instruments are gone, and all that’s left is surrendering to aliens and their secretive procedures. Honestly, I might be tempted to give the Grorks a try if they opened an office in my neighborhood.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Nothing overtly sinister happens to Melissa, but you’ve planted seeds of potentially horrific outcomes for us humans. Can you tell us a bit about revealing just enough information without spelling everything out for readers?</strong></em></p>
<p>Johanna: What happens? The rallka-urk juice microbes infiltrate our water system and turn all life on Earth into a new species of bone hungering zombies. Wait, no. The Grork’s reproduction rate is staggering and their babies only feed on human flesh. Just kidding.</p>
<p>This isn’t a story with a cut and dry horrific ending. It might all end up fine. The Grork practices may create a world with no dental problems . . . but what will the Grorks do then? What scares me are how quickly Grorks learned to manipulate human institutions – the media, marketing, and the law – to ingratiate themselves into human lives. We humans love grabbing the next great idea without considering the consequences: think asbestos, plastic bags, social media, chemical sunscreens, and SUVs that get 7 miles to a gallon. All those may be great ideas, but at what cost?</p>
<p>The horror is seen during the interaction between Cheryl and Greg. With no research, they are embracing Grorks and encouraging Melissa to do the same. All they care about is how great their teeth look. Intended and unintended consequences are never considered. No one has done their homework and that feels very familiar and frightening to me.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">The Grorks are so vividly described, with their giant, smiling mouths. Where did the inspiration for them come from</span>?</strong></em></p>
<p>Johanna: I’m thrilled that the Grorks came across so clearly, because I can see them perfectly in <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15900 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/nhia-moua-jQYofLnS0TI-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/nhia-moua-jQYofLnS0TI-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/nhia-moua-jQYofLnS0TI-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/nhia-moua-jQYofLnS0TI-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />my mind, except they have snail-like eye-stalks which somehow weren’t written. The story inspiration came from a remarkably calm emergency dental appointment. I was eating a birthday cupcake and one of my seven crowns fell out while chewing. (Worst birthday present ever, but at least it didn’t hurt.) My dentist met me in his office, examined the situation, and told me it was an old crown and the glue holding it on my tooth had just worn out. He took my crown across the room and started cleaning it up and getting it ready for installation. The drilling and scraping were a good five feet away from me. We chatted like normal people who don’t put their hands in each other’s mouth. A little gluing and I was good as new. I thought, “This was great. Why can’t the dentist always be like this?”</p>
<p>Well, my dentist can’t pull off disembodied dentistry, but an alien dentist could, and a story was born. That said, I have no idea where I came up with the Grork globular toothy physiology, but they were a hoot to create.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">What was the most challenging part of this story to write and why? What was the most enjoyable and why?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Johanna: The most challenging part of the story was the dialogue. Typically, I use conversation to build characters and relationships, but after several weeks holding my lips motionless with my fingers while trying to read lipless Grork dialogue out loud, I gave up and put in a few paragraphs of narration. My other challenge? My ideal reader is my mom, and her dental phobia dwarfs mine. She’s managed to read the story twice – once before and once after publication – but it’s not her favorite. She says I’ve “succeeded in creating emotion in my reader,” which is a nice way of saying my story scares the crap out of her. Sorry, mom.</p>
<p>My favorite part was creating the Grorks and their world. I love that they are genderless, and I had a whole version where I made up new pronouns for them. That was fun, but I didn’t have the writing chops to make it readable. I love that their sexuality doesn’t fit any human norm, but that humans have accepted their differences. Ironic given that we struggle accepting the diverse varieties of human sexuality. I love that they do amazing work for the needy, even if their motives are suspicious. Oh, and the Grognorg is awesome. What a wonderfully helpful little symbiotic creature – unless it’s not.</p>
<p>However, the truly best part is having my first story out in the world. I’ve been a writer in the closet for seven years now, not letting my colleagues at work or school know about my night job. After this publication I’ve shared my avocation with anyone who will listen; it’s been thrilling. My favorite moment was reading &#8220;Grork Dentist&#8221; aloud to my eleven-year-old daughter. She laughed at the right places. She worried at the right places. She felt the flossing shame. Sure, I could have done that pre-publication, but cracking the spine on a physical copy of <em>LSQ</em> and reading my daughter an alien bedtime story was a life high-point.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 038 author interview: Jennifer Lee Rossman and &#8220;Pocketful of Souls&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-author-interview-jennifer-lee-rossman-and-pocketful-of-souls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 038]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to another Tuesday where we interview authors from our current Quarterly. This week we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15861 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/susie-ho-hCGxE6Hi9o4-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/susie-ho-hCGxE6Hi9o4-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/susie-ho-hCGxE6Hi9o4-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/susie-ho-hCGxE6Hi9o4-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Welcome to another Tuesday where we interview authors from our current <em>Quarterly</em>. This week we had the pleasure of chatting with Jennifer Lee Rossman about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/pocketful-of-souls/">Pocketful of Souls</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: A little girl as an antagonist is a rarely seen character. Where did the idea for Amy come from?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: To be honest, I don’t know where the idea for Amy came from. I don’t want to spoil the story, but the idea for the plot twist came before the idea for Amy. My story is about hell and death and sins. But it’s also a sweet story, so I think a young child was really the only character who could give it the right feel. Plus, tiny demon children are awesome. Especially if they’re equal amounts cute and creepy.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Even though Amy has the appearance of an innocent five-year-old, she obviously wasn’t as innocent in life as she looked. A backstory like that, I’m sure, is best left to a reader’s imagination. Can you talk a bit about the benefits of letting the reader fill in the blanks versus giving the whole story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: Amy is a sweet little girl. Amy is also a demon who lives in hell and collects souls for the devil. How she ended up that way is not important to the story, so I didn’t write about it. It wasn’t really a conscious decision on my part to leave the audience wondering about her backstory, but I do like a little mystery in my stories. (My personal theory? The Darkness was lonely and has a <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15862 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/arisa-chattasa-hFbXhpFYyW4-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/arisa-chattasa-hFbXhpFYyW4-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/arisa-chattasa-hFbXhpFYyW4-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/arisa-chattasa-hFbXhpFYyW4-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />soft spot for children, but children don’t end up in hell very often so it “adopted” her from heaven. I think that’s why Amy has such a preoccupation with her, um, collection.)</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Even though this story deals with heavy topics like the fate of one’s immortal soul, it’s still full of humor. Do you think this work would have told a much different story without the humorous elements? Why does humor play such an important role?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: I think the story could easily have been really really dark. It could have delved into religious philosophy and morality. But instead I chose to make jokes about the computers in hell running Windows Vista. Again, not really a conscious choice on my part; I just have an inability to take anything seriously. I also think humor and silliness make stories more accessible to people. More people will read a funny story about a smol demon child named Amy (as I repeatedly referred to it on Twitter before giving the story actual name) than will read a serious story about the logical fallacies in religious dogma.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging part of this story to write and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: The story actually flowed pretty well and didn’t give me much issue. I probably wrote the first draft in a day and a half. The most difficult part was the title. For the longest time, the file was just called “Amy.” To be completely honest, I’m not in love with the title “Pocketful of Souls,” but I think it’s cute and kind of ominous, like Amy herself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 038 Author Interview: Alexandra Grunberg and &#8220;Blue Lips and Frozen Lashes&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-author-interview-alexandra-grunberg-and-blue-lips-and-frozen-lashes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 038]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Back again for another Issue 038 author interview, are we? Great! Let&#8217;s chat with Alexandra&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Back again for another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-038/">Issue 038</a> author interview, are we? Great! Let&#8217;s chat with Alexandra Grunberg about her flash piece &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/blue-lips-and-frozen-lashes/">Blue Lips and Frozen Lashes</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I’m always amazed by flash fiction. How the heck do you fit a whole story into 1000 words or less? What’s your secret?</strong></em></p>
<p>Alexandra: The secret is… Practice! I’ve probably written over fifty pieces of flash fiction, of wildly varying quality, and each time I write one, it feels more and more natural. At this point, I find writing flash fiction easier than writing a traditional short story. I work well with a specific frame that helps me visualize the complete arc. I also really enjoy writing flash fiction, especially when I’m working on a longer piece simultaneously, because in one writing session I can get that satisfaction of a completed work compared to the days or months or years it takes to write longer works of fiction.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Beitris turns out to be more than just an altruistic hiker in the end. Do you plan to <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15831 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/osman-rana-LSUuu25azuM-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/osman-rana-LSUuu25azuM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/osman-rana-LSUuu25azuM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/osman-rana-LSUuu25azuM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />write more about her? Where did the inspiration for this character come from?</strong></em></p>
<p>Alexandra: At the moment, this is the only story I have planned for Beitris. My flash worlds and characters tend to exist in their small bubble because they belong in their bubble. I got the idea for Beitris the same place I get the ideas for most of my short fiction: Pierre Dubois’ “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Great-Encyclopedia-Faeries-Pierre-Dubois/dp/0684869578">The Great Encyclopedia of Faeries</a>.” I try to write every day, and if I don’t have an idea in mind, I just turn to the next chapter in his book and use it as inspiration. I’ve written about aliens in space inspired by selkies and nightmare monsters inspired by faerie trees. This story was a more direct kind of inspiration based on the chapter, “Blue Ladies, Ice Virgins, and Mountain Faeries.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></p>
<p>Alexandra: I tend to always be working on multiple projects at once. Besides continuing to write short fiction, I am working on a horror/thriller screenplay with the film company Magic Dog Productions. This is one of many projects I’ve written with Magic Dog, and our horror film “<a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5078618/">Bugs: A Trilogy</a>” is available for free on Amazon Prime. I am also pursuing my DFA in Creative Writing at the University of Glasgow, where I am working on a post-apocalyptic novel adaptation of Shakespeare’s <em>The Merchant of Venice</em>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 038 Author Interview: Elizabeth Guilt and &#8220;Violent Silence&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-author-interview-elizabeth-guilt-and-violent-silence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 038]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re here today to share a chat with Issue 038 author Elizabeth Guilt about her&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-15659 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/markus-spiske-507983-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/markus-spiske-507983-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/markus-spiske-507983-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/markus-spiske-507983-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />We&#8217;re here today to share a chat with Issue 038 author Elizabeth Guilt about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/violent-silence/">Violent Silence</a>.&#8221; Enjoy!</p>
<p><span class="im"><em><strong>LSQ: You’ve taken a popular element of speculative fiction–increasingly human-like androids–and turned it on its head here. What made you think of having an android with not just human qualities, but an actual human brain?</strong></em></span></p>
<p>Elizabeth: The first thought for the story was an android regretting that they didn&#8217;t experience human bodily sensations: being out of breath, having a pounding heart rate &#8211; they felt only the &#8220;violent silence&#8221; that Sherri describes. In order to miss that, they&#8217;d have to have known it, which requires them to have experience of &#8211; or at least understanding of &#8211; being human. The idea of a human brain inside a constructed body followed very naturally from that.</p>
<p>Also, like Garth, I want to believe that as a living being I am special, and that an artificial consciousness can&#8217;t be as powerful and flexible as a brain. Although AI is coming along in leaps and bounds all the time, there&#8217;s still no consensus that anyone&#8217;s yet produced something which can pass the Turing test.</p>
<p>Once we&#8217;ve reached the point (and I&#8217;m sure we will) where a bot can hold a conversation that convinces people they&#8217;re talking to a human, that&#8217;s very different from creating a thinking consciousness. AI is principally a machine learning algorithms inferring rules from the data they&#8217;re given, and then applying those rules to judge future data: they don&#8217;t truly &#8220;think&#8221; in the way I understand that word. They&#8217;ll replicate any biases from their training data, without questioning them.</p>
<p>Of course, you then start to get into the philosophical questions around what constitutes thought and consciousness. Approaching them stealthily through science fiction feels like a much more practical proposition than trying to tackle them head on.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do you envision a future in which human/droid hybrids like Sherri could be possible? What would be the moral implications?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: The moral implications of being able to take a brain from a human and implant it into a full android body get pretty thorny pretty quickly.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s the question of consent &#8211; Sherri never mentions if she had had any say in whether her brain was given new life following her death. I can imagine situations where individuals, corporations, or governments would be keen to restore a brain to a state where they can interact with it &#8211; for evidence in court, or to retrieve information, or just to speak to a loved one again. Can someone be restored like that against their will, and once they have been, who takes responsibility for their future?</p>
<p>You quickly run into the perennial question of what is human. Should a human brain in a robot body have the same rights as a human? Would failing to carry out repairs to the robot body be the same crime as medical negligence? If you purchase a robot, do you own it and is that akin to slavery? Given that a mechanical body is presumably indefinitely repairable, is having your brain transplanted into a robot body a form of immortality?</p>
<p>I could imagine a human brain in a synthetic body playing out very differently depending on context. Do we see the plastic body as a shell to house the brain, allowing someone to continue living after their human body has crumpled with age or illness? Or do we see the functioning android, performing some vital task, as the important aspect and the brain as a replaceable organic part?</p>
<p>I think it&#8217;s easy to hold confused and quite contradictory opinions on this kind of question. In the story, Garth reasons to himself that Sherri is surely human, but also makes it clear that he doesn&#8217;t consider the Sherri he has met to be the same person as the &#8220;real&#8221; Sherri.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: We’re moving toward a more automated future, perhaps like the one in which “Violent Silence” is set. What are your thoughts regarding robots taking over the workforce and the like? Do you think humans won’t stand a chance without droids, like in your story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I think a lot of the current drive for automation comes from business cases rather than a need for survival: companies want to cut costs, produce goods faster, make decisions based on data. Jobs that have previously been done by humans are handed off to robots or computers when it&#8217;s cheaper or more efficient &#8211; so plenty of businesses won&#8217;t stand a chance without automation, but that&#8217;s a very different story! Given the vast resources that would be required to create a whole &#8220;artificial human&#8221;, there would need to be a very compelling reason why doing it was better than employing an actual human.</p>
<p>In an ideal world, the mechanical, repetitive tasks will be done by robots, and humans left free to do the more interesting or creative work. Automating a task may increase the output, and thus actually create more jobs at the next stage of the process. It&#8217;s still a hard sell if your particular job has been automated out of existence, though. And that&#8217;s been happening to skilled workers for a couple of hundred years; it&#8217;s not a new problem.</p>
<p>I think the interesting changes in our world at the moment are coming from analytical algorithms, <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-15661 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-516603-unsplash-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="548" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-516603-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-516603-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-516603-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />where computers can draw inferences that aren&#8217;t available to humans simply because of the scale of data required. Obviously, we see a lot of baleful headlines about algorithms ruining everything, but some of the applications around, for example, the use of medical data, have the capacity to be transformative. In terms of actual robots, though, our whole approach to mechanization pretty much requires them to remain unthinking beings.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging part of this story to write and why? What was the most enjoyable and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: Having given my characters army backgrounds, and set the story in an ongoing conflict, I realized I&#8217;d landed myself the job of writing descriptions of military operations. I have absolutely no experience to draw on for that, and it&#8217;s not even a style of fiction I regularly read. The story doesn&#8217;t require correct real-world detail, but I was lacking the most basic knowledge and vocabulary. Even without the military angle, I find it difficult to describe people moving through terrain because I have no visual imagination.</p>
<p>Fortunately the story didn&#8217;t require in-depth descriptions. I just needed to furnish a reason for the characters to be in the area, and give them something to run away from!</p>
<p>The most enjoyable sections, even though they&#8217;re tiny, were the interactions with and around the campfire. People today, living in places where they have central heating and modern cookers and no actual daily need for fires, are still fascinated by flames. With all the technological toys we have today, sometimes we still choose fire and drums, which we&#8217;ve been playing with for thousands of years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 038 Author Interview: Allison Epstein and &#8220;The Plover&#8217;s Egg&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-author-interview-allison-epstein-and-the-plovers-egg/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 038]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Join us again for another Issue 038 author interview, won&#8217;t you? This week we chat&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15654 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/tom-barrett-525188-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/tom-barrett-525188-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/tom-barrett-525188-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/tom-barrett-525188-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Join us again for another Issue 038 author interview, won&#8217;t you? This week we chat with Allison Epstein about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-plovers-egg/">The Plover&#8217;s Egg</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: Tell us a bit about the relationship between Marya and the mariner. He knows her &#8220;secret&#8221; and yet chooses not to tell anyone, instead taunting her with his own pursuit of Elizaveta. </b></em></p>
<p>Allison: The relationship between Marya and the mariner is definitely a testy one, which made it really fun to write! One of the things I wanted to explore was relationship power dynamics, which informed the performativity and possessiveness that both Marya and Aleksander display. In Aleksander’s mind, are you even in a relationship if you aren’t flaunting it in someone’s face?</p>
<p>I also see Aleksander as sort of a grifter—someone who doesn’t play by court rules, but who plays to win. He’s less concerned about the fact that his competition is a queer relationship, and more interested in the fact that he’s come out on top. In that way, I have a deep affection for him: he’s a self-serving garbage person, but in an honest way.</p>
<p><em><b> LSQ: Marya and Elizaveta, in their own ways, are both outsiders who seem not to belong. How does this shape their characters and their interactions with each other? </b></em></p>
<p>Allison: You’re right, I think it’s partly Elizaveta’s outsider status that draws Marya to her. Marya is on the margins in a number of ways: class, gender, sexuality, etc. Finally, someone even more of an outsider than her arrives—and, incredibly, that person shows an interest in her. It’s a sort of freedom, one she can’t help but take.</p>
<p>However, what Marya can’t understand is that Elizaveta’s outsider status isn’t just societal. She’s something else altogether. It’s not that Elizaveta doesn’t have emotions; it’s more that those emotions can’t be tracked in human terms, the way a god’s can’t. In a way, mistaking one sort of outsider status for another is what dooms Marya in the end.</p>
<p><em><b> LSQ: Elizaveta&#8217;s change at the end is hinted at from the very start, given where the mariner found her. Do you know what her plans were if she had married him? Or was that not in her plan at all? </b></em></p>
<p>Allison: I imagined Elizaveta having one specific aim: to be in full control, always. It’s a cliché that relationships are a game of give-and-take, but Elizaveta’s only real offering is the grace of her attention. If she’d married Aleksander, she’d have expected more of the same total devotion. However, I don’t think she expected either Aleksander or Marya to live up to that. Her demand of submission was as untenable as their attempts to possess her. (Don’t date any of these people, is what I’m saying.)</p>
<p><em><b> LSQ: What was your inspiration for this story? </b></em></p>
<p>Allison: There’s a scene at the end of Helen Oyeyemi’s short story “Drownings” where two characters look over the side of their boat and see the city of the drowned below. The story is about more than this, obviously (and it is <i>amazing</i>), but my brain latched onto the idea of one person looking down into the water and another person’s open eyes looking back. Of course, an image isn’t a story, but I knew that’s where I wanted to begin.</p>
<p>This particular story was also a therapeutic exercise for me. Just before I began, a writing instructor told me flat-out that my stories were dragging, and he could tell it was because I was bored with my subject matter. I took this as permission to start putting my pet obsessions back in my fiction: Imperial Russia, atmospheric weather, ballroom dancing, salmon. (For some reason, I spend a lot of time thinking about salmon.) “The Plover’s Egg” is basically the result of combining that initial image and deciding to have <i>fun </i>again.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect of this story to write and why? What was the most enjoyable? </b></em></p>
<p>Allison: Getting the ending right was a nightmare. My earlier drafts included at least four different <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15655 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/drew-farwell-481114-unsplash-300x181.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="181" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/drew-farwell-481114-unsplash-300x181.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/drew-farwell-481114-unsplash-768x463.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/drew-farwell-481114-unsplash-1024x618.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />unsatisfying endings. It took me ages to realize what the problem was: letting either Marya or Aleksander get what they wanted made the story about <i>them, </i>while my gut always knew this was Elizaveta’s world entirely. Once the power dynamics between the trio finally clicked, Elizaveta’s final move felt both inevitable and satisfying.</p>
<p>The most fun part was the setting, for sure. Historical fantasy is my happy place. I love the research, the costuming, the dialogue quirks, and when you add in magic it’s just everything I enjoy. I’d love to spend more time writing in this world, but we’ll see where that goes…</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 038 Author Interview: Dawn Trowell Jones and &#8220;The Witch Road&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-author-interview-dawn-trowell-jones-and-the-witch-road/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 038]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We love our authors and are so excited when we get to chat with them.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15624 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/thuya-14-1505653-unsplash-300x218.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="218" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/thuya-14-1505653-unsplash-300x218.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/thuya-14-1505653-unsplash-768x559.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/thuya-14-1505653-unsplash-1024x745.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />We love our authors and are so excited when we get to chat with them. Today we&#8217;re thrilled to share a conversation with Dawn Trowell Jones, author of &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-witch-road/">The Witch Road</a>&#8221; from our recent Issue 038.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about the concept of a Waysegger. Is this character based on known folklore or totally of your own making?</strong></em></p>
<p>Dawn: It isn&#8217;t derived from any particular character in folklore, but folklore, being what it is, seeps into us. A Waysegger is an interloper. She arose out of the soup of my life experiences – a mentor/protector of a sort, though remote, dangerous, and not especially comforting to Tempie. The name Waysegger is a corruption of the middle Dutch word for soothsayer, <em>wijssegger</em>. In short, I made her up.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: In your story, the witch is a symbol of fear but also salvation. Can you speak a bit more on this dichotomy? What inspired you to write a story with a witch character with such complexity?</strong></em></p>
<p>Dawn: I&#8217;ll try. Tempie suppresses her fear of the witch, is even drawn to her, perhaps instinctively recognizing that the essence of what appears awful and fascinating about the Waysegger can also be found within herself. An internalized myth to Tempie, maybe, but a way of capitalizing on the power of myth to the people beyond the veil. This story is social science-fiction. An early beta-reader asked me why, given the title, Tempie and Cale don&#8217;t actually start on the road until so far into the story. I feel Tempie has always been on the Witch Road, a victim of it who owns it. This is because of the type of person she is and the disruptive way she thinks, tending towards the shamanistic, though in a childlike pragmatic way.</p>
<p>As for the other question: respect.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do you yourself know what&#8217;s in store for Tempie and Cale after they pass through the rift?</strong></em></p>
<p>Dawn: No, I don&#8217;t. It was important to leave the possibilities open. The rift scene at the end frames the entire story. When it does, the events that precede it reveal a hidden structure or plan – and the possibility of an organic deviation from the plan. Nested realities. Tempie is clever. I wanted her to be above average in intelligence and compulsively creative. Flawed but resilient. I wonder how the Waysegger&#8217;s people are making use of the girls they&#8217;ve collected, the ones the Town got rid of. And now a boy. If Tempie had lived a full life on the Fringe, even under the best of circumstances, which this wasn&#8217;t, exhaustion would likely have set in and crushed her. What role will she play in this shiny new world – an outsider, with a mind like that? I wanted the question to hang.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was your inspiration for this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Dawn: Oh, wow. Sometimes thoughts and experiences just simply condense into an idea that has no better way of expressing itself. But there were some pop influences, such as the cadence of an actor from Georgia, Scott Wilson, who passed away in 2018. This is the mayor&#8217;s speech. As I sit here thinking about your question, the character Antonia from Willa Cather&#8217;s <em>My Antonia</em> pops into mind – rather insistently. I see the influence now. It may help to know that Antonia&#8217;s fate angered me when I read it, more than twenty years ago. The donkey doll is a doll I&#8217;d always <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15625 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/james-coleman-666811-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/james-coleman-666811-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/james-coleman-666811-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/james-coleman-666811-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />wanted to make. There&#8217;s a three-hundred-year-old Gullah tradition of basket weaving on the coast of South Carolina. For the setting, I pulled from my childhood, adventures with friends, unsupervised, sometimes barefoot on scorching-hot sand, imagining witches or whatever in the dark overgrown places we couldn&#8217;t physically get to. My closest friend then had a younger brother. I have a younger sister. The conflicted sense of responsibility (and love) a child can feel for a younger sibling is hard to capture, but I wanted to try. Tempie&#8217;s family home was loosely modeled after an old hunting cabin my aunt used to own, right on the marsh, stifling and humid in the summer, eerily overgrown. Nothing but a round wooden room.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect of this story to write and why? What was the most enjoyable?</strong></em></p>
<p>Dawn: The most challenging? Straddling the light and dark. A child&#8217;s perspective. There&#8217;s more than one climax. The first turns on the failure of an idea. Capturing that moment was tough. In a way, this story is a simple tune played on top of noise, yet the noise belongs to the tune, feeds into it, and carries vital information. It was a difficult story to write.</p>
<p>Most enjoyable? I&#8217;d say it was when I got to the point where I&#8217;d added all I wanted to add and cut all I wanted to cut, and the story felt complete. I thought, &#8220;Now it must go out into the world, like Tempie, and survive on its own.&#8221; That felt great.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 038 Author Interview: Mary E. Lowd and &#8220;Looking for Sentience&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-author-interview-mary-e-lowd-and-looking-for-sentience/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 10:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 038]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s Tuesday and you know what that means &#8212; another interview with an author from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15614 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-517860-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-517860-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-517860-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />It&#8217;s Tuesday and you know what that means &#8212; another interview with an author from our current issue, Issue 038! Today we chat with Mary E. Lowd about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/looking-for-sentience/">Looking for Sentience</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The testing of sentience in robots is such a fascinating, debatable topic. How did you settle on some of the rules that Gerangelo refers to when determining sentience?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mary: I&#8217;ve been thinking about sentience since I was a kid and memorized Data&#8217;s poem, &#8220;Ode to Spot,&#8221; from <em>Star Trek: The Next Generation</em>. Data refers to his cat, Spot, as not being sentient (although, &#8220;a true and valued friend&#8221;) in the poem, and the android&#8217;s own sentience is famously debated in the episode, &#8220;The Measure of a Man.&#8221; In this way, <em>Star Trek: TNG</em> created a scale from Spot to Data, from non-sentient to sentient. And I&#8217;ve been thinking about it ever since.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what I&#8217;ve concluded: I don&#8217;t know where the line falls between Spot and Data. But I do know that both of them can express their desires to be treated decently, and if a creature expresses its desire to you &#8212; that you treat it decently &#8212; then you should. And part of treating a creature decently &#8212; it seems to me &#8212; is to respect what it knows about itself. If it says it&#8217;s sentient, then what right does anyone else have to disbelieve it? This is the entire concept behind the Turing Test &#8212; when you can&#8217;t tell the difference between non-sentient and sentient anymore, then maybe there isn&#8217;t one.</p>
<p><strong><em> LSQ: Gerangelo has a clear disdain for &#8220;organics.&#8221; In the world you&#8217;ve created in this story, do other sentient robots feel the same way? Or, to ask another way, do you see that as a common reaction once a robot achieves sentience? Why or why not?</em> </strong></p>
<p>Mary: Hah, oh my, this question amuses me, because Gerangelo is not representative of the other robots I write about at all. (Though, he may be my favorite.) Basically, when we program machines to do things, they do what we&#8217;ve programmed them to do. In the case of Gerangelo, a young, foolish, misanthropic roboticist programmed a robot to be her perfect soulmate. When she outgrew her snarky phase&#8230; he didn&#8217;t. And because he was sentient, she couldn&#8217;t do anything about it. Basically, he&#8217;s a life lesson that just keeps teaching: be careful what you program, because once your creation gets out of your hands, it may take on a life of its own. And in the case of Gerangelo, sue his creator for half of her robot emporium, set up a competing shop across the space station from her, and be a snarky thorn in her side for the rest of her life.</p>
<p>That said, most of the time, when people program robots (or computers, AI, etc.), they program them to serve a useful purpose, or put another way, to be helpful. And so, most of the robots I write about want &#8212; at a deep level &#8212; to be helpful.</p>
<p><em><strong> LSQ: The fact that Nancy is an organic, not a robot as Gerangelo has expected, sends a strong message of inclusivity; namely, that anything can become sentient and therefore should be free. Can you comment further on this theme? Did issues in today&#8217;s news influence this at all?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mary: My feelings on this issue are so strong that simple words fail me, and I end up writing <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15615 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-795965-unsplash-300x219.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="219" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-795965-unsplash-300x219.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-795965-unsplash-768x562.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/franck-v-795965-unsplash-1024x749.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />stories instead. But yes, the message of inclusivity is intentional, and yes, it relates to so many of the horrors in the news these days. If someone looks different, sounds different, or their body works differently, that&#8217;s not an excuse to deny their fundamental rights, their basic personhood. And no, those rights and that personhood do not extend to lumps of cells that have parasitically attached to a uterus any more than they extend to an idea for a computer program, drunkenly scrawled on a napkin at a restaurant.</p>
<p><em><strong> LSQ: What was your inspiration for this story? Have you written about AI before? Were there any challenges you encountered when writing this story?</strong> </em></p>
<p>Mary: I&#8217;ve been writing about Gerangelo and the sentience tests, off and on, for more than a decade. They both first appeared in my story, &#8220;My Fair Robot,&#8221; which was published at <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> five years ago. Since then, Gerangelo and Maradia (the roboticist who created him) have appeared in quite a few of my stories and are also featured in a novel that&#8217;s still seeking a home. Most notably, &#8220;The Three Laws of Social Robotics&#8221; just came out in the May/June issue of <em>Analog</em>, and I have a series of six stories about Maradia&#8217;s robots upcoming in <em>Daily Science Fiction</em>. However, if readers want something to sink their eyes into right now, I&#8217;ve put together a guide to where to find stories about them online here:  <a href="http://deepskyanchor.com/robot-stories/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://deepskyanchor.com/robot-stories/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1561141020570000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEZqvofyaOrPzWsF1I2KUa8oHs-pQ">http://deepskyanchor.com/robot-stories/</a></p>
<p>&#8220;Looking For Sentience,&#8221; in particular, was the result of watching my writing group&#8217;s reactions to my previous robot stories. They always wanted to know more about the sentience tests, and so I tried to delve more deeply into the question of what Gerangelo is looking for by showing him discovering sentience where he didn&#8217;t expect it.</p>
<p><em><strong> LSQ: Can you tell us more about being a &#8220;furry writer&#8221;?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mary: I never outgrew wanting to read stories about animals, and it turns out that I&#8217;m not the only one. Basically, furry fiction is about animals &#8212; that can mean anything from <em>Zootopia</em> (where animals replace humans) to <em>The Secret Life of Pets</em> (where we get in the heads of the animals at our feet). It&#8217;s kind of a meta-genre, since you can write any kind of story with animals as the main characters &#8212; sci-fi, fantasy, mystery, horror, romance, anything. But for some of us, when a story centers on animals, it&#8217;s more colorful, more fun, simply a better way to spend your time. So, I write about animals, because I love animals. And it turns out, there are a lot of us, and that&#8217;s amazing. I&#8217;ve found the furry writing community to be a wonderful, welcoming, supportive place &#8212; both as a writer and a reader. Anyone who wants to learn more about it should check out The Furry Writers&#8217; Guild:  <a href="https://furrywritersguild.com/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://furrywritersguild.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1561141020570000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE2qtlFPwUzsev0fiNgJg7OunFO9g">https://furrywritersguild.com/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 038 Author Interview: Johanna Staples-Ager and &#8220;The Extent&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-author-interview-johanna-staples-ager-and-the-extent/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 038]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 038 interview time! Today we chat with Johanna Staples-Ager about her short story &#8220;The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15572 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/mat-reding-1291579-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/mat-reding-1291579-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/mat-reding-1291579-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/mat-reding-1291579-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Issue 038 interview time! Today we chat with Johanna Staples-Ager about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-extent/">The Extent</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ:</em> <span class="im">Stories in the form of an epistolary are always fun, as they create definitive layers to plot and character, the most basic of which is the finder/reader of the documents and the author of the documents themselves. What made you choose this format for your story? </span></strong></p>
<p><strong>Johanna</strong>: &#8220;The Extent&#8221; started out as a list: Hair, Scars, Tattoos, Names, and so on. It was an obsession list, a list of objects and concepts and motifs I&#8217;ve become obsessed with in the process of writing a post-apocalyptic novel and reading large amounts post-apocalyptic fiction. But as I started expanding the list, exploring the meaning of each word, Annika&#8217;s voice started coming through, and I knew the process of definition was no longer my own. Clearly, my narrator wasn&#8217;t content to just define each word &#8212; she was in a bad place, and each subject, each thing offered a way out for her, a way out of that bad place. But was her story a cry for help? A rallying cry? A warning? Maybe all of the above, maybe none of the above. Either way, I knew her story was going to take her out of that bad place for good, and that her escape would ask extraordinary things of her as both a narrator and as an agent in her own life. As I spun the line of the story further, the flashcards and the found-document format of the story came in, grounding the story&#8217;s format as both a list and an act of defiance.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Most of Annika&#8217;s personal notes on the flash cards are in some way about personal identity and through them we see how it&#8217;s been stripped away from her and her fight to get it back. Can you tell us more about Annika&#8217;s character? What&#8217;s her backstory</span>?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Johanna</strong>: Annika Yang remains somewhat of a black box to me. I think this is partially because she&#8217;s writing to Smith, the very person who stripped away much of her identity, and partially because she&#8217;s a writer and someone who feels a lot, making her doubly protective of her selfhood. I do know that she&#8217;s good at survival, good at pushing herself, good at flying under people&#8217;s radar. She&#8217;s had a lot of time to put up walls between herself and the world, and she&#8217;s been treading the line between action and inaction for years, using passive as opposed to active defiance to stay sane. I&#8217;ve coded her as having a Chinese father and a white mother. I like to think that she grew up near the ocean, with her parents and her two younger sisters, filling notebooks with lists and doodles every day, sleeping in an old house that creaked every night, with a radio constantly dribbling out pronouncements of doom in the background. Maybe she liked history class in school before everything went wrong, liked diving into the truth underneath the biases presented in the classroom. Annika&#8217;s a little afraid of her own voice, indeed fiercely protective of it, and like many post-apocalyptic narrators, she could be almost anyone. But unlike the undifferentiated narrators of much post-apocalyptic sci-fi, I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s necessarily a bad thing. Even if Annika&#8217;s hidden many of the specifics of herself from Smith (and therefore the reader), she <i>owns </i>her voice &#8212; so I loved allowing her to keep secrets, in the same way that she lets Eden keep her secrets, too.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Scars, both physical and emotional, are an important motif in your story. What does this say about the dystopian future you&#8217;ve created and how it impacts your characters</span>?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Johanna</strong>: There&#8217;s a reason scars made it onto the obsession list. I tend to write what I&#8217;m afraid of, or what makes me angry, and move from that place of anger or fear towards some kind of emotional release. Scars fascinate me particularly because they can hold so many emotions &#8212; anger and fear being the usual, but also pity, love, pride, the entire spectrum of emotions that can arc through a person when they&#8217;ve been hurt. They&#8217;re often used as a shortcut to a Dark Backstory in fiction, which I find a cheap under-utilization of their narrative power. Especially as I dive into dystopia, a genre where scars are the norm, I want to find the ways that people live with themselves and their scars &#8212; how they move beyond anger and fear to something else, something that can at the very least be carried. I want to write not necessarily what created a particular physical or emotional scar &#8212; although that&#8217;s an important aspect of learning how to carry it &#8212; but about all the little things that a character does to make it easier to live with that scar. For Annika, writing is one of those things. Many of my POV characters who have scars &#8212; and in my dystopia, they all do &#8212; tend to be artists in some way, allowing them to create that critical emotional release for themselves.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">What was the most challenging aspect of this story to write and why? What was the most enjoyable part</span>?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Johanna</strong>: The most challenging aspect was working in hints of Annika&#8217;s backstory, the memories <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15573 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/sonic-panji-1376065-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/sonic-panji-1376065-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/sonic-panji-1376065-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />that had been stripped away from her, the things she kept most secret. That&#8217;s one of the funny things about writing and reading dystopian fiction: dark, awful things can become commonplace, while lighter and happier things, any memories of goodness, can become almost more painful than the present itself, both to read and to write. It&#8217;s very easy for a post-apocalypse to contain only nihilism and abandoned buildings, and it&#8217;s hard to make any good memories of the pre-apocalypse a rounder flavor than bitter or saccharine. The most enjoyable part of writing &#8220;The Extent&#8221; was the action, the scene in which Annika and Eden are stumbling four-legged and bleeding towards the surface. Once I had done all the exposition, the careful tweaking of the setup, the &#8220;Blood&#8221; section flowed out of me easily. Even though it contains, like most of the rest of the story, terrible things, it was also a moment of great release for both me and Annika, and stayed almost entirely intact throughout revision.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">This story just touches on what seems to be a very complex world in terms of war, politics, geographical/geological/<wbr />ecological changes, etc. Do you have plans to revisit this world in the future</span>?</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>Johanna</strong>: Yes, definitely. This particular world comes from the novel I&#8217;m working on. As soon as I knew that the narrator of &#8220;The Extent&#8221; was in a bad place, I took the almost reflexive shortcut of making that bad place Black Mile, the underground military school I already carried in my mind. I intended to use the story as an opportunity to explore Black Mile and the potential of all the things on my obsession list. I&#8217;m looking forward to exploring more concrete exposition of this world in my novel&#8217;s third-person format.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
