<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Waifs, Wolves &amp; Warriors &#8211; Women in Greek Mythology &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/warriors-women-in-greek-mythology/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 22:20:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Promiscuous</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/promiscuous/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Suz Thackston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 12:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Waifs, Wolves & Warriors - Women in Greek Mythology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26717#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=26717</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The gaggle of girls runs shrieking from the weaving room, freed from their efforts to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><br />The gaggle of girls runs shrieking from the weaving room, freed from their efforts to learn the arts of spinning and fabric-making, wild with excitement at having time to play before sundown. The slanting rays of the sun pour through the open doorway and light the figure of an old woman, wrapped in a dark robe.<br /><br />Little Elara hesitates on the doorstep. She looks back at the huddled figure, so still by the banked fireplace. Casting a longing glance at her friends who are already kicking a wooden ball back and forth, she creeps back to stand in front of the old woman.<br /><br />“Madam,” she murmurs. “Can I bring you anything? Would you like some water or wine?”<br /><br /><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26778 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/danie-franco-CeZypKDceQc-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/danie-franco-CeZypKDceQc-unsplash-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/danie-franco-CeZypKDceQc-unsplash-681x1024.jpg 681w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/danie-franco-CeZypKDceQc-unsplash-768x1155.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/danie-franco-CeZypKDceQc-unsplash-1021x1536.jpg 1021w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/danie-franco-CeZypKDceQc-unsplash-1362x2048.jpg 1362w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/danie-franco-CeZypKDceQc-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1702w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" />Dark eyes peer at her. The old woman is silent for a few moments. The girl wonders if she is dumb, or addled as the very old so often are. She has been told to stay away from the crone, but her heart is moved by the solitude of the old woman, who rarely stirs from her spot by the fire, spinning endless skeins of wool into fine thread. <br /><br />Finally the woman speaks. “I would welcome a cup of wine, dear girl. But I would value your company more. Will you sit with me a while?”<br /><br />Elara darts a glance toward the kitchen where the women are working. “Madam, I do not dare.” Her voice drops to a whisper. “But I will bring you wine, if it pleases you.” At a nod from the crone, she runs to the wineskin and pours a cup, watering it half-and-half as her mother has taught her, and carrying it carefully back to the old woman. <br /><br />“Thank you,” says the crone. She drinks, sets the cup down and adds, “If ever you have the desire to hear a tale, girl, come sit with me. But now go play with your friends.”<br /><br />Elara ducks her head and scampers outside. She releases the breath she didn’t know she was holding. But the whisper of laughter underlying the creaky old voice stays with her. She finds herself wondering, throughout the next few days, about the promised tale. It feels like a tickle on the nape of her neck.<br /><br />A day comes when the adult women are occupied with a birthing, and the other girls take advantage of the lack of supervision to explore the nearby hills. Elara slips away from them and seeks out the crone by the fire. She tiptoes forward.<br /><br />“Madam, it is I, Elara. I would like to hear your tale, if it would please you to tell me.”<br /><br />The old eyes glint. A claw-like hand emerges from the dark robes and indicates that Elara should draw up a stool. The girl complies, casting a quick glance out at the bright afternoon. But the desire for the tale is too compelling, and she settles by the crone’s knees, looking up expectantly into the creased face. <br /><br />“I was an Athenian princess. Didn’t know that, did you? You think princesses are all fine silks and fancy hairstyles, and always always young. And so I was, little one, as heedless and empty-headed as you. But my sisters and I were aware of the dangers of being part of the royal family of King Erektheus and Queen Praxithea. We knew our father barely considered us, but that our mother treasured us; so we swore an oath that if one of us died of unnatural causes, the rest would commit suicide, bringing down the curse of the Erinyes upon our father. We foolishly thought that our oath would encourage our mother to protect us.<br /><br />“Foolish indeed, as my father sacrificed my poor little sister, aptly named Kthonia, in order to win some stupid war or other. Two of my sisters went through with the pact. I did not, as I was already married to Kephalos and out of the palace before my murderous papa did the vile deed. For that, at least, I can thank my husband.<br /><br />“And marriage to Kephalos was happy, for a time. He was besotted with me, and I loved whetting both our appetites to the point of frenzy. I even extracted a promise from him that he would remain faithful to me, and I to him. No hardship on my part―he was skilled. Don’t look so puzzled, girl, you’ll understand soon enough. <br /><br />“But what I didn’t realize was that he felt there were built-in exceptions; slave boys and girls, of course, but others too, so long as they weren’t part of the Athenian aristocracy. Well, I didn’t see things quite his way. I enjoyed playthings too, when he was away and I was bored. I kept my oath exactly as he kept his. <br /><br />“Some tales say that he left for eight years to test me. Foolish tales, believed by foolish people. He did go away for several years, ‘exploring’ as he called it―another word for pirating. I didn’t mind. He’d come home with plenty of gifts for me, and if he strayed the marriage bed while he was gone, so did I. Equally foolish is the story that he disguised himself as my lover, Pteleon. Men like to think that all women are as stupid as they. He walked in on me enjoying myself with Pteleon, who was not only young and vigorous, but had brought me a very pretty golden tiara as a gift. <br /><br />“It was probably the sight of me sitting astride Pteleon, the crown askew on my auburn locks and Pteleon’s hands locked on my breasts, that set my poor husband off. Had we been able to spin polite fictions to each other, we would have settled back in nicely together. But with the whole household aware of the homecoming scene, he had perforce to roar and flail and publicly repudiate me. Before long he took up with a girl so lovely it soon became legend that he had been seduced by the dawn goddess herself. I don’t begrudge him his Eos. Hindsight has shown me that I didn’t give him a way to save face, and men have done stupider things out of wounded pride. <br /><br />“Nonetheless, there was no remaining in Athens for me. I set out for Krete ‘for my health’ (which was more literally true than I cared to think about) and to visit Queen Pasiphae on the tenuous pretext of a largely imaginary distant relationship. Pasiphae was nobody’s fool. She took one look at me in all my youthful glory and packed me off to the temple of Artemis on the far tip of the island, a safe distance from the palace and King Minos, buried in the society of holy virgins. <br /><br />“Or so she thought.<br /><br />“Word reached Minos that a vibrant young priestess was hunting the forests around the Artemis<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26780 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/engin-akyurt-C4AjJTsG8Hs-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/engin-akyurt-C4AjJTsG8Hs-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/engin-akyurt-C4AjJTsG8Hs-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/engin-akyurt-C4AjJTsG8Hs-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/engin-akyurt-C4AjJTsG8Hs-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/engin-akyurt-C4AjJTsG8Hs-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> temple, and he wasted no time investigating for himself. There’s some twaddle about me curing him of ejaculating scorpions and serpents, and it’s true that some of his offspring with his wedded wife were horrifying. All I did was employ a method of prophylaxis known for generations among the women of my family. A drawstring purse of thin flexible toadskin inserted…..well, never mind that, girl. Suffice it to say, we had many a merry meeting in the shaded woodlands of Krete, and no embarrassing outcomes.<br /><br />“ Minos was, like my husband, besotted with me. He did give me rich gifts, and shrewdly bestowed some particularly generous largesse upon the temple and its head priestess. Eyes were judiciously averted when I was ‘out hunting’ for long stretches of time, and no one questioned whence came my beautiful bronze-tipped javelin or Laelaps, my Kritikos Lagonikos, a hunting hound of unparalleled talent. <br /><br />“But all good things come to an end, and Pasiphae had spies everywhere. A time came when I perceived that it would be prudent to leave Krete swiftly and secretly, and so in due time I slipped back into Athens. <br /><br />“There was a fair bit of curiosity about my javelin and my elegant hound as I traveled back home. As a lark, I told my fellow travelers on the ship to Athens that my treasures were a gift from Artemis. Since I’d been an Artemisian priestess for so long, I had no trouble making it sound authentic. I must have succeeded because I hear that story repeated still. Who knows? Maybe there’s something to it. I wouldn’t put it past the Arrow-Pouring One to have put it into my lover’s head to give me divinely inspired gifts. <br /><br />“Laelaps was fiercely devoted to me. Her last act, years later, was to pull down a magnificent buck I’d speared with my javelin. She licked my cheek with her blood-stained muzzle and fell dead at my feet. <br /><br />“But the fiction that the javelin couldn’t miss was based on the simple fact that I was an excellent huntress. I rarely missed my mark, and it was easily forgotten when I did.<br /><br />“My years as a huntress altered my appearance. I no longer looked like a pampered Athenian princess and matron. I was lean and wiry, with sun-bleached hair and tanned skin and bright eyes, not like the soft, dull creatures so prized in the city. After passing Kephalos in the agora and he not even recognizing me, it occurred to me to play a prank on my dear husband. I cut my hair, bound my breasts and put on the attire of a young man. I contrived to meet him in the woods, me with my Laelaps and javelin. <br /><br />“You’ve heard that he tried to purchase my Artemisian gifts from me? And that in my guise as a young man I demanded instead that he bed me?<br /><br />“No? Well, pass by that for now. The truth of the matter is that he only pretended fascination with my javelin and hound because he was, on a level he didn’t understand, fascinated with me. He didn’t understand why he felt so drawn to the lithe hunter he saw before him, not recognizing the half-forgotten wiles I’d used to seduce him as his wife. He still couldn’t resist a sidelong glance through lidded lashes, or a particular roll of hip and buttock. He didn’t come reluctant to my bed, he was a maddened bull. When he got me naked and I revealed myself to him, it was touch-and-go whether he would mount me or murder me. <br /><br />“But, as you see, I’m still here.<br /><br />“Don’t look so alarmed, girl. You’re near old enough to know about what happens between men and women. What no one tells girls like you is how much fun it can be.<br /><br />“Still and all, after my adventures I could not settle back into the cloying cocoon of domesticity. This time I planned better; I amassed a small fortune in small, transportable treasure—mostly jewels—in the year or so I spent with my husband. I paid well for spies to keep me informed of his activities, so I wasn’t surprised when he began a dalliance with yet another in his long string of dawn-hued beauties, his Eos girls. <br /><br />After securing my hidden retirement here in this blessedly remote deme, I packed what I needed and hid my belongings and a horse near the main road. Dressed in my young man attire, my spear and hound in hand, I crept to the woodland glade where Kephalos trysted with his light-o’-love. I waited silently until the girl moved into the trees for a call of nature. In a trice I had her bound and gagged, a fresh-killed fawn left in her stead—a common bardic stand-in for dead girls— and I whisked her off into the night.<br /><br />“Kephalos had a lot of explaining to do when his story changed rapidly from a missing girl to a missing wife and her missing magical gifts, not to mention the dead fawn. Especially when the girl, whom I left loosely tied near the road, miraculously reappeared with her own version of the story. I have to admire how he ended up spinning it. Making me out to be jealous of Eos, and him accidentally killing me with my own weapons, was a masterstroke of narcissism. Especially casting me as an innocent little fawn. I hear he shed real tears over his ‘mistake’. A rascal, my husband, but overall an entertaining one. Sometimes I even miss him.<br /><br />“It didn’t take long for the myth-machine to inflate the tale that I had been hiding in the bushes and that Kephalos slew me in error, using my own javelin and hound. It didn’t take long for me to figure out what a gift my ‘death’ was to me. Had Kephalos known how much easier he made it for me to disappear, it would have tweaked his nose, but I’m grateful to him. <br /><br />“I was surprised to find that the quiet life here suited me. There were lovers when I wanted them, and none who wanted to own me. The women are smart enough to recognize my value and a few have become friends. I worried for a while that Kephalos might decide that my death being a sure thing would benefit him, and that he would look for me. But I hear he fell off a cliff quite a few years back. Probably drunk.<br /><br />“And in all these years, no one has ever heard the entirety of my tale. Minos and Pasiphae and even old Kephalos, they all have their stories, growing in color and absurdity with every passing year, but few sing tales of Prokris. And when they do, it’s only as my path crossed those of the more famous.<br /><br />“But you, little Elara. You have the truth of it, right from the Slut herself. My only fault was<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26781 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ryan-spencer-XGKaRnWjv1c-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ryan-spencer-XGKaRnWjv1c-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ryan-spencer-XGKaRnWjv1c-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ryan-spencer-XGKaRnWjv1c-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ryan-spencer-XGKaRnWjv1c-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ryan-spencer-XGKaRnWjv1c-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/ryan-spencer-XGKaRnWjv1c-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /> refusing to let all those men tell me what I could and couldn’t do. They won in the end with their lying accounts of me, but I regret nothing.”<br /><br />Elara sat motionless. The old woman lapsed into silence and closed her eyes. Finally the girl rose and slipped outside, just before the women returned, laughing and chattering in high spirits after the successful birth. Elara did not seek out the other girls. She meandered into the woods, looking for somewhere quiet to think about what she had just heard. <br /><br />* * * * * * *<br /><br />Prokris is a name that shows up several times in Greek myth, so it’s anybody’s guess as to whether she was extremely promiscuous or that there are many girls named Prokris who got conflated and their myths conjoined. Accounts vary as to whether Prokris or her husband, Kephalos, strayed first, or when and how she got her magical spear and hunting dog, or just what happened in Krete with Minos, but there are enough common threads to weave together a coherent storyline without straying far from the source materials. <br /><br />She was an Athenian princess, third daughter of the famous Erektheus and his queen, Praxithea. Two of her sisters died in a suicide pact, after their father sacrificed another sister, Kthonia, in order to fulfil a prophecy that would allow him victory in battle. Lucky Prokris was already married to Kephalos and escaped their fate. <br /><br />There are quite a few versions of just how Prokris and Kephalos came to split up, but whoever gets the blame, the cause is infidelity or suspicion of it. They seem to have been very much in love, to the point of swearing fidelity to each other, something most men would not have considered (and Kephalos probably had an out for sleeping with slaves, or boys.) Maybe Kephalos stayed away for years to test his wife, seduced her while in disguise and then accidentally killed her after they reconciled. Perhaps Prokris listened to malicious gossip, suspected her husband of infidelity and spied on him. Hearing him call to a breeze, not to a lover, to cool him off after a heated hunt, she realized her mistake. Kephalos heard a rustling in the bushes as she made her way to him, thought she was a wild beast and killed her. Some say the dawn goddess Eos fell in love with handsome Kephalos and seduced him, so he tried to blame Prokris for infidelity to assuage his own guilt. Maybe she fled to Artemis, who initially rejected her because of her non-virgin status, but relented and gifted her with a javelin that always found its mark and a hunting dog who always brought down its prey. Others say she made her way to Krete, where she cured Minos of a particularly nasty genital issue that caused him to ejaculate scorpions and snakes, and that he was the one who gave her the nice presents. <br /><br />Sophokles wrote a play entitled ‘Prokris’ which would have given us a cohesive narrative, but, sadly, it is one of many of his plays which has been entirely lost.<br /><br />One thing is certain, no matter which version you pick, and that is the ongoing theme in Greek myth of women’s fidelity being both ever-suspect and of supreme importance. Prokris gains a slight advantage over many of her promiscuous mythic sisters in that in at least a few versions she doesn’t die horribly.<br /><br />But some authors just couldn’t resist. Pherekydes of Athens in the oldest source available, and the prolific Ovid (who wrote her story twice and killed her off each time), both claim that poor Kephalos unwittingly spears his wife, sometimes with the very javelin she gifted to him, and that she dies in his arms.<br /><br />Just as good Greek women are supposed to do. <br /><br /><br /><br />The Greek Myths by Robert Graves, Chapter 89 ‘The Loves of Minos.’<br />Women of Classical Mythology by Robert E. Bell, Pages 381 and 382.<br />https://www.theoi.com/Olympios/ArtemisFavour.html#Prokris<br />https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Procris<br />https://www.greekmythology.com/Myths/Mortals/Procris/procris.html<br />https://mythologystories.wordpress.com/2014/03/07/greece-9/<br />http://01greekmythology.blogspot.com/2014/12/king-minos-and-procris.html<br />https://www.shmoop.com/study-guides/mythology/cephalus-procris<br /><br /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daughters of Ares</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/daughters-of-ares/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Suz Thackston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 11:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Waifs, Wolves & Warriors - Women in Greek Mythology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25869#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=25869</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Deina wheels her battle mare in a tight circle and fires a rapid volley of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Deina wheels her battle mare in a tight circle and fires a rapid volley of arrows into the ragged loop of Scythian soldiers bearing down on her. One by one, they fall, all but the last who wrenches his head aside in the nick of time and flees, looking over his shoulder with wide white eyes. Deina reaches back to her quiver, but it is empty. Cursing, she claps her heels into the mare’s ribs. Red Karneia bares her teeth and runs down the foot soldier. He screams as he goes down under the slashing hoofs, a scream which dissolves like the jelly he has become. <br /><br /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-25924 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/pexels-thiago-schlemper-6432651-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/pexels-thiago-schlemper-6432651-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/pexels-thiago-schlemper-6432651-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/pexels-thiago-schlemper-6432651-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/pexels-thiago-schlemper-6432651-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/pexels-thiago-schlemper-6432651-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/pexels-thiago-schlemper-6432651-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Too soon for Deina the battle is over. The acolytes scour the field, finishing off enemy survivors and collecting spent weapons. Deina sees the other riders gathering, raises her fist to her sister warriors and gallops to join them. She finds her partner cleaning a sword cut on her horse’s flank, the big black standing hipshot and relaxed under her ministrations. <br /><br />Areia grins up at her through the sweat, blood ,and brains spattered on her face. “Saw that last maneuver,” she says, applying ointment to her mount’s wound. “Almost like you’re trying to impress Queen Penthesilea. Show off.”<br /><br />Deina nudges Karneia into a tight trot, circling the black, who pins his ears. Areia scratches his withers, glaring at Deina.<br /><br />“I’m leading him back to camp,” she says. “Have some hot wine ready for me when I get there.” Deina salutes and kicks Karneia into a snorting gallop back to the base camp.<br /><br />As the acolyte girls and male slaves heat baths and prepare food for the Amazons, the warriors lounge about the campfires, cleaning their weapons and recounting the day’s battle. The Scythian scum would think twice before attempting to invade Lycia again. Areia’s laugh rings through the camp as she tells of Deina’s decisive final assault.<br /><br />“There were at least a dozen, coming at her from all sides, scuttling with their little swords. Most of Deina’s arrows were spent, and I thought she would go to her javelin or sling. But, quick as a cat, she fitted an arrow to her bow.” Areia leaps to her feet to act out the scene. “Ffffttt! Ffffttt! One by one, faster than the eye could follow, she put an arrow straight into the eye or through the throat of each doomed one. Then she tossed her bow and empty quiver at the last fool and sent that hell bitch mare of hers after him. Karneia danced in his blood, the same color as her hide, while Deina laughed.”<br /><br />Deina, snorting at how her lover takes liberties with a good tale, starts to remonstrate and then catches herself. Nothing wrong with a little fame and glory. As the other Amazons raise their goblets to her, she stands and takes an exaggerated bow. The camp erupts into a frenzy of cheering. Finally, the warriors let their servants lead them to hot baths and hot food.<br /><br />Deina and Areia, bathed, fed, and exhausted, retire to their tent. Deina coaxes Areia down into their sleeping furs, pauses as she sees Areia’s eyes widen. The light from the campfire flickers through the opened flap of the tent. As Deina turns to look, the firelight is blocked by the massive form of Penthesilea, almost as broad as she is tall. She enters silently and stands stock still inside the tent, her expression invisible in the shadows.<br /><br />The warriors kick themselves free from the blankets. Areia drops to a knee, head bowed, right fist across her chest, Deina a heartbeat behind her. The silence stretches, grows interminable. Deina flicks a quick glance up at the queen, gulps, then sighs in relief as she sees white teeth gleam in a grin. <br /><br />The Amazon queen’s face seems carved of smooth granite, wide and flat and hard. Her still, small eyes rarely blink. Those eyes can freeze a foe with the potency of an adder, but now they crinkle in the corners as she sits on the sleeping furs. The two warriors shift to make room for her. They are tall women, but crouched before the immensity of the queen, they seem like children. <br /><br />“You fought well today.” Penthesilea’s voice is curiously soft. Some strain to hear her in war councils, but on the battlefield her roar makes the ravens leap into the air in fear. Deina and Areia exchange a wide-eyed glance, suppressing their delight, then shift their gaze back to the queen. She falls silent. The warriors wait. They know their queen. She speaks seldom and never without cause. <br /><br />“You have both borne children for the tribe,” she says finally. They nod. <br /><br />When the silence lengthens again, Deina says, “I have borne two sons and a daughter, and Areia three promising girls. We both use the same Gargarean man. He has proved a reliable stud, giving us strong healthy babies. My older son has been returned to his father. The other, my youngest child, is still with his wet nurse.” <br /><br />Penthesilea nods. “I have petitioned our father Ares and consulted the oracles. After your performance today, it is time to tell you what I have decided. You are both hereby released from the onus of producing children for our tribe. We have two dozen horses suitable for battle training who will arrive by moondark. In addition to your regular duties, you are both in charge of evaluating and training them.” She stands, her leather creaking. “I am proud to have women such as you in my ranks.”<br /><br />Deina and Areia drop to salute, barely repressing their whoops of delight. But before the queen can leave their tent, running feet can be heard approaching. The two warriors sit back on their heels as an acolyte, her young face flushed with exertion and excitement, bursts into the tent.<br /><br />“My queen,” she squeaks, then catches herself and falls to one knee, right fist to left shoulder. “I’m sorry,” she gasps, but Penthesilea leans down from her height and tips the girl’s face up with one finger.<br /><br />“Take a breath, child,” she says. The acolyte, almost a teenager, gulps and pushes her wild black hair away from her face. She takes a shuddering breath and meets the queen’s gaze. <br /><br />“Your majesty,” she starts again. “There is an envoy from Troy. King Priam has sent word that he seeks your aid in the battle on the beaches! The envoy requests your presence immediately.” Excitement creeps back into her voice as she delivers her message. Her dark eyes sparkle.<br /><br />Penthesilea steps outside the tent, the girl close on her heels, and draws herself to her full height. She towers against the starry sky. Deina and Areia follow and stand at attention. <br /><br />“So,” muses the queen, in that deceptively gentle voice. “The men are realizing they cannot stand alone. Let us see what they offer in return for the aid of the Daughters of Ares.”<br /><br />They stride together through the sleeping camp toward the light of the queen’s tent. <br /><br />* * * * * *<br /><br />Wonder Woman showed up in DC Comics in 1941. Since then there have been many characters <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-25925 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Wonder_Woman-195x300.jpg" alt="" width="195" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Wonder_Woman-195x300.jpg 195w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Wonder_Woman.jpg 255w" sizes="(max-width: 195px) 100vw, 195px" />based on Amazons in popular fiction, from Xena Warrior Princess and the muscular, curvy heroines of Frank Frazetta right up to the explosion of women warriors so prevalent in modern fantasy and science fiction. <br /><br />The Amazons were not figures of admiration in Greek mythology. Fear tinged with awe is as close as the ancient writers came to praise for this mythical tribe, which has no proven historicity. There is, however, plenty of evidence of potential inspirations, including <a href="https://www.science.org/news/2020/01/archaeologists-unearth-graves-ancient-warrior-women-russia">this grave site</a> in western Russia from 2020. <br /><br />While much of the <em>Iliad</em> is sprung from Homer’s vivid imagination, even more of it has been later proven to have historical basis. The stories of the Amazons are gaining in factuality as archaeology continues to make new discoveries. <br /><br />The Greek myths inevitably depict females who battle males as monstrous, unnatural, and fearsome. In their tales they are slain or resexualized into wives, at which point their stories virtually end.</p>
<p>Because the thoughts and reactions of women were rarely explored in ancient Greek writings, we can’t say for sure how they received the tales of their forbidding—and forbidden—sisters. But anyone who has known or been a little girl can find it extremely likely that, through the vast span of ages, there has been a lot of &#8220;Let’s pretend we’re Amazons!&#8221; played around hearths and hills, long before cultures found such games acceptable.<br /><br />When Wonder Woman came out it was inconceivable that women would take on combat roles in the U.S. military. Today women represent 16% of the enlisted forces and 19% of the officer corps.<br /><br />Like most Greek genealogies, the birth of the Amazons has a few different sources. The most common one tells us that they are descended from Ares, the god of war, and Harmonia, a nymph associated with harmony and concord. They give birth to Otrere, the first Amazon queen. Other authors claim Otrere is the consort of Ares and the mother by him of Penthesilea and Hippolyta, two of the most famous Amazon queens. <br /><br />It would be fascinating to see the influence of Harmonia explored in the development of myths about the Amazons. <br /><br />Hmmmm……….<br /><br /><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazons#">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amazons#</a><br /><a href="https://www.worldhistory.org/amazon/#:~:text=In%20Greek%20mythology%2C%20the%20Amazons,Themiskyra%20on%20the%20Black%20Sea">https://www.worldhistory.org/amazon/#:~:text=In%20Greek%20mythology%2C%20the%20Amazons,Themiskyra%20on%20the%20Black%20Sea</a><br /><a href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/Amazon-Greek-mythology">https://www.britannica.com/topic/Amazon-Greek-mythology</a><br /><a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/amazon-women-there-any-truth-behind-myth-180950188/">https://www.smithsonianmag.com/history/amazon-women-there-any-truth-behind-myth-180950188/</a><br /><a href="https://www.theoi.com/Heroine/AmazonPenthesileia.html">https://www.theoi.com/Heroine/AmazonPenthesileia.html</a><br /><a href="https://www.theoi.com/Olympios/AresFavour.html">https://www.theoi.com/Olympios/AresFavour.html</a><br /><a href="https://www.theoi.com/Olympios/AresFamily.html#Amazones">https://www.theoi.com/Olympios/AresFamily.html#Amazones</a> <br /><br /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LIttle Bears</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/little-bears/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/little-bears/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Suz Thackston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Waifs, Wolves & Warriors - Women in Greek Mythology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25373#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=25373</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Khloe hides her toy bow and arrow in the folds of her saffron gown, glancing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25512 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/arrow-161517_1280-268x300.png" alt="" width="268" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/arrow-161517_1280-268x300.png 268w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/arrow-161517_1280-915x1024.png 915w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/arrow-161517_1280-768x859.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/arrow-161517_1280.png 1144w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Khloe hides her toy bow and arrow in the folds of her saffron gown, glancing down the line of fidgeting girls to where her mother stands watching. Khloe is supposed to give up her childish weapons as an offering to Artemis Agrotera, the Huntress, during this Brauronia ritual, as a symbol of her approaching adulthood. But Khloe is hoping to keep at least one arrow, a secret symbol of her unspoken hope. Her brothers laugh at her for her fierceness, her wildness, her love of playing the goddess during pretend hunts. They called her ‘Arktos’, or Little Bear, long before she was old enough to dance the bear dance at the temple in Brauron.<br />Her sharp gaze fastens on one of the little girls who is holding a doll and weeping silently, big bright tears coursing down her plump cheeks. <em>That one is too young for this. She is still a baby, wanting her dolls and her mother. Only girls who are brave and strong should dance the arkteia and wear the bearskin gown.</em><br />Khloe is proud that she has been selected for service to Artemis at the Brauron temple for a year before returning to her family for marriage and full adulthood, a service that begins today. Her feet begin to shuffle as she thinks about the ancient, feral ritual about to begin. She will don the bear mask and take on the aspect of the frightening beast, growling and swatting at the other Little Bears who will prowl the sanctuary with her. <br />Khloe harbors a secret hope that Artemis herself will appear to her during her year of service, will shoot her with a divine silver arrow and transform her from an ordinary mortal girl into an oreiad. Joining the band of mountain nymphs who run, hunt, play and swim in Artemis’ train seems to Khloe a far better fate than being married off to produce fat, squalling babies for a lumpish husband. <br />Her nimble fingers separate a toy arrow from the rest and slide it into the leggings she wears under her bear-dress. She will make the offering to the goddess as is proper, but she will keep this symbol of her worthiness to serve Artemis more directly. And permanently.<br /><br /><br />Phoebe fidgets in her bright yellow dress, clutching her toy bear in one hand. She is not afraid of the bear dance, nor of leaving her favorite toy at the feet of Artemis’ statue. She feels at home among the animals who belong to the Potnia Theron, the Mistress of Beasts. It is the other girls who alarm her, and the priestesses and family members who are here to observe the rites and make sure they are properly carried out. Phoebe knows most of the girls standing in the line in their yellow robes, but rules and rites are difficult for her to remember. She is afraid of making a mistake, of making a spectacle of herself, of censorious eyes piercing her, of being slapped—or worse, shunned.<br />Phoebe is one of the older girls taking part in the ritual, at almost twelve while most of the others are around ten, with a few as young as five or six. She pleaded with her mother, who interceded with her father, to let her stay a little kore for another year, then another. Her mother understands, as few adults do, the difficulties Phoebe has with interacting in groups and following specific rules as the ritual requires. But she cannot put off any longer her participation in the bear dance, the first step out of the innocence and ferity of her childhood, overseen by Artemis. <br />Phoebe’s throat is dry. She glances along the line of girls and catches the eye of Khloe, another of the older girls. Khloe winks at her and makes a fist—<em>Be strong!</em>—and Phoebe lifts her chin. Is she not the best at acting out the ritual and comic dramas in her village? Is she not the one whom the other children seek out to learn about the animals in their region, since she loves and observes the wild creatures whenever she can escape her duties? Is she not known for being a girl to whom anyone can turn for comfort, friendship and advice?<br />She smiles back at Khloe, then glances down at her shabby, dilapidated cloth bear, made for her by her mother when she was a baby. She hugs it to her, squeezes her eyes shut, then opens them wide and lets the bear dangle from her fingertips. She will be a brave and fierce arktos in the dance. She will give up her toy to the goddess. She will perform the ritual actions as expected and move from kore (little girl), to parthenos (young virgin), in preparation for becoming a nymphe (girl ready for marriage), then a gyne (married woman).<br /><br />Ismene holds her spinning top loosely as she watches the musicians ready their drums and<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25509 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/goddess-2774132_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/goddess-2774132_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/goddess-2774132_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/goddess-2774132_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/goddess-2774132_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/goddess-2774132_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> double flutes for the arkteia. She has enjoyed studying the action of the toy and observing the criteria that govern its spinning motion, but she is ready to give it up. She knows that Artemis Phosphoros, the goddess who illuminates the world with the light of knowledge, will present her with more intricate and fascinating things to study and from which to learn. Ismene loves the way each new facet of comprehension informs and even alters earlier stages of learning. She never tires of the process.<br />Ismene sometimes wishes she were a boy and could attend school. The tidbits of philosophy and science she coaxes out of her brothers fascinate her. But her mother, with her bright eyes that miss nothing, has gently encouraged Ismene to teach herself to observe, experiment, disassemble and create with the objects in her everyday life. Ismene has learned to cloak her ongoing analyses within the accepted, and therefore ignored, activities of women and to add to her store of knowledge without bringing upon herself the censure of the men. She has no doubt that she can continue her path of self-enlightenment through marriage and motherhood. <br />Ismene is interested to discover the knowledge couched with the rites, soon to be revealed, and the new opportunities that may be available to her as a parthenos that were not as a kore. <br /><br />As the music begins, each girl steps forward in her bright yellow krokoton and lays her offering at the feet of the statue of Artemis. They file past the altar, each accepting a basket of figs from the Brauron temple head priestess. Followed by the mothers, aunts, grandmothers and priestesses, they move into the sanctuary where they will don the bear masks and perform the arkteia. After this and other ritual actions, they will shed their ‘bear suits’, both masks and saffron gowns, and move into the next stage of their advancing maturity.<br /><br />* * * * * * * * * * * *<br /><br />Brauron was not the only site of bear-focused initiation of young girls in ancient Greece, simply the one best recorded. The ritual taming of the feral nature of girls took place in many forms. The Ortheia festival in Sparta tells of girls wearing the masks of Gorgons while boys were whipped until blood flowed. <br />Artemis rules over the wild and dangerous natural world, the primal place from which we all come and which we all carry within us. She reminds us that the ferocity of animals pulses only skin-deep beneath our veneer of civilization. Walls, lights and technology give us a facade of safety, but the bear is always lurking, prowling outside the comfort of community as well as within our own psyches. <br />Little girls have easy access to this casual ferocity until they are trained to ignore it. The initiation rites disclose the unease with which humans attempt to distance ourselves from the danger of living in and being part of the world, a world where death can come without warning, even to the young and innocent.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25511 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woman-3664231_1280-300x188.png" alt="" width="300" height="188" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woman-3664231_1280-300x188.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woman-3664231_1280-1024x641.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woman-3664231_1280-768x481.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/woman-3664231_1280.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> <br />Artemis is a liminal goddess, present at birth and dealing death. The garments of women who died in childbirth were offered to Artemis at the Brauronia festival.<br />The Little Bears, the Arktoi, did not leave behind the protection of the goddess, not until their marriage, when they moved formally from Artemis’ sphere to that of Hera. But it represented their first step away from being little girls, free of the constraints that maturity brings, and also terribly vulnerable to the accidents, predations and illnesses which took so many young children right up to modern times.<br />It is fitting that little girls who died before reaching adulthood, as well as women who died in labor, were thought to have been pierced with the silver arrows of the Huntress. <br /><br />Cult of Artemis at Brauron &#8211; Wikipedia<br /><br />https://medium.com/@LoaLight/arktoi-the-little-bears-of-artemis-8e4df70798cf<br /><br />Callisto: GreekMythology.com.<br /><br />https://www.greekmythology.com/Myths/Mortals/Iphigenia/iphigenia.html<br />https://www.theoi.com/Olympios/ArtemisFavour.html#Hippolytos<br /><br /><br /><br /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/little-bears/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Artemisia the General</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/artemisia-the-general/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/artemisia-the-general/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Suz Thackston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Waifs, Wolves & Warriors - Women in Greek Mythology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24829#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=24829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Artemisia gazes out over the water, the wind in her face, sea spray beading in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>Artemisia gazes out over the water, the wind in her face, sea spray beading in the tight black coils of her braids. Her city of Halicarnassus shrinks behind her. She’s glad to get away from the stifling dullness of court, its endless calculating politics and fawning courtiers and whining supplicants. Action is what she craves, and the opportunity to pit her wits against the men who try to curry favor with her while talking down to her as if she were a witless child. She has answered Xerxes’ call to arms with a speed that startled her clucking, puffing courtiers. She and the five ships of her kingdom’s fleet are eager to shake off the dust of the polis and streak toward battle.</em> <br /><br />Historical women rarely make it into this blog, but there are a few in Greek history who are so powerful and memorable that their exploits achieve mythic status. Artemisia, queen of Halicarnassus, a Greek city-state that was part of the Persian empire, is so fascinating that she has shouldered her way forward and demanded her spotlight.<br /><br />Artemisia’s name is derived from the goddess Artemis, huntress, warrior and goddess of wild and feral things. As warlike and fierce as the goddess is, she’s a perfect patron for the warrior-queen who terrified her male military peers and drew praise and admiration from the Persian ruler, Xerxes. <br /><br /><em>The queen’s thoughts fly to her small son, cared for in her absence by trusted family members. She needs to hold Caria until he comes of age, damn her husband’s eyes for dying so young. Her only choice was to entrust their child to scheming politicians or take the throne herself, her eagle eyes dulling in the fog of tradition, rules, etiquette and the numbing minutiae of rulership. But this…this is what she was born for. Command, not queenship. Battle with sword and spear, not the endless dagger thrusts of political debate and court rhetoric. </em><br /><br /><em>She takes a deep breath of the cold sea air.</em><br /><br />Artemisia I of Caria’s kingdom included the polis of Halicarnassus and the nearby islands of Kos, Nisyros and Kalymnos, all under the Archaemenid satrapy of Caria, part of the Persian empire, in modern day Turkey. She was of Greek and Carian descent from her father, and Cretan descent from her mother. Her exploits are often confused with those of Artemisia II of Caria, who built the ancient wonder of the world, the Mausoleum at Halicarnassus, for her brother/husband. <br /><br /><em>Artemisia had not been at the Battle of Marathon, but the Persians’ surprise defeat there had shocked her and the rulers of all the other satrapies. King Xerxes has now amassed the greatest fleet the world has ever seen, greater even than the fabled fleet said to have laid siege to Troy. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-24892 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Artemisia_at_the_Battle_of_Salamis-237x300.jpg" alt="" width="237" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Artemisia_at_the_Battle_of_Salamis-237x300.jpg 237w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Artemisia_at_the_Battle_of_Salamis-808x1024.jpg 808w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Artemisia_at_the_Battle_of_Salamis-768x974.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Artemisia_at_the_Battle_of_Salamis-1212x1536.jpg 1212w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Artemisia_at_the_Battle_of_Salamis-1615x2048.jpg 1615w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Artemisia_at_the_Battle_of_Salamis.jpg 1740w" sizes="(max-width: 237px) 100vw, 237px" />He could not lose again. Artemisia plans to be a part of the victory. She and her warships had been with the great Xerxes’ navy at Artemisium, fighting the stubborn Greeks to a standstill. Xerxes’ ground forces simultaneously overwhelmed the tiny company of Spartan resisters at Thermopylae. Now they were gleefully sacking the hastily abandoned upstart polis of Athens.</em> <br /><br />It was at Artemisium that Xerxes had taken notice of his sole female general and her wily, unexpected tactics. <br /><br /><em>Artemisia glances back at the mainmast, where a halyard coils around the base, an Athenian flag neatly folded under it. A passing sailor sees a smile flicker across her face and hurries away, a chill running down his spine. The crew had been shocked when their queen had the Greek flag run up during the battle at Artemisium, then thrown into confusion at her order to ram one of their Persian allies. But the fire in her eyes had cowed them, and they did as ordered, right before an Athenian trireme would have rammed them. When the Athenian captain saw their flag and their prow buried in a Persian hull he had changed course and let them be.</em> <br /><br />There was no clear winner at Artemisium, but history gives the nod to the Persians. The allied Greek fleet, consisting of about 270 triremes from Athens, Sparta, Corinth and a handful of smaller polises, was tiny compared to the gargantuan number of Persian warships. But Xerxes lost approximately one third of his ships in a gale on the way to the engagement, then a couple hundred more in another storm as they attempted to sneak around the Greeks and trap them. The two fleets duked it out over a three day period, ending when the Greek allies received word of their defeat at Thermopylae. They withdrew to Salamis, leaving the plain of Attika to be overrun by the Persians, who took the abandoned polis of Athens and razed it. Xerxes enjoyed his brief moment of triumph, having taken the most strategically important parts of mainland Greece and the prized polis of Athens. Then the brilliant Athenian politician and general Themistokles rallied his tattered, decimated troops at Salamis.<br /><br /><em>A knock at the door interrupts a meeting between Artemisia and her second-in-command, a grizzled one-eyed veteran with a creative mind for tactics, a vicious temperament, and unshakeable loyalty to her. At her terse word a flustered lieutenant opens the door, bobbing and stammering. The queen’s eyes narrow. The boy gulps and manages, “It’s King Xerxes, my lady. He’s called a war council and he wants you there!”</em><br /><br /><em>Artemisia and her captain exchange a tight smile. Without a word, she rises, buckles on her sword and flings her purple cloak around her shoulders. With the captain one pace behind her, she brushes past the gaping young marine and strides to the gangplank.</em><br /><br /><em>Fires blaze on the beach, leaving no doubt where the council is taking place. About a hundred of Xerxes’ finest commanders are seated on rocks and logs in a rough semi-circle before the Persian king’s opulent tent. Artemisia surveys the scene. She motions to her captain.</em><br /><br /><em>“Zana, find me a place close to the front, but not too close. We will not be meekly shunted to the sidelines.”</em><br /><br /><em>Zana’s single eye gleams. Artemisia waits, motionless in the shadows, as he shoves his way through the throng, ignoring curses and complaints, his expression withering any who try to prevent his passage. He pauses by a good-sized boulder about twenty feet from Xerxes’ pavilion. Two well-dressed young men are sharing it. When he returns five minutes later, having parted the crowd with his queen pacing serenely in his wake, he stares down at the young nobles. They gaze back, with welcoming smiles that falter and fall off their faces. Zana jerks his head. One starts to bluster but the other, looking closely at the wolf face of the older man, takes his companion’s arm and they quietly vacate the stone. Zana removes his cloak, lays it across the boulder, and hands his queen onto the seat. A ripple of exclamations, incredulous laughter, and a mutter of protest eddies out through the crowd, but dies as Artemisia tosses back her now-loose mane of ebony hair and smiles her white, feral smile. Zana takes his place behind her, hand on the hilt of his sword. </em><br /><br /><em>The Persian king, taller than everyone else present, steps out of his tent. He surveys his commanders, his cold eyes assessing them, taking his time. The murmuring crowd falls into an awed silence. Artemisia smiles to herself. She recognizes the psychological ploy. It is one she often resorts to herself, an icy, tacit reminder of who holds the power. </em><br /><br /><em>In his deep, beautiful voice, Xerxes summarizes the battle they have just fought. There are nods as he terms it a victory, although Artemisia keeps her face carefully still, knowing how skillfully the desperately outnumbered Greeks fought and the damage they had wreaked on the Persian navy. Xerxes tells his commanders that they now have the choice to pursue the allies to their bolthole at Salamis, or gather their plunder from sacked Athens and the decimated Attikan plain and go home. One by one he asks each man to share his thoughts. One by one, each man firmly makes the case to take the fleet to Salamis and pound the Greeks into a final, resounding defeat. </em><br /><br /><em>Everyone has spoken by the time Xerxes’ eyes fall on Artemisia. He smiles slowly. The Carnian queen feels the circle of men draw back, away from her, isolating her, the distance palpable. Only Zana remains at her back. She cannot see his face but knows he is looking steadily back at the King of Kings, respectful but not one whit cowed. </em><br /><br /><em>Xerxes does not spare a glance for the underling. He walks with a stately tread through the crowd, commanders scrambling to clear his path. He stops before Artemisia. She meets his eyes, smiles into them and rises. She does not curtsy. She bows to her king, man to man. </em><br /><br /><em>Xerxes smiles back. “And you, my only female general. What say you to this plan? Do you agree with the rest that we should finish what we’ve started and crush the upstarts into jelly?”</em><br /><br /><em>Artemisia’s voice rings out clear in the firelight. “Great king, you have already won a victory of which the poets will sing through the ages. Athens is razed, the Greek polises are panicked, the villages and settlements scattered and demoralized. We can now prevent supplies getting through by sea and starve the remaining holdouts all across the Attikan plain, picking them off at our leisure. Your name strikes terror into the hearts of your enemies and none will dare to stand against you again. But the Greek navy, as we have just seen, are formidable sailors and warriors. They will fight fiercely to the last, even though they cannot win. There is no need to incur any further damage to your mighty fleet, nor to put yourself in harm’s way. You are already victorious. So here is my advice: do not commit the fleet to battle, because at sea your men will be as inferior to the Greeks as women are to men.” </em><br /><br /><em>The king’s eyes bore into her. Silence falls, heavy as a shroud. Artemisia feels Zana shift behind her, but her head is high and her smile never falters. </em><br /><br /><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-24893 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Xerxes_by_Ernest_Normand-244x300.jpg" alt="" width="244" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Xerxes_by_Ernest_Normand-244x300.jpg 244w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Xerxes_by_Ernest_Normand-831x1024.jpg 831w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Xerxes_by_Ernest_Normand-768x946.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Xerxes_by_Ernest_Normand-1247x1536.jpg 1247w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Xerxes_by_Ernest_Normand.jpg 1312w" sizes="(max-width: 244px) 100vw, 244px" />Xerxes’ chiseled face splits into a huge grin. Turning on his heel, he bellows, “Hear the Carian queen! Would that I had a hundred of her! I’d toss the rest of you into the midden heap and I would rule the whole world!” He strides back to his tent and pushes through the rich fabrics hanging at the door. There is a long, long pause, then subdued muttering. Eyes flash white in the firelight as men glance at Artemisia, then away. Not deigning to look at any of them, Artemisia walks with a firm stride to her ship, Zana at her back.</em><br /><br />Despite his delight at the perspicacity of his female general, Xerxes decided to take the counsel of the majority, many of whom had more years of battle experience than the Carian queen. He deployed his troops to Salamis.<br /><br /><em>“10,000 drachmas,” laughs Zana as the flagship leads the Helicarnassian fleet toward the narrow straits of Salamis. “Not one of the other generals has such a bounty on his head! The Greeks are rightly terrified of you, my queen!” Artemisia grins back at him and tucks a stray lock of hair under her helm. She advised against this battle but since it is upon her, she is eager to engage. Her flag catches the sun, high on the midmast, and the oars send spray sparkling in their wake as they race forward. That very morning she overheard two of the Persian generals muttering that the bounty should be sufficient to scare the woman home to her throne and leave warring to her betters. She has marked their ships, just in case she has occasion to teach them a lesson in warfare.</em><br /><br />The Greeks successfully lured the cocky Persians into the narrow straits of Salamis by feigning retreat. Then they turned a bold and frankly insane attack on the larger, heavier, more numerous warships of the Persians, which found themselves unable to pivot effectively in the tight confines. Artemisia was pursued by a deadly trireme from Athens and was unable to slip away from it, blocked in the busy, churning waters by both friendly and hostile ships. <br /><br /><em>Artemisia has seconds to act. She whirls to her mainmast where Zana is poised, watching for her signal. She nods. In one swift motion Zana releases the halyard with the Carian standard. Even as it crumples to the deck, the Athenian flag is hoisted to the peak where it unfurls, catching the sun. But Artemisia doesn’t wait to see its effect. Seeing a Persian ship wallowing haplessly nearby, blocked fore and aft, she grasps her helmsman’s shoulder and points. Well-trained by Zana, he does not hesitate for even a second. The nose of the ship turns to her ally and leaps forward. The quartermaster takes it in with a single glance and bellows, “Impact!” </em></p>
<p><em>The ram of Artemisia’s warship crunches through the hull of Persian ship. The queen has one immensely satisfying glance at one of her detractors righting himself from his headlong tumble across the bridge, shouting incoherently at her. She looks over her shoulder at the Athenian. The trireme has veered off and is in hot pursuit of another lumbering Persian ship. Quick as a cat, Zana has whipped the Greek flag down and is raising their own again. Artemisia gives the order to have the rowers back her ship out of the hapless Persian ship, and scans the busy waters for her next quarry. </em><br /><br /><em>Across the bay, high on a hill overlooking the water, Artemisia can see Xerxes’ elaborate canopy, its colors bright against the brown earth. She can just make out the tall figure, towering over all others, hand raised high in her direction. Even through the flood of battle adrenaline she feels a flush of pleasure. Catching Zana’s eye, she points toward a Greek ship in hot pursuit of one of her own allies. Her lips pull back in a snarl. </em><br /><br /><em>Time to go hunting.</em><br /><br />Herodotus tells us that Xerxes, after seeing Artemisia flip her flags and deceive the enemy, exclaimed, “My male generals have turned into women and my female general into a man!”<br /><br />Sadly for Xerxes, Artemisia’s wiliness was not enough to bring him victory. The menacing, heavy Persian ships turned out to be no match, in the confined straits of Salamis, for the fast, light, maneuverable Greek triremes. Afraid to be cut off and forced to remain in Greece where he could be captured or killed, Xerxes again turned to the one person who had given him good advice before the disaster. Artemisia reiterated that Xerxes had already accomplished his stated mission, to raze Athens, and that he could comfortably return in triumph to Persia, leaving his general, Mardonius, with a large force to finish mopping up on the mainland. She pointed out that if Mardonius succeeded the victory would be Xerxes’, but if he failed, the failure would be pinned on him while Xerxes would be safe at home. Xerxes took her advice this time and headed back to Persia, leaving Mardonius to lead the troops to their ultimate defeat, and Mardonius’ death, at Plataea the following year. <br /><br />Before he left, Xerxes is reputed to have given his female general a suit of Greek armor, and her captain a distaff and spindle. Artemisia was given the honor of escorting Xerxes’ illegitimate children to safety at Ephesus. At this point, history loses track of her. Apparently she never went back to her throne in Halicarnassus. Her son, Pisindelis, became tyrant when he came of age, with no mention of his mother. But historians have left us with some speculations as to what became of the formidable general. Pausanias tells us that the Spartans, always admiring of a worthy foe, used detritus left over from the Persian invasion of their territory to make a beautiful marble statue of her in their Persian Hall in the agora. Photius, writing almost 400 years after the Persian Wars, claims she fell in love with a prince named Dardanus, and, after he rejected her advances, threw herself into the sea and drowned. While nothing contradicts this account, it seems unlikely that a woman like this would end so pitifully.<br /><br />It’s almost impossible to find women in ancient Greece giving accounts of their experiences in their own voices. Even the most famous, Sappho, didn’t leave clear lines on what was her own history and what was fiction. When we read Herodotus quote Artemisia as saying to Xerxes, “So here is my advice: do not commit the fleet to battle, because at sea your men will be as inferior to the Greeks as women are to men,” we don’t know if he is romanticizing her conversation with Xerxes (to which he was certainly not privy) or if she was cagily playing to the societal norms of her time. <br /><br />But of one thing we can be sure —Artemesia I of Caria, mother, queen, general and badass, was inferior to no man and she knew it. <br /><br /><a href="https://kosmossociety.chs.harvard.edu/?p=41265">https://kosmossociety.chs.harvard.edu/?p=41265</a><br /><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artemisia_I_of_Caria">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artemisia_I_of_Caria</a><br /><a href="https://www.worldhistory.org/Artemisia_I_of_Caria/">https://www.worldhistory.org/Artemisia_I_of_Caria/</a><br /><a href="https://www.thoughtco.com/artemisia-warrior-queen-of-halicarnassus-3528382">https://www.thoughtco.com/artemisia-warrior-queen-of-halicarnassus-3528382</a><br /><a href="https://www.factinate.com/people/lethal-facts-artemisia-i-caria-pirate-queen-ancient-greece/">https://www.factinate.com/people/lethal-facts-artemisia-i-caria-pirate-queen-ancient-greece/</a><br /><a href="https://sourcebooks.fordham.edu/ancient/480artemisia.asp">https://sourcebooks.fordham.edu/ancient/480artemisia.asp</a><br /><a href="http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper/text?doc=Perseus:text:1999.01.0160:book=3:chapter=11">http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper/text?doc=Perseus:text:1999.01.0160:book=3:chapter=11</a><br /><br /><br /><br /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/artemisia-the-general/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Girl Who Swings</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-girl-who-swings/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-girl-who-swings/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Suz Thackston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 11:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Waifs, Wolves & Warriors - Women in Greek Mythology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24359#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=24359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What would it be like to be a girl who meets a god? Maybe it&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>What would it be like to be a girl who meets a god?<br /><br />Maybe it goes something like this.<br /><br /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-24444 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/adrian-dascal-o3JuHcZjSew-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/adrian-dascal-o3JuHcZjSew-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/adrian-dascal-o3JuHcZjSew-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/adrian-dascal-o3JuHcZjSew-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/adrian-dascal-o3JuHcZjSew-unsplash-1229x1536.jpg 1229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/adrian-dascal-o3JuHcZjSew-unsplash-1638x2048.jpg 1638w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/adrian-dascal-o3JuHcZjSew-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />Once upon a time, in the region of Athens, there lived a girl called Erigone. Athens was small then but developing importance due to the interest taken by such gods as Athena, Poseidon and Demeter. <br /><br />Erigone lived with her father, Ikarios, and her mother, Phanothea. She was a happy girl of about ten, with unruly curls of deep brown, with a sheen of purple like the bloom of a wild grape, and brilliant hazel eyes. She helped her father tend the goats and her mother spin and weave the linen for their clothing, all the while singing the songs her mother taught her.<br /><br />“Erigone!” called her father one spring dusk as shadows pooled in the sheltered dell outside their home. “Draw water from the well and fetch bread and mead! A stranger approaches!”<br /><br />Erigone dropped the spindle she had been holding for her mother and ran to the door. Her father was standing by the gate of the goat pen, shading his eyes with one hand as he peered into the darkening road before their house. His dog, Maera, stood beside him, hackles raised. Erigone joined them, watching the approaching figure. She thought for a moment that there were many people, dancing and swirling around the central form, but as the person drew nearer she could see that it was just one man, his steps halting as if he were very tired. <br /><br />Maera started forward, barking, as the man stumbled to a halt in the road before their home. She stopped suddenly, lowering her head, and crept toward the stranger. To Erigone’s surprise, their fierce dog licked his hand. <br /><br />Ikarios’s hand fell on her shoulder. She whirled and ran to the well behind their home, lowering the bucket and then straining to raise it, brimming, to the surface. Phanothea came to the door as Erigone carried the bucket inside. The woman took a basin from a shelf and set it before the fire. Erigone filled the basin and fetched a clean cloth, then began cutting slices of coarse bread while her mother hurried to milk a goat. Erigone burned with curiosity as she listened to her father greet the stranger and invite him inside.<br /><br />A young man, so tall he needed to bend his head as he came through the door, preceded Ikarios into the house. He looked around, removed his cloak and smiled at the little girl before the hearth. Ikarios took the cloak and gestured to a stool close to the fire. <br /><br />“Please sit, traveler, and allow my daughter to tend to you. My wife&#8230;ah, there you are, Phanothea. We are honored with a guest. Sir, will you take milk or mead?”<br /><br />The young man said nothing as he sat before the fire and allowed Erigone to draw the dusty boots from his feet. He sighed as she washed the grime of travel from his feet with cool, clean water. Ikarios and Phanothea stood respectfully nearby. Erigone could see the burning desire in her mother to ask questions, but xenia, the custom of reciprocal hospitality between guest and host, kept her silent until the guest was ready to share.<br /><br />Erigone sat back on her heels and peered shyly at the young man to see if he was satisfied with her efforts. Her breath caught in her throat at her first good look at the man sitting at her family’s hearth. Blue-black curls cascaded around a face of such beauty that he seemed to have stepped from a bard’s tale. His cheeks were as smooth as a maiden’s, his lips full, curved in a secret smile, and his eyes were a deep amethyst. He reached down and touched her cheek with a long finger. <br /><br />“Thank you, little one,” he murmured in a voice like music. He turned that enigmatic smile to Phanothea and said, “Mistress, I thank you for your offering. I will take a little honeyed milk, if it does not discommodate you.”<br /><br />For the first time in her life, Erigone saw her mother at a loss for words. After opening and closing her mouth several times, Phanothea turned silently to make the drink.<br /><br />Ikarios set the bread on a platter with a nub of cheese and some dried figs. Erigone carefully <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-24446 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/karina-vorozheeva-ZHolOF0-e1Y-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/karina-vorozheeva-ZHolOF0-e1Y-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/karina-vorozheeva-ZHolOF0-e1Y-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/karina-vorozheeva-ZHolOF0-e1Y-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/karina-vorozheeva-ZHolOF0-e1Y-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/karina-vorozheeva-ZHolOF0-e1Y-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/karina-vorozheeva-ZHolOF0-e1Y-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />carried the soiled water outside and poured it onto the pomegranate tree as her mother had taught her. Water never went to waste in their arid region. When she returned to the house she joined her parents, sitting silently watching the stranger eat. He was not bothered by the three sets of eyes intent upon him, but finished his meal with seeming pleasure, scattering the last few drops and crumbs into the fire.<br /><br />“Your courtesy is as welcome as a cool breeze on a hot summer’s day,” he said finally, gesturing for them to join him in front of the fire. “I have a gift for you in return.” He pulled a skin bag from under his robe and set it before them. Phanothea brought a clean bowl and Ikarios rose to pour the contents of the bag into the bowl.<br /><br />A sharp, sweet smell filled the little room. Erigone gazed with wonder at the rich, red-purple liquid glimmering in the firelight. Darker than blood, it yet evoked the feeling she got seeing the gush of red liquid from the throat of a sacrifice.<br /><br />“Bring me water, little one,” he said to her. She ran out to the well and returned in moments with a brimming pail. Nodding his thanks, he asked Phanothea to give him a small bowl. He added water to both bowls, enough to the small bowl to dilute the color to a pale rose. He held the large bowl up to the fire, thanked Hestia, sipped, and handed it to Ikarios. A smile played across his mobile face as he watched his host. Ikarios’s jaw dropped. The stranger gestured for him to give the bowl to Phanothea, then he handed the small bowl to Erigone.<br /><br />“Drink,” he whispered to her. Never taking her eyes from his face, she did as she was bid. Her mouth filled with a strange sweetness and a puzzling undertone of bitterness. She held it in her mouth for a long moment before she swallowed. Warmth followed the liquid down her throat and into her stomach.<br /><br />“What is this?” said Ikarios in a tone of fear and reverence. “The nectar served upon Mount Olympos must taste much like this.”<br /><br />The young man rose to his feet, his head brushing the ceiling of the little hut. White teeth gleamed in a smile that promised delight and ferocity. His voice, though not loud, rang inside the small abode like a silver bell. <br /><br />“I am Dionysos,” he said, “son of Zeus and thrice-blessed Semele. This is my gift to mankind. This is wine.”<br /><br />Dionysos stayed with Erigone’s family for a full moon phase, teaching them the cultivation of the vines and explaining how to press the juice of the grapes and ferment it. Ikarios, always a careful study, listened and learned rapidly.<br /><br />All too soon the family gathered in front of the house to see their mentor off. Phanothea had filled a sack with dried goat meat, bread and figs, which the young man carried slung over his shoulder along with his wine bags. He embraced Ikarios, bowed gravely to Phanothea and knelt before Erigone. She was weeping unashamedly. <br /><br />“Why do you have to go?” she gasped, lifting wet eyes to his face. “We love you.”<br /><br />He cupped her face in his long, beautiful fingers. His purple eyes gazed deeply into hers. “I am not made to stay in one place, my small friend,” he told her. “My gifts must be spread widely, and thus my cultus. It is important that your family aid me in this endeavor.” As she blinked at him uncomprehendingly he kissed her forehead. “I love you too,” he whispered. “I always will.”<br /><br />He stepped into the road and out of their lives. Their last glimpse of him as he rounded a curve was his final wave, his joyous laughter wafting to them through the bright air. Maera sat in the middle of the road and howled. <br /><br /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-24447 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/boudewijn-huysmans-Gji9uTRJzmI-unsplash-300x201.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="201" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/boudewijn-huysmans-Gji9uTRJzmI-unsplash-300x201.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/boudewijn-huysmans-Gji9uTRJzmI-unsplash-1024x685.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/boudewijn-huysmans-Gji9uTRJzmI-unsplash-768x514.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/boudewijn-huysmans-Gji9uTRJzmI-unsplash-1536x1028.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/boudewijn-huysmans-Gji9uTRJzmI-unsplash-2048x1371.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Ikarios tended his new vineyard with zeal. The first year the vines produced just a few little grapes, not enough to press. There were more the second year. In the autumn of the third year, as Erigone approached adulthood, the clusters of grapes hung sweet and fat, glowing like jewels in the hot sunshine. The family remembered the instructions left to them by the beautiful young god, pressing the juice and fermenting it in the jars Phanothea had made for them as the vines matured. They set most of the jars aside to age, but as the autumn gew colder and the leaves flew, they opened the first jar and tasted the wine. It was sharp and bitter, but the heat that they remembered from their visitor’s brew warmed their bellies and made them laugh.<br /><br />Ikarios set aside a few jars of new wine to take to the agora in Athens, a few days journey from their home. Erigone was awakened a few days before market day by a roar from the vineyard. She ran outside to find her father stomping between the vines, examining the nibble marks on their trunks and leaves. A billy goat leapt over a broken-down place in the fence, eyes wide, Maera at his heels. As Erigone and Phanothea stared, Ikarios strode after the goat, dragged him to the stump behind the hut where their butchering took place, and after a swift prayer, cut his throat.<br /><br />Ikarios’s brow was thunderous as he began to butcher the goat. “Those vines are a divine blessing,” he growled to his women who were still staring wordlessly at him. “No goat will defile them.” His angry gaze fell on Maera. “If you let that happen again, you’ll join him.” Maera’s ears and tail drooped.<br /><br />Erigone was excited to go to market with her father for the first time. They loaded up their donkey with the jars and fabrics Phanothea had made to trade, goat milk and goat meat, and the skin of the billy goat who had raided their vineyard, sewn into a round sack and filled with air. Finally, Ikarios added the jars of new wine. <br /><br />Trade was brisk at the agora. Phanothea was known for her skill in weaving but even more so as a bard. Soon there was a crowd around her as she sang the song she had created about a fascinating stranger bearing gifts of knowledge and delight. As she sang, Ikarios passed around cups of the new beverage, grinning with satisfaction at the reactions from the crowd. When the song was finished he threw the inflated goat skin into their midst, roaring with laughter at the impromptu game of kickball that ensued among the folk, intoxicated with wine and camaraderie.<br /><br />The family arrived home well after dark, warm despite the cold of the star-spangled night, laden with the goods from the market. It had been their most successful day of trading ever.<br /><br />That night, Erigone slept warm in her cot, snuggled into a new fur blanket, and dreamed of Dionysos.<br /><br />In early spring, when the very first spears of snowdrops and crocus poked through the snow, Ikarios opened the first of the saved wine jars. A rich odor permeated the hut. Erigone turned from the loom where her mother was instructing her and followed her nose to her father, who stood staring into the dark depths of the jar. <br /><br />“Father!” she said. “It doesn’t smell anything like it did last autumn.”<br /><br />“No,” he agreed. He looked at his wife. She nodded sharply.<br /><br />“What are you waiting for?” she asked. “Let’s taste it!”<br /><br />Erigone fetched water while Ikarios poured the strong wine into a bowl, then diluted it with water. The taste, while still sharper than the wine from Dionysos’s bag, was more mellow and sweet than the new wine. But the heat that coiled in their bellies was now familiar. They sat for a while before the fire, enjoying the warmth from inside and out.<br /><br />Phanothea rose. “We must create a shrine to this god,” she said. “This is a gift unlike any other.”<br /><br />Ikarios nodded. “And more. We must take this gift and spread it among the people of our land. He left us to spread his worship and his gift. Can we do less?”<br /><br />Spring was well underway when Ikarios left his home, the donkey once again laden, but this time with jars of wine. Maera went with him, dancing with excitement at the adventure, the plume of her tail waving madly. Phanothea and Erigone saw him off, waving as he rounded the corner where four years ago they had seen Dionysos disappear. The two women put their arms around each other and stood looking at the empty road for a long time.<br /><br />A moon phase passed. Then another. The days were longer, the sun warmer, the earth softer. Phanothea and Erigone tended the goats, made cheese, spun thread, wove linen cloth, planted the garden and made clay pots, but nothing could deflect their growing concern.<br /><br />As the two women worked in the vineyard one warm afternoon they heard a familiar sound from far down the road. It grew closer. They stood. Erigone dropped the paring knife she was holding.<br /><br />“Mother, it’s Maera!” she cried. Lifting her skirt, she ran out into the road, Phanothea following. <br /><br />Maera rounded the curve and flew to the girl, throwing herself into Erigone’s arms. She was skin and bones, her thick fur matted and filthy, her body covered with wounds, her beautiful tail dragging in the dirt. Her voice rose, no longer a bark but a wail, a terrible sound. <br /><br />Erigone felt a chill run through her. She held the crying dog, rocking back and forth, but nothing soothed poor Maera. Phanothea and Erigone led her back to their home, combed and washed her, tended her knots and cuts and bleeding paws, and fed her gruel. Despite her starved condition, the dog barely touched her food, crying and whimpering until she fell into a twitching, exhausted sleep before the fire. <br /><br />The women stared at each other.<br /><br />“I must go find him,” said Erigone. “I’ll leave in the morning. I’ll take Maera with me.”<br /><br />“You cannot,” replied her mother. “It’s too dangerous.”<br /><br />“I must,” repeated Erigone. Phanothea said no more, but turned to start packing. <br /><br />Erigone and Maere headed west, then turned north, as Ikarios had planned to do. During the first week they met homesteaders like themselves who remembered meeting Ikarios and expressed delight at the wine he had shared with them. <br /><br />But soon thereafter they came to a small hamlet where furtive glances and closed doors were as eloquent as Maera’s shivering and pain-filled eyes. The hope in Erigone’s heart withered. Before she met the woman who told her the grim story, she knew. She came to a dwelling on the outskirts of the hamlet where a woman was feeding a flock of chickens. She started as she saw the thin dog, and her face fell as she beheld the desperation in the young girl’s eyes. <br /><br />“Yes,” she replied to Erigone’s now-familiar inquiry. “I saw him, and his dog as well. You’d better come inside.” She led Erigone into the little home and gave her refreshments as xenia required, then took her hands and gazed into her tired face.<br /><br />The story that she told struck Erigone like a blow. Ikarios had arrived in the hamlet more than a moon phase prior, just a few wine jugs left, Maera prancing at his side. The herdsmen and fishermen who were nearby were called home and everyone gathered to hear his tale, and, more importantly, to taste his exciting new beverage— a gift, as he said, from a god. He produced an inflated goatskin bag, and the community spent a wonderful afternoon drinking the wine and playing with the bag, kicking it, laughing, falling down and making fun of each other. <br /><br />Several of the men drank a great deal of the wine and fell heavily asleep after staggering around the hamlet and speaking incoherently. Others who had indulged less tried to wake them but could not. That was when one of the young men, after vomiting up purple liquid, shouted, “Poison! This man has poisoned us!”<br /><br />The woman was silent for a time. When she resumed the story, she spoke hesitantly. Ikarios had begged the folk of the hamlet to see reason. Then he had begged for his life. The men sent the women and children into their homes and dragged him away. She said that was all she knew. But her face belied her words. <br /><br />When her story was told, the woman turned her eyes from Erigone’s face. She escorted the girl out of the house and closed the door behind her. Erigone stood frozen, a voice inside her head screaming “No, no, no, no, no.” She didn’t recognize the voice, her own voice, her voice when she had still been a very little girl. <br /><br />Maera took Erigone’s skirt in her teeth and tugged. Erigone stared down at the dog with sightless eyes. She pulled the skirt free, ran to the house and pounded on the door. <br /><br />“Where is he?” she screamed. “Where is my father’s body? What have you done with him? I must perform the rites!” She beat her fists on the door until they ran with blood, but no one answered. Ripping her hands through her hair, she ran to the center of the hamlet and cried aloud, ululating, her sobs tearing through the soft afternoon sunshine. <br /><br />No one came to see. The doors stayed shut. Erigone wept with only Maera howling a dirge with her. <br /><br />Finally Erigone collapsed into exhausted silence. She sat alone in the dust. <br /><br />Once again Maera tugged at her mistress’s skirt. Erigone lifted bleary eyes and saw the dog, thin and knotted with bruises, and rose wearily to her feet. Maera trotted toward a hill that lay to the south of the village, stopped and looked back to make sure Erigone was following her, then led her up and over the hill.<br /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24448 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tim-jones-1YFJ3-2nrgM-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tim-jones-1YFJ3-2nrgM-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tim-jones-1YFJ3-2nrgM-unsplash-1024x577.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tim-jones-1YFJ3-2nrgM-unsplash-768x433.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tim-jones-1YFJ3-2nrgM-unsplash-1536x866.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/tim-jones-1YFJ3-2nrgM-unsplash-2048x1154.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><br />On an open field, about a mile from the hamlet, stood a gnarled oak tree and an old well. As Maera topped the hill she threw back her head and howled, a terrible sound of grief and fury. She ran down the hill and across the field, throwing herself down at the stones around the well, her body shaking in paroxysms of horror. Erigone ran after her, almost tripping over large stones that lay scattered before the well. She looked around wildly. There was no sign of Ikarios. She hurried over to the great tree. Caught on a branch she saw a torn piece of cloth, fluttering in the gentle breeze. She reached up for it and turned it over in her hands. Her mother’s needlework was as familiar to her as the sound of her singing. Erigone was holding a piece of her father’s traveling cloak.<br /><br />She looked back at the well. It was clearly long abandoned, probably dry, but the stones that bordered its rim had been torn up and lay disheveled in the soft grass. Some of them bore dark stains. <br /><br />Erigone crept to the mouth of well. Maera howled one last time and lay silent, panting. The girl peered over the lip. The well was deep. Darkness mercifully hid what lay below, but the smell left no doubt as to where Ikarios had finally escaped his tormentors. <br /><br />Erigone staggered to the shade of the oak and collapsed. Maera crept into her arms. They lay intertwined for a long, long time.<br /><br />Dusk inched across the field from the western mountains. The shadow of the oak tree stretched and deepened. As the sun slid out of sight and the sky turned lavender and pearl, Erigone rose. She tore her robe into strips and tied them together, good, tight knots as her father had taught her. She looped the rope over her arm and climbed into the oak tree, not too high, just enough to find a good stout branch. She was a slight girl, and not very tall. She tied one end of the rope firmly to the branch, the other around her neck. She let go of the tree and fell.<br /><br />Maera watched until the form stopped jerking and swung gently in the gathering dark. She did not make any sound. As night fell across the field, stars blazing in the heavens, the dog walked slowly to the well. She paused on the rim, then jumped in.<br /><br />In the deep darkness before rosy-fingered dawn brightened the sky, a figure appeared silhouetted against the stars. The form of a tall young man, hair in riotous curls about his head, strode to the well, then the tree. Luminous tears, shimmering pale violet, ran down his cheeks. <br /><br />By the time the sun rose, tree and well were empty. There was no one in the field where horrors had taken place.<br /><br />As time passed, something terrible stalked grimly through Athens and the villages and hamlets surrounding it. The figure of a maiden, slender and slight, with burning amber eyes, was reportedly seen near groups of playing children.<br /><br />For no reason that anyone could explain, young girls began hanging themselves from trees, first one or two, then a few, then many. Parents tried to keep their daughters in sight at all times, but just as children have always done, girls found ways to elude the watchful eyes and found trees. They hanged themselves alone. Best friends and sisters swung from trees together. In some unspeakable instances, entire groves creaked and danced with great clusters of ghastly fruit. In one hamlet, where a deflated goatskin ball lay abandoned in the weeds, every single girl under the age of twenty took their own lives and those of the baby girls and toddlers they brought with them to the tree.<br /><br />Phanothea left her empty home, abandoning her goats, her loom and her vineyard, and made her way to Delphi where she appealed to the Pythia, the oracular priestess of Apollon. When she had her answer, she created a new form of verse, the hexameter, and composed a song that was soon sung in every home on the Attikan plains. It told the story of Ikarios and Erigone, and how at the Anthesteria, the festival of flowers in late winter, their shades could be propitiated. The Aiora, the festival of swings, was instituted to appease the shade of Erigone. As bright ribbons fluttered from branches, and laughter echoed from swings installed from strong boughs, sanity returned to the girls of the region.<br /><br />Phanothea stayed in Delphi and spent the rest of her life in service to Apollon and the Pythia. <br /><br />The folk of Attika noticed new stars gleaming in the skies. One shone within the constellation of Canis Minor, where Maera now hunts joyfully across the night sky as Procyon. The constellation known as Bootes, or Arcturus, shines with the soul of Ikarios. Erigone is honored as the beautiful constellation Virgo.<br /><br />They shine down upon the whole world, a gift to all. A gift no less beloved and far less dangerous than the liquid amethyst, the blood of the grape, the heady wine of Dionysos. <br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br />https://www.theoi.com/Heros/Ikarios.html<br />https://www.britannica.com/topic/Erigone<br />http://01greekmythology.blogspot.com/2015/05/erigone.html<br />https://oxfordre.com/classics/view/10.1093/acrefore/9780199381135.001.0001/acrefore-9780199381135-e-2487<br />https://www.theoi.com/Titan/AsterSeirios.html<br />http://www.ianridpath.com/startales/canisminor.html<br /><br /><br /><br /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-girl-who-swings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Erinyes</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-erinyes/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-erinyes/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Suz Thackston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Waifs, Wolves & Warriors - Women in Greek Mythology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22632#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=22632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The temple of Apollon at Delphi in the pearly light of dawn. The Pythia, oracle&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22782 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/orestes-pursued-by-the-furies-d3dbc2-209x300.jpg" alt="" width="209" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/orestes-pursued-by-the-furies-d3dbc2-209x300.jpg 209w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/orestes-pursued-by-the-furies-d3dbc2.jpg 445w" sizes="(max-width: 209px) 100vw, 209px" />The temple of Apollon at Delphi in the pearly light of dawn. The Pythia, oracle priestess of the god, enters the temple to commence morning prayers.</em></p>
<p><em>Seconds later she runs out, screaming. Looking in through the open door we can see an exhausted and terrified young man, dripping blood. He is seated upon the omphalos, the huge boulder within the sanctuary that is the sacred navel of the world. He holds a bloody sword and an olive branch wreathed in white wool. </em></p>
<p><em>He is surrounded by women, sleeping on benches. </em></p>
<p><em>And oh, such women. Rustling, murmuring, heaving like a herd of seals in their black rags and tattered feathers. Even in their slumber they incite mindless terror.</em></p>
<p>Thus opens <em>The Eumenides</em>, the third play in the trilogy of the <em>Oresteia</em> by Aeschylus. Orestes has made it to the temple of Apollon to seek sanctuary from the terrible Erinyes, or Furies, who are seeking vengeance for his murder of his own mother. But if he dares move from the omphalos, they will be upon him.</p>
<p>Legend has it that brave warriors screamed and fainted when the skene door opened to show the Furies surrounding the hapless Orestes. Pregnant women miscarried on the spot (belying the conventional wisdom that women weren’t allowed into the theaters).</p>
<p>It was a sensation.</p>
<p>Hyperbole, most likely, but it underscores the fear with which the ancient Greeks regarded the Erinyes, ancient goddesses of justice and retribution. The punishments are terrible. Orestes was right to shelter in the only place that might give him sanctuary from their vengeance. Madness, disease, starvation, and agony are just a few of the weapons in their arsenal. In some ancient depictions they just look like winged women, but in most they are ghastly, with snakes entwined in their hair and coiled around their waists, carrying whips, with the faces of hags. In later works they’re said to serve Hades and Persephone by torturing criminals for eternity in a prequel to the Christian Hell.</p>
<p>If the attention of these goddesses seems extreme, consider what it must have been like to live in a society with no police force, jail, or rehabilitation systems. Travelers could die if not given shelter, but who today would unlock the door and welcome an unexpected stranger to their hearth? Without ironclad taboos against foul play, endless clan vengeance was the only recourse (and indeed, that is at the heart of Aeschylus’s trilogy.) Fear of divine retribution was all that kept citizens of a nefarious bent from preying upon the more generous of the population.</p>
<p>Their parentage differs according to source, but most consider them born of the drops of blood that fell to the earth when Kronus castrated his father Ouranos. They are more ancient than the Olympians, and while some say they bring about the will of Zeus, a more likely explanation is that the god of Law rarely has cause to interfere with the punishments meted out by these goddesses. They number at least three: Alekto, or Anger; Magaera, or Jealousy; Tisiphone, or Avenger. Crimes against the natural order are the ones most likely to get their attention—violence against family members, particularly the elderly or very young; murder, especially within a family (killing in battle is exempt); hubris, or disrespect toward the gods; violation of xenia, the <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22783 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Orestes_Pursued_by_the_Furies_by_William-Adolphe_Bouguereau_1862_-_Google_Art_Project-300x249.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="249" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Orestes_Pursued_by_the_Furies_by_William-Adolphe_Bouguereau_1862_-_Google_Art_Project-300x249.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Orestes_Pursued_by_the_Furies_by_William-Adolphe_Bouguereau_1862_-_Google_Art_Project-1024x850.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Orestes_Pursued_by_the_Furies_by_William-Adolphe_Bouguereau_1862_-_Google_Art_Project-768x638.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Orestes_Pursued_by_the_Furies_by_William-Adolphe_Bouguereau_1862_-_Google_Art_Project-1536x1276.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Orestes_Pursued_by_the_Furies_by_William-Adolphe_Bouguereau_1862_-_Google_Art_Project-2048x1701.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />ancient law of reciprocal hospitality.<br /><br />Orestes is the only recorded victim who escaped their wrath, and it took a gigantic societal shift for it to happen. After a trial with the Erinyes as prosecutors, Apollon as defense attorney and Athena as judge, the court system takes over judgment in these cases. The Furies are forced to accept being relegated to protective spirits, propitiated in a temple built for them in Athens and being re-named the Eumenides, or Kindly Ones. Clearly this is an effort to keep them pacified, like referring to meddlesome fae as the Good Folk.</p>
<p>Theseus, that bold-faced buccaneer, gets rescued from being stuck to a stone chair and whipped endlessly by the Furies when Herakles comes along and yanks him free. He leaves behind the skin of his buttocks, later healed by a skin graft from a sheep. His descendants are said to keep warm in winter from wearing the wool grown on the arse of their esteemed ancestor.</p>
<p>But if you’re not lucky enough to have a mighty hero, or in Orestes’s case a god or two, in your court, you’re going to have to rely on purification and atonement. Herakles himself learned this lesson after murdering his wife and children, then suffering madness at the hands of the Erinyes. His purification ritual was so intense that it became the basis for the Lesser Eleusinian Mysteries, which provide appropriate cleansing for the Greater Eleusinian Mysteries, which require stringent ritual purity. The <em>Argonautika</em> describes rites used by the witch Circe to free a murderer from torment by the Erinyes, and other sources tell how one can use the blood of a piglet or a nice fat steer or, more reliably, the intercession of Apollon. But atonement of some sort is always required. No free rides when it comes to the Erinyes.</p>
<p>Voices in the wind. They shriek and gibber. Fear knots in the pit of your stomach. They are coming.</p>
<p>Search your mind. Have you violated the ancient laws? Have you disrespected your parents or abused the elderly? Committed murder? Have you behaved improperly toward a supplicant of your favor? Worst of all, have you violated xenia?</p>
<p>If so, beware. The goddesses who govern curses that haunt any of these types of criminality will pursue you relentlessly, to madness, death, and beyond.</p>
<p>Better start running.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.theoi.com/Khthonios/Erinyes.html">https://www.theoi.com/Khthonios/Erinyes.html</a><br /><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Erinyes">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Erinyes</a><br /><a href="http://www.neokoroi.org/religion/gods/eumenides/">http://www.neokoroi.org/religion/gods/eumenides/</a><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-erinyes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The All-Prevailing Night</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-all-prevailing-night/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Suz Thackston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 12:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Waifs, Wolves & Warriors - Women in Greek Mythology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22054#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=22054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the dawn of creation emerge the Protogenoi, the primordial gods who set in place&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>At the dawn of creation emerge the Protogenoi, the primordial gods who set in place the very foundations of the cosmos.<br /><br />One of the first children of Kaos from whom everything else flows is Nyx, the goddess of night. Modern folk tend to conflate her with her sibling and mate Erebos, or Darkness, but they are not the same being. It is through the union of Night and Darkness that Hemera, the goddess of Day, and Aethyr, the bright upper air, come into being. <br /><br />Night and Darkness bear within them the seeds of Light.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22197 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/goddess-4825714_1920-300x240.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="240" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/goddess-4825714_1920-300x240.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/goddess-4825714_1920-1024x819.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/goddess-4825714_1920-768x614.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/goddess-4825714_1920-1536x1229.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/goddess-4825714_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><br /><br />Nyx has a host of other children, most conceived parthenogenetically. Hypnos (Sleep), Thanatos (Death), Moros (Doom), Oizys (Pain), the Keres (Destroyers), the Moirai (Fates), Eris (Strife), Geras (Old Age) and Hades’ ferryman, Kharon, are just a few of her unsettling offspring.<br /><br />One shouldn’t get too hung up on the family trees of the Protogenoi, though, as they get scrambled into all sorts of interesting combinations by various sources. The main thing to keep in mind is that she’s one of the very first.<br /><br />Nyx was envisioned by ancient authors as being the mists that veil the sky at eveningfall and obscure the light of day. Hemera scatters her mother’s mists with the rising of Helios the sun and allows Aethyr to shine through.<br /><br />Like all the Protogenoi, Nyx is viewed with a mixture of caution and reverence by the ancient Greeks. Some describe her as a figure of terror, driving a shadowy chariot drawn by raging, inky horses. Yet others speak rapturously of her diaphanous veils, stars gleaming through the mists and swirling around her.<br /><br />The Orphics regard Nyx as a field of unknowability, without personality or consciousness as we understand it. We conceive of her as a goddess and ascribe human-like attributes to her because we need these handles in order to wrap our minds around the idea of her. But, as we can see from the almost non-existent cultus to her in the ancient world, praying to her or setting up shrines and rituals to propitiate her or attempting to communicate with her directly indicate a fundamental misunderstanding of her nature. Her darkness is indicative of her being utterly beyond our comprehension. She is only a single emanation from Kaos, the potential in which everything exists but is not yet manifest. She is a cauldron. A melting pot. A womb.<br /><br /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22199 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/woman-644000_1920-300x212.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="212" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/woman-644000_1920-300x212.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/woman-644000_1920-1024x724.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/woman-644000_1920-768x543.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/woman-644000_1920-1536x1086.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/woman-644000_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Watch the sun sink and the veils gather. Observe the way the eastern sky brightens in concordance with the sunset flare of colors, then faints into the arms of Erebos. Wonder at the stealthy debut of the stars as they prick through the deepening blue. The sky at dusk is so entrancing that night will likely enfold your world entirely before you look around and realize how engulfed you are in the cloak of Nyx.<br /><br />You’re not outside of her. You are part of the warp and weft of her being. Like the stars themselves, you gleam in her veils. Breathe her into your lungs and belly. You are a creature of the night. <br /><br />Don’t worship Nyx with shrines and statues. Immerse yourself in her. <br /><br />Her very self sparkles with stars. <br /><br />You are one of them.<br /><br /><br />https://www.theoi.com/Protogenos/Nyx.html#Cosmogony<br />https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nyx<br />http://www.hellenion.org/nyx/orphic-hymn-to-nyx/<br />https://www.hellenicgods.org/nyx&#8212;nyx<br /><br /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Antigone the SJW</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/antigone-the-sjw/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/antigone-the-sjw/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Suz Thackston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Waifs, Wolves & Warriors - Women in Greek Mythology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19690#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=19690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Antigone is probably not a lot of fun to go out drinking with. In addition&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19695 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Antigone is probably not a lot of fun to go out drinking with. In addition to being morally upright, devoted to family, committed to doing the right thing no matter how difficult and devoutly pious, she is inflexible, judgmental, argumentative, and maybe even a little priggish.<br /><br />Antigone’s play was written by the great playwright Sophokles who was famous for creating the &#8220;tragic hero&#8221;, a character faced with a crisis in which disaster can only be averted by compromise which entails a total betrayal of something they hold supremely important. They refuse to accept the compromise despite persuasion, threats, or violence, resulting in being termed &#8220;deinos&#8221;, a term which means terrible, wondrous and strange, and ending in destruction. Most Sophoklean heroes are both admirable and repellent, and Antigone is no exception.<br /><br />She stands in splendid isolation.<br /><br />Antigone’s story is set in Thebes, a city viewed by golden age Athens as a place where conflicts and dilemmas get pushed to their limits and resolution is impossible. Its concerns with polis (city-state) politics is especially interesting considering its first production during the height of Athens’s glory, then resurfacing sixty years after Sophokles’s death when the famous orator Demosthenes read to his political opponent Kreon’s speech on the proper loyalties of a citizen. Even Aristotle quotes the play repeatedly in his treatise <em>Politics</em>.<br /><br />Antigone and her siblings are the children of Oedipus and his mother/wife Jocasta, whom he married with neither of them knowing the other’s identity. This family is ill-omened right out of the gate. The two boys, Eteokles and Polynices, are dead, having just killed each other in the battle for the soul of Thebes told more fully in Aeschylus’s <em>Seven Against Thebes</em>. Antigone and her sister Ismene are left to mourn them as their uncle Kreon takes over the rulership of Thebes. His first act as king is to declare Eteokles, who fought on behalf of Thebes to hold the throne, a hero, and Polynices, who attempted to enforce his claim on the throne by attacking Thebes, a traitor. Eteokles is to be buried with full honors, Polynices to be left unburied for the scavengers. Anyone who attempts to bury him will be stoned to death.<br /><br />Antigone is having none of it.<br /><br />She tells her sister that she plans to defy Kreon and bury Polynices, in accordance with both divine law and family obligation. Ismene, while sympathetic, is afraid of the anger of the new king, and points out that they owe him their fealty both as head of their oikos (household) and their ruler. Antigone flares up at this and declares that even if her sister has a change of heart and wants to help, Antigone won’t let her, pointing out that “Even if I die in the act, that death will be a glory,” and, “I have longer to please the dead than to please the living here.”<br /><br />Ismene, representing the obedience expected of a good ancient Greek maiden, fears for Antigone and begs her to at least do the burial honors on the sly. Antigone sneers at her for her cowardice, adding, “I will suffer nothing as great as death without glory,” before sweeping out on a wave of self-righteousness, leaving poor Ismene to flounder in her wake, meeping her terror and love for her sister.<br /><br />Kreon is a bloviator. In his declaration of his own kingship he extols his own virtues as a man who has been tested and demonstrated amply his own character, principles, and judgement, as well as mansplaining how anyone who places friendship over patriotism is worthless. “Such are my standards. They make a city great.” Even the admiring chorus, consisting of the elderly citizens of Thebes, is a little anxious about the absolutist statements. Their concern gets them browbeaten into abject accord with their king.<br /><br />When a messenger enters and, after some hemming and hawing, delivers the news that an unknown person has performed the rites over Polynices’s corpse, the chorus suggests timidly that it might be the work of the gods. Kreon erupts in fury that anyone could defy his edict, let alone think the gods would care about the disposition of the body of a traitor. He leaps to the unfounded assumption that his soldiers have been bribed, and promises the hapless sentry who <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19696 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tom-morel-SbPXdHqnI84-unsplash-300x192.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="192" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tom-morel-SbPXdHqnI84-unsplash-300x192.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tom-morel-SbPXdHqnI84-unsplash-1024x654.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tom-morel-SbPXdHqnI84-unsplash-768x491.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tom-morel-SbPXdHqnI84-unsplash-1536x981.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/tom-morel-SbPXdHqnI84-unsplash-2048x1308.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />brought the news that unless he produces the traitor, Kreon will “String you up alive and wring the immortality out of you.” After being denied the opportunity to speak in his own defense, the sentry declares that he’s heading for the hills, leaving the chorus to mutter about doom and evil portents.<br /><br />But the sentry is back before too long, hauling a bound Antigone with him. He tells his irascible king that he and his men were wronged by Kreon’s harsh words, but since they caught the real perpetrator in the act they felt duty-bound to bring it to Kreon’s attention. He adds that nonetheless he’s decamping, as he wants nothing more to do with Thebes’s jerk-in-chief.<br />He gives the story in gory detail, describing the slimy, softening corpse and its smell. A dust storm blinded them, but when it passed they saw the wailing girl, scooping up dry dust to scatter over her brother and pouring libations from a fine bronze urn onto the corpse. She did not flinch from arrest nor make any attempt to lie or evade her captors. When Kreon demands she speak she shrugs and says, “I did it. I don’t deny a thing.” She informs her uncle that she is obeying divine law which supersedes that of a mere mortal king and that dying will be a small pain compared with the dishonor Kreon offers her brother. <br /><br />The chorus shake their heads, mumbling about how like her father Oedipus she is—wild, passionate, unable to bend in adversity. But Kreon vows to break her, as tempered iron, spirited horses, and slaves all break when their lord and master lowers the boom. He accuses her of insolence, not just for her actions but her lack of shame over them, then whirls on poor Ismene and accuses her of complicity. <br /><br />Ismene is in hysterics but Antigone is coldly scornful. She asks what, other than her arrest and execution, her uncle wants of her and snaps at him to stop moralizing and get on with it. She mocks the chorus for being wimps and accuses Kreon of being power-drunk, causing Kreon to shout, “Go down below and love, if love you must. Love the dead! While I’m alive no woman is going to lord it over me.”<br /><br />Antigone will not even allow her devastated sister to share her fate. “Never share my dying, don’t lay claim to what you never touched. My death will be enough.” At this point Ismene lets us know that Antigone is actually engaged to Kreon’s son Haemon by pleading with Kreon to consider this, but Kreon sniffs that “There are other fields for him to plough.” He has guards take the girls away as the chorus moans about generational curses.<br /><br />Haemon tries to soften his dad’s position by promising filial obedience, which does indeed please the king. Kreon tells his son that being married to a disobedient woman would be a misery and to spit her out and let her make her bed among the dead. Haemon points out that although unmaidenly, Antigone’s position is noble. That while he’s proud of his dad, maybe just a smidgeon less self-righteousness might not hurt, and that no one is infallible. A bitter, sharp exchange follows, ending with Kreon accusing his son of being a woman’s slave, and Haemon calling Kreon crazy and hinting darkly that Antigone’s death will cause another death. Kreon splutters that he’ll bring the dang girl out then and there and kill her in front of Haemon. Haemon rushes out yelling that Kreon will never see him again. When the chorus prophesies that Haemon might do something stupid in his rage, Kreon replies wearily that nothing his son can do will save the girls. The chorus, aghast, asks if he’s really planning to execute both of his nieces. A crack appears in his armor of fury and he commutes Ismene’s sentence and changes Antigone’s from stoning to being walled up in a cave.<br /><br />Left alone to ponder all of this awfulness, the chorus talks about the terrible, destructive power of Love. When Antigone is escorted back to stand before them, they bemoan having to watch her go to her fate while she weeps that her bridal bed will be that of Hades, not her longed-for husband. They all agree that this is a continuation of Oedipus’s ghastly story of passion, incest, and murder. Kreon, entering just in time to hear this last, counters with, “Your own blind will, your passion has destroyed you.” Denying her last request to say goodbye to her loved ones, he orders the guards to take her away and immure her swiftly. She is dragged out lamenting her unjust fate, calling upon the gods to witness that she never transgressed, and to mete out to her tormentors a fate at least as horrible as her own.<br /><br />The blind seer, Tiresias, tells Kreon that the gods are angry with him and that perhaps he should rethink some of his recent decisions. After a furious argument in which Kreon accuses Tiresias of taking bribes, the seer storms out. But Kreon is shaken despite himself. He tells the chorus that he will go himself and set Antigone free, leaving them to praise Dionysos in their relief. <br /><br />But it’s short-lived. <br /><br />A messenger enters and tells them that despite all the great things Kreon has done for Thebes he is not to be envied. Kreon’s wife Eurydice comes along and asks why all their faces are so <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19697 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/levi-clancy-jZaQOzrC3XU-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/levi-clancy-jZaQOzrC3XU-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/levi-clancy-jZaQOzrC3XU-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/levi-clancy-jZaQOzrC3XU-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/levi-clancy-jZaQOzrC3XU-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/levi-clancy-jZaQOzrC3XU-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />long. The gruesome details unspool. The messenger went with Kreon to Polydices’s poor disintegrating body and washed and buried it properly. Upon returning to the city, they heard a long wail, which Kreon recognized as the voice of his son. They rushed to Antigone’s tomb and dragged away the rocks, only to find her hanging from a noose made from her own veils. Haemon clung to her, shrieking, but when Kreon tried to pull him off, Haemon spat at him and lunged at him with a sword. Kreon ran away and Haemon threw himself upon the sword, clutching his wife-to-be’s body to him. Upon hearing this dreadful news, Eurydice leaves without saying a word. <br /><br />As the chorus and the messenger speculate uneasily on the queen’s next move, Kreon enters with Haemon’s body on a bier. As they all mourn, another messenger arrives to deliver the news that Eurydice has also committed suicide. Her body is brought out on an &#8220;ekkyklema&#8221; (a &#8220;rolled-out thing&#8221;). Confronted with all this death, Kreon is overcome with horror and grief. “Come, let it come! The best of fates for me that brings the final day, the best fate of all! Oh quickly now—so I never have to see another sunrise. Whatever I touch goes wrong—once more a crushing fate’s come down upon my head.”<br /><br />The play ends with the chorus saying, “Wisdom is by far the greatest part of joy.”<br /><br />Antigone is an early Rosa Parks, performing a dangerous act of civil disobedience. She undervalues her duty to her polis, maybe, but then we have to look at Kreon undervaluing his to family and oikos. Kreon believes that citizens must obey laws even if they disagree or there will be anarchy; Antigone that individual understanding of right behavior supersedes human law or there will be totalitarianism. Finding a balance is no less a problem today than it was in 5th century BCE Athens. <br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /><a href="https://www.greekmythology.com/Myths/Mortals/Antigone/antigone.html">https://www.greekmythology.com/Myths/Mortals/Antigone/antigone.html</a><br /><br /><a href="https://www.ancient.eu/Greek_Theatre/#:~:text=Greek%20theatre%20began%20in%20the,influenced%20Hellenistic%20and%20Roman%20theatre.">https://www.ancient.eu/Greek_Theatre/#:~:text=Greek%20theatre%20began%20in%20the,influenced%20Hellenistic%20and%20Roman%20theatre.</a><br /><br /><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antigone">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antigone</a><br /><br /><a href="https://www.ancient-literature.com/greece_sophocles_antigone.html">https://www.ancient-literature.com/greece_sophocles_antigone.html</a><br /><br /><br /><br /><br /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/antigone-the-sjw/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hestia the Enigma</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hestia-the-enigma/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hestia-the-enigma/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Suz Thackston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 10:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Waifs, Wolves & Warriors - Women in Greek Mythology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19084#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=19084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Greek mythology is one of our richest sources of ancient tales. The gods, heroes, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Greek mythology is one of our richest sources of ancient tales. The gods, heroes, and spirits who populate the mountains and cities of ancient Greece throng our collective consciousness. Whether or not one reads or watches media about the Hellenic gods, almost all of us have absorbed bits and pieces, and are familiar with the names and some of the stories.<br /><br /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-19142 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Hestia_Giustiniani-160x300.jpg" alt="" width="160" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Hestia_Giustiniani-160x300.jpg 160w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Hestia_Giustiniani.jpg 483w" sizes="(max-width: 160px) 100vw, 160px" />But we run into a wall when we try to research the most widely-known and worshipped goddess of the pantheon. Hestia was at the center of each campfire, family dwelling, city structure and municipal office. The family prayers began and ended each day with libations to her. No feast or public meeting or religious ritual could begin without invoking her favor at the beginning and thanking her at the end. Her most famous epithet is &#8220;First and Last&#8221; because she was so very ubiquitous in every facet of Hellenic life, from the poorest hovel to the grandest palace.<br /><br />So why the dearth of myths about her? <br /><br />Let’s start with what we do know. She is the oldest daughter of the Titans Kronos and Rhea, and sister to five of the most important Olympians—Zeus, Demeter, Poseidon, Hera and Hades. Her &#8220;first and last&#8221; designation comes from the gruesome myth of Kronos devouring his own children. Fearing that his offspring will follow his example and depose him as he did his own father, Ouranos, he seizes each baby as Rhea bears them, beginning with Hestia, and gulps them down. Keeping them safely contained within his own body ensures his continued dominance, or so he thinks. Rhea is none too pleased with this treatment of her children. After bearing her youngest, Zeus, she offers her husband a stone wrapped in swaddling clothes, while the baby is whisked off to Crete to be raised in secret. Blissfully unaware, Kronos gulps down the stone. When Zeus comes of age, he conspires with his grandmother Gaia to sneak an emetic into Kronos’s wine. Kronos proceeds to vomit up his children in the backwards order of their swallowing, so firstborn Hestia emerges last. This is where we get the epithet, although it’s far more likely that the myth came into being to explain the cult practice rather than the other way around. <br /><br />The same is true about one of the few other myths we have about Hestia, the one explaining her status as &#8220;parthenos&#8221; or eternal virgin. Like her nieces Athena and Artemis, Hestia eschews sexual activity. Both her brother Poseidon and her nephew Apollo are enamored of her and seek to seduce her. She petitions Zeus to grant her permanent unmarried status and he grants it to her. It should be noted that some modern scholars translate &#8220;parthenos&#8221; as a woman not under male control, one free to make her own choices, rather than being in a state of permanent chastity.<br /><br />The only other story associated with Hestia comes from Ovid’s <em>Fasti</em>, thousands of years after her worship was established. Rhea gives a great banquet, inviting all the gods, satyrs, nymphs and nature spirits, including Priapos. He is a minor god who protects gardens, beehives, and flocks, and is known for his comically enormous phallus and erotic proclivities. Hestia withdraws from the festivities to nap in the garden where Priapos spies her. He tries to sneak up on her but is spotted by a donkey who brays loudly and wakes the goddess. At her shriek, the other gods come flying to her rescue and lascivious Priapos is soundly beaten for his presumption. But it must be noted that Ovid tells almost the exact same story within the same work, but names the nymph Lotis as the object of Priapos’s unseemly desire. There are no Greek works that tell this tale. <br /><br />For any other goddess, this lack of stories would indicate lack of importance. But Hestia is a civic goddess without parallel. The centrality of the hearth from the rudest cave to the most lavish palace cannot be overstated. When colonists set forth from their own towns to found new settlements, they took flame from their community hearths and used it to consecrate their new homes. The birth of children was celebrated with the &#8220;amphidromia&#8221; ritual by carrying the baby <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19143 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jeremy-bishop-td7G4W1HSIE-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jeremy-bishop-td7G4W1HSIE-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jeremy-bishop-td7G4W1HSIE-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jeremy-bishop-td7G4W1HSIE-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jeremy-bishop-td7G4W1HSIE-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/jeremy-bishop-td7G4W1HSIE-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />around the hearth, introducing them to the goddess. It was the job of town and city officials to tend the communal flame, and considered a terrible omen and dereliction of duty if it should go out. If the central fire died a new one had to be kindled from a lightning strike, a &#8220;burning glass&#8221; i.e. sunlight magnified through glass, or rubbing sticks together. A family could relight their own hearth fires from the municipal hearth, but the public hearth required wildfire. <br /><br />My scarcity of source material led to much hair-tearing when it came to writing this blog post. Other than my daily practice of offering my first cup of coffee and final prayers to Hestia every day, I had little on which to hang my authorial hat. So I did the next best thing. I contacted two friends whose devotional practices revolve around this elusive goddess.<br /><br />I chatted first with Anne Hatzakis of the greekrevivalistmommy blog who has been writing about Hestia and her importance in ancient Greek culture for years. Anne’s blog, linked at the end of this post, isn’t solely about Hestia but a simple search yields a wealth of posts and essays that emphasize how vital the goddess’s influence was in every facet of rural and urban life. She also wrote the excellent essay, &#8220;Hestia: the Overlooked Olympian,&#8221; also linked below.<br /><br />Then I had a long and fascinating conversation with Melitta Stafford, a devotee of Hestia whose involvement with the goddess goes all the way back to her childhood. While much of the conversation involved the facts of Hestian worship discussed in this post and more extensively in Anne’s work, Melitta has some unusual insights about how Hestia’s centrality to life and association with the hearth had an unexpected impact on her life.</p>
<p>As a child, Melitta was homeless and queer, a combination uniquely able to make a young person feel unsafe. A vision of a simple fire came to her during a prayer of desperation. Research led her to Hestia, to whom she prayed for a home and family of her own. But Hestia began with helping Melitta find her home in an even more personal way, within her very skin. The realization that she is a woman and her subsequent transition meant that Melitta could finally be at home in her own body. Or, as this very Southern gal puts it, “Home is where the heart is” in the most literal possible sense. Melitta also pointed out the unusual fact that Hestia’s temples were not only the first stop for new arrivals, but places of sanctuary where refugees and criminals could claim sanctuary. Unlike many gods, Hestia’s compassion extends to people without arete, the Greek concept of excellence (or even goodness.) All are welcome to partake of her warmth. <br /><br />Hestia was so intrinsically associated with the hearth that the names become conflated. You often find references to the &#8220;family hestia,&#8221; where light, warmth, cooking, and fellowship all took place. It is interesting that there are so few statues or artistic renderings of her, in light of her importance in all family and community activities. She is usually depicted as a young woman, modestly attired and often veiled, with a gentle face. The many hymns written to her underscore attributes of gentleness, grace and kindness. Some writers even claim that she gives up her seat upon Olympos to Dionysos, the later and more ebullient arrival, in keeping with her desire to live a quiet life out of the limelight. Others push back against this interpretation in light of her importance to humanity.<br /><br />Maybe it’s easy to overlook the quiet goddess with few famous statues or epic tales. The Greeks in whose society her worship arose seemed content to enjoy her perpetual presence in their midst without requiring much beyond the first and last libations at feasts, first fruits, or an occasional offering of her sacred animals, the pig or a year-old cow.</p>
<p>But one should keep in mind what beginnings and endings entail. There is the pain and blood of childbirth juxtaposed with the fear and finality of death. Or, on a larger scale, the cataclysm of the Big Bang set against the potential cold silence at the end of the universe. <br />When I ask her about these matters, all I get is a secret smile. <br /><br /><br />https://greekrevivalistmommy.com/<br /><br />https://sites.google.com/site/hellenionstemenos/Home/articles-and-essays/hestia-overlookedolympian<br /><br />https://www.theoi.com/Ouranios/Hestia.html<br /><br />http://www.hellenion.org/hestia/<br /><br />https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hestia</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hestia-the-enigma/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ariadne, the Cretan Princess</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ariadne-the-cretan-princess/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ariadne-the-cretan-princess/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Suz Thackston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Waifs, Wolves & Warriors - Women in Greek Mythology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17902#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=17902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ariadne did not respond to my Facebook friend request. In fact, none of the usual&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Ariadne did not respond to my Facebook friend request. In fact, none of the usual methods of introduction worked, not the hopeful offerings left in the orchard, not the poring over source material and internet links, not standing under the starlight and chanting her name. <br /><br />Finally, after several fruitless weeks, I tried something different. I carried raw milk and a chocolate truffle into the almost-full moonlight, poured out the libation onto the roots of the Dionysos pine tree and began to dance.<br /><br /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18102 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/beasty-7aUgMBxhVNU-unsplash-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/beasty-7aUgMBxhVNU-unsplash-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/beasty-7aUgMBxhVNU-unsplash-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/beasty-7aUgMBxhVNU-unsplash-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/beasty-7aUgMBxhVNU-unsplash-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/beasty-7aUgMBxhVNU-unsplash-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/beasty-7aUgMBxhVNU-unsplash-2048x2048.jpg 2048w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/beasty-7aUgMBxhVNU-unsplash-550x550.jpg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Her story ran through my mind like brilliant threads on a loom. You know it. The Cretan princess who fell in love with the dashing hero, Theseus, defying her father to help him. The one who devised the ingenious method of bringing her lover safely back through the labyrinth by giving him a ball of yarn, which he unrolled, then followed back out after killing the Minotaur. <br /><br />What sort of relationship did she have with her monstrous half-brother, with his man’s body and bull’s head and carnivorous appetite? How about her bloodthirsty father, Minos, who had the labyrinth built to contain his stepson, then demanded an annual tribute from Athens of boys and girls to feed the beast? And what of her sexually adventurous mother, Pasiphae, who slaked her lust for Minos’ prize bull by donning a cow suit? Was Theseus a real love for her or just a girlish infatuation with a famous hero?<br /><br />Most importantly—did he abandon her, did she die, or did she really become the cherished bride of Dionysos? Accounts vary wildly. Some say Theseus absentmindedly sailed off, leaving her sleeping on the beach. Others insist that she was pregnant and her lover wasn’t interested in becoming a daddy. There are accounts that claim she died in childbirth, others that Artemis took her down with her deadly arrows. But how then did she end up with her own constellation?<br /><br />Unanswered questions spun in my mind, then whirled off into the night sky as I danced. All conscious thought slipped away, bit by bit, as the spiral dance took possession of me. The dog and cats kept pace with me for a while, then dropped out and went about their individual night journeys as I danced and danced, in front of the shrines, between the trees, a complex pattern through the orchard, around the house, down the driveway, up onto the deck with the early mosquitoes buzzing in my ears. <br /><br />Eventually, I realized I was not alone; Ariadne whirled beside me, spun circles around me, pirouetted past me, casting a silvery shadow on the cold grass.<br /><br />The dance took all my breath, leaving none for speech. We danced together, the Cretan princess and I, the wild wind blowing our hair across our faces, Orion’s Belt pointing to the pure radiance of Venus, the moon tossed amid the branches of the orchard trees who danced along with us. <br /><br />The princess, the bride, the goddess is forever young, but I am old and heavy-limbed. Finally I could dance no more, and collapsed on the bench at the Demeter shrine to catch my breath. Eyes glinting, Ariadne prowled around me, her hair in tangled ringlets, dangling past her hips. She was so heart-stoppingly innocent, a lamb, a kitten, so unaware and at risk in the windswept night. I wanted to cradle and protect her, take her inside, keep her safe, wall her away from wild things and spirits who would prey upon her heedless gaiety. <br /><br />But a glimpse of those wide topaz eyes held me back. For all her innocence, she is supremely dangerous. A young tigress, to be admired and even adored, but never approached without the full understanding that she might kill you. It could be deliberate, or absent-minded, or even affectionate, an annoyed swat with razor claws. She might be sad when she wanted to dance or play with you again, but there would never be remorse, for there would be no malice. She might dance ecstatically with you, exuberant and mesmerizing, then become over-excited and take a bite out of you. She would dance away, laughing, with crimson lips and bright eyes, then return and prod your bleeding corpse, baffled at your limpness. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18103 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/hulki-okan-tabak-spmbpgtvOiw-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/hulki-okan-tabak-spmbpgtvOiw-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/hulki-okan-tabak-spmbpgtvOiw-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/hulki-okan-tabak-spmbpgtvOiw-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/hulki-okan-tabak-spmbpgtvOiw-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/hulki-okan-tabak-spmbpgtvOiw-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/hulki-okan-tabak-spmbpgtvOiw-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1706w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><br /><br />But so sweet. So compellingly, irresistibly sweet. <br /><br />No wonder Theseus fled from her in terror when he realized that the amoral feral nymph he had mistaken for a mere princess might kill him in his bed. No wonder Dionysos fell in love with her and crowned her his bride. She’s the epitome of a maenad. <br /><br />My cats prowled with her, wary but intrigued. The dog pressed tightly against my legs, trembling slightly. <br /><br />The princess did not speak to me. She pulled my hair, tugged at my hand, tried to entice me into dancing with her again, but the fire had drained from my limbs, and all I could do was watch her in wonder. She bared her teeth at me, and for a long, chilling moment I thought she might go for my throat, but she turned away and wandered disconsolately between the cherry trees, a silver-white blossom drifting down to catch in her hair. The cats followed her, and for a while the four of them danced together, leaving dark prints in the silvered dew.<br /><br />The dog whined, looking up at me pleadingly. I looked down at her and rubbed her ears, scratching under her collar.<br /><br />When I looked up, Ariadne was gone. The cats were making their way back to us with delicate steps. <br /><br />I looked up at the moon-bright sky, finding the Big Dipper’s handle and following it down toward the north-east horizon, where <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corona_Borealis">Ariadne’s constellation</a>, the celestial crown, was just starting to blaze. <br /><br /><br /><a href="https://www.theoi.com/Georgikos/Ariadne.html">https://www.theoi.com/Georgikos/Ariadne.html</a><br /><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ariadne">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ariadne</a><br /><a href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/Ariadne-Greek-mythology">https://www.britannica.com/topic/Ariadne-Greek-mythology</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ariadne-the-cretan-princess/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
