<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Chloe N. Clark &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/chloe-n-clark/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 18:59:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Finale: Fare Thee Well</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/finale-fare-thee-well/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chloe N. Clark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 16:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ghosts and Fandoms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The title of this post comes from the song, but also from the surprisingly powerful&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The title of this post comes from the song, but also from the surprisingly powerful ending of a recent <em>Supernatural</em> episode, a show I&#8217;ve had a complicated relationship with over the past few years, but which was the first show that got me really into Fan Studies as an academic discipline. This seemed a particularly fitting title for a goodbye post then.</p>
<p>Since June of 2014, I&#8217;ve been lucky enough to write monthly columns for <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> (a magazine and website that I hold dear). In these columns I&#8217;ve talked Fan Studies and Genre Studies. However, like all great things (I think that&#8217;s how the cliche goes) it must come to an end. I&#8217;ve recently graduated from my MFA program and am seeking full-time teaching work and want to devote some time to that search, as well as completing revisions on a sci-fi novel I&#8217;ve been working on (during my MFA).</p>
<p>To send off this column, I thought it would be good to look at some additional resources for Fan Studies as well as to talk about some of the speculative shows (with fandoms surrounding them) that I have found the most compelling/powerful over the years.</p>
<p>One of the absolute best resources for Fandom scholars is the <a href="https://fanstudies.org/fan-studies-journals/">Fandom Studies Network</a>. They have a website, but also are on twitter and have a Facebook group. Their information on journals of Fandom Studies is fairly comprehensive. I&#8217;d also like to push two of my favorite fandom scholars (who I had the honor to interview for this column!): <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/s1e6-interview-with-a-fan-scholar-or-two-pt-1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lynn Zubernis and Katherine Larsen</a>, creators of <a href="https://fangasmthebook.wordpress.com/">Fangasm!</a></p>
<p>I also want to recommend some of the shows that have most influenced my own fandom studies: <em>Supernatural</em> (of course!), <em>The X-Files</em>, <em>Orphan Black</em>, <em>Battlestar Galactica</em>, <em>Veronica Mars</em>, <em>iZombie</em>, <em>The Misfits</em>, and <em>Dead Like Me</em>. All of these shows explore (or explored) genre in amazing ways (sometimes not through their entire runs, but it&#8217;s hard for perfection to last).</p>
<p>Finally, I&#8217;d like to send a big thank you out to <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> who not only published one of my short stories, early in my writing career, but also gave me this wonderful chance to write about something I love. I will continue to enjoy reading every amazing thing they publish. And, dear readers, if you&#8217;d like to keep up with me, I&#8217;ll still be tweeting so many things @PintsNCupcakes This may be the finale, but as always, Keep Fannin On!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S2/ E6: Eclipsing, an interview with the editors of Sunvault, Part 2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/s2-e6-eclipsing-an-interview-with-the-editors-of-sunvault-part-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chloe N. Clark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 16:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ghosts and Fandoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, favorite readers! Last month, was the first part of my interview with the editors&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello, favorite readers! <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/s2-e5-eclipsing-an-interview-with-the-editors-of-sunvault-part-1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Last month, was the first part of my interview</a> with the editors (Phoebe Wagner and Bront Weland) of the upcoming <em>Sunvault,</em> an anthology of eco-speculative writing and solar punk, which is being published by the lovely Upper Rubber Boot Press. A Kickstarter to help fund the anthology will begin soon and <a href="http://www.upperrubberboot.com/sunvault-will-open-for-submissions-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">submissions will also soon be open!</a></p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>1.) How did the idea for the anthology come about?</strong></p>
<p>PW: The lack of anything else in genre today. As I become more environmentally aware, I wanted to see how fantasy, science fiction, and horror were affecting these conversations. What I read usually leaned more toward apocalyptic stories, not always, but often. I hoped to find stories about characters trying to overcome rather than survive. My first introduction to solar punk emphasized the hope or positivity the genre tried to inspire, so I was drawn to that hope.</p>
<p>BW: This is all Phoebe&#8217;s fault. One day she came up to me and said, &#8220;I&#8217;ve been thinking about putting together an anthology of environmental SF. Do you want to help?&#8221; and here we are and its all been downhill from there.</p>
<p><strong>2.) You both are currently first year students in an MFA program with a focus on Environment. What does Environment mean to you in terms of your own writing? In terms of the pieces you hope to receive for the anthology?</strong></p>
<p>PW: In my work, environment primarily means setting. How woods or fields or farmland shapes different people. I&#8217;m branching into more environmentally pointed stories, but I like searching for the magic in a landscape and invoking it through words. For the anthology, I hope to read stories that directly engage with the environment, whether it&#8217;s a changing landscape or fossil fuel dependence. As long as there is a clear and creative engagement with the environment, preferably during a tipping point, I&#8217;ll keep reading.</p>
<p>BW: My environment has always been community. Language. Culture. Obviously, I&#8217;m invested in the health of our world&#8217;s physical environment, but I like to see the way these ripples disturb the ponds of smaller groups of people. For the anthology, physical, traditional environment is a priority, but I&#8217;m still hoping to see how this affects communities, not just the world.</p>
<p><strong>3.) Have either of you done editing work like this previously? What aspect most excited you about this project? Do you have plans of how you&#8217;ll be working together?</strong></p>
<p>PW: I&#8217;m finishing the transition to managing editor of the national journal <em><a href="https://flyway.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flyway: Journal of Writing and the Environment</a></em>, and what excites me about working with the journal is also what excites me about the anthology: seeing the work of fellow creators. As for how we will be working together, we already share an office in addition to weekly Dungeons &amp; Dragons sessions, so we have plenty of chances to check in and rearrange workloads or argue over our favorite pieces that have come in.</p>
<p>BW: I&#8217;ve spent some time as a slush reader and copywriter/editor, but this will be a totally new experience! I&#8217;m excited to dive into the creation of this project. The slush reading. The art. The reading. The reading. The reading. Finding that one story that you didn&#8217;t know you needed until it ended up in your slush pile. As I answer these questions, Phoebe is off to my right working on website design. She&#8217;s handling our main sites and I&#8217;m taking charge of social media and the majority of contact with the authors were talking with for commissions. Come submissions time, I have a feeling we&#8217;ll split the reading pile and still be overwhelmed, swimming in stories to get through.</p>
<p><strong>4.) I know that you&#8217;re planning a fundraiser for the anthology. Can you tell us about it?</strong></p>
<p>PW: The publisher, Upper Rubber Boot, will be hosting a Kickstarter in April. I&#8217;m excited to pick out the rewards, and hopefully some of those rewards will give us the opportunity to interact with our future readers! One reward is definitely going to be some space spray art painted by me, which I&#8217;m excited to give away! We have some exciting stretch goals to allow even more great artists and writers to submit work to the anthology.</p>
<p>BW: We&#8217;re running a Kickstarter that will be up in April. The rewards will be standard for anthology fundraisers, meaning different levels for eBooks, paper copies, personal thank yous, etc. but well also have extra flare at the higher levels. Not to mention stretch goals for more stories.</p>
<p><strong>5.) What will catch your eye as editors (in terms of pieces that will get accepted)? Is there anything potential submitters should stay away from in their stories? Any other advice for them?</strong></p>
<p>PW: Stay away from ending on the disaster. There&#8217;s more beyond that. I want the tipping points, but I want to see how people are fighting for hope or working toward change, even if the characters fail. Be creative! Don&#8217;t be afraid to try to solve these environmental problems.</p>
<p>BW: When I&#8217;m reading, my constant question is: Where&#8217;s the magic? I&#8217;m looking for stories that are magical in their language, in their ideas, in their execution. So twist my mind with prose that&#8217;ll blow me away. Make me think from new perspectives. Send us your stories that haven&#8217;t been told this way before. We especially hope to see submissions from authors outside the dominant, Anglophone world of SF: queer authors, disabled authors, and any underrepresented voices. We also want to see stories about these voices that we don&#8217;t often hear in SF. Hard sells will be overly didactic stories or stories that are just the patriarchy. I&#8217;ve read plenty of both and they never work for me. When it comes down to it, though, submit! If your story straddles the genre/non-genre line or walks the line of solarpunk or eco-speculation, send it. What&#8217;s the worst that could happen?</p>
<p><strong>6.) When will submissions open? How long will they stay open?</strong></p>
<p>At the moment, we are looking at about two months, starting in May.</p>
<p><strong>7.) Whats the thing you&#8217;re most excited about going into this project? Most nervous about?</strong></p>
<p>PW: I&#8217;m most excited to see the ideas of change that I want to find in these pages. Most nervous, making an anthology our readers can&#8217;t put down.</p>
<p>BW: I cant wait to explore this new genre and see what impossible things we will find in our submissions pile. I&#8217;m also giggly levels of excited about our cover art, too. Nervous? Do editors get nervous? As it turns out they do. Running a Kickstarter is scary. There&#8217;s a lot riding on it and in the end we can&#8217;t choose whether or not we get funded. So please, please consider backing us!</p>
<p><strong>8.) If you had to sum up the anthology in one sentence, you&#8217;d say:</strong></p>
<p>PW: This anthology will inspire you with a creative look at the environmental questions of today and tomorrow.</p>
<p>BW: <em>Sunvault</em> is something new entirely.</p>
<p><strong>14.) Question you wish I&#8217;d asked?</strong></p>
<p>PW: You did a wonderful job! Thanks, Chloe!</p>
<p>BW: When will the anthology be published? Were anticipating a Spring 2017 release. Which one of us is the real editor and which is the fake that hides behind the others hard work: The answer is Phoebe, to both.</p>
<p>Well, a big thank you to Phoebe (and, also, Bront). For now, check out <a href="https://www.facebook.com/sunvaultantho/?fref=ts">Sunvault on Facebook</a>, on Twitter (@Sunvaultantho), on <a href="http://morecolorfulmetaphors.tumblr.com/post/140231580134/sunvault-anthology-will-open-for-submissions-soon">Tumblr</a>, <a href="https://sunvaultantho.wordpress.com/">WordPress</a>, and the official page at <a href="http://www.upperrubberboot.com/sunvault/">Upper Rubber Boot Books</a>. As always, join the conversation @PintsNCupcakes and til next time: Keep Fannin On!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S2/ E5: Eclipsing, an interview with the editors of Sunvault, Part 1</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/s2-e5-eclipsing-an-interview-with-the-editors-of-sunvault-part-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chloe N. Clark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 17:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ghosts and Fandoms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As many of you know, dear readers, I often focus in on genre and its&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As many of you know, dear readers, I often focus in on genre and its uses. For the next two columns, I&#8217;m lucky to be able to bring you an interview with the editors (Phoebe Wagner and Bront Wieland) behind an awesome-sounding new anthology, <a href="http://www.upperrubberboot.com/sunvault/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Sunvault</em></a>. <em>Sunvault </em>will be <a href="http://www.upperrubberboot.com/sunvault-will-open-for-submissions-soon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">opening for submissions soon</a>, so this also a good chance for any writing readers to learn what the editors are looking for!</p>
<p><strong>1.) Hello, could you tell us a little bit about yourselves?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Phoebe Wagner (PW):</strong> Hi, Chloe (and dear readers)! I come from a small town in Pennsylvania where I grew up running wild outside pretending my backyard was Middle Earth, and I spent rainy or snowy days reading. When I&#8217;m not elbow deep in words, I love kayaking with my husband or chilling in a brew pub.</p>
<p><strong>Bronte Wieland (BW):</strong> Phoebe and I are both currently in our first year of Iowa States Creative Writing and Environment program. Are you familiar with it?</p>
<p>I did my undergrad at the University of Wisconsin Madison, studying Math and Linguistics. I was a writer then too, but it wasn&#8217;t my main focus. It was more a favorite and familiar hobby among the myriad new experiences I was trying to soak up at college. The plan was to work really hard and be a genius mathematician or go on to get a linguistics PhD looking at language documentation.</p>
<p>Somehow I ended up teaching ESL in Spain instead, where I had always wanted to live anyway, and where I found myself diving further into my writing than ever before. So I applied to programs and now, instead of living in the warmest climate in Europe, I&#8217;m back in the Midwest.</p>
<p><strong>2.) Describe your project.</strong></p>
<p><strong>PW:</strong> The anthology came about when I saw the lack of environmentally focused anthologies in the science fiction and fantasy genres. Bronte and I had recently discovered solar punk and felt the genre narrowed the scope and encouraged more community and hope. If everything comes together, the stories will inspire creative inspections of some of the greatest problems of our time: environmental issues.</p>
<p><strong>BW:</strong> Besides being really really exciting, SUNVAULT (published by Upper Rubber Boot Books) is an anthology of speculative short fiction that focuses on integral moments of change. SUNVAULT is bold, ambitious stories in science fictional, fantastical, or otherwise speculative settings, that deal with people experiencing and fighting to survive global and societal shifts. We want our authors to be looking past the narrow lens of apocalyptic, end-of-the-world literature. Stories of hope and overcoming hardship are just as important to us as the typical, sometimes easy, stories of disaster we often find when talking about major change.</p>
<p>We are looking within the framework of solarpunk, though, and its important to keep in mind the punk part of this genre distinction. It&#8217;s about counterculture, challenging norms, finding and embracing new views and new ways and waves of life.</p>
<p><strong>3.) This column is fascinated with genre (along with, of course, fan studies). Can you both discuss what genre means to you (as writers) and how it will play into your anthology?</strong></p>
<p><strong>PW:</strong> To me, genre means freedom. Yes, genre has its own boarders, but for each boarder, there is a writer or artist crossing into some new realm. My work has always drifted toward genre because I love pushing against the boundaries and seeing what weird roads my imagination drags me down.</p>
<p><strong>BW:</strong> As I&#8217;m sure everyone reading your column knows, genre is an impossible word. Genre extends so far, in my eyes. Science fiction, fantasy, horror, etc. all are obviously genre. Beyond the classic canon of SF lit, folklore is genre. Magical realism (Jorge Luis Borges, Isabel Allende, Gabriel Garcia Marquez) is genre. Emily St. John Mandels <em>Station Eleven</em> is genre. Helen Oyeyemi, Ruth Ozeki, Franz Kafka, China Miville, the list goes on forever. And this isn&#8217;t even mentioning all the amazing work coming out of magazines like <em>Shimmer</em>, <em>Asimovs</em>, <em>Beneath Ceaseless Skies</em>, <em>Fantasy &amp; Science Fiction</em>, <em>Uncanny</em>, and all the other magazines putting out SF right now.</p>
<p><strong>4.) Eco-spec and solar punk both sound fascinating. Can you describe them a bit more, though? What authors represent this for you?</strong></p>
<p><strong>PW:</strong> Well, eco-spec sounded good and captured this idea of engaging with fantasy and sci-fi, tapping into that creativity, but geared toward environmental issues. In regard to solar punk, Paolo Bacigalupi comes to mind. His novels <em>The Windup Girl</em> and <em>The Water Knife</em> embody the idea of tipping points and how characters react in such moments, whether inspired to problem solve, serve themselves, or make bucket-loads of cash. Since solar punk is so new, there isn&#8217;t a William Gibson of the movement yet. We hope our anthology can give rise to some of these voices and help build the genre. The foundation of the genre is currently Solarpunk. Notes toward a manifesto, created by Hieroglyph out of ASU, but its still a developing genre.</p>
<p><strong>BW:</strong> This is hard, because were working with incipient concepts here. Solarpunk and eco-speculation are emerging facets of genre and we&#8217;re hoping to help push them into full view. Solarpunk, at its core, is about a future, or an idea, of ingenuity in clean energy and sustainability. Especially with that idea of counterculture and community, as I mentioned above. Eco-speculation inspects the way we interact with, and change, our environment, and what effects that will have in the future. It&#8217;s the way we experiment recklessly with our surroundings like we would never be able to experiment on subjects that were visibly mortal. It&#8217;s about the ways we are careful too, and how we try to protect and defend the world around us. Think of Margaret Atwood&#8217;s MaddAddam trilogy. Think of Paulo Bacigalupis body of work. We don&#8217;t know of many authors writing firmly in these genres right now, so one of our hopes with the anthology is that we can find them and introduce them to the world.</p>
<hr />
<p>While that&#8217;s all of our room for now, the interview continues next month, when the interview will tackle submissions and the environment in writing. Until then, check out<a href="https://www.facebook.com/sunvaultantho/?fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> Sunvault on Facebook</a>, on Twitter (@Sunvaultanth), on <a href="http://morecolorfulmetaphors.tumblr.com/post/140231580134/sunvault-anthology-will-open-for-submissions-soon" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tumblr</a>, <a href="https://sunvaultantho.wordpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WordPress</a>, and the official page at <a href="http://www.upperrubberboot.com/sunvault/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Upper Rubber Boot Books</a>. As always, join the conversation @PintsNCupcakes and til next time: Keep Fannin&#8217; On!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S2/ E4: &#8221; Dr. Sexy, MD. I think it&#8217;s based on a book.&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/s2-e4-dr-sexy-md-i-think-its-based-on-a-book/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chloe N. Clark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 16:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ghosts and Fandoms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For this month’s column, I’ve decided to focus in on a specific episode from a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For this month’s column, I’ve decided to focus in on a specific episode from a specific fandom-beloved show: “Changing Channels” from the fifth season of <em>Supernatural</em>. I chose this specific episode, not only because it’s an episode that in many ways caters to its fanbase but also because it directly comments on and uses other genres. Please note that season five has a lot of dramatic happenings and SPOILERS are ahead so please read at your own caution.</p>
<p>“Changing Channels” is my favorite episode of <em>Supernatural</em>. In addition, I put it in my top-25 episodes of any television show of all time. I know, I know, these are some major claims I’m making here, but I’m not making them willy-nilly.</p>
<p><em>Supernatural </em>is a show known for episodes that play with dramatic structure and formula: from the alternate universe show-within-a-show of “The French Mistake” to the 200<sup>th</sup> episode which featured a musical based on the lives of the characters within the show. “Changing Channels,” however, is one of the first times they so obviously upended the nature of what makes a show. The cold open reveals the Winchesters partaking in a strangely forced version of a comedy, complete with opening credits that seem to be ripped from <em>Three’s Company</em> era shows, including a cheesy theme song.</p>
<p>We then jump back in time to see how the boys ended up in this predicament. It involves a Trickster and some inter-angel warfare, so I’m not going to get too far into the why. What it boils down to, though, is that the Winchesters are stuck “changing channels,” i.e. jumping from generic examples of different television show types until they can figure out how to get out of the loop. This allows the show to capitalize on the full conceits of many popular shows: romantic medical drama (<em>Dr. Sexy, MD) </em>to the afore-mentioned laugh-tracked situational comedy to a <em>CSI: Miami</em> that includes the characters all wearing sunglasses at night. The show utilizes not only the dialogue beats of each type of show, but also the camera-work, music, and acting.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/tumblr_m5mco2JlFE1r217qeo7_r3_250.gif" rel="attachment wp-att-5971"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5971 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/tumblr_m5mco2JlFE1r217qeo7_r3_250.gif" alt="tumblr_m5mco2JlFE1r217qeo7_r3_250" width="250" height="176" /></a></p>
<p>The episode becomes a kind of meta-commentary on what genre is and also how hard it is to fit into a genre when you don’t belong within it: Sam and Dean desperately want to return to their own show’s universe. <em>Supernatural</em> is at its most compelling when mixing genres: the show has never been purely horror and it knows that. This episode seeks to say that genres are things to jump between.</p>
<p>And, lastly, one of the reasons I find this episode so compelling is that it hides maybe its most brutal line of dialogue ever within the episode. Stuck in a Japanese-style game show, Dean must answer a question that he doesn’t understand (being that it’s spoken in Japanese). The question is whether the Winchester’s mother would still be alive if Sam was never born. The answer, which Dean gives correctly, is “Yes.” What’s brilliant about this is not only that it’s hiding a hopeless truth about the show within one of its most surreal and comedic moments, but that the truth is never actually revealed to either the Winchester’s, as neither understands Japanese which in some ways makes it a kinder moment.</p>
<p>While I’d love to dissect this episode in more depth, I’m running out of space. However, I’d love to know what your favorite episodes are? Favorite moment from “Changing Channels?” Let us know, @lunaquarterly or @PintsNCupcakes. Next month, I’ll be back with an interview with the editors behind an exciting new anthology! Til then: Keep Fannin’ On!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S2/ E3: Winchestered</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/s2-e3-winchestered/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chloe N. Clark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 16:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ghosts and Fandoms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If anyone goes into fandoms, there is one fandom that always seems to pop up&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If anyone goes into fandoms, there is one fandom that always seems to pop up on the internet. It was also the fandom that first drew me into fandom studies. A fandom that has a gif for everything (no, really they <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/mlew15/definitive-proof-that-the-supernatural-fandom-ha-h0se#.ia9EjPp4">do</a>) and more ship pairings between the 4 central characters than even seems possible. Yes, of course, I&#8217;m writing about <em>Supernatural.</em></p>
<p>The SPN fandom is too big for one column alone and so, here, I&#8217;ll be focusing more on an overview. <em>Supernatural </em>premiered on September 13<sup>th</sup>, 2005. It is now in its 11<sup>th</sup> season and, while some fans have defected due to what are reasonable complaints about the direction of the show, it retains an extremely vocal and large fan-base.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/index.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5455 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/index.jpg" alt="index" width="284" height="177" /></a>The essential premise is that two brothers (Sam and Dean Winchester) follow in their father&#8217;s footsteps: Hunting Things. Saving People. The Family Business. The things they hunt (and save people from) are demons and monsters straight out of folklore and mythology. One of the aspects that most drew me into the show was their use of these myths and stories: often staying true to the lore itself and to the feel of story-telling. The show, especially in its early seasons, felt like a filmic version of a collection of American folklore from women in white to passing chupacabra references.</p>
<p>The show relies on the chemistry between its lead actors and the now very lived in feel of their performances. Credit is due to Jensen Ackles and Jared Padalecki, who never seem to tire in their performances of these characters. In later seasons, the boys were joined by the stellar Misha Collins and Mark Sheppard (playing the angel Castiel and the King of Hell, respectively).</p>
<p>But, what makes the show such a draw for fandoms? One of the biggest aspects might be the involvement that the show, its actors and creators, have with their fans. Not only are they prevalent at conventions, but they maintain active social media presences where they engage their fans daily. They also incorporate the fandom itself into the shows canon (SPN may be the only show to ever pull off the notion of books being written about the main characters that spawn conventions, cosplay, and fan fiction within the universe of the show itself). In an episode from their last season, aptly titled &#8220;Fan Fiction&#8221;, there was an even musical based off of the books in the show that were written about the events of the show. I&#8217;m not even sure of the layers in that previous sentence and I&#8217;m the one that wrote it.</p>
<p>So, readers, who out there is an SPN fan? Are you sticking with the show? If so, what draws you to it? If you&#8217;ve left the show in the past few seasons, what pushed you away? Let us know @lunaquarterly or @PintsNCupcakes and until next time: Keep Fannin On!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S2/ E2: I Was a Teenage X-Phile</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/s2-e2-i-was-a-teenage-x-phile/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chloe N. Clark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 15:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ghosts and Fandoms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Truth is Out There. If you immediately sat up in your seat when reading&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Truth is Out There. If you immediately sat up in your seat when reading that line then you may, like me, be an X-Phile. I’ve decided to look at the <em>The X-Files </em>this month because of the impending reboot (continuation?) of the show.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/ciwpcygwiaanmd7-e1441941392883.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5205 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/ciwpcygwiaanmd7-225x300.jpg" alt="ciwpcygwiaanmd7" width="225" height="300" /></a>The show originally aired, on Fox, from 1993-2002. It quickly amassed a dedicated following, through its use of in-show mythology, chemistry between its leads, and smart blending of real science and almost-real science. David Duchovny was chronic believer Fox Mulder, and the sublime (yeah, really, there is nothing the woman can’t do) Gillian Anderson was skeptic Dana Scully.</p>
<p>The show smartly strode between two worlds: that of a show with an intricate mythology and overall story arc that became more and more developed as the show progresses, and that of a <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/MonsterOfTheWeek" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Monster of the Week</a> (arguably, <em>The X-Files</em> was one of the main progenitors of the Monster of the Week style). Looking back at the show now, I have to confess that the episodes I love and which still hold up are almost entirely the MotW ones. The mythology becomes too cluttered and riddled with holes. However, some of the singular episodes remain some of my favorite episodes of television ever (“Bad Blood,” “The Unnatural,” “Clyde Bruckman’s Final Repose,” and who can forget the horror of “The Host”? Shudder.)</p>
<p>The fandom of <em>The X-Files </em>called themselves X-Philes and were often firm Sculder shippers (that’s the portmanteau of my choosing). The chemistry between the leads made this an easy relationship to ship. I never shipped Sculder, loving seeing a platonic but still deeply loving friendship portrayed on television (alas, this was not to be).</p>
<p><em>The X-Files </em>remains compelling today for several reasons. One of them, I’d say, would be the depiction of Scully. Scully remains one of the best characters on television. She was competent, fiercely intelligent, funny, and allowed to both show her emotions and still be the more stoic character between her and Mulder (a rarity in a show with mixed gender leads). The show also dealt with faith in a fascinating way (at least for the majority of the show’s length, the last few seasons not so much). Scully, a skeptic and scientist, is deeply religious in her dedication to science and in her faith.</p>
<p>As the show, and X-Philes everywhere, prepares for its return, one has to wonder how the fandom will take this new incarnation of a deeply loved program. Will it right the wrongs of the show’s final seasons? A question for my readers: are you looking forward to the new X-Files? Why or why not? Contact me @lunaquarterly or @PintsNCupcakes and let us know. And til next time Keep Fannin’ On!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S2/ E1: First Fandoms</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/s2-e1-first-fandoms/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chloe N. Clark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 17:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ghosts and Fandoms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was recently thinking about how and why people join fandoms. There is the obvious:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was recently thinking about how and why people join fandoms. There is the obvious: they end up falling in love with a created world or characters. Yet, how does one go from being a passive fan to a true fandom member? Then, I began to wonder about the fandoms that get people started with fandoms.</p>
<p>So, I went back through my own memories to try to figure out which was my first fandom. Arguably, it was <em>The X-Files </em>(making me an X-Phile—the preferred name for the fandom’s members). I not only loved the show, but also read books about it and based on it (of which, there are surprisingly many). Why <em>The X-Files</em>? Well, not only was it well-written and acted with genuine chemistry between the cast (though, let me state here that I am firmly NOT a shipper of Mulder and Scully), but it also combined two of my favorite things: the procedural elements of detective shows with elements of the paranormal (which, it should be stated, differs from the supernatural, in that paranormal refers to unexplainable events believed to have roots in, as yet, undiscovered science). My other favorite show at the time was <em>Homicide: Life on the Street. </em>So, I firmly could consider myself as much part of a detective fandom as I am of any other. How did my enjoyment and “fanship” of these two shows differ? I remain a supreme fan of <em>Homicide </em>(which I will happily argue is one of the greatest television shows of all time) and less of a fan of <em>The X-Files. </em>While, I read books about <em>The X-Files</em> at the time and even wrote my first attempt at a spec screenplay as an episode of the X-Files when I was young, I would argue that <em>Homicide </em> has influenced my writing far more (through the amazing dialogue and construction of character arcs and scenes). So, which of these is the true “first fandom”?</p>
<p>In an informal survey of friends, most people stated their early fandom as being <em>Harry Potter. </em>Though, I wondered if that was a true first fandom or the first fandom that they consciously felt part of. Some friends stated an early love of <em>Power Rangers</em> but didn’t consider it a fandom because they were so young when viewing it. Is there an age requirement for fandoms? The recent fan-made update on <em>Power Rangers</em> (starring the brilliant Katee Sackhoff) shows an argument for their certainly being a fandom based around the show.</p>
<p>So, while I’m not sure that I’ve answered my original question, I may have raised some interesting questions for further exploration. I will leave this month with another question: what was your first fandom? And how has it shaped your ideas about fandoms? Let us know @lunaquarterly or let me know @pintsncupcakes. Until next time, keep fanning on!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S1/ E12: Gone &#8216;Shipping</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/s1-e12-gone-shipping/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chloe N. Clark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 15:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ghosts and Fandoms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have a confession to make: I’ve never been a shipper. If you know fandoms,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have a confession to make: I’ve never been a shipper. If you know fandoms, you’ll know what I mean by shipper. If not, this column will make an attempt to explain the concept of shipping and its importance to fandoms.</p>
<p>Ship is short for relationship. The practice in fandoms refers to the fan preference for a certain relationship within the source material. This might be relationships that play out in the material— Hermione and Ron, for instance—or it might be a relationship that doesn’t exist within the material, but is hinted at (or just hoped for)—Hermione and Harry, for example (to keep the HP examples rolling). In fact, these two opposing pairings are probably the most fought about ship in the Potter fandom.</p>
<p>These relationships are often explored in fan fiction, fan art, or lengthy explanations on Tumblr. From ship, we can leap to another term: OTP. OTP stands for a fan’s preferred pairing or “own true pairing,” which could be anything from Delphine and Cosima on <em>Orphan Black</em> (an established relationship within the show’s universe) to Ross and Chandler on <em>Friends</em> (not an established relationship within the show’s universe). While mostly romantic relationships are explored, there is also the shipping of friendships, which leads to one of my favorite terms: BrOTP. My current favorite BrOTP is probably Ravi and Liv on <em>iZombie</em>, for example.</p>
<p>The ships often than have mash-up names (a practice that I’m curious to know the history of. It seems a more recent phenomena, but I’d love to see a history of this). In shows, themselves, <em>Glee</em> might be an example of a space where they made these ship names seemingly part of the show from Finchel to Klaine. This was also brought up (in yet another of their wonderful hat tips to fans) in an episode of <em>Supernatural</em>, in which Dean and Sam learn of fans’ shipping of Castiel and Dean—Destiel.</p>
<p>One of the shows I always think of when I think of shipping is <em>The X-Files</em>, although I strongly did not like this pairing, where fans ardently supported the idea of a romantic relationship between Mulder and Scully. However, I don’t remember ever hearing of Sculder or Mully (please tell me Sculder was the preferred term, someone!).</p>
<p>As I said in the beginning, though, I’ve never been a shipper. I don’t pick Angel over Spike or Harry over Ron. I usually enjoy whatever a creator has chosen to do with their characters. While I might like some fandom relationships over others (Cophine, yes! Veronica and Piz, no!), I still enjoy the way these relationships shape and change a created universe. However, I’m curious to know what ships are your favorites? Are you a Spock/ Kirk shipper? Is your OTP Brittana? Do you have an all-time favorite BrOTP? Let me know in the comments, or on Twitter @lunaquarterly or @pintsncupcakes! And until next month, keep fannin’ on!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S1/ E11: Welcome to the Club</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/s1-e11-welcome-to-the-club/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chloe N. Clark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 15:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ghosts and Fandoms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For this month, I thought I’d tackle a particular show which has its own fandom&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For this month, I thought I’d tackle a particular show which has its own fandom (something I hope to continue to do throughout the course of this column). When I was going through possible choices, I had a few criteria: it had to be a fandom I was already part of, I wanted a somewhat newer show (later, I plan to devote columns to long running fandoms, such as Supernatural, Buffy, etc.), and I wanted it to be somewhat timely. So, I struck on one of my current favorite shows, which recently saw the premiere of its third season: <em>Orphan Black</em>. I’m trying to have as few spoilers as possible, but if you want to watch the show with absolutely NO foreknowledge you may want to skip this column and come back after watching (which I suggest you do immediately!).</p>
<p><em>Orphan Black</em> runs on BBC America and premiered in 2013. It was created by Graeme Manson and John Fawcett and stars the incredible (really, like mind-bendingly incredible) Tatiana Maslany. And why, you may ask, is Maslany just so incredible?</p>
<p>The answer to that lies in the premise of the show:  Sarah Manning discovers one day that she is part of Project Leda. The project: clones. Maslany not only plays Manning, but also plays all of her sestras (clones). These include suburban soccer mom Alison, brilliant scientist Cosima, violent and unhinged Helena, and more. Maslany brings such personality to each role that it’s extremely easy to forget, while watching, that the characters are played by the same woman.  These are some of the best, most diverse, and most nuanced female roles on television.</p>
<p>Maslany, it must be mentioned, is also surrounded by a whole slew of incredible actors: from Jordan Gavaris to Evelyne Brochu. To top that off, the show features incredible writing, humor, and some of the smartest sci-fi currently around. So, it’s no wonder that a fandom quickly sprang up around the show.</p>
<p>The <em>Orphan Black</em> fandom, called Clone Club (the name given to the clones on the show by Cosima), includes fan fiction, ‘ships (Cosphine forever, obviously), and, of course, endless speculation on what exactly is going on with Project Leda. And just like any other show with a fandom out there, many discussions surround which clone is your favorite clone. I find myself flipping back and forth quite often. Every clone is my favorite clone (this might be a me problem, I also have never been able to pick a favorite between Winchester brothers), though that might again be testament to how fully these characters have been written and how totally Maslany inhabits each one.</p>
<p>So, dear readers, who is your favorite clone? Do you write any OB fan fiction? Have a favorite ship? Or is there another fandom you’d like to see explored? Let us know @lunaquarterly or @pintsncupcakes. Until next month: Keep fannin’ on!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>S1/ E10: Fic-tional, Pt. 2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/s1-e10-fic-tional-pt-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chloe N. Clark]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 16:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ghosts and Fandoms]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last month, this column saw the first half of my interview with fan fiction writer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last month, this column saw the first half of my interview with fan fiction writer Jennifer Hutchins. This month will be the continuation of that interview as Ms. Hutchins tackles questions about community and her own writing.</p>
<p><strong>6.) How would you describe the fanfiction community (or communities) that you belong to? </strong></p>
<p>Very diverse, very fun (except when there’s wank being thrown around), and hell-bent on destroying brain cells. *grins*</p>
<p>Each one has their quirks. The Sherlock one is very, very stubborn. They can be bitter, irritating, and loyal to a fault. There can be infighting, and it can get ugly quickly. But if you look past the wank, the people are amazing and so kind and nice and generally pretty great.</p>
<p>The Bond fanfic community&#8230;well, we are just a bit bloodthirsty, and a few of us have an unhealthy obsession with guns, girls, and Q. Or Alec. Or James himself. There’s very little infighting &#8211; we accept that some people haven’t seen the Connery films, and we do not speak of Quantum of Solace. It’s just not done. We are a tight-knit group, and we tend to keep to ourselves.</p>
<p>The Marvel fans. Ooooooh boy. Um. Look up Farmer Clint, Civil War meme, and anything involving text posts. We are a loony group. Most of our fic pre-Winter Soldier is nothing but fluff and mostly about Tony Stark. Post-Winter Soldier is&#8230;oh, god, the ANGST. BUCKY NO. *sobs* There’s a very distinct delineation between Pre and Post CATWS. And then the Age of Ultron trailer came out and we collectively went batshit.</p>
<p>A new one I’m getting into is the Teen Wolf fandom, and so far all they ever talk about is knotting and werewolves and kinks and Stiles. I’m in love (despite only seeing the first episode), but I haven’t done any writing in it. I probably will soon, though.</p>
<p><strong>7.) What’s the best way for someone to get involved with fan fiction or fan fiction communities?</strong></p>
<p>Start writing! Really, it’s that easy. Get yourself a Livejournal or Tumblr or AO3 (right now, AO3 is having issues and might still be invite-only). Follow fandom blogs &#8211; great ideas abound there if you don’t think of something on your own. Join a writer’s chat on IIRC &#8211; The Antidiogenes Club and Rootcellar are great ones and are the ones I’m regularly in. Another one is Inner Circle. Put yourself out there, and you will make friends and get noticed.</p>
<p>We are generally very welcoming to the point of going a bit overboard sometimes, but you will be accepted! And don’t worry if you don’t get a lot of hits on your stories, or if you don’t get a lot of kudos or views: someone out there loves your writing and wants more!</p>
<p><strong>8.) What’s one thing that you’d like everyone to know about fan fiction or its writers</strong>?</p>
<p>The writers &#8211; We aren’t the stereotypes. We are single, married, widowed, divorced; ranging in age from teens (though the chats are 18+ only for legal reasons, I’m completely positive there’s places for teen writers) to 50+; and hail from all walks of life. We may fangirl and obsess, but there’s more than just celebrities on our minds. We help each other through difficult times, and we are great friends. We are creative, wild, fun, and very outspoken. We will talk about anything. Anything. The works &#8211; I’m sure you’ve heard the arguments both for and against fanfiction. But I’ve seen some weekend writers churn out stories that knock any best seller right off its pedestal.</p>
<p>What fanfiction is: a creative outlet for people to explore different aspects of their respective favorites &#8211; whether it’s a alternate universe where everyone turns to werewolves or a sidestory about Mike Stamford and Molly Hooper, a ‘what if’ story full of angst or a ‘sex pollen’ porn story similar to something seen on <a title="" href="https://www.tubev.sex/categories/1657/shemale">shemale sex at tubev</a>.</p>
<p>Fanfiction is a catalyst, a decompression valve, an escape from the world or a way to get into the world. It could be the beginning of something more &#8211; no less than four of my writing companions are published authors and have done so through fanfiction.</p>
<p><strong>9.) What are you currently working on</strong>?</p>
<p>Oh dear. That’s a funny thing. Um. Everything.</p>
<p>A 007/Q/Aston Martin Vanquish Volante car porn story (because car porn is the best thing ever), a Steve Rogers/Natasha Romanov edgeplay fic, a Bucky Barnes and Little Shit story (for an ongoing series), the next chapter of my 007/ Q clubbing fic, a Bucky/Steve body worship story, a Ace!Steve/Sam story, a one-shot where Bucky is left with synthesia, and a fic where Peggy Carter passes away (which is more of a catharsis for me since I’ve lost my husband).</p>
<p>Oh, and a Kingsman/Bond crossover that’s been pecking at my brain since Valentines Day.</p>
<p><strong>10.) How can our readers find your work?</strong></p>
<p>I post strictly to Archive of Our Own: <a href="http://archiveofourown.org/users/a_xmasmurder">http://archiveofourown.org/users/a_xmasmurder</a></p>
<p>I warn you: it’s a mess. *grins*</p>
<p><em>Please do check out some of Jennifer’s excellent work! Do you write or read fan fiction? Let us know in the comments or on Twitter! And, as ever, keep fannin’ on!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
