<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>If This Then That &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/if-this-then-that/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 02:19:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>For the Wise Wizards</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/for-the-wise-wizards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rocky Breen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 10:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[If This Then That]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17717</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you always play a wizard in D&#38;D, then I’ve got some books for you.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you always play a wizard in D&amp;D, then I’ve got some books for you.<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17723 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/allie-smith-BQVMG5sRg1I-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/allie-smith-BQVMG5sRg1I-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/allie-smith-BQVMG5sRg1I-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/allie-smith-BQVMG5sRg1I-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/allie-smith-BQVMG5sRg1I-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/allie-smith-BQVMG5sRg1I-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/allie-smith-BQVMG5sRg1I-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<p>Personally, spellcasting is the last role I would take in a party, but for those interested in amassing lore, legend, and alchemical sciences, memorizing set spells every night is a small sacrifice.</p>
<p>For those of you wondering about the mechanics of the world and curious about figures from history, these few books should entertain and inform you.</p>
<p><strong><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17772 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Americas-women-bookcover-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Americas-women-bookcover-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Americas-women-bookcover.jpg 333w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><em>America&#8217;s Women: 400 years of Dolls, Drudges, Helpmates, and Heroines</em> by Gail Collins</strong></p>
<p>These are the kinds of stories I wish I had read in history classes growing up. I&#8217;m American, but the figures in Collin&#8217;s <em>America&#8217;s Women</em> were left out of my education in school.</p>
<p>Not that they were all wholesome and inspiring. The first woman mentioned by name in Collins&#8217; history was a Viking woman named Freydis, daughter of Erik the Red, who &#8220;organized a massacre of her business partners, finishing off the wives and female servants herself.&#8221; (Collins xvi). Definitely not #lifegoals.</p>
<p>When we think of the pursuit of equal voting rights in the US, it&#8217;s interesting to learn that for many white women, they &#8220;were not all that interested in the right to vote&#8230;.The liquor industry was right&#8211;many women wanted to vote just so they could use the ballot box to ban the sale of alcohol&#8221; (316). Good ole&#8217; Puritanism for you, there.</p>
<p>Collins doesn&#8217;t shy away from the messy nature of humanity&#8211;no one is truly perfect, and the women of America&#8217;s history are no different. But that doesn&#8217;t mean we shouldn&#8217;t know about them.</p>
<p><strong><em><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17722 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Venemous-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Venemous-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Venemous.jpg 333w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Venomous: How Earth&#8217;s Deadliest Creatures Mastered Biochemistry</em> by Christie Wilcox</strong></p>
<p>Both of this book and the next which I recommend have two things in common: both use etymology and history as a way to connect various, complex science concepts for the reader, and both authors have a very obvious and contagious passion for their respective fields.</p>
<p>With Wilcox&#8217;s <em>Venemous</em>, I learned that platypi and a handful of mammals have venom&#8211;and all along, here I thought none did! In fact, platypi are <em>incredibly</em> venomous, enough to require morphine as treatment for the excruciating pain. Further, I learned about the history of antivenoms and how different venomous animals are ranked in terms of victim mortality depending on the parameters of injection.</p>
<p>One thing which surprised me in a book seemingly about the very non-human world of venom was the very human stories behind this science. A rising PhD student goes for a swim; the box jelly stings that nearly kill her inspire her to devote her research solely to understanding those creatures. A man injecting himself with snake venom for immunity from his pets and to satisfy personal curiosity, despite the danger. There&#8217;s even a Princess Bride quote!</p>
<p><strong><em> Dark Matter and the Dinosaurs: The Astounding Interconnectedness of the Universe</em> by Lisa Randall<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17721 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/DarkMatterCover-300x300.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/DarkMatterCover-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/DarkMatterCover-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/DarkMatterCover.jpeg 450w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></strong></p>
<p>Personally, I find it relaxing to learn about what we know of <em>order</em> in the kosmos&#8211;and that the origin of the word &#8220;cosmology&#8221; comes from the Greek concept of order, structure. Reading this book will give you, too, a deeper understanding of some similar-sounding but actually different words: anti-matter, dark matter, and dark-energy. If you read <em>The Three Body Problem</em> and felt like your comprehension of physics was pushed to the max, Randall&#8217;s nonfiction here will be a slightly friendlier hand with no plot to think of, just science in a fairly easy-to-understand tone.</p>
<p>The premise of Randall&#8217;s book here is simple, but is not anywhere near proven as theory; Randall argues that the overwhelming presence of dark matter led to the demise of the dinosaurs. That meteor, she points out, would not have come hurtling at us if it were not for dark matter, and this raises many questions about what we do and don&#8217;t understand about the physics of the universe.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve found it fascinating, and I prefer this kind of reading before bed. I guess I&#8217;m not so different from you spellcasters after all, but I still think I&#8217;ll stick to playing a rogue in D&amp;D.</p>
<p>_________________________________</p>
<p><b>About this Column: </b>With occasional parentheticals a la Robin McKinley, <i>If This, Then That</i> connects the dots between niche interests for <em>LSQ</em> readers and the books that suit them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>More Time on Your Hands? Reading about Public Health</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/more-time-on-your-hands-reading-about-public-health/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rocky Breen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 14:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[If This Then That]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;re lucky enough to have more time on your hands because of the coronavirus&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17556 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/washing-hands-239x300.jpg" alt="" width="239" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/washing-hands-239x300.jpg 239w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/washing-hands-817x1024.jpg 817w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/washing-hands-768x963.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/washing-hands-1225x1536.jpg 1225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/washing-hands-1633x2048.jpg 1633w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/washing-hands-scaled.jpg 2042w" sizes="(max-width: 239px) 100vw, 239px" />If you&#8217;re lucky enough to have more time on your hands because of the coronavirus pandemic and are looking for some interesting reads, I&#8217;ve got some books for you.</p>
<p>I work in higher education, and my campus has just gone on spring break. Following spring break, however, like many schools, in-person classes will be cancelled for online distance learning, and we&#8217;ve suspended all university-related programming. Social distancing is a word I&#8217;ve never heard so frequently, and it means that some of us will be preferring time alone out of consideration for others, to keep this thing from spreading.</p>
<p>On one hand, I&#8217;m a little sick that we can&#8217;t seem to talk about anything else. But on the other hand, I have a hard time focusing on topics that don&#8217;t encompass this pandemic. So if you&#8217;re like me, I have some interesting reads on very opposite sides of the public health spectrum that should keep you entertained and informed when it&#8217;s hard to focus on topics other than health.</p>
<p><strong><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17552 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/the-panic-virus-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/the-panic-virus-198x300.jpg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/the-panic-virus-675x1024.jpg 675w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/the-panic-virus-768x1166.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/the-panic-virus.jpg 938w" sizes="(max-width: 198px) 100vw, 198px" />The Panic Virus</em> by Seth Mnookin</strong></p>
<p>This detailed look at the origin of anti-vaccination sentiment was originally published back in 2011. It explores the various sources and realities of parents&#8217; choices to not vaccinate their children and the public health crises that can occur because of those harmful choices. <a href="https://cmsw.mit.edu/seth-mnookin-the-panic-virus/">Mnookin</a> chronicles the last 150 years of this anti-vaccination rhetoric and how little it&#8217;s changed. These days, the anti-vaccine sentiment is most typically associated with terrible research from 1998 and has led to a fear of children becoming autistic or that the ingredients (such as mercury) in the vaccine would harm children.</p>
<p>The first chapter opens with the 2006 narrative of a woman whose child contracted Hib, Haemophilus influenzae type b. Hib is an infection that the doctors didn&#8217;t expect the child to have because most infants receive multiple doses of the vaccine. Their various tests for strep throat, etc., had actually <em>worsened </em>the child&#8217;s rapidly closing throat until an older doctor was called in and recognized the illness. The mother had chosen not to vaccinate because her <em>chiropractor</em> put the fearworm in her ear about studies linking vaccines to autism.</p>
<p><em>The Panic Virus</em> stays pretty squarely focused on the medical reality of disinformation in public health, specifically vaccines. But I found it interesting that that exact mother was afraid of her child becoming autistic because there actually were a lot of autistic children in her community—something I would personally expect could be a reason to have a <em>more</em> open mind about <a href="https://www.autism-society.org/stories/neurotypical-neurodivergent-dichotomy/">neurotypologies</a>, but in this case, did not got that way.</p>
<p><strong><em>Eugenics in the Garden</em> by Fabiola López-Durán<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17553 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Eugenicsinthegarden-210x300.jpg" alt="" width="210" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Eugenicsinthegarden-210x300.jpg 210w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Eugenicsinthegarden.jpg 336w" sizes="(max-width: 210px) 100vw, 210px" /></strong></p>
<p>This book is a look at another harmful way of thinking, eugenics, but from a very different angle than I&#8217;ve ever heard before: urban planning, architecture, and design as mediums for building toward a &#8220;perfect form of humanity.&#8221; <a href="https://arthistory.rice.edu/faculty/fabiola-lopez-duran" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">López-Durán&#8217;s</a> introduction says it best: &#8220;This book examines the dynamics of this form of eugenics, which first appeared in France and then spread throughout Latin America—the only region in the &#8216;developing&#8217; world where eugenics was systematically implemented and institutionalized.&#8221; (López-Durán 3)</p>
<p><a href="https://necsi.edu/what-lamarck-believed">Lamarck&#8217;s theories of evolution</a> &#8220;set the stage for a particular orientation toward environmental-genetic interaction, empowering an apparatus that made race, gender, class, and the built environment critical measurements of modernity and progress.&#8221; (López-Durán 4)</p>
<p>The connection between a book about urban planning, architecture, and eugenics may not seem immediately connected to public health. But if you know that mortality rates of pregnant women of color are dire, you can imagine the sort of underlying bias that directly affects healthcare. Moreover, López-Durán makes the explicit connection for us by looking at how certain medical workers supported eugenics theories and how their authority helped it carry weight in being institutionalized practice in Latin America.</p>
<p><strong>Work Cited:</strong><br />
López-Durán, Fabiola. <em>Eugenics in the Garden Transatlantic Architecture and the Crafting Of Modernity</em>. Austin: University of Texas Press, 2018.</p>
<p>_________________________________</p>
<p><b>About This Column: </b>With occasional parentheticals à la Robin McKinley, <i>If This, Then That</i> connects the dots between niche interests for <em>LSQ</em> readers and the books that suit them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fiction for the Food-Lovers</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fiction-for-the-food-lovers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rocky Breen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[If This Then That]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The easiest way to get me to pick up a book is to tell me&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17208 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/matheus-frade-KO46ZfbNdtY-unsplash-300x220.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="220" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/matheus-frade-KO46ZfbNdtY-unsplash-300x220.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/matheus-frade-KO46ZfbNdtY-unsplash-1024x751.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/matheus-frade-KO46ZfbNdtY-unsplash-768x564.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/matheus-frade-KO46ZfbNdtY-unsplash-1536x1127.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/matheus-frade-KO46ZfbNdtY-unsplash-2048x1503.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />The easiest way to get me to pick up a book is to tell me it has gratuitous helpings of food described in the pages. My roommates used to poke fun at the way I often relaxed before bed, thumbing through a gourmet vegetarian cooking magazine. &#8220;Food porn&#8221; they called it before that had become an actual hashtag (before hashtags were really a thing, even).</p>
<p>If, like me, you find that a good book could always be better if its pages were peppered with food-focused scenes, then I&#8217;ve got some stories for you. Only two of them are speculative, but, again, this is about fiction with lots of food in the narrative. We&#8217;ll treat speculative elements as garnish here.</p>
<p><strong><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17207 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/51YXQdzfukL._SL500_-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/51YXQdzfukL._SL500_-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/51YXQdzfukL._SL500_-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/51YXQdzfukL._SL500_.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />With the Fire on High</em> by Elizabeth Acevedo</strong></p>
<p>From the title and cover art alone you could surmise that this story will feed your soul. A friend who recommended it to me had me at the plotline: a teen mom, Emoni, in her senior year of high school pursues her culinary dreams.</p>
<p>Chapters in <em>With the Fire on High</em> are short with no words wasted, all beautiful and arranged to be as magical and heart-hitting as the food Emoni makes.</p>
<p>The slam poetry performer and author Acevedo calls NYC home, with heritage from the Dominican Republic. In this and her two other novels (<em>The Poet X</em> and the upcoming <em>Clap When You Land</em>) she explores the meanings of being Afro-Latina, of family, and of being female in a world that raises its youth to see the feminine as fractured, frail, and challenges the notion pleasure is shameful.</p>
<p>If you want to learn more about the Acevedo, I strongly recommend listening to <a href="http://NPR/ interview with Acevedo: https://www.npr.org/2019/05/26/727194556/portrait-of-elizabeth-acevedo">her interview with NPR</a>.</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/salt-skin-and-pie/">Salt-Skin and Pie</a>&#8221; by Alena Sullivan<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17209 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/kari-shea-DesRxj28Ns-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/kari-shea-DesRxj28Ns-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/kari-shea-DesRxj28Ns-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/kari-shea-DesRxj28Ns-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/kari-shea-DesRxj28Ns-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/kari-shea-DesRxj28Ns-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></strong></p>
<p>This one is one of <em>LSQ</em>&#8216;s own published short stories, from Issue 25. It&#8217;s on the longer side for a short story, but it earns that length with the issues it balances: the loss of a child, the loss of a relationship, the tug of the ocean and numbness, the comfort of food, and the kiss of hope found in new friendship. Also, a wlw taste of romance!</p>
<p>All that plus pies makes this a story I&#8217;ve never forgotten.</p>
<p><em><b><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17210 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Kinou-nani-wo-tabeta-209x300.jpg" alt="" width="209" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Kinou-nani-wo-tabeta-209x300.jpg 209w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Kinou-nani-wo-tabeta.jpg 348w" sizes="(max-width: 209px) 100vw, 209px" />What Did You Eat Yesterday?</b></em><b> (<em>Kinou Nani Tabeta?</em>) by Fumi Yoshinaga</b></p>
<p>This slice-of-life manga about a gay couple&#8211;Kakei-san and Kenji-kun&#8211;in Japan debuted in 2007 as one of the first of its kind: a story that treated gay characters not as a fantasy or joke, but as real people going through the ups and downs of daily life. The manga recently got its own drama adaptation; I could do without some of its scripted silliness, but on the whole I found it a faithful adaptation with spot-on acting from the main characters.</p>
<p>And food is central to the plot! Kakei-san is a lawyer&#8230; but since he and Kenji won&#8217;t be having kids, Kakei-san worries about their future without children to look after them in old age. Hence, operation save-lots-o-money is borne, and it&#8217;s on a shoestring budget that Kakei unleashes his creativity and passion in the kitchen. Meanwhile, his boyfriend goes and buys pricey Hagen Daaz ice cream from the convenience store on a whim&#8230; You can see where some of the tension in this story is born. But the best part? Author Fumi Yoshinaga gives us <em>the recipes</em> for what Kakei makes.</p>
<p><strong><em>Sunshine</em> by Robin McKinley<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17211 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Sunshine_Robin_McKinley_novel_cover-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Sunshine_Robin_McKinley_novel_cover-198x300.jpg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Sunshine_Robin_McKinley_novel_cover.jpg 200w" sizes="(max-width: 198px) 100vw, 198px" /></strong></p>
<p>This was my first Robin McKinley book and it is still my favorite because its filled with descriptions of all kinds of desserts. The main character is, after all, a baker. It&#8217;s worth pointing out, too, that while this is a novel about vampires, it&#8217;s unlike any other vampire book I&#8217;ve read. For starters, there&#8217;s no la-la-people-can-totally-date-vamps element; vampires&#8217; status as heartless monsters is very firmly rooted in this story, even as the main character skates on the edge of something like friendship with a right-out freak among vampires (<em>a la</em> that recent <em>Venom</em> movie).</p>
<p>Warning, though: you can&#8217;t read this without opening the cupboard and bemoaning a lack of flour up to the task of filling the craving to bake and eat that this book inspires: cinnamon rolls, chocolate anything, cherry pie, blueberry muffins. Even in the scene where Sunshine eats a bunch of fresh-from-the-tree apples with straight-from-the-cellar wine on a bunch of furs by a fireplace stokes that same spot in my brain that is stimulated by all the baked goods.</p>
<p><strong><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17212 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/81Bb1PGA9WL-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/81Bb1PGA9WL-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/81Bb1PGA9WL-678x1024.jpg 678w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/81Bb1PGA9WL-768x1161.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/81Bb1PGA9WL-1016x1536.jpg 1016w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/81Bb1PGA9WL-1355x2048.jpg 1355w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/81Bb1PGA9WL.jpg 1694w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /><a href="https://www.jasmineguillory.com/royal-holiday">Royal Holiday</a></em> by Jasmine Guillory</strong></p>
<p>And speaking of baked goods&#8230; readers, do you enjoy scones? Better stock up before you read this one. Jasmine Guillory writes the best romance I&#8217;ve ever read, and while <em>Wedding Date</em> is still my favorite of hers, <em>Royal Holiday</em> takes a different cake(!) for making me want to eat all the time.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the gist of the plot: Vivian is an older woman and the long-divorced mother of a professional stylist. When her daughter is invited to be the substitute stylist to British royalty, Vivian travels along with to the Sandringham Estate, where she meets Malcolm, the charming Private Secretary to the Queen. There&#8217;s more than just food in this novel, of course, but the food was my favorite surprise in this book, including, beyond scones, delicious sandwiches prepped in the kitchen, breakfast ready and waiting first thing in the morning, and Nigerian soups in a London restaurant.</p>
<p>_________________________________</p>
<p><b>About this Column: </b>With occasional parentheticals a la Robin McKinley, <i>If This, Then That</i> connects the dots between niche interests for <em>LSQ</em> readers and the books that suit them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Time Travel Gems</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/time-travel-gems/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rocky Breen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[If This Then That]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For those of you who love Outlander or The Time Machine (or Ludo&#8217;s rock-opera Broken&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16994 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />For those of you who love <em>Outlander</em> or <em>The Time Machine</em> (or Ludo&#8217;s rock-opera <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broken_Bride"><em>Broken Bride</em></a>), I&#8217;ve got some books for you.</p>
<p>The allure of time travel, I think, is that these stories always come so multi-faceted. You can&#8217;t tell a story about time travel without presenting certain important questions for the characters: will they return to their &#8216;own time&#8217;? Is it accidental, or by choice? How will they respond to the different political and cultural climate of the times? Will they assimilate, or prevail with their own thoughts or interpretations? What will they carry back with them?</p>
<p><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16993 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/josh-appel-0nkFvdcM-X4-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/josh-appel-0nkFvdcM-X4-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/josh-appel-0nkFvdcM-X4-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/josh-appel-0nkFvdcM-X4-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/josh-appel-0nkFvdcM-X4-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/josh-appel-0nkFvdcM-X4-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />&#8220;<a href="https://firesidefiction.com/issue34/chapter/a-place-out-of-time/">A Place Out Of Time</a>&#8221; by Elsa Sjunneson</strong></p>
<p>Short story, not a novel, over at <a href="https://firesidefiction.com/about/">Fireside Fiction</a>, which does a lot of similar work as <em>LSQ</em> in the realm of short spec fic. In this short story, you will find extrapolations of some very important questions one should ask themselves before time traveling: How would someone like me survive? And what&#8217;s the point in going at all if I know the likelihood is zero?</p>
<p>Time travel is always dangerous. But Sjunneson imagines a group of researchers with various disabilities, especially the perspective of the main character in a wheelchair. Victorian London? Future UK? US in 1941? Even modern to him the time isn&#8217;t safe, as a time when people want to use science to &#8216;fix&#8217; him.</p>
<p>This line moved me: &#8220;As I mark my timeline with black dots, showing me where my body is not welcome, I discover that my machine and I may have few places to go. Few places to research, to experience time.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><em>The Little Shop of Found Things</em> by Paula Brackston</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16992 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/9781250229502_p0_v3_s550x406-194x300.jpg" alt="" width="194" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/9781250229502_p0_v3_s550x406-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/9781250229502_p0_v3_s550x406.jpg 263w" sizes="(max-width: 194px) 100vw, 194px" /></p>
<p>This novel is blessedly the first in a series, and it has a strong course of mystery running through it, but my favorite part is how well Brackston writes <em>stakes </em>and<em> characters</em>. Little to big, there&#8217;s always a difficult choice to make, competing priorities, which, even when we&#8217;re talking about the main character&#8217;s decision to sing for the first time in a long time, feels so <em>right</em> in a novel with time travel. The main character, Xanthe, has so much agency, and she tries to time things right. But doing so requires so much juggling and wit and bravery that even without someone&#8217;s life on the line (there is!), I&#8217;d be riveted.</p>
<p>The various characters feel so real, too, and dynamic. Her mother has severe arthritis and has a hard time getting around, but has a passion and skill for antiques. She&#8217;s also gloriously proud of her daughter. The townspeople, too, in this adorable village known for its popular antique markets, made me feel like I was going to a different place, for sure, even when I wasn&#8217;t reading in a different time. I won&#8217;t spoil the rest, though. You&#8217;ll just have to read it.</p>
<p><strong><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-16995 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/foreverwar_200-f7f81599cf5ff603fa45ca90a9e4fc34475a8e80-s300-c85.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="301" />The Forever War</em> by Joe Haldeman</strong></p>
<p>An oldie, but a goodie. I&#8217;m not usually drawn into older and longer sci-fi works, because the big-name ones were written by dudes with surprisingly small imaginations when it came to things like, oh, gender equality and consent. But <em>The Forever War,</em> while not technically a time travel novel, is on this list because the writing is so good and looks long at the effect time dilation could have if we, say, had a space military conflict. To be fair, I read a bit of Quantum Physics 101 before this at the recommendation of a friend, which helped me understand the science of why certain things occurred (such as the MC living for hundreds of years and aging more slowly).</p>
<p>This novel is often characterized as a challenge to the realities of the Vietnam War, and by someone with personal experience, no less. Perhaps that&#8217;s why it feels so grounded. Have you seen <a href="https://youtu.be/nCwwVjPNloY">Adam Driver&#8217;s Ted Talk</a> about going from the Marines to acting? In it, he talks about how he struggled to find meaning when he returned to civilian life. The main character in <em>The Forever War</em> struggles with that concern throughout the whole novel. What&#8217;s the meaning of the conflict, the harsh training, the countless comrades&#8217; lost lives? What&#8217;s the meaning of all of that when you return to &#8216;civilian&#8217; life and learn they just watch TV all day and talk about pointless things? Where was this technology where you can regenerate a limb back when the war started? These questions, too, are part of a discussion of time: how do we use the time we have?</p>
<p>_________________________________</p>
<p><b>About this Column: </b>With occasional parentheticals a la Robin McKinley, <i>If This, Then That</i> connects the dots between niche interests for <em>LSQ</em> readers and the books that suit them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Japan Beyond Manga and Anime</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/japan-beyond-manga-and-anime/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rocky Breen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[If This Then That]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;re interested in learning about Japan beyond manga and anime, I&#8217;ve got some resources&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16808 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clay-banks-hwLAI5lRhdM-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clay-banks-hwLAI5lRhdM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clay-banks-hwLAI5lRhdM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clay-banks-hwLAI5lRhdM-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clay-banks-hwLAI5lRhdM-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/clay-banks-hwLAI5lRhdM-unsplash-2048x1367.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re interested in learning about Japan beyond manga and anime, I&#8217;ve got some resources for you.</p>
<p>This post comes with a disclaimer: despite a long-standing relationship with Japan (including 12 years of language study, 2 years&#8217; residence, and 2 years&#8217; of working in a Japanese office in the U.S.), I&#8217;ve never been very interested in anime or manga. There are some I like, but you may as well ask me if I like TV or books. Both are mediums, and creations in either medium will have target demographics in mind during production, different stylistic choices reflective of the creators on board, etc. Just think about how different <em>Howl&#8217;s Moving Castle</em> is from<em> Naruto</em>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16809 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/bud-helisson-kqguzgvYrtM-unsplash-300x239.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="239" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/bud-helisson-kqguzgvYrtM-unsplash-300x239.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/bud-helisson-kqguzgvYrtM-unsplash-1024x816.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/bud-helisson-kqguzgvYrtM-unsplash-768x612.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/bud-helisson-kqguzgvYrtM-unsplash-1536x1224.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/bud-helisson-kqguzgvYrtM-unsplash-2048x1632.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>But for some people, manga and anime have their own specific charm. Many of the people I&#8217;ve met studying Japanese and travelling to work in Japan began that journey with a favorite manga or anime. Several of them shared their thoughts with me on their experience, and the summary of their thoughts comes to this: expectations of a different place and its people rarely meet reality, and the cultural concepts that challenge you most will likely be concepts you never knew to expect.</p>
<p>I never expected that one of my most heated moments in Japan would be debating with a fitting room attendant at Uniqlo about me trying on a bra over my bare skin. Yet there I was, saying, &#8220;Do you really mean to tell me that Japanese customers go in there and try the bra on <em>over</em> their shirts? What&#8217;s the point?&#8221; While my Japanese friend whispered to me, &#8220;You can just go in and do it anyway&#8211;she&#8217;s not going to know.&#8221; (After a few iterations I was given a disposable faux-cloth vest which I could use to determine an accurate fit&#8211;why the conversation didn&#8217;t start there is beyond me.)</p>
<p>All it takes is a look at your own home culture to see how the different layers of gradation shift in the light of time to make different shapes, different unique phenomena. Without further ado, here are some resources if you&#8217;re curious about Japan&#8217;s shifting contrasts.</p>
<p><strong><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16810 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/TheJapaneseHaveaWordforIt-300x300.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/TheJapaneseHaveaWordforIt-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/TheJapaneseHaveaWordforIt-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/TheJapaneseHaveaWordforIt.jpeg 450w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />The Japanese Have a Word for It</em> by Boyé Lafayette De Mente</strong></p>
<p>Have you seen the new <em>Queer Eye: We&#8217;re In Japan!</em>? If not, add it to this list of resources, but there&#8217;s a moment in Ep 3, &#8220;The Ideal Woman,&#8221; where Antoni does not realize how hot the coals at his feet could have gotten in that conversation (timestamp 34:18). Why? Because he was, naturally, approaching the conversation in a very American way: very directly challenging what past factors led to the present situation and questioning the parties involved. It&#8217;s a makeover show, and that&#8217;s necessary.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.japantimes.co.jp/community/2017/06/25/our-lives/remembering-life-works-boye-de-mente-giant-writing-japan/">late Boye</a>&#8216;s book has a word (several, in fact) for the cultural hotsocket that got forked in that conversation and it&#8217;s preserving <em>face</em>. (Namely, Antoni&#8217;s challenge to the mother to review the situation came off, through a Japanese lens, as questioning her value and competency as a mother&#8211;just look at her face and how she processes the convo.)</p>
<p><em>The Japanese Have a Word for It</em> might be old (1997) and lack some important updates (loads more international peeps and greater presence of English loanwords, for starters), but it&#8217;s a reliable compass to anyone who wants to know more about Japanese cultural axioms.</p>
<p><strong><em>A Tale for the Time Being</em> by Ruth Ozeki<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16811 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/tb-cover-993x1500-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/tb-cover-993x1500-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/tb-cover-993x1500.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></strong></p>
<p>This is one of my all-time favorite books, though it has some really hard moments. Bullying, for starters, child (self-)prostitution, attempted sexual assault; and regular, thematic, deliberate discussion of suicide. I love that it&#8217;s an I-novel, though, which is a novel that fictionalizes the author into a story. The author is Ruth Ozeki, a &#8220;<a href="http://www.ruthozeki.com/about-ruth">novelist, filmmaker and Zen Buddhist priest</a>,&#8221; who has dual nationality with Canada and the U.S.</p>
<p><em>A Tale for the Time Being</em> is, in my words, actually two stories that sound and crescendo together: the first tale is about Ruth, who finds the journal of a teenage Japanese girl among the debris from the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2011_T%C5%8Dhoku_earthquake_and_tsunami">2011 tsunami</a> washed up on the shore near her home. Ruth reads and translates the diary (written at different points in English, Japanese, or French), worrying over what she might learn of the girl&#8217;s fate while also confronting her own struggles on marriage, faith, and the pain and challenges of having an aging mother who is very different from yourself.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16812 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/gregory-hayes-rb9LrfoHbb8-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/gregory-hayes-rb9LrfoHbb8-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/gregory-hayes-rb9LrfoHbb8-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/gregory-hayes-rb9LrfoHbb8-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/gregory-hayes-rb9LrfoHbb8-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/gregory-hayes-rb9LrfoHbb8-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>The other tale is about Nao, the girl writing the diary who says very early on she wants to kill herself, but who takes the time to explain how she lived in the U.S., gets bullied upon return to Japan, loves her Buddhist nun grandmother, discovers a historic family war relic, and becomes a bully herself at one point.</p>
<p>It is fiction, but this book goes deep into some very Japanese concepts while also highlighting aspects of life for those with Japanese-heritage living outside of Japan.</p>
<p><strong><em>The Rape of Nanking</em> by Iris Chang<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16813 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/nanking-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/nanking-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/nanking.jpg 333w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></strong></p>
<p>I had a very hard time reading this. A high school history teacher learned I was teaching myself Japanese (11 years ago!) and said I needed to read this book. Having since seen a lot of people exoticize Japan and put it up on a pedestal, I&#8217;m so grateful my teacher recommended this book to me and nipped any possibility of that in the bud.</p>
<p>As an American, the side of WWII I learned was obviously more focused on what happened once the US was involved: the American bomb raids and resulting starvation experienced by Japanese civilians, Hiroshima and Nagasaki, and the American occupation after. The Nanjing massacre happened before all that, winter 1937-1938.</p>
<p>This is a nonfiction historical book by a Chinese-American descendant of one of the massacre&#8217;s survivors. The book goes in great detail to contextualize, narrate, and <em>prove</em> the massacre (or, more appropriately, genocide) committed by the Japanese army in China&#8217;s historical capitol. When you read the news and hear about tensions between Japan and China, this book can put things into perspective for you especially if you pay attention to the part where Japanese curricula wouldn&#8217;t teach this point of their history and at certain times outright denied it happened. For comparison to what you know about the Holocaust, in Nanjing most of the estimated 300,000+ casualties (civilians) were killed over the span of a few days, though the event itself spanned weeks.</p>
<p>Serious content warnings for everything you can think of that might happen in war, especially sexual assault and mutilation, including very graphic images and descriptions of war atrocities. The wikipedia page about the event itself, too, is very explicit on these fronts.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16814 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/918uah9Xu3L._SX342_-244x300.jpg" alt="" width="244" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/918uah9Xu3L._SX342_-244x300.jpg 244w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/918uah9Xu3L._SX342_.jpg 342w" sizes="(max-width: 244px) 100vw, 244px" />I know, not a happy resource to end on. Just remember why you started reading this&#8211; the beauty of <em>Studio Ghibli</em> animations with their anti-war bent, the tongue-in-cheek humor of <em>Ouran High School Host Club</em>, and the feminism-doesn&#8217;t-have-to-exclude-femininity glitter in <em>Sailor Moon</em>. But this list is here when you&#8217;re ready for those more serious topics, too.</p>
<p>_________________________________</p>
<p><b>About this Column: </b>With occasional parentheticals a la Robin McKinley, <i>If This, Then That</i> connects the dots between niche interests for <em>LSQ</em> readers and the books that suit them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fantasy Finances</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fantasy-finances/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rocky Breen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[If This Then That]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you ever wonder how the fantasy heroes or superheroes pay their rent or insurance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16509 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/v2osk-c9OfrVeD_tQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/v2osk-c9OfrVeD_tQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/v2osk-c9OfrVeD_tQ-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/v2osk-c9OfrVeD_tQ-unsplash-1024x681.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />If you ever wonder how the fantasy heroes or superheroes pay their rent or insurance when all they ever seem to actually buy are cute pastries at market stalls and drinks at Starbucks, I&#8217;ve got some books for you.</p>
<p>Personally, I grew up low-income. Food stamps, rarely eating out, and not doing summer camps did not define my childhood, but were things I became aware that others experienced differently in the U.S. I didn&#8217;t fly in an airplane until I was 19, on my way to Japan for study abroad with scholarships and student loans fueling the way. There, I cut my hair instead of paying roughly $50 for the cheapest salons to do it for me.</p>
<p>Suffice it to say, I roll my eyes at the plethora of fantasy books that never address that thing that makes the world go round: money. Will it buy us happiness? No. And don&#8217;t get me wrong, sometimes I write posh princesses with a lot of resources at hand because it&#8217;s nice to imagine luxury sometimes. But even that feeling gets at one of the fundamental concept in economics&#8211; scarcity&#8211;and I crave to see more fantasy settings that address it.</p>
<p>Here are two fantasy books that keep scarcity, economics, and money intrinsic to their world and character-building. (I&#8217;m focusing on fantasy because something about the vulnerable vacuum of space or the &#8216;future&#8217; part makes many sci-fi books address scarcity head-on, compared to fantasy ones.)</p>
<p><strong><em>A Court of Mist and Fury</em> by Sarah J. Maas</strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16510 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/CourtofMistFury-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/CourtofMistFury-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/CourtofMistFury-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/CourtofMistFury-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/CourtofMistFury.jpg 1650w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<p>This is Book #2 in a series. I almost didn&#8217;t finish the first book because, while normally I&#8217;m an easy-sell for <em>Beauty &amp; the Beast</em> retellings, there was a lot of pain in that first one. That first book was <em>A Court of Thorns and Roses</em>, which you&#8217;ve probably heard of. Book #2 here deserves some content warnings for partner abuse, discussion of sexual assault, molestation and harassment, and violence (gore). Book #1 has molestation and drugs (and violence + gore).</p>
<p>A friend of mine calls this book, &#8220;A Love Letter to Consent,&#8221; and I feel like she&#8217;s right, but what I want to talk about now is how this book and its prequel address scarcity concepts.</p>
<p>In the first book, the main character Feyre is the one person keeping herself or her family from starvation. Her father was a wealthy merchant, lost everything, and then never got a job after moving his daughters to a small hovel at a wintry homestead village. Feyre hunts from the age of fourteen. Even after she falls into graces with Fae nobility and is fed and clothed, she never forgets what it was like to be so desperate with bare resources.</p>
<p>In <em>A Court of Mist and Fury</em>, she leaves an abusive relationship that kept her living like a queen but with none of the power; she was caged, weak, and controlled. As Feyre moves on and finds new allies, her feelings and the natural concerns of one moving through the world &#8212; how will I earn the money to put food on the table and keep from freezing?&#8211; are regularly addressed, which was a pleasant surprise.</p>
<p><strong><em>Mistborn</em> by Brandon Sanderson <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16511 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mistborn-182x300.jpg" alt="" width="182" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mistborn-182x300.jpg 182w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mistborn-768x1264.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mistborn-622x1024.jpg 622w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Mistborn.jpg 1350w" sizes="(max-width: 182px) 100vw, 182px" /></strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s sheer coincidence that both of the books I want to share here have &#8216;mist&#8217; in their title. You&#8217;ve probably read this one, too, but I&#8217;ve been hankering to re-read it myself.</p>
<p>Similar to the other book I mentioned, <em>Mistborn</em> is part of a series and begins with a young woman doing all she can to keep from starving. The lower classes are oppressed by a god of a ruler and varying gifted elite who exploit and violate the lower classes. (CW: direct references to sexual assault and violence against women; also violence.) The plot follows a rebel group&#8217;s attempt to revolt against that system.</p>
<p>For me, the economic beauty here is how the magic system was intrinsically connected not just to power but also to resources. Metal consumption or adornment is the key to Allomancy, while Feruchemy relies on storing certain traits in &#8216;metalminds,&#8217; for release later. One must go without something to save up a more concentrated version of it, such as vision or memory.</p>
<p>Naturally, this affects how characters relate to each other, too. Who is paid what and how are supplies gathered for this multi-year secret attempt to overthrow a god? Vin, the main character, never shakes the wariness and resourcefulness that kept her alive on the streets, and we see her regularly questioning things like impractical clothing or finery and waste.</p>
<p>_________________________________</p>
<p><b>About this Column: </b>With occasional parentheticals a la Robin McKinley, <i>If This, Then That</i> connects the dots between niche interests for <em>LSQ</em> readers and the books that suit them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Babbling Bards and their Badinage</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/babbling-bards-and-their-badinage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rocky Breen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[If This Then That]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16342</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you always play a bard in D&#38;D, I’ve got some books for you. If&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you always play a bard in D&amp;D, I’ve got some books for you. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16344 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/photo-1545331567-f17305b1ea64-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/photo-1545331567-f17305b1ea64-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/photo-1545331567-f17305b1ea64.jpg 751w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>If you always play a bard, you&#8217;ve probably got your own way of saying what it means to be one and why you like it so much. I&#8217;ve established <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/if-this-then-that-rogue-readers/">before</a> that I always play a rogue, but as a writer, I imagine there&#8217;s a thrill to reshaping the D&amp;D game around you through the power of story and rhyme and rhythm that comes with the Bard class.</p>
<p>In the words of <a href="https://www.dndbeyond.com/classes/bard">D&amp;D Beyond</a>, &#8220;[W]ords and music are not just vibrations of air, but vocalizations with power all their own. The bard is a master of song, speech, and the magic they contain.&#8221;</p>
<p>While I&#8217;m not alone in occasionally poking fun at Bard players (just look up the definition of &#8216;Badinage&#8217;&#8211;it&#8217;s how they approach the game), the way they playfully question their settings and affect change without a traditional weapon is truly at the heart of table-top roleplaying. These next two recommendations are for you who appreciate the innovation required to simultaneously honor lore and speak it anew.</p>
<p><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16343 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/BowlesFeatheredSerpent-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/BowlesFeatheredSerpent-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/BowlesFeatheredSerpent.jpg 333w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><em>Feathered Serpent, Dark Heart of Sky: Myths of Mexico</em></strong> <strong>by David Bowles</strong></p>
<p>You ever get goosebumps when you read good poetry? I cry&#8211;weird as it is, I really just get teary-eyed from joy when the words on the page flow in a way that delights me. I teared up when I first read this book.</p>
<p>Bowles read the classics like <em>Beowulf</em> and <em>The Odyssey</em> and yet <a href="http://www.cincopuntos.com/products_detail.sstg?id=290">&#8220;he had never read a single Aztec or Mayan myth until he was in college</a>.&#8221; He set out to weave together in splendid bardic fashion the stories of Mexico. From the two brothers at the beginning of creation (and who make up the book&#8217;s name) to the Spanish invasion and resultant destruction, you&#8217;ll be inspired by how <em>Feathered Serpent </em>is so real and relatable while simultaneously fantastical and immersive.</p>
<p>Each section of the book opens with a Convocation. At the end of the final one, titled <em>Conquest and Courage</em>: &#8220;And if you look closely at our palimpsest souls, you can see the ghostly tracings of all we ever were, indelible if faint, ready to be read again by open hearts and minds&#8221; (Bowles, p 241).</p>
<p>Bowles, like all bards who deserve the word, seems very aware of the ways that both the past and present warp the world we see and the stories that &#8216;matter.&#8217; He shows this awareness obviously in his mission to shed light on Mesoamerican tales.</p>
<p>Additionally, even when dealing with cultures and time periods which skewed patriarchal roles, Bowles&#8217; <em>Feathered Serpent</em> did an incredible job of including and honoring the legacies of women, my favorite being horse-taming (and traitor-stomping) Erendira.</p>
<p><strong><em>Lore Olympus</em> by Rachel Smythe<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16345 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/LoreOlympusWebtoon-300x203.png" alt="" width="300" height="203" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/LoreOlympusWebtoon-300x203.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/LoreOlympusWebtoon.png 670w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></strong></p>
<p>I know I said I have &#8216;books&#8217; for you, but this wouldn&#8217;t be a list for bards without breaking the prose mold a little; this one&#8217;s a <a href="https://www.webtoons.com/en/romance/lore-olympus/list?title_no=1320&amp;page=1">webcomic.</a></p>
<p>At first, I was trepidatious because <em>Lore Olympus</em> is a re-telling of many Greek myths but primarily Persephone&#8217;s Abduction. And hello, Greek myths are full of violent, male-dominated storylines that make my skin crawl. I was also on the fence about the art style.</p>
<p>I was happy my gut was wrong on both points. The art style grew on me and is refreshingly different from prominent styles elsewhere.</p>
<p>And so far, the author effectively uses content warnings at the beginnings of chapters that have sexual assault or partner abuse. The series isn&#8217;t over, but that sensitive topics like those were my biggest concern with a Greek storyline. Personally, I can handle that content sometimes if I know it&#8217;s coming and in what shape it will be. This is <span style="text-decoration: underline;">not</span> <em>Game of Thrones</em>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16346 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/TiredHarp-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/TiredHarp-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/TiredHarp.jpg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />More importantly, however, <em>Lore </em><em>Olympus </em>opens up those very criticisms I have of the old myths, re-centers them, and allows us to experience difficult topics under a modern lens. I love how the author stares down (and <em>nails down</em>) the characteristics of so many figures we&#8217;re familiar with in Greek mythology&#8211;like Hecate and Apollo (helpful spoiler: he <em>does not </em>look good here), and refashions them as part of a dynamic story. I&#8217;m not the only one who thinks so, either&#8211; <a href="https://deadline.com/2019/10/lore-olympus-webtoon-and-the-jim-henson-company-will-partner-for-ya-animated-series-1202757078/">The Jim Henson Company</a> has announced plans to develop an animated adaptation of <em>Lore Olympus</em>.</p>
<p>Finally, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever seen an <a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/words-at-play/what-does-otp-mean-one-true-pairing">OTP</a> that was <em>so OTP</em> in just the dialogue and body language. The connection between Persephone and Hades reads so realistically it&#8217;s addictive.</p>
<p>_________________________________</p>
<p><b>About this Column: </b>With occasional parentheticals a la Robin McKinley, <i>If This, Then That</i> connects the dots between niche interests for <em>LSQ</em> readers and the books that suit them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>For Fellow Migraine-Sufferers</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/for-fellow-migraine-sufferers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rocky Breen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[If This Then That]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If, like me, you suffer migraines and headaches frequently, I&#8217;ve got some books and one&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16152 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/meredith-hunter-iS0Aq3QPsJ4-unsplash-1024x577.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="411" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/meredith-hunter-iS0Aq3QPsJ4-unsplash-1024x577.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/meredith-hunter-iS0Aq3QPsJ4-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/meredith-hunter-iS0Aq3QPsJ4-unsplash-768x433.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /></p>
<p>If, like me, you suffer migraines and headaches frequently, I&#8217;ve got some books and one game for you.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not going to play doctor here. My recommendations will not be nonfiction medical texts or anything like medical advice.</p>
<p>Even if I were a doctor, there are two spins on migraines: the personal (what your body uniquely experiences) and the uncontrollable. There have been weeks where I did everything I could that I knew my body needed&#8211;got eight hours of sleep, drank lots of water, exercised to relieve stress, and ate regular meals without MSG. But a volatile storm system (I cannot control the weather) or someone&#8217;s super strong perfume (also beyond my control) would lay me up for three days in a cold, dark room with a vicegrip headache and intermittent nausea.</p>
<p>During that migraine KO period, I don&#8217;t always just lay there. I get up and munch on ice cream because it tastes good and gives me a bit of relief, even though my digestive tract has shut down from the pain and will punish me later for this choice.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m hoping these stories below supply a different sort of relief when your eyes are ready for reading and you want to feel seen or understood. Not all of them actually feature headaches or even a relatable illness, but all come to mind when I want others to have some insight into my condition.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/thearcanagame?lang=en">The Arcana (Game)</a> by Nix Hydra<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16153 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/thearcana-300x147.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="147" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/thearcana-300x147.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/thearcana.jpg 700w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></strong></p>
<p>This fantasy/romance visual novel is free to play on various platforms of mobile phones. The plot begins as a murder mystery and evolves into a personal romance against larger than life supernatural entities pulling the strings across different continents.</p>
<p>Nadia Satrinava (the character in the middle of the image above) suffers headaches regularly. One character gives her a neti pot and suggests she experiences allergies or at least regular nasal congestion (I get the latter, courtesy of the headaches). Nadia was effectively in a coma for three years but now catalyzes events of the story to look into the murder of her husband and improve her city. Along the way, she tries to regain lost memories and revitalize her magical abilities. You can see her character most by romancing her, but she leaves an impression even if you pursue another character.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignleft" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/7/70/The_Hero_and_the_Crown.jpg" /><strong><em>The Hero and the Crown</em> by Robin McKinley</strong></p>
<p>Anytime I&#8217;m down for the count, I think about this book, which, published in 1984, is probably not new to any <em>LSQ</em> reader. Aerin, the main character, ingests a poisonous plant called surka; it will kill anyone not of royal blood, and while Aerin survives, she is ill for years. The symptoms at first were hallucinations and near-blindness, dizziness and stomachaches.</p>
<p>Eventually, Aerin bonds with her father&#8217;s retired war horse when she has energy enough but not capacity enough to roam as freely and easily as she could have before. She&#8217;s walking with a cane and can&#8217;t see very well when she goes to the horse: &#8220;It was a kind of trapped restlessness combined with a feeling of kinship for the equally trapped and restless Talat that drew her to his pasture.&#8221; (Chapter 3 of <em>The Hero and the Crown</em> by Robin McKinley).</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;Umbernight&#8221; by Carolyn Ives Gilman<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16163 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/john-fowler-d2YMQ-hZ3og-unsplash-300x257.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="257" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/john-fowler-d2YMQ-hZ3og-unsplash-300x257.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/john-fowler-d2YMQ-hZ3og-unsplash-768x659.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/john-fowler-d2YMQ-hZ3og-unsplash-1024x879.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></strong></p>
<p>This short story is less about one person dealing with a specific illness or condition as it is a <em>Pitch Black</em> -style team race for a dusty colony in space to fetch supplies during &#8220;Umbernight&#8221;&#8211;the emergence of a binary star through a nebula which casts the planet into X-radiation. The people on the colony usually stay hidden underground during this, but the team chosen to fetch supplies has to make do with radiation-blocking suits and tents.</p>
<p>The twist, if you&#8217;ll let me spoil it, is that an entire ecosystem develops in this X-ray season, which transforms the landscape and adds nearly insurmountable obstacles to the team&#8217;s progress.</p>
<p>Sometimes, on a day to day basis, this is how migraines seem to me. I go out with my armor, my bag o&#8217; medicine in case the worst hits, and sometimes even that isn&#8217;t enough to fully prepare me. &#8220;Umbernight&#8221; is one of my favorite SFF stories of all time.</p>
<p>Talking to others with migraines has helped me feel like I&#8217;m not alone. Despite how many people suffer migraines (1 in 5 women and 1 in 16 men, according to the <a href="https://americanmigrainefoundation.org/">American Migraine Foundation</a>), they&#8217;re often misunderstood or seen as headaches you can simply take OTC medicine for and move past (they aren&#8217;t).</p>
<p>There&#8217;s something speculative about that dynamic, I think. Our books, our stories in SFF and horror try to question the assumed and pry up those things that are overlooked or misunderstood to see them clearly, and personally, I always think of the stories above to conceptualize this new stage of my life.</p>
<p>_________________________________</p>
<p><b>About this Column: </b>With occasional parentheticals a la Robin McKinley, <i>If This, Then That</i> connects the dots between niche interests for <em>LSQ</em> readers and the books that suit them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>For Readers Wading through Heartbreak</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/for-readers-wading-through-heartbreak/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rocky Breen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[If This Then That]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My good friend is separating from her partner of fifteen years. In sharing the sad&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15948 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/fabio-jock-51U-PW1y3ts-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/fabio-jock-51U-PW1y3ts-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/fabio-jock-51U-PW1y3ts-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/fabio-jock-51U-PW1y3ts-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />My good friend is separating from her partner of fifteen years. In sharing the sad news with me, she also told me about a trip to the cinema made difficult because she had to choose between something that definitely had romance (cue unhappy thoughts) and a macho movie with lots of car chases, guns, and explosions. She chose the macho movie. (Thankfully, she ended up in the wrong theater for actually the right movie at that time for her: Dora.)</p>
<p>Some people, in the wake of a breakup, crave examples of what they&#8217;re going through to feel less freaked out and less isolated. Personally, I watched more <a href="https://medium.com/jane-austens-essays/modern-austens-guide-to-breakups-342a46110e7f">Jane Austen</a> adaptations after a bad breakup than I had during the whole of the relationship itself. Others, meanwhile, want to steer clear of the topic as a whole.</p>
<p>If, like my good friend, you&#8217;re going through a breakup and want to avoid mushy plots, I&#8217;ve got some speculative genre recommendations for you.</p>
<p><strong><em>Pegasus</em> by Robin McKinley</strong> <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-15945 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Pegasus.jpg" alt="" width="183" height="275" /></p>
<p>Yes, she&#8217;s my favorite author, but I kept this book on my shelf unread for years, strangely afraid I would be disappointed just because the cover features a very majestic pegasus. I always thought it would be a very fluffy, Lisa Frank, candy sweet story, but <a href="http://robinmckinleysblog.com/yes-question-three-read-all-about-it/">it isn&#8217;t</a>. The story winds through the politics of a human nation and their allies, Pegasi, which are a culturally, linguistically, and of course biologically separate group. I loved the exploration of culture shock and friendship. When I feel like being distracted from my troubles, I pick up this book.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the first in a series and has a pretty intense cliffhanger, though, if that helps you estimate its worth to you in this difficult time.</p>
<p><strong><em>Saving Montgomery Sole</em> by Mariko Tamaki</strong> <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15946 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/SavingSole-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/SavingSole-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/SavingSole.jpg 331w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></p>
<p>This book isn&#8217;t technically speculative&#8211;it&#8217;s YA. I include it anyway because it&#8217;s a fast read and very subtle, leaving a lot of interpretation up to the reader. The fantasy-adjacent storyline teeters on the main character, Montgomery (AKA Monty), buying a crystal amulet and finding (through confirmation bias) that the amulet gives her some mild wish-fulfillment powers. Throughout the book, she&#8217;s frustrated and sometimes angry, with good reason in a number of cases.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no romance, unless you count Monty&#8217;s ridiculously adorable moms, whose presence in the town rarely escapes public notice. The fact that Monty has two moms (instead of something more heteronormative), becomes one of the central tension points for the story. Monty is frustrating sometimes, but in a relatable way to even an adult reader like myself.</p>
<p><strong><em>Assassin&#8217;s Apprentice</em> by Robin Hobb <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15947 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Robin_Hobb_-_Assassins_Apprentice_Cover-202x300.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Robin_Hobb_-_Assassins_Apprentice_Cover-202x300.jpg 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Robin_Hobb_-_Assassins_Apprentice_Cover.jpg 240w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" /></strong></p>
<p>This book was originally published in 1995. I could just as easily put Tamora Pierce&#8217;s <em>Alanna</em> on this list, but I&#8217;m pretty sure you, dear reader, know that one already. Besides, <em>Assassin&#8217;s Apprentice</em> is one I myself read in the wake of a breakup, so I&#8217;m giving it priority here.</p>
<p>The pace of <em>Assassin&#8217;s Apprentice</em> is slow and winding. Sometimes we see each day pass for the character. Sometimes years pass and we revisit him when he&#8217;s older. Always, he&#8217;s growing and changing and while he does develop feelings for someone in his teen years, nothing culminates from his interest, and the bulk of the story is not devoted to this crush.</p>
<p>If you haven&#8217;t read this book yet, it&#8217;s about a boy, Fitz, who apprentices to the court&#8217;s assassin. The boy is the bastard son of a would-be king. The unique magic, <a href="https://awkwardbotany.com/">botanical training</a>, intrigue, and bullying Fitz experiences all seem small and inconsequential at first, but these notes later crescendo, taking the reader through to the climax of the story.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s surprisingly hard to find SFF that dodges romance, but I hope these three get you started with what you need on the difficult path of healing ahead.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Language Lovers</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/language-lovers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rocky Breen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[If This Then That]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;re the sort of LSQ reader who&#8217;s memorized Klingon, Al-bhed, or Elven, I&#8217;ve got&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15743 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dmitry-ratushny-wpi3sDUrSEk-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dmitry-ratushny-wpi3sDUrSEk-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dmitry-ratushny-wpi3sDUrSEk-unsplash-768x509.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dmitry-ratushny-wpi3sDUrSEk-unsplash-1024x678.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />If you&#8217;re the sort of LSQ reader who&#8217;s memorized Klingon, Al-bhed, or Elven, I&#8217;ve got some books for you.</p>
<p>As someone with a degree in Linguistics, I&#8217;m obliged to tell you that the most boring question you can ask a linguist is, &#8220;What&#8217;s the hardest language I can learn?&#8221;</p>
<p>The answer is subjective and dependent on so many variables: What&#8217;s the native language you speak? What&#8217;s hard to you about the new language? What&#8217;s hard to you about your own native language? Have you studied any languages before now? You may as well ask what the hardest subject in primary school or what the most difficult job out there is.</p>
<p>A much more interesting activity with language, and what drew me to the major initially, is to observe those many <em>variables</em> in languages much the way a biologist might observe lichens or wolf packs.</p>
<p>For the language nerds among our readers, I&#8217;m happy to recommend the following goodies.</p>
<h4><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15737 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/9780241180020-195x300.jpg" alt="" width="195" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/9780241180020-195x300.jpg 195w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/9780241180020.jpg 279w" sizes="(max-width: 195px) 100vw, 195px" />The Sense of Style: The Thinking Person&#8217;s Guide to Writing in the 21st Century</em> by Steven Pinker</h4>
<p>What it is: a book about how to write nonfiction well. You&#8217;ll learn about garden path sentences (the sort that you have to read and reread and reread but still can&#8217;t glean the meaning of) and how to avoid writing them. You&#8217;ll learn which rules from Strunk and White or Hodges, etc., make no sense and, in fact, were violated by their composers.</p>
<p>Steven Pinker is a well-known and experienced scientist yet he writes so accessibly, even hilariously. (Noam Chomsky, on the other hand, is also a well-known and experienced scientist, yet his writing is notoriously winding and difficult to parse).</p>
<p>Pinker is great at walking the essential tightrope between descriptivism (what&#8217;s happening in language, including in the brains of its users) and prescriptivism (AKA &#8216;how one <em>should</em> use a spoken/signed language&#8217;), <a href="http://itre.cis.upenn.edu/~myl/languagelog/archives/003588.html">that can of worms.</a></p>
<p>It makes sense to have a healthy dose of prescriptivism in orthography and rhetoric. What if I suddenly decided to follow-through for Webster, who wanted to <a href="http://mentalfloss.com/article/53723/26-noah-webster%E2%80%99s-spelling-changes-didn%E2%80%99t-catch">modernize English spelling</a>? What if I forgot the importance of commas in writing, &#8220;Let&#8217;s go eat, Grandma!&#8221;</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re the sort of person who wants to red-pen this column (I use too many parentheticals, don&#8217;t I?), then <em>Sense of Style</em> is my first recommendation for you. And I think you&#8217;ll like it!</p>
<h4><em>Language Files</em> edited by Vedrana Mihalicek and Christin Wilson <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15738 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/langfiles-235x300.jpg" alt="" width="235" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/langfiles-235x300.jpg 235w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/langfiles.jpg 360w" sizes="(max-width: 235px) 100vw, 235px" /></h4>
<p>What it is: a textbook introducing key concepts in the science of linguistics. Signed languages are not ignored! (Most of those examples are from ASL, however.) Comics about semantics, Venn diagrams about sweaters and mammals, sentence trees, culture, and context are all explored in a deep yet still easy-to-follow manner with thought experiments and exercises aplenty.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a big book, y&#8217;all. But there&#8217;s a reason it&#8217;s used in many universities as a primer in the science of studying language.</p>
<h4><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15739 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/makingsense-231x300.jpg" alt="" width="231" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/makingsense-231x300.jpg 231w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/makingsense.jpg 313w" sizes="(max-width: 231px) 100vw, 231px" />Making Sense of Language: Readings in Culture and Communication</em> edited by Susan D. Blum</h4>
<p>What it is: a collection of academic papers, excerpts, and essays in various but mostly sociolinguistic topics. Pre- and post-reading questions and layman terms introductions to each entry are included. Labov&#8217;s classic &#8220;Social Stratification of (r) in New York City Department Stores&#8221; appears, as does Whorf&#8217;s &#8220;The Relation of Habitual Thought and Behavior to Language,&#8221; and Lakoff and Johnson&#8217;s seminal, &#8220;Metaphors We Live By.&#8221;</p>
<p>The best description I&#8217;ve read of culture shock and foreign language exhaustion is David Antal&#8217;s &#8220;A Linguistic Odyssey: One family&#8217;s experience with language shift and cultural identity in Germany and France.&#8221; The uniqueness of law to its country of practice is illustrated in Yanrong Chang&#8217;s &#8220;Courtroom Questioning as a Culturally Situated Persuasive Genre of Talk.&#8221;  Mary Bucholtz&#8217;s &#8220;The Whiteness of Nerds: Superstandard English and Racial Markedness&#8221; from 2001 is now a snapshot at the performative aspects of nerd culture in the past; read it and compare it to nerd culture now.</p>
<p>If you are the sort of person who thinks about the social meaning of language—culture, race, law, gender, power, religion, and all these other intersections manifesting in language, this book is a good reason to at least dip your toes in <em>Language Files </em>(above) for some Linguistics fundamentals; most of the entries in <em>Making Sense of Language</em> are written for peers in academia. Alternatively, if you try to read some and get a little lost, look around a little online and see who else is talking about it. You might find simpler explanations.</p>
<h4><a href="https://lingthusiasm.com/"><em>Lingthusiasm</em></a> by Gretchen McCulloch and Lauren Gawne</h4>
<h4><a style="color: #d93d3d;" href="https://lingthusiasm.com/"><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15740 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/tumblr_static_1nw903mq1iiskc888s04808s0-300x90.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="90" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/tumblr_static_1nw903mq1iiskc888s04808s0-300x90.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/tumblr_static_1nw903mq1iiskc888s04808s0-768x230.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/tumblr_static_1nw903mq1iiskc888s04808s0-1024x307.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/tumblr_static_1nw903mq1iiskc888s04808s0.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></em></a></h4>
<p>What it is: a podcast about different topics in linguistics. Each episode runs about 30 minutes, and the transcripts go up, too, if you want/need to read along. This is a recent, current, ongoing update to the previous two, which are a bit older.</p>
<p>Some recent topics have been: &#8220;Why spelling is hard — but also hard to change,&#8221; &#8220;Evidentiality&#8221; (something American English really hates, in my observation), &#8220;Pop Culture in Cook Islands Māori,&#8221; &#8220;Why do we gesture when we talk?&#8221; and &#8220;Making books and tools speak Chatino&#8221;.</p>
<p>The creator also has a forthcoming book called <em>Because Internet</em>. Yeah. I thought you&#8217;d like that.</p>
<h4><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-15741 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/starshipiris.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/starshipiris.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/starshipiris-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /><a href="https://procyonpodcasts.com/starship-iris/">The Mysterious Case of the Starship Iris</a></em> created by Jessica Best</h4>
<p>What it is: an audio drama! That&#8217;s right. It&#8217;s a fiction podcast. The way language is handled in the universe of<em> Starship Iri</em>s is so reflective of the variety that exists in our own world.</p>
<p>Not only can you hear about imaginary English dialects across the terra-formed space diaspora (Earth is no more, it sounds like), you can also enjoy a trans translator (I see what they did there) who speaks the modern and archaic form of at least one alien language and hypothesizes about nano-bot cognition and use of pronouns.</p>
<p>In case your head hurts reading all the super sciency books I recommended earlier, I thought I&#8217;d leave you with this leap out of reality. Listen, and let it re-kindle that desire you have to explore language and ask questions about the universe.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
