<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Geek Girls in the Library &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/geek-girls-in-the-library/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:45:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Neither Comics Nor Librarian</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/neither-comics-nor-librarian/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tammy Garrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 17:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geek Girls in the Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Where in the world have I been? Life has gotten in the way! First, I’m&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Fandom.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8053 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Fandom-300x300.jpg" width="300" height="300" /></a>Where in the world have I been? Life has gotten in the way! First, I’m not a librarian right now, which is a scene I am thinking of leaving temporarily or permanently. I’m also hiding out from the fandom community.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Comic Librarian, indeed.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I’m not sure if I’m disillusioned with the profession as a whole, or my last job. I still believe in the power of libraries to change lives. I believe that young adults deserve a level of service they seldom get in libraries. Libraries don’t value the presence of young adults because they’re loud, they’re mischievous, and sometimes get into trouble. That hasn’t changed.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But I think I’m tired of dealing with the constant pushback for now. I may be ready to fight the good fight again later. What pushback? Not only do you have to negotiate with other librarians, and library administration, but you have to often push back against the community, the perception of the library as not being valuable, and the round after round of library de-funding.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I get that that is the job. Library advocacy, advocacy for young adults, and the general stress that goes with library funding issues. That’s why who you work with can make or break a situation. I think I worked in an environment that broke it for me. And now I’m taking time off, without regret.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So why am I hiding from fandom? Isn’t that the other part of my street cred and appeal? If you’ve spent any time on the internet involved in fandoms, you know that there is drama. I remember there being drama in the Sherlock Holmes fandom in the 1990s (and really, what kind of drama could happen in a hundred year old fandom?) But still&#8211;the corner of fandom I was in was not fond of women, much less young women infiltrating. The Baker Street Irregulars, the most prestigious part of that fandom, had only start inducting female members. Good old boys club, indeed.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/index-3.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8052 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/index-3.jpg" width="259" height="194" /></a></p>
<p dir="ltr">I ended up on a semi-date with a guy in his 30s who wore a deerstalker and a Doctor Who scarf, it got kind of weird, and I bowed out of the fandom, after spending years trying to prove myself to “not be like the other girls” and more like one of the guys in that fandom, which is toxic femininity. Trying to be taken seriously by men by trying to conform to the majority male interests and patterns is throwing your fellow women under the bus.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I’ve wandered in and out of fandoms before; Batman, Doctor Who, etc. All of them have had their own dramas. I remember another bout of toxic femininity/misogyny that revolved around the Doctor Who companion, Rose, and how horrible she was for loving the Doctor. Then came misogyny and racism that revolved around Martha Jones, the first black companion, and how allegedly clingy she was with the Doctor (and generally horrible).</p>
<p dir="ltr">With the advent of BBC’s Sherlock, I again slipped back into Sherlock Holmes fandom, this time in a corner with a focus on women bloggers and fanwork creators. It felt safer. But, alas, the drama found me again. Fandom follows real-life cycles of agreement and disagreement and fallings-out. But again I found myself mixed up in misogyny from female fans. This time regarding a male/male relationship that was never going to happen, and how horrible women characters secretly were. <br class="m_152585996085792054m_8244211713020639020gmail-kix-line-break" /><br class="m_152585996085792054m_8244211713020639020gmail-kix-line-break" />There’s no point in fighting misogyny with people who will never listen to your opinion, much less consider it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">SO I suppose that is where I am now&#8211;tired of fighting the good fight, and taking a break. At some point I may rekindle my love for both librarianship and the sheer joy of loving a piece of media with other people who love the same thing, but for now, I am on hiatus. Perhaps I will have strong opinions next month.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Till then, if you feel so inclined, check out my Young Adult Sherlock Holmes novel from MX Publishing: The Twisted Blackmailer <a href="http://tinyurl.com/TwistedBlackmailer" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://tinyurl.com/TwistedBlackmailer&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1487818992628000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEd5uqXvxYsZtsNhO5ZE1ZGBG1N8w">http://tinyurl.com/TwistedBlac<wbr />kmailer</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Librarian fails at being a nerd who plans ahead. Reel at eleven.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/librarian-fails-nerd-plans-ahead-reel-eleven/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tammy Garrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 17:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geek Girls in the Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m officially the nerd librarian where I work. The director is a nerd. But most&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m officially the nerd librarian where I work. The director is a nerd. But most of the time he has to keep his administrative hat on, and can’t let his freak flag fly. I’m in charge of a lot of the programming, so I have the opportunity to bend those programs to my strong suits. Like this fall’s<em> Doctor Who</em> party, and last week’s<em> Star Wars</em> party. Conveniently I can throw parties for premiers of TV shows and movies that appeal to the masses and let me indulge in stuff I probably care way too much about.</p>
<p>Please, let me share my feelings about how Mrs. Hudson from BBC <em>Sherlock</em> and Wilf from <em>Doctor Who</em> would make the perfect couple. Also, I count fan fiction as actual books read for Summer Reading.</p>
<p>Sometimes, being a super-huge nerd who gets to incorporate that into their daily job dealings can have its own problems.</p>
<p>I’m learning to work ahead. Yes, I should have learned this in fourth grade, with the rest of the kids. But I’m a slow learner. Remember when your teacher said ‘you can’t do this all in one night, so you’d better start early’? That used to be more of a challenge than a warning. I found out later it was a magical combination of executive dysfunction, ADHD and OCD. Yes. OCD has prevented me from starting projects until the day before they were due for the last, oh, thirty-two years of my life, give or take.</p>
<p>Which is a sad story when you are both a library administrator and in charge of the vast majority of your library’s programming. Yes. For the last nine years of being a librarian, I have been flying by the seat of my pants. I’ve been putting together programming the day before, or the day of, based entirely on whatever I had put on the flyer at the beginning of the month. I have written grant proposals the day before they were due (and I have gotten the grants) and I have planned actual university classes I have taught an hour before the class began.</p>
<p>I know that sounds like bragging. In a way, maybe it is. The classic hum-brag (a brag disguised as humbleness). But in reality, it does cause more problems than it solves. What problems are solved by procrastination? Well, the OCD perfectionism has to take a back seat when you are flying by the seat of your pants, trying to meet a deadline, instead of trying to make everything as good and perfect as you know it could be, in your mind. It quiets the ADD, because you are forced to focus. It also kicks executive dysfunction in the teeth, and usually the adrenaline rush caused by the deadline will override the brain’s inability to grasp the task at hand and outline the steps necessary to get a task done. And when you have executive functioning issues, anything that a normal person sees as three steps (open litter box, scoop poop, dispose of poop) becomes a million tiny tasks in my mind (probably also aided by autism). I’ve counted, cleaning the litter boxes takes me approximately 21 micro-steps.</p>
<p>So I see two weeks of library programming, consisting of a craft, sometimes a movie, games and accidental learning, with each program lasting about four hours, as some impossible task. This, to me, requires somewhere upward of 37,509 steps. Yes, I’ve counted.</p>
<p>I planned a theme for each day of winter break, when the kids would be flooding the library looking for something to do. I made sure there would be extra staff on the schedule, to help with the programming. Believe it or not, most kids under the age of twelve mostly need help doing the crafts themselves, and playing whatever games are on hand. Any game that says it is for 8+ actually needs an adult to help ten year olds play it.</p>
<p>I even had boxes for each day of programming, labeled appropriately. Crafts went into those boxes as I found them, prizes, relevant books, etc. I had entire days worth of activities planned by the first week of December.</p>
<p>Except I forgot one little thing.</p>
<p>The first day of winter break was the 18th. Yes. These kids have over two weeks off of school, and the first day was Friday, only slightly more than half-way through the month. If that isn’t terrifying, I don’t know what is.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Star-Wars-party-Invitation-blank.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5900"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5900 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Star-Wars-party-Invitation-blank-213x300.jpg" alt="Star Wars party Invitation - blank" width="213" height="300" /></a>Conveniently, however, December 18th was also the premier of the new <em>Star Wars</em> movie. Rejoice! We have a theme! We have a party idea!</p>
<p>So I threw myself into <em>Star Wars</em> planning. I had decorations, I had games and crafts, and I had movies to show. And even better, I had backup crafts. Backup games. Backup movies. I was so ready I could kinda cry a little.</p>
<p>I just forgot one little thing.</p>
<p>Staff.</p>
<p>Oh.</p>
<p>Yes. I was so intent on making a <em>Star Wars</em> party to end all <em>Star Wars</em> parties, that I forgot to actually staff the darned thing. Lesson to future librarians, and future administrators: actually have employees or volunteers on hand when you throw a six-hour party. Oops.</p>
<p>So, I spent six hours trying to keep kids under control. Kids on the first day of winter break. I helped them with crafts. I controlled the glue gun with an iron fist. I dished out popcorn until I finally just had to cut them off and say we’d run out (a big fat huge lie). They drank six gallons of lemonade in less than two hours, and they used every single puppet face I had meticulously hand-drawn and cut out the day before.</p>
<p>Also, do you know what happens when you give twenty-five children and their parents popcorn during movie time?</p>
<p>Basically, it’s a sad story that ends with you spending an hour vacuuming the entire party room. To paraphrase and abuse the words of the Buddha: life is pain.</p>
<p>Friday was a mess of my own design. Half an hour at the radio station to promote both the party and everything else happening over break, then an emergency trip to Walmart, because I had forgotten to check out one of the <em>Star Wars</em> movies a month ago, so I could hold onto it for the party, where I spent $45 on three DVDs that weren’t even the original versions (I have a chub-rub-esque relationship with the Special Editions), and $15 on the <em>Star Wars</em> Lego movies. Oh yeah. And a <em>Star Wars</em> shirt that didn’t really fit. It’s cute. But it doesn’t fit.</p>
<p>Back to work to finish putting party stuff together; photocopying the BB8 craft, putting things in the party room and setting up, then a whole morning and afternoon of scissors, glue, popcorn, overly excited kids who demanded their free poster for showing up at the movie at the beginning of <em>Return of the Jedi</em> even before Leia had killed Jabba the Hutt. Epic cleanup, a sore back, and only myself to blame.</p>
<p>So that’s how my Friday went. Learn life lessons. Learn them from my mistakes. If you’re going to plan ahead, make a list. Check it twice. Maybe even make sure that extra help is on your list, and that it matches the lists for all of the other things happening that week. Monday I have no game planned, but I sure do have crafts and staff on hand. Modify lists as necessary. Weep into your oatmeal if you find it relieves stress. Do whatever you need to.</p>
<p>That is my bit of wisdom gleaned from all of this, my first attempt at really, truly planning ahead. More lists taped to boxes. More help. More backup crafts.</p>
<p>I guess what I’m saying is, I’m going to plan ahead to plan ahead better.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is &#8220;Pop Culture Librarian&#8221; an official title?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pop-culture-librarian-official-title/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tammy Garrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 17:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geek Girls in the Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At some point, between running a one-day comic convention for my library and hosting a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At some point, between running a one-day comic convention for my library and hosting a <em>Doctor Who</em> party at the launch of the new season, I realized that I’m not categorically a “young adult” librarian. And most of the time patrons wouldn’t recognize me acting as the assistant director, since I am usually running a program for one or another age group during the monthly board meetings.</p>
<p>I’m beginning to see myself more as a pop culture librarian. I have a teen section that isn’t just for teens; a lot of the pop culture in our library finds its way there, from manga to <em>Wired Magazine,</em> simply because it doesn’t seem to ‘fit’ anywhere else. In a certain way, harboring the <em>Batman</em> comics over near the John Green and <em>The Hunger Games</em> serves in a way to (hyperbolically) ghetto-ize it. There are two sides to the coin: the impression may be that the BBC Sherlock Casebook is too immature, or of too low quality for adults. And on the other hand, when adults go into the Young Adult section to pick up the latest Sword Art Online or Wonder Woman, they’re making the teen section just a little less teen-friendly.</p>
<p>Is there a solution? I don’t know. I’m planning a massive renovation of the area in an attempt to give the teens the space they need, but still give access to graphic novels and other pop culture interest items to the rest of the library patrons. I curate those collections carefully, trying to make sure they’re the best they can be.</p>
<p>It’s not just that sort of collection development that has moved me away from being a general Young Adult librarian to a pop culture curator and librarian. I run programs. A lot of programs. From programs every afternoon for school-aged kids, to teen, adult and family programs. We painted faces for Halloween. I’m perfecting my creepy doll, and my years of doodling the Batman symbol in my high school notebooks is finally paying off. We have adult movie night, where I am (hopefully) showing the original <em>Night of the Living Dead</em> and discussing it, because I feel it has literary and movie history merit. Doctor Who Club, Anime Club, a Minecraft Crafting day… and that’s just a few of the things this month.</p>
<p>I’m also holding <em>NBA 2016</em> hostage in my office until some of the older boys make few behavior improvements. There is a story by Spike Lee incorporated into the basketball game, so I look forward to watching them play it, as much as I enjoy watching them play the <em>Batman Arkham</em> games. For the plots. The same reason I read Playboy. I swear.</p>
<p>And as the assistant director, I get to justify having two game systems in the library, and why I am holding <em>NBA 2016</em> hostage, and why our library is much louder than it used to be. It can make being an administrator strange sometimes, especially when you try to delve into the evolution of libraries in the 21st century as a lively community space for learning and growing, as opposed to a gatekeeper of culture, as it used to be in the last century. The last person I explained this to didn’t like that answer. Nor did they appreciate the suggestion that they use the computer lab as a quiet study area since that is what it was designed for.</p>
<p>I do my fair share of telling kids not to run in the library, not to yell, not to knock over a zillion DVDs like they are Kiva blocks. And I am telling them constantly that their shoes are untied, or that they have to wear shoes in the library. You wouldn’t think that would be a problem, but it is. I want you to feel at home in the library. But not so much that you run around in stocking feet (or worse, with the pre-teens, sockless and with great stench) or fall asleep on our furniture. I encourage the staff to kindly set kids on the path of righteousness, which includes walking in the library, wearing shoes, and not screaming as if they are being eaten by lions.</p>
<p>Still, kids get excited. Especially when we have things happening in multiple parts of the library. They often have to pass through the usual quiet spots, and our library’s beautiful arched skylights echo every voice in the building. So I do understand why some people are put-off by the chaos. But I will still defend kids. Not just ‘my’ teenagers, but all of them. We aren’t a playground. But we’re also not a penitentiary. If they’re running or whooping, it means they’re excited by what is going on, and maybe, just maybe, excited about learning. I know that can be hard for older patrons to sit with. It’s hard to remember what it was like to be that age and be so enthusiastic about something as simple as a paper doll craft.</p>
<p>The adults who are a bit younger seem to be kinder toward the new face of the library. Especially the ones that have shown up at our <em>Star Wars</em> and <em>Doctor Who</em> parties, and whom I expect to see again at the new Anime and Doctor Who clubs. Next weekend we’re going to keep with the Halloween theme and watch <a href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/school-live" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>High School Live</em></a>, which is the second scariest anime I have ever seen, and the 4th Doctor <em>Doctor Who </em>episode &#8220;The Pyramids of Mars&#8221;, due to the high volume of mummies and people in masks.</p>
<p>I’m also looking toward other months and other programs, like a <em>Star Wars</em> celebration for the launch of the new movies, a <em>Frozen</em> day, some sort of <em>Transformers</em> program (at the request of the pre-teen boys) and all the way into the far future with summer reading programs about sports for adults, where I may be permitted to unleash my unholy knowledge of the history of baseball upon some unsuspecting patrons (I’m convinced that leaving the Red Sox is what put Babe Ruth’s life into a downward spiral) just for the fun of it.</p>
<p>So, no. I’m not clinging to the classical interpretation of the library the way I probably ought to. I got rid of all the “classic” young adult literature, and non-fiction that was ‘good’ for them. I’ve tossed a lot of things from other collections that may have been classics, or of some use to someone, but weren’t circulating. My apologies to Asimov and Sagan. No apologies or explanations given to Heinlein or Hubbard. I even have a theory I could get rid of every book in the library by Tolstoy and no one would notice, not even the other librarians. People just aren’t into stark, bleak and tragic Russian literature, like they once were. I’m not sure, exactly, who I could sell the story of Anna Karenina to. Here, have this depressing book that ends with suicide by steam train (spoilers). It will make a great holiday fireside read. If your family is super-depressing it may cheer you up.</p>
<p>I love history, I love science. I have a special place for classic literature (though I take the dead white men with a grain of salt) and I try to cram that into as many heads as I can. I know a lot about it. And I know a lot about this other area that is important to our patrons: <em>The Walking Dead</em>, the final issue of <em>Naruto</em>, making Light Sabers out of pool noodles, the entire history of<em> Doctor Who</em>, Golden Age Flash, the sadly deceased <em>Dresden Files</em> TV show, and how to paint a zombie that looks like its face has half fallen off. I’m chock full of these things. Maybe it&#8217;s my age (I’m one month older than the cutoff for millenials) or my general lack of enthusiasm for the literary and art history of dead white men. Or I am a super-massive nerd who was suckled on stories about Batman and Spider-Man before I could even talk.</p>
<p>But at the end of the day I want to watch<em> The Muppets</em>, try to level up my Pokemon and write a little fanfic for this show and that. I’m not really a responsible adult, I just play one on TV.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gaming: an essay of sorts. OR: mischievous God reigns chaos upon Library Land.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/gaming-an-essay-of-sorts-or-mischievous-god-reigns-chaos-upon-library-land/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tammy Garrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 15:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geek Girls in the Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Once upon a time, everyone in Library Land, the librarians, the teachers and the public,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Once upon a time, everyone in Library Land, the librarians, the teachers and the public, all agreed that graphic novels and comic books were good for our youth. Graphic novels encouraged reading for reluctant readers, taught kids how to think in a visual and literary way, and told stories kids needed to read. It was a joyous time in Library Land. Everyone read graphic novels: superheroes, manga, non-fiction, non-traditional comics. People read everything they wanted. And if they didn&#8217;t like graphic novels, well, they didn&#8217;t read them at all. The war was over. The battle was won.</p>
<p>Then, along came a trickster librarian. We can call this librarian&#8230;Loki, maybe. And Loki bought an Xbox One for the library. Some people didn&#8217;t notice. It only came out for special occasions. Loki found this level of usage to be unsatisfactory. Loki wanted young adults in the library, and Loki knew that young adults loved one thing beyond emoticons and free Frostees from Wendy&#8217;s. They loved <em>Halo</em>.</p>
<p>And so, the Xbox began to make appearances every day at the library. It arrived on a golden ship. Announcements were made over the loudspeaker. It was even mentioned in marketing materials, and in the local newspaper.</p>
<p>Now, Loki was a trickster God. He cared very little for the opinions of naysayers. He cared mostly about chaos and followers. However, Loki&#8217;s boss, let&#8217;s call him Oden for the sake of argument, was worried about the opinions of actual library patrons, taxpayers and local figures.</p>
<p>&#8220;How can kids learn about reading if they are shooting things?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Kids are just going to play video games all day, and not learn anything!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;My tax dollars are meant for books, not <em>Grand Theft Auto</em>!&#8221;</p>
<p>Even though Oden had no problem with video games in the library, He still pushed Loki forward, &#8220;you created this mess, now you get to fix it.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/tumblr_muceicO0Ns1rzsryqo1_500.gif"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5215 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/tumblr_muceicO0Ns1rzsryqo1_500-265x300.gif" alt="tumblr_muceicO0Ns1rzsryqo1_500" width="265" height="300" /></a>Loki shrugged. He was the one who wanted <em>Halo: Masterchief Edition,</em> after all. &#8220;First, good sir, or ma&#8217;am,&#8221; he coughed. It was possible that particular taxpayer was either a human in a chicken suit, or, in fact, a very large chicken. It was so hard to tell these days. &#8220;I cannot bend the ear of a youth to tell him or her about the wonders of the written word if said youth is not in the library.&#8221;</p>
<p>The chicken sat down, feathers unruffled.</p>
<p>&#8220;And to you, good madam, with the long floral dress and Coke Bottle Glasses, I say that I have power over the children.&#8221;</p>
<p>He grinned and the patrons gasped as he pulled something from his pocket. Some winced and shied away.</p>
<p>Loki held up his smartphone. &#8220;I give unto you&#8230;Xbox Glass! I can kill any game remotely and take control of the system. The young whippersnappers cannot play forever! For I possess the ultimate power!&#8221;</p>
<p>The crowd gasped and whispered amongst itself for a moment, until the old man with the clucking false teeth pointed with his cane at the trickster god. &#8220;Oh yeah, well what about <em>Grand Theft Auto</em>! I don&#8217;t want my grandchildren racking up points for hitting cops and whores! I don&#8217;t care how good the soundtrack is!&#8221;</p>
<p>Making a face, it was Loki&#8217;s turn to shy away. &#8220;Sir, I don&#8217;t know who bought you that game for Christmas, but you should stop playing it. You have lost all respect for women and possibly your connection with reality. We don&#8217;t buy adult games. We buy cooperative games. Older and more experienced youth teach others and instruct them on how to play. They talk each other through the levels, and discuss strategy. When they play sports games, they have to come up with a strategy, execute it as a team, and use their hand-eye coordination to accomplish the team goal. It is like actual sports, but without parents yelling at the officials and yelling unseemly things from the stands.&#8221;</p>
<p>The old man grumbled, but stepped back into the crowd.</p>
<p>&#8220;Don&#8217;t be afraid, patrons! A new era is upon us! Digital storytelling! Games with cooperative modes, games that promote building and engineering! Games in Japanese where your children must read the subtitles!&#8221;</p>
<p>The patrons looked at each other and frowned. The person in the chicken suit waved a feathery wing at the library god. &#8220;We&#8217;ll let it pass for now. But we have our eye on you!&#8221;</p>
<p>And being a trickster god, Loki, the Youth Librarian, poofed away from their sight, and to the nearest GameStop to purchase a shiny new PS4.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Am Pretty Sure Batman Doesn&#8217;t Have These Problems</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/i-am-pretty-sure-batman-doesnt-have-these-problems/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tammy Garrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 18:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geek Girls in the Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I started a new job as an assistant director at a new library in December.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<figure id="attachment_4053" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-4053" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/14395792952_f66d1aa6ae.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-4053" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/14395792952_f66d1aa6ae-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-4053" class="wp-caption-text">Photo By: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/togawanderings/14395792952/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Thomas Galvez</a></figcaption></figure>
</div>
<div>I started a new job as an assistant director at a new library in December. For a long time, my concerns were taken up strictly by the tasks of moving and settling into a new house, and learning the aspects of my new job. Eventually it seemed like I had a handle on everything I was going to, and I had more time to ruminate on the change in position, the change in town, and the change in the nature of my job.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I am in charge of the performance of actual human beings now. I had a department with which we had some trouble, and the stress was making me anxious. That seems to be working out. But my anxiousness wasn&#8217;t going away. I had gotten rather worked up about a lot of cataloging issues. The Star Wars books were not in the same area because they were catalogued by author. The DVD section had movies from the same series in both the drama and sci-fi sections. I found a book in the biography section that was OBVIOUSLY supposed to go in the 636s, because it was the biography of a cat, not a human. I had new books piling up for young adults, even though they weren&#8217;t really new because no one kept track of them.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The bulging shelves and the multiple copies were stressing me out. I would walk past yet another biography of Hitler, and wonder how many a library could have, then start calculating how many were published by mainstream presses, and therefore available for libraries to buy, and determined I would have to get rid of nine books to keep up with the yearly influx of books about Hitler.</div>
<div></div>
<div>This stuff made me angry when I wasn&#8217;t at work. It made me anxious when I was in my office,  and would put me near a meltdown if I saw too many consecutive ’out of order’ or ’not-right’ things as I walked through the library.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I had a headache all the time. My office was a shambles and I wasn&#8217;t getting to all the things I wanted to do, because my mind was filled to the brim with ’not-right’ things existing outside of my office. And while under my control, technically, as a library administrator, it was out of my control just how many of them there were. I could spend a year fixing everything, and it would never be right.</div>
<div></div>
<div>It was miserable, and overwhelming. Only I didn&#8217;t quite realize that it was my obsession with fixing things that was overwhelming me. It is very common for a sensory processing disorder to accompany autism. I was used to that. Bright lights, loud sounds, bad textures of clothing and food&#8230;it really could be a nightmare sometimes. Something that had made my evenings at the library unbearable due to loudness level had been taken care of, and things were very quiet.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Eventually I got in to see a new psychiatrist. That is one of the problems with moving&#8211;you start over with every single doctor anew. Which meant rediagnosis. It isn&#8217;t a fun part of the process. She started asking me questions down a long list, and I ran through them as always. Yes, no, here is what it is like&#8230;and then came a bunch of questions I had answered before, but answered more honestly this time. Yes, I have to have a routine in the morning. BUT IT ISNT Obsessive Compulsive Disorder. IT IS SO I WONT FORGET ANYTHING. Yes, I count things. BUT IT ISNT OCD. It is because I just like to.</div>
<div></div>
<div>And I knew every  single one of these questions was directed toward a certain diagnosis, and while I answered them honestly for the first time ever, I kept saying how it couldn&#8217;t be OCD. It was the autism or it was just what I liked to do, and it wasn&#8217;t hurting anybody, therefore it wasn&#8217;t OCD.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I left the office miserable. I really didn&#8217;t need one more thing to deal with. On the one hand, if I had OCD I had been dealing with it all of my life without noticing. And dealing with it poorly, in some cases. On the other, there comes a tipping point where people don&#8217;t believe you can possibly have THAT many disorders. Especially invisible ones that make your life hell, because oh, you are so successful.</div>
<div></div>
<div>But I started applying OCD to some of the things causing me headaches&#8211;the cataloging, the locations of things, how things looked at work&#8230;</div>
<div></div>
<div>It was a library. It&#8217;s was supposed to be orderly, damnit. And here we were with biographies about cats in with the biographies about people! I was having a hard time with things being “good enough” instead of “right” as dictated by my strangely wired brain. That evaluation helped me take things down a notch.  Because I was certain I was doing everything wrong and that I was working on all of the wrong things because I couldn&#8217;t get everything done all at once, or fix the entire collection, all at once.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I am sure normal librarians (whatever those are) do not spend three or four hours contemplating exactly how to catalogue a Dungeons &amp; Dragons manual so that it will be visible and accessible. Especially when it is going into a room that will be locked (and therefore inaccessible) most of the day. I felt like I was being destroyed by tiny things. Is that what my life had become? A fiefdom of tiny issues that did not matter in the grand scheme of the library, much less the world? I really felt like I had dedicated myself to something stupid and pointless.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I suppose, in retrospect, the nature of my job, or my life was not wasted on a miniature kingdom of microscopic problems, my brain was inflating those problems and constantly putting them forward on my “to do” list so they were always hanging in front of me. I&#8217;m not sure how to deal with it yet. I am going to go to work <span class="aBn" tabindex="0" data-term="goog_820802444"><span class="aQJ">tomorrow</span></span> and only fixing the DVDs I have already put in my office. I will actively attempt to ignore thinking about the Star Wars and Forgotten Realms books spread out across the library.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I will start using an actual list program to truly prioritize what really needs to be done. And then I will go from there.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I am vengeance! I am the night!  I am… a book weeder.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/i-am-vengeance-i-am-the-night-i-am-a-book-weeder/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tammy Garrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 20:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geek Girls in the Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Like Batman, when curating the collection in your library, it’s best to swoop in like&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Like Batman, when curating the collection in your library, it’s best to swoop in like a force of nature, be swift, and if at all possible, work in the dead of night.</p>
<p>What the hell am I talking about?</p>
<p>There are two aspects of curating or developing a collection that a librarian has to worry about: what they add, and what they get rid of. Adding can be tricky business. What will actually check out? What will serve the patrons best? You use statistics, and conversations with users, professional literature and your education to make decisions regarding purchases, or which donations to accept.</p>
<p>That’s actually the easy part. You gather all of that information, see what publishers are promoting as being popular (that’s how it works&#8211;a book becomes a bestseller because a publisher says it will be and throws all of its marketing prowess behind said book), and look for the best prices, then place your order. That’s nothing.</p>
<p>So what do you get rid of?</p>
<p>Nothing.</p>
<p>Everything.</p>
<p>Whenever I have changed jobs and come into a new library, I inevitably have to weed. It’s not because I think the new library’s collection is insufficient; usually it’s because the library’s collection is bulging with books. In other words, no one has done a good thorough weeding in a very long time. Or, they have only weeded books that haven’t been checked out in a very long time, but have left things they felt were too valuable to get rid of.</p>
<p>Which I understand. We’re librarians. We love books and the knowledge they contain. We feel protective of our collections, even the old books that might not be checked out any more, but maybe cannot be replaced. It’s not a bad sentiment.</p>
<p>However, a library is not a warehouse for books. And even if it were, we just don’t have the room. There is no library in the world that has the room it would like to keep everything of value. My favorite library, the Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, in Pittsburgh Pennsylvania, is a wonderful library for research. It is in a college town, surrounded by universities that have students. People come from all over the world for its niche books and rare collections. There are parts of the library sealed off by translucent doors and walls where books are, literally, warehoused, and can only be retrieved by Certified Grownups (<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />) employed by the institution.</p>
<p>Even they get rid of books. Even they get rid of duplicate copies when the clamor for a new book has died down, and you end up with thirty-two copies of Twilight no one wants to read. The books are sold to the public, given to other institutions, or just plain recycled.</p>
<p>There. You know the library’s dirty secret. Those 50 Reader’s Digest volumes from the 1960s that you donated? They ended up in a recycling bin. Which is one reason why I prefer to do my dirty deeds in the dead of night.</p>
<p>Patrons have a similar feeling toward books as librarians and library workers. If they see you removing books from the collection, even from bulging shelves that can no longer handle the weight, and they know that the books are being removed permanently from the library, there will be protest and interference.</p>
<p>Assuming you make it from the the stacks to the staff area of the library, you have another obstacle: the people you work with. They will gather around like judgemental wolves, prepared to tear your flesh off while criticizing you for removing their childhood favorite, or an award winner, no matter how battered, no matter how long-forgotten. The librarian’s preservation instinct often leans more toward pieces of paper than toward oneself. They WILL run into a burning building to bring out that signed copy of Island of the Blue Dolphin. They just will.</p>
<p>So, what makes me different than patrons, or other librarians? Why can I go through the stacks and pull three hundred books in a day to render null and void without batting an eye? Am I a sick monster?</p>
<p>Yes. Probably.</p>
<p>Librarians are book hoarders by nature. I am not. I have moved a lot, and have come to appreciate the weight of all of those books. And the odds of me actually reading them again. So I got rid of many books over the years. Some donated to libraries I worked at, good books sent off to friends and family to experience the same happiness I did. Some sent to thrift shops when I knew my own taste would be of little use to anyone. My personal ‘home library’ consists of a few short bookshelves overstacked with reference material for writing, graphic novels I can’t part with, and novels by writers over which I obsess, or about subjects over which I obsess. Things that are hard to find in libraries because I haven’t bought them for the library yet like my large and uncataloged of Doctor Who novels.</p>
<p>I keep telling myself… I’m a librarian. I WORK in a library. I spend more time with my work library than my home library. And what we don’t own, I can either order, or borrow from another library. Cos every book you buy is another book you have to move.</p>
<p>I’ve always been less precious about weeding than other librarians at work, but it took me a while to build that into my personal life. Now it’s a general way of living. I don’t care how well-bound the book is, if it is on out of date material, or hasn’t circulated in many years, it has to go. I don’t care how popular an author is, if it is a book from early in their 30-year writing career, where they’ve turned out many similar stories, and the book is damaged, I am going to make it go away and never come back. That’s right. I’m not reordering it. Do we have books that have similar information? I keep the newer one. Do we have multiple copies? I keep the prettier one. If you have coffee stains, torn pages or water-wobbled covers, you are all on the chopping block. I am sorry, you have to go. We don’t need the 1996 Kansas Driving Test booklet. We just don’t. We’re not a research library. We’re not a preservation library. Our patrons mostly check out best sellers and DVDs.</p>
<p>There is a purpose for holding on to every telephone book for every single year  from Rochester, New York, if you’re a library that specializes in those sorts of things. And if I need it for historical purposes or research, I know which library to hit. But at this point, the chemistry book circa 1970 needs to go, along with any books discussing cold fusion that were published prior to my birth. I would toss my own mother in the pile for the book sale. I’m brutal.</p>
<p>But it’s like caring for a forest. Things may need to be destroyed completely by fire so that new life will grow, or stripped away with big clippers. But then light gets in; books that had been lost in a sea of other books are suddenly discovered again. New books have room to breathe on the shelves. And people find something old or interesting or helpful, waiting just for them on a tidy shelf tucked away in the 800s.</p>
<p>You do all of that big work of removing so much so that people can find MORE. More isn’t always better. Think of the needle in the haystack. Who cares how good the needle is, if you can’t find it for all of the hay? Burn the hay, walk off with the needle.</p>
<p>And be sure to do it in the dead of night, with the lights off. Weeding while wearing night-vision goggles IS an option. I’m sure you can work it into the budget somewhere. Skulk around in silence, maybe wear a cape. You’ll figure out what to do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Long Game</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-long-game/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tammy Garrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 16:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geek Girls in the Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This year at our state library conference, my presentation on girls and comics in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This year at our state library conference, my presentation on girls and comics in the library was standing room only. It was interesting and surprising to see that many people in a ballroom to listen to anyone at all talk about girls and comics. But more importantly they were there to listen to me. Which meant I would not be alone in an empty room for an hour, which is always one of my great fears both at science fiction conventions and actual grown-up conferences.</p>
<p>They cared. Librarians from rural and urban libraries throughout a Midwestern state actually cared about the challenges girls face entering fandoms, and were not opposed to the feminist ideas that I brought up slowly throughout the hour. I covered topics from dudebros to cosplay not equaling harassment. I even talked about the difference between the heroic pose and the sexy pose on comic covers.</p>
<p>I got questions, both during the session and in the hall after. I actually missed the next panel I had intended to go to, since I was talking to folks about everything from purchasing orders to podcasts.</p>
<p>Sure, for an hour and a half I was a bit of a rock star. A god among librarians. And for the rest of the day, people would stop me in the halls to tell me they enjoyed my talk. I felt like I should be signing things. This is very good for the battered self esteem. And I am glad this went well. I&#8217;m glad my message was accepted and even embraced.</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t about bragging. This is about excitement over the opportunity for next year.</p>
<p>This year my talk was primarily about girls. I did slip into discussing characters, comics and services for LGBTA teens briefly. And it was unlike four or five years ago, when I gave a presentation about millennialist, said something uncomfortable, and had at least three middle aged librarians immediately walk out. Maybe we are making progress and I can move on to the next stage of advocating for under-represented young people: LGBTA youth.</p>
<p>LGBTA youth are under-represented in the library, yes. They need books and materials that speak to their unique challenges and needs. They need librarians who will provide, without judgement or hostility, the materials they want or need. But this is a microcosm of the world outside the library doors. LGBTA youth face not being accepted by peers, social structures, and parents. Most homeless youth are LGBTA. They often live in areas that provide little to no sex education, and sex ed directed solely toward straight, cis youth.</p>
<p>If a queer student can&#8217;t get solid information or emotional support from the community or from family, the very least we can do for this group is provide quality materials in a calm, safe environment.</p>
<p>I would like to see librarians go further and be able to reference community resources, or be able to provide a safe, friendly ear, even if we don&#8217;t have answers for their complex issues. Librarians have become strong allies for many under-represented groups over the years. I don&#8217;t think asking them to be good allies for LGBTA youth is out of the realm of possibility. Or, if they can&#8217;t handle that, at least provide quality materials and services without judgement or reproach.</p>
<p>As for my part, I think it has been a slow introduction to the challenges modern young adults face, over several years of mailing list participation and state library conference presentations I can work up to more difficult and less pleasant issues.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a long game, but if it helps even a few kids, it is far worth the process.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Preaching to the Choir (or not)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/preaching-to-the-choir-or-not/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/preaching-to-the-choir-or-not/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tammy Garrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 15:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geek Girls in the Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the end of next month, I am going to be standing in front of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the end of next month, I am going to be standing in front of a ballroom full of librarians at our state library conference. I am going to spend fifty minutes waxing on about comics, girls in libraries, STEM fields, and whatever else makes its way into my PowerPoint presentation. Fortunately, I like to hear the sound of my own voice.</p>
<p>The good news: most of the librarians in my conservative state are sold on the idea of having graphic novels in the library. It’s taken about ten years,  but they show up at panels and discussions involving graphic novels, manga, anime, teen programming and outreach. Finally, the converted.</p>
<p>So why bother with yet another presentation about comics in the library? Am I preaching to the choir?</p>
<p>I proposed this session because I think there’s still more to confront on this topic. And obviously some planner from the state conference agreed, because they approved my presentation and gave me a prime slot for my vociferations. So for fifty minutes, I will be beating a dead horse.</p>
<p>Maybe.</p>
<p>The funny thing about librarians is that most are women. It’s a whole different world than most workplaces. Historically, it had been a man’s job, like teaching and nursing, until communities discovered that they could pay women less for the same quality of work. It remains women’s work to this day.</p>
<p>It may sound like I am digressing, but I am not. Libraries are primarily the domain of women. Tech and STEM fields are dominated by men, so are other high visibility fields like law, politics and the entertainment industry. I think, when you come into work every single day and see nothing but female faces, you forget that feminism has not solved all of our equality problems just yet.</p>
<p>This isn’t an article about comics in the library, really. It’s about what those comics represent: a whole world outside the library that is hostile toward women in every aspect of life, from enjoyment of something as simple as a comic book to not being run out of an engineering program by self-entitled men.</p>
<p>Comics, and most genre media have been seen as a hobby for boys and men, even though girls have been reading comics and enjoying comic-related media since its’ inception. A quick google search can turn up pictures of girls reading comics as far back as the 1940s. We’ve always been there. We’ve not been taken seriously, but we’ve always been there. Girls and women read comics and enjoy other media, such as cartoons, movies and video games featuring the characters they have come to love.</p>
<p>The catch that seems to hang up a lot of men: women tend to encounter comics, science fiction and genre films in a way far different to men. This is not a hard and fast rule. Just a general guideline. Women gravitate toward relationships, subtext (even if it is humorous, made-up subtext) and the generation of new material based on the thing they love (fanfic, cosplay, fan art, etc). They also form strong bonds and friendships through this. Not that guys don’t, women just do it in a different sort of way, usually through the Mutual Admiration Society.<strong><strong><br />
</strong></strong></p>
<p>To some men, this is a threatening prospect of women invading their space, and that women are expressing themselves differently than men. Things that women do are often considered to be lesser than the pursuits of men, simply because they are seen as women’s work. Otherwise, we would not live in a world where there is literature, which sounds pretty all-inclusive, and ‘women’s literature,’ or writers, and ‘female writers.’ There are so many other examples and avenues that place women as the ‘other’ in this world. Whole books have been written on the subject, most with far more grace and luster than I can manage. But I will say this: the societal attitude that anything women do is of a lesser variety, or meant only for other women is deeply embedded in both mainstream and in nerd culture.</p>
<p>Some men see themselves as the gatekeepers of fandom. They have decided what is and is not the correct way to express one’s joy over a piece of media. And obviously their way is the better way because it is the male way, which is obviously the default. The way of the universe.</p>
<p>The problem? Not only do micro-aggressions drive women away from fandom, and away from friendships, self-expression and media they clearly love, certain portions of fandom have gone so far as to declare some girls and women “fake geek girls.” They claim the girls are only into video games, or science fiction shows, or comics, to impress guys. Some openly mock the products that girls and women make, showing their creativity and their love for a character or show. They editorialize (or are downright mean) about cosplay construction skills (or body-type), art/writing ability, giggling girlish enthusiasm. Anything female-involved is a target.</p>
<p>It’s dangerous being a girl and stepping out into the world. In any way, shape or form. Women encounter outright mocking to threats via the Internet (including incidence of female nerds speaking out about an issue and receiving death and rape threats). This is aside from all the other mixed signals society sends to girls and women. Do you want to be the only girl in your upper-level math class, or engineering program? Isn’t that a terrifying prospect?</p>
<p>If we push girls out of boy spaces when they are young, and don’t allow girls to stand up for themselves by saying hey, I don’t cosplay or dress for you, and I don’t read comics or play games for you, I do it for me, none of these girls will have the confidence to take the first steps into male-dominated fields. Nor will boys and men learn that women are allowed to be there. They are not there to be the object of anger or sexual aggression or the butt of jokes. They are there because they deserve to be there, and those men should shut up and work with their colleagues like professionals.</p>
<p>It starts with Barbie, maybe. But I think hobby interests are really the thing that either lets girls step up with confidence and say “yes, this is the thing I like to do, my hobby, interest and obsession, and I am going to do it any way I want without fear or intimidation,” or drive girls back into the corners of the Internet, creating their own safe spaces that men never see. Which perpetuates the idea that girls do not exist in fandom.</p>
<p>We’re making strides. Women write and draw comics, and blog about them. Conventions are seeing gender parity. And yet, when a group of girls dressed as Amy Pond passed by at a Doctor Who convention, middle-aged men were chuckling about the “Gaggle of Ponds.”  They commented on how “everyone” wanted to dress like Amy and how several of them were “too obese” and had the “wrong body type.” News to those men: NO ONE has Amy Pond’s body type. Karen Gillan is approximately 98% legs. Does it hurt those men in any way that a chunky girl is dressed as a character she loves? No. But they feel entitled to editorialize.</p>
<p>And that, is what we need to fight against. To the point of being annoyingly outspoken, especially in in front of our girls, so they can see someone fighting for them. So they know that the women around them are unafraid of body criticism, hobby criticism and all the other types of harassment women face daily. So they know they can be that person too. Be their own super hero, as it were. They can push back against the good ol’ boys’ club and be brave enough to step through the closed club doors. We have to fight for our girls. And for ourselves.</p>
<p>&#8211;Your Friendly Neighborhood Librarian</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/preaching-to-the-choir-or-not/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Personal Encounter With Batman -or- The Long Roundabout Story of How Comics are Important for Everyone.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-personal-encounter-with-batman-or-the-long-roundabout-story-of-how-comics-are-important-for-everyone/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tammy Garrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 16:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geek Girls in the Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2714</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Once upon a time, Batman saved my life. It wasn’t one of those dark alley&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Once upon a time, Batman saved my life.</p>
<p>It wasn’t one of those dark alley things. He didn’t swoop down from a rooftop and save me from the Joker or a crazed bad guy with a knife. But, Batman saved me. Robin was there, too. I might not be writing this today without the Caped Crusader and Robin, the Boy Hostage. Simple fact of life.</p>
<p>Now, some of these things I have already mentioned in my essay published in <em>Chicks Dig Time Lords</em> (Ed. Lynne M. Thomas and Sigrid Ellis), but this is different. This is the dirty version of the tale.</p>
<p>I have a laundry list of issues. It’s nearly impossible to name them off without sounding like a hypochondriac or an old woman. A severe panic disorder, deep depression, a sensory processing disorder, autism, and asthma so bad I spent three weeks in the hospital when I was fourteen after it was complicated by a severe allergy attack, and it took me nearly a year to recover from. And once I destroyed every tendon in my leg playing tennis in gym class. Yup. Gym class. It wasn’t even real tennis.</p>
<p>That’s one part of the equation. School was difficult, nigh impossible with a sensory processing disorder, and the ability to pick up subtext around my peers. I had numerous problems at home, probably for the same reasons. I was sick, a bit of a weakling, and my depression raged out of control. And high school being as it was, I was severely lacking in the friend department. I spent most of my time wanting to cease existing.</p>
<p>This is the era of Kurt Cobain’s suicide, the jaded Gen X-ers, and when hating things was both a sport and an artform. A perfect storm to feed my suicidal thoughts and tendencies, in a world where no one noticed me, and it seemed like no one cared. I had trouble in class, and I felt like my pain was absolutely visible on me, and no one reached out to help.</p>
<p>My freshman year of high school started out hopeful for a fresh start, but by my sophomore year I was teetering on the edge of self-destruction.</p>
<p>Right around then, DC Comics started a storyline called Knightfall. The short of it: the deconstruction of Batman by putting him through endless trials with no rest or relief.</p>
<p>That was something I could identify with. Heavily.</p>
<p>A villain had come from practically nowhere, and had brought Batman’s world into chaos. He’d busted all the inmates out of Arkham Asylum, leaving Batman to put the rogues gallary back behind bars, all the while dodging all the obstacles that the major villain had put in place for Batman. It was difficult, it was painful, it was exhausting, and it never ended.</p>
<p>This wasn’t just an allegory for my teenage life. I was living it. The world was too bright and loud, constantly crushing my senses. My sleep problems were perpetual and it was a struggle to put one foot in front of the other every day. But Batman did it, day and night, getting psychopaths off the streets to keep them from harming people en masse. This is the first lesson taught to me by Knightfall: you can keep going, no matter how painful, if you must. Your will is stronger than the rest of you, and it can keep you carrying on well past the point when others would have quit.</p>
<p>It took me nearly twenty years of doing this to learn the flip side of this lesson: that while you can do this longer than you ever thought possible, human beings are not perpetual motion machines. We stop. We break; like the culmination of the Knightfall storyline, which saw Bane, the villain, breaking Batman’s back over his thunderous, muscled leg.</p>
<p>Sure, I had a nervous breakdown. But Batman kept me on my feet for nearly twenty years’ worth of misdiagnoses and mismanaged medications and therapies. It took me still another year to get through being broken, like Batman had gotten through. It wasn’t easy, sometimes it felt like I would never crawl out of that pit, but eventually I did. On the other side was actual real medical help for my actual real depression and debilitating anxiety.</p>
<p>I was finally, for the first time in my life, able to get up, and dust myself off, and move forward. Not with heavy shoes and feet that dragged across the floor with each infinitesimal step, but actually move forward. Actually walk. That’s not just metaphorical. I also got better asthma meds, and was able to finally walk a significant distance without having to use the nebulizer due to my airways constricting.</p>
<p>And after, like… twenty four or thirty-six issues of side-stories and actual stories, and a year of real time, Batman got up and carried on. He beat the crap out of the ally-gone-rogue who had taken his place as Batman, and he’d reinstated himself as the Dark Knight. Sure he had help from this doctor with, like, magical healing powers, but it’s comics and what do you expect? Still: Batman got back in the cowl in the end, and carried on with a new beginning.</p>
<p>Why am I bothering with this? A lot of reasons. I’ve said before that comics and superheroes are our modern mythology. The point of a mythology is that it resonates with us on some deep level. It makes sense to us, speaks to us, asks us to do better, and changes us. Sometimes it’s something hopeful to latch onto, or just a lifesaver to clutch onto when the stormy waves crash over us, and we’re all alone and lost at sea.</p>
<p>(A++, super metaphor, would use again)</p>
<p>What I’m saying is: I think we all need that. We all need to know we can persevere. That we can affect the world for the better. That the path to doing the right thing will not be easy, but it will be worth it. And, as in the case  of Peter Parker, sometimes we create our own problems.</p>
<p>This isn’t just a message for white dudebro boys from the suburbs (the 14-36 target audience of comics, tv and movies), that’s a message for everyone. Everyone deserves that message. The mixed race child in the inner city needs to know there’s a Miles Morales inside of him. The latino kid in the desert deserves to know there is a Blue Beetle waiting for them. That people with disabilities can still be heroes like Barbara Gordon and Hawkeye. That they won’t be left out of being a hero if they’re LGBT. Those are messages for everyone, regardless of your race or sex or background. And it isn’t just that everyone deserves those messages. And sometimes they need those messages: the typical comic fan needs to see that people that aren’t like them can be heroes, too.</p>
<p>&#8216;Til Next Time,</p>
<p>&#8211;Your Friendly Neighborhood Librarian</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Note on &#8220;literature&#8221; From Your Friendly Neighborhood Librarian</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-note-on-literature-from-your-friendly-neighborhood-librarian/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tammy Garrison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 15:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Geek Girls in the Library]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2329</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Excuse me, may I have a rant? Well, regardless of your answer, I am going&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Excuse me, may I have a rant? Well, regardless of your answer, I am going to take one, anyway.</p>
<p>Since roughly around, oh, Sophocles’ time, people have been complaining that “kids today,” don’t have an appreciation for the classics. That education is slacking off. That students are coming out of school with less knowledge, and are less literate and well-read than previous generations.</p>
<p>Before compulsory, tax-funded education, schooling was a privilege usually reserved for those of wealth, and of those children, mostly males went to school. Good old sexism and classism at work. Whole segments of the population were illiterate, or barely literate. But the students who went to school had hundreds of years of the written word at their disposal. Latin, Greek, Virgil, Ovid. Really, when’s the last time you read Ovid? He’s a poet. He wrote smutty stuff, if it encourages you at all to check out his work.</p>
<p>Students learned by rote, and while all had received the same education, not all carried it with them in the same way. In other words, not everyone was automatically scholarly, nor did they stay in the hallowed halls of academia once their education was complete.</p>
<p>And let’s face it, even in the 20th century, not everyone was cut out for the type of education being provided. Students dropped out early, or just decided they were “not for school learning.” We have a much higher retention rate now, despite the constant fretting over drop out rates. And illiteracy dropped from 20% in 1870 to less than a percent a century later. Obviously the educational system, for all of its flaws and troubles, is, to some degree, working.</p>
<p>So why aren’t we reading Ovid in the original Latin? Why do we offer an “easy language” version of Shakespeare’s plays to high school freshmen? Why is The Scarlet Letter as feared as Wuthering Heights? Why are the books on the reading lists such painful reading for our kids today?</p>
<p>First, I would like to point out that in days gone by, books were a precious commodity. Up until the 1800s, very few were in print. Choices were limited.  Books were read over and over, even after the advent of movable type, simply due to lack of reading material, and the cost of purchasing copies of books, which were printed and bound by hand until the 20th century.</p>
<p>Second, we produce more information and data each year than in the whole history of the world, combined, up to the advent of the computer. There are a lot of materials vying for teens’ attention. I also am attracted by shiny covers, characters who are like me, and that I can relate to, and situations I have been through.</p>
<p>Which leads me to my third point: “The Classics” as they’re taught in schools today are almost universally stories by privileged white European or American men, with the exception of people like the Bronte sisters and Mary Shelley. This singular view is hard enough for a teenager to swallow. But also consider: these books were written, originally, for educated adults, in an era where the reader spoke in a way similar to the author, and had cultural touchstones similar to that of the author.</p>
<p>Sure, that’s the point of education, teaching students about these books, but that’s why they slog through them with absolutely no joy. And I think we’re doing them a disservice by pretending that all of the world’s “great writers” were European, and probably male. Male is the status quo. Fiction written by men is “literature.” Fiction written by women is “women’s literature.” We don’t teach minority and female students that they can be great writers by exposing them to great books, nor do we teach white boys that people other than straight white boys can write great literature, which, in and of itself is a disservice.</p>
<p>The Lord of the Flies is held up as a piece of literature that reflects the destruction of a society without consequences. All of us are doomed to give in to the demons of our nature, and so away from civilization the last vestiges of humanity fall away and we become animals. Except, that’s only what happens when a bunch of privileged European white boys find themselves stranded on a deserted island. Our literature curriculum gives far too much power to to the white male experience as somehow being universal. Kids will disconnect when there is nothing in the book they are reading that sounds like them or looks like them. It becomes a story that happens to someone else, far away and long ago. Something unimportant.</p>
<p>We live in a fast-paced world thanks to the Internet, and language evolves quickly. Yesterday’s noun becomes today’s verb. Even our sentence structure is changing rapidly. It is slowly becoming acceptable to split infinitives, end sentences with prepositions, and even remove articles and adjectives from sentences and still be understood. “Because reasons” is my favorite example.</p>
<p>And this language is vivid, it is fast, and it communicates ideas, concepts and moods very quickly. “asdfasdf” conveys a sense of excitement so overwhelming that the author is incoherent with joy and can’t type anything thoughtful about the subject.</p>
<p>So kids stumble over language written hundreds of years before, especially the many layers out-of-use words and phrases in things like Chaucer and Shakespeare. Even Oscar Wilde and Hemingway are from another time and place that can be difficult for a modern student who speaks a variety of situational vernaculars to grasp.</p>
<p>And instead of blaming the curriculum or the passage of time, we blame the students. We blame the teachers for not beating a love of Hawthorne (who was super misogynistic) or Steinbeck (who basically stole Grapes of Wrath from the female reporter who called her stories in from the midwest, while he sat in his cushy office in New York) into our children.</p>
<p>There are over a million books printed each year. And for every reader there is a book. But maybe not this particular cart full of books. Some of the books, perhaps. But not all of them. And not the way we teach them now&#8211;as if students are just not trying hard enough to understand Elizabethan English. Maybe we need to remember just how fast the world moves. Maybe we need to remember that students ARE reading. Just not what you think they should be. Harry Potter still counts. That fan fiction they stayed up until three in the morning reading still counts.</p>
<p>Relate it to that. To the modern world our kids live in. Bring Shakespeare forward, before you take the kids back in time. They’re excellent at meta, just spend a few minutes on Tumblr and you will see that. Let them tear Macbeth to pieces and read it as the comedy it was obviously intended to be. Let them ship Horatio and Hamlet (Ophelia didn’t have to die, I say!) and let them bring something to the work, if you want them to take something away as well.</p>
<p>We’re living in the future. Our literature education should be worldly, and of the whole world. It should make our students experts in the classics while allowing them to show their own expertise. Because Richard III really does deserve a Coldplay fanvid.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
