<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Constructing Fantasy &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/constructing-fantasy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 02:25:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Worldbuilding Beyond SFF</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/worldbuilding-beyond-sff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ella Syverson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 10:34:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Constructing Fantasy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am standing in the water and it is cool and soft against my calves.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27292 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/qusai-akoud-4c-S3I1IUUw-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/qusai-akoud-4c-S3I1IUUw-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/qusai-akoud-4c-S3I1IUUw-unsplash-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/qusai-akoud-4c-S3I1IUUw-unsplash-768x509.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/qusai-akoud-4c-S3I1IUUw-unsplash-1536x1017.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/qusai-akoud-4c-S3I1IUUw-unsplash-2048x1356.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I am standing in the water and it is cool and soft against my calves. I breathe in: pine, sweetfern, earth, lily pads. I breathe out: shivering slightly in the cooling moonlit air. In that moonlight, reflected and distorted, I see the pines sway on the gently rippling surface of the lake. A mosquito buzzes in my ear. I swat it.</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I wonder absently if my nakedness is welcome here, but the moon is up now and the cars are gone. There isn’t camping here, so people rarely stay. If they’re camping, they go up the road another few miles to Birch Grove. Or 150 feet off any trail or road — this is Forest Service land. (Colonized land. Ojibwe land.) You can see the scars of it: trees planted in rows from logging. Sandy pine barren trails for ATVs. Picnic tables. White women standing in the water. Swatting mosquitoes. </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this flash of creative nonfiction, I am writing a portrait of a place. Setting the scene in space and time in the way it relates to characters and action. I am worldbuilding. Worldbuilding is often considered in the context of speculative and SFF work, but is just as vital to writing good literary fiction or creative nonfiction. All stories have a setting. But thoughtful construction of a setting brings it from being a drab backdrop to your plot and characters to an interactive and interesting force within the story. So what does worldbuilding mean in this context? And how can you develop it for your next writing project?</span></p>
<p><b>Do your homework</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When writing about a real place instead of an imagined one (or even an imagined place based in real life, such as the fictional town of Stars Hollow, Connecticut in </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gilmore_Girls"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gilmore Girls</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">) it is important to understand the things that make that place unique, the lived experiences of the people who’s place you’re writing about, and the way that place shapes those experiences and the experiences of your characters. This doesn’t necessarily have to take the form of research, it can also come from your own history and experiences of a place, or from hearing those experiences from other people. The closer you can come to personal connection with a place, the more genuineness and specificity you’ll be able to easily add.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, it’s good to understand the broader context of a place including history, demographics, politics, economics, ecology, geography, etc. Some of these may be directly relevant to your story, help you develop characters or backstories, or just make the world feel more expansive and connected. This is relevant no matter the scale of the world you’re building. Maybe you’re writing a political thriller, and you have a character who is a US Senator. You’ll need to have an understanding about the different states in America, and their general politics in order to develop the Senator’s character and find out which state they represent. Maybe you’re writing about playing in your backyard as a child. You’ll want to think back and remember what bugs might have been in the yard, how it changed throughout the seasons, what color the picket fence was, etc. </span></p>
<p><b>Place as Character</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To me, the best worldbuilding is when a place feels like a main character in your story. Think about the brooding, gothic nature of Thornfield Hall in</span> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jane_Eyre"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jane Eyre</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The house itself has personality and a key role in the plot of the book. It’s also an important tone setting element. </span><a href="https://nkjemisin.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">N.K. Jeminsin’s</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> novel (speculative, I know, bear with me) </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The City We Became</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> makes the concept literal. The story imagines the city of New York, a city with a well established cultural and literary character, as six humanoid avatars that represent. Bronca, a hot tempered lesbian Lenape woman in her 60s who runs an art gallery represents the Bronx and is the knowledge keeper of the city, while Manny, a young, queer Black man with no memory of his background represents Manhattan and is a ruthless defender of the City.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the place you’re writing about was embodied, who would they be? How is your setting shaping your story? What are your character’s relationships to the place, and do they change over time? Who are the people that make up this place, and what are their personalities like? What are the tone and themes of the place you’re writing about? Are themes in your story physically embodied in your place? What does your place have to say? How do they say it?</span></p>
<p><b>Detail, detail, detail!</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sensory detail is what makes a place feel real. Make sure not just to focus on imagery, but on the other senses as well: sound, smell, touch, even taste. A fun exercise in revision is to take a couple pages of writing and color code each of the sensory details, with a different color for each sense. This way you can get a better picture of what kind of detail you’re already adding, and what you might want to add more of. This makes writing feel fuller, as well as drawing in readers who might be more attuned to different senses.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another good exercise is just to practice writing descriptively about whatever place you’re in, setting an intention to include as many sensory details as possible. You can also try imagining places you’ve been before and know well. You may be surprised which details are the ones that stick with you in your memory, and this kind of recognition is a helpful reminder that the most obvious details are not always the most interesting, or even the most descriptive. For example, when I remember waiting for the bus as an elementary schooler, it isn’t the putrid yellow color that sticks with me, it’s the smell of diesel exhaust.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From scanning Google maps in your research to drawing your own maps of a fictional town in rural America, worldbuilding can be one of the most exciting parts of writing. So don’t let it fall to the wayside!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What your apocalypse fantasy says about you</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-your-apocalypse-fantasy-says-about-you/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ella Syverson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 11:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Constructing Fantasy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What do our apocalypse fantasies say about our dreams and ourselves? Similarly to horror, apocalyptic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26905 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/daniel-lincoln-Mn3lkbSQRLY-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/daniel-lincoln-Mn3lkbSQRLY-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/daniel-lincoln-Mn3lkbSQRLY-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/daniel-lincoln-Mn3lkbSQRLY-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/daniel-lincoln-Mn3lkbSQRLY-unsplash-1229x1536.jpg 1229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/daniel-lincoln-Mn3lkbSQRLY-unsplash-1638x2048.jpg 1638w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/daniel-lincoln-Mn3lkbSQRLY-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />What do our apocalypse fantasies say about our dreams and ourselves? Similarly to horror, apocalyptic fiction is a genre that investigates fear by taking our fears to the farthest possible extent: in horror, death, violence, and terror; in apocalyptic fiction, the end of the world. Post-apocalyptic fiction is entirely rooted in world building (and world destroying, I guess). It gives us a blank slate to make a new world in which to play out our fears and fantasies together. Our visions of the apocalypse are based in our understanding of the biggest vulnerabilities and challenges facing the security of our societies and communities. Our fantasies represent how we idealize our own individual role within those scenarios. How does the apocalypse scenario you’re drawn to reflect on your identity? Let’s see if I can guess.</p>
<p><strong>Pandemic</strong></p>
<p>There’s two options here. Did you start obsessively reading plague novels during COVID, or did you start before it was cool? If you find yourself in the first category, you need reassurance that we made it through the Spanish Flu. You’re a systems thinker with a closet stocked with way too much toilet paper, and when you get wine-drunk you talk about your crush on Dr. Fauci. You’re the mom friend and an expert on everything because you read a Twitter thread on it. If you’re in the second category, congratulations. You’ve waited years for plague doctor masks to be back in style, and you already knew supply chain shortages would be a thing. You’re terrified by body horror and like to feel like you can think your way out of any situation. You imagine yourself stocking up on rice and beans and fleeing to the countryside. When it comes down to it, you like the idea of having a bit fewer people on the planet, and you wouldn’t mind the time alone.</p>
<p><strong>Zombie Apocalypse</strong></p>
<p>You want to be the main character in your own action film. You crave the disruption to everyday life, and would rather focus on survival than paying rent. You wear cargo pants and drink your <img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-26991 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/nathan-wright-igpwuxZofgo-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/nathan-wright-igpwuxZofgo-unsplash-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/nathan-wright-igpwuxZofgo-unsplash-680x1024.jpg 680w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/nathan-wright-igpwuxZofgo-unsplash-768x1157.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/nathan-wright-igpwuxZofgo-unsplash-1020x1536.jpg 1020w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/nathan-wright-igpwuxZofgo-unsplash-1360x2048.jpg 1360w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/nathan-wright-igpwuxZofgo-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1700w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" />coffee black. You are fundamentally distrustful of other people, especially those different from you. In your apocalypse fantasy, there’s definitely an attractive woman, and maybe a sex scene. You’re an adrenaline junkie. You’re fiercely protective of the people you love, but you know you’d have the guts to kill them if they got bitten. You know that sometimes, violence is the answer.</p>
<p><strong>Environmental Disaster</strong></p>
<p>You are depressed.</p>
<p><strong>Nuclear Holocaust</strong></p>
<p>You have a pin that says “Question Authority,” but you equally question humanity. You grew up hiding under your school desk, and knew even then that it wouldn’t save you. You work out and yeah, you know how to throw a punch when it comes down to it. You’ve *thought* about your bunker, and are definitely planning on getting around to making it someday. You have a beard and a gun. You don’t go hunting, but you’ve got some property in Minnesota. You’re an independent, and you don’t vote. You think you’re a realist, but you are actually a pessimist. Other people don’t get it. You know you have what it takes.</p>
<p><strong>Alien Invasion</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26992 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dino-reichmuth-t9OGCATN-vg-unsplash-300x209.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="209" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dino-reichmuth-t9OGCATN-vg-unsplash-300x209.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dino-reichmuth-t9OGCATN-vg-unsplash-1024x714.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dino-reichmuth-t9OGCATN-vg-unsplash-768x535.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dino-reichmuth-t9OGCATN-vg-unsplash-1536x1070.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dino-reichmuth-t9OGCATN-vg-unsplash-2048x1427.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />You hang out around the local coffee shop and are generally regarded as a “chill person.” You’re always down to talk about aliens. Or psychedelics. The government lies to us, you just have to open your mind. You knew a guy once, who saw something. You have stories. You’re a little quiet, but your eyes are deep and wild. At least that’s what your girlfriend told you. You’re not a big fan of people, they’re too wrapped up in mundanity and conformity. You believe in a better world order. When the aliens come you’ll be terrified, of course, but a part of you will feel as if your life is complete.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fanfiction as Reconstructive Worldbuilding</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fanfiction-as-reconstructive-worldbuilding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ella Syverson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 11:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Constructing Fantasy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Fanfiction has long been a realm in which readers can take control of source material,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26732 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photo-1521175776577-f8e0c1e5ecb7-300x180.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="180" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photo-1521175776577-f8e0c1e5ecb7-300x180.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photo-1521175776577-f8e0c1e5ecb7-1024x613.jpeg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photo-1521175776577-f8e0c1e5ecb7-768x460.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photo-1521175776577-f8e0c1e5ecb7.jpeg 1270w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Fanfiction has long been a realm in which readers can take control of source material, add to it, and rework it with their own imaginings. It is often focused on characters and their relationships, primarily romantic and/or sexual (often queer), and therefore contains much critical reading of characters as written as well as radical rewritings of those characters. However, it is also valuable to examine the potential of fanfiction to give insight into the worldbuilding of its source material, especially when that source material is science fiction, fantasy, or speculative fiction that is set in a constructed world. Whether intentionally or not, fanfics often expand and critique the worlds they’re writing about in a variety of ways.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the most common ways that fanfiction does this is by exploring areas of the worlds they inhabit that aren’t visible or are not fully fleshed out in their source material. For example, a</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Lord of the Rings</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> fic might describe life in the Hobbits’ home, the Shire, with more mundane detail than was possible in the books. We could meet new characters and places, learn about customs and experiences, and visualize social interactions and structures that give a deeper perspective into this part of the fantasy world. Fanfiction provides a place to answer questions that would never be answered in their source material. What educational systems exist for children on the planet Coruscant in the Star Wars universe? What does a typical day of living in District 8 of the Hunger Games world look like? In canon-compliant fics in particular, this is the kind of worldbuilding that is most present.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some fics, known as Alternate Universe (AU) fics, reshape or completely diverge from the worlds of their source material. The point of these fics is often to explore how the original characters would react if they were placed into an entirely new environment, and thus an entirely new scope of worldbuilding akin to any other piece of fiction writing is required. Oftentimes this takes the form of placing the characters into a “real world” setting. The most well known example of this is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fifty Shades of Grey</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which</span><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/fifty-shades-of-grey-started-out-as-twilight-fan-fiction-2015-2?op=1"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> infamously began as a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Twilight</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> fanfic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on fanfiction.net. This trope highlights the ways in which worldbuilding shapes the plot and characters of a story, often allowing for new ideas and scenarios that add new perspective to the source material’s existing world and characters.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Books are imperfect; movies, TV shows, bands, celebrities, and other content we consume is imperfect. Oftentimes important perspectives and concepts are missing or erased from the source materials we love. Not only does this cause harm in that it can perpetuate stereotypes and/or erasure of marginalized communities as well as promoting messages and ideologies that have a real life negative impact, erasing critical perspectives or concepts from a world leaves the world that much less full and real feeling. For example, in the Harry Potter books there are no canonically (using this word to refer only to original source material, not retroactive information sharing by the author) queer characters, and few characters of color and/or differing religious background. Fanfiction provides an arena in which to explore these concepts and integrate them into a constructed world, expanding and deepening its boundaries and possibilities. The most widely popularized Potterfic, </span><a href="https://slate.com/culture/2021/11/all-the-young-dudes-harry-potter-fanfic-wolfstar-tiktok.html"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">All the Young Dudes</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, is an excellent example of this</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fanfic writers are frequently dismissed as writers and as worldbuilders because they are assumed to be solely co-opting existing stories, characters, and worlds without the same level of creativity as other writers. The wealth of creative imaginings and reimaginings, of world building and rebuilding, that exists within fanfiction disproves this misconception. Fanfiction is critical, creative, cooperative, queer, and reconstructive of the worlds we love exploring.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Building a Magic System</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/building-a-magic-system/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ella Syverson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 13:43:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Constructing Fantasy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26311</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What is magic, and how does it work? Is magic something done by wizards with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26312 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/dollar-gill-0V7_N62zZcU-unsplash-300x168.jpg" alt="Open book, blue crystal ball, fairy lights." width="348" height="195" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/dollar-gill-0V7_N62zZcU-unsplash-300x168.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/dollar-gill-0V7_N62zZcU-unsplash-1024x575.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/dollar-gill-0V7_N62zZcU-unsplash-768x431.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/dollar-gill-0V7_N62zZcU-unsplash-1536x862.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/dollar-gill-0V7_N62zZcU-unsplash-2048x1150.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 348px) 100vw, 348px" />What is magic, and how does it work? Is magic something done by wizards with wands and pointed hats, or is it the mystical force you encounter in the fae realm? Magic systems are an essential element of most fantasy worlds, but they can look very different in different stories. Let’s explore a few questions you’ll want to consider when building the magic system for your next fantasy world.</p>
<p><strong>What role does magic play in your story?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before deciding anything about the magic system of your world, it’s important to think about why it’s there in the first place. What is magic adding to your world, and what role does it play in your story? Is it there to make a world feel more whimsical, more alien, or more fantastical? Is it there to create and/or resolve conflict? Is it a metaphor for other forms of power? Is magic a central element of your story, or is it just there for flavor? Determining this from the start can help you answer the next questions about what form your magic system will take.</span></p>
<p><strong>Hard vs. soft magic</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In </span><a href="https://www.brandonsanderson.com/sandersons-first-law/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">this article</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Brandon Sanderson describes two ends of a spectrum for magic systems: hard and soft magic. Hard magic systems have consistent and well defined rules and limitations of operation that are clearly described to readers. Soft magic systems are intentionally obscured from readers and rely on wonder more than rules. For example, magic in Tolkein’s world is soft: it is powerful and present, but we don’t get the full picture of what it can and cannot do. This makes the world feel expansive and wonderful. On the other hand, magic in the Marvel Cinematic Universe is hard: each superhero has well defined powers and the rules of these powers and the universe are consistent (or at least are intended to be). This brings viewers in on the magic, and allows characters to use magic to solve problems in a way that is engaging. Sanderson’s first rule of magics is “An author’s ability to solve conflict with magic is directly proportional to how well the reader understands said magic.&#8221; So depending on how you want to use magic in your story, you may want to make it hard, soft, or more likely some combination of the two.</span></p>
<p><strong>Who does magic?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who has the ability to perform magic in your world? Is it just humans, or can other species (elves, dragons, etc.) also use magic? If so, do they use the same magic system, or a different one? Among humans, can everyone use magic, or just those born with it? How do people learn to do magic? How does magic using interact with other identities, such as race and class?</span></p>
<p><strong>How do you use magic?</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What does one have to do to perform magic? Do you need a wand, speak a spell, or concentrate your energy? Are there magical artifacts, potions, or plants? How does one person’s magic interact with another’s? How does magic interact with the physical world, and with other living beings? What does magic look like? Sound like? Smell like? </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Feel</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> like?</span></p>
<p><strong>Origin of magic</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is magic made of? It could be like the Force, in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Wars</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a power that is everywhere, waiting to be tapped into. It could also be intrinsic to people, a part of being a witch, wizard, etc. Where does magic come from? Is it a finite resource? It could be granted by the gods, written into DNA, or simply a part of the world, like gravity. </span></p>
<p><strong>Limitations and dangers</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How far can you go with magic? There has to be some limitations or risks to prevent magic users from becoming all powerful, and to maintain some challenge for magic using protagonists. Maybe magic users run out of strength or energy to perform spells (think “<a href="https://www.dndbeyond.com/sources/basic-rules/spellcasting">spell slots</a>” in Dungeons &amp; Dragons), or maybe there are risks involved in using magic that is too powerful (like when Ged summons a shadow creature in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Wizard of Earthsea</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">). Maybe using too much magic corrupts the user (like Willow in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buffy the Vampire Slayer</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">), or maybe there are things magic just can’t do (for example, how <a href="https://harrypotter.fandom.com/wiki/Gamp%27s_Law_of_Elemental_Transfiguration">Gamp’s Law of Elemental Transfiguration</a> dictates magic can’t be used to create food out of thin air in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Harry Potter.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">)</span></p>
<p><strong>Magic in society</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How is magic integrated into the societies of your world? It might be a largely accepted and normalized part of life, it might be stigmatized, it might be controlled by an elite class, it might be secret and exist only in underground communities. It might also be different in different regions. The way magic is integrated or separated from society can be a source of conflict, an aesthetic choice, a plot element, theme, or metaphor, and certainly a compelling component of worldbuilding.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Romanticization as Worldbuilding</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/romanticization-as-worldbuilding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ella Syverson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 13:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Constructing Fantasy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Picture this: soft piano music plays. Sunbeams peek through window curtains. A manicured hand pours&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26050 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/camille-brodard-rT7J3nQ64b4-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/camille-brodard-rT7J3nQ64b4-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/camille-brodard-rT7J3nQ64b4-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/camille-brodard-rT7J3nQ64b4-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/camille-brodard-rT7J3nQ64b4-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/camille-brodard-rT7J3nQ64b4-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Picture this: soft piano music plays. Sunbeams peek through window curtains. A manicured hand pours water through a coffee filter into a ceramic mug. They smile at you in their floor-length mirror as they show off their autumnally colored outfit with matching tote. The camera pans around the room to show off their potted plant or book collection. As they step outside, you can almost smell the rain-kissed orange leaves as they’re shuffled through by feet in leather boots and wool socks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All this in 15 seconds, before scrolling to another video. Like many other young people, I’ve spent a lot of time on TikTok, especially during the pandemic. I’m captivated by </span><a href="https://electricliterature.com/main-character-tiktok-autofiction/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">this genre of video</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in that it reflects a practice that I’ve seen permeate from social media into our perceptions of our own inner and outer worlds: romanticization (think </span><a href="https://carolinianuncg.com/2021/03/30/dark-academia-students-romanticize-college-life-again/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">cottagecore or dark academia</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). To romanticize the mundane is to recognize its inherent beauty, and to actively seek and imagine it. In the context of social media especially, this can be dangerous in that it obscures reality, creates unrealistic beauty standards for life, and can even romanticize aspects of our lives that are harmful (e.g. </span><a href="https://www.nysmho.org/archives/the-romanticization-of-mental-illness"><span style="font-weight: 400;">mental illness</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). But in obscuring reality, romanticization also brings us closer to a world of fantasy. Is it possible to use the instinct to romanticize our own lives to create fantasy worlds instead?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve found that when I’m consuming content that is actively romanticizing mundane aspects of life (like drinking coffee and walking through dead leaves) I am more conscious of the details of these occurrences as I’m experiencing them. I’m present and more perceptive of beauty. I feel the way the sun hits my face and smell the hint of rain in the air. I stop to look at a view of the mountains glimpsed through the trees and notice a pair of friends laughing as they walk through campus to class. I catalogue sights and senses in a way I might not otherwise. These are the same types of sights and senses that bring worldbuilding to life. Instead of coffee and college campus, think instead about the worn oak wood of the bar at the medieval tavern, the crackling heat of the hearth, the taste of dry bread and salty soup. These are the similarly portrayed details of a high fantasy world, whose aesthetic stems from an excessively romanticized vision of life in the real world—in medieval Europe. What we look for in fantasy is rarely realistic depiction, but fantastic worlds made visceral through romanticized depiction.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Romanticizing the mundane in everyday life helps to identify the most compelling minutiae of place that bring a world vivacity and fantasy. When we imagine a fantasy version of our own lives in which the autumn colors and scent of rain are at the forefront, we can interrogate what makes those sensations pop. We can recognize throughlines between what makes romanticized TikToks and romanticized fantasy worlds good. Perhaps it’s nature, food, weather, clothing, mood, smells, music, colors, etc., all working in concert to create a cohesive aesthetic. What is the aesthetic of your fantasy world? What are the images and sensory details you recognize as being notable and romantic in your life or in the media you consume? Are similar images and sensory details present in your writing? Are these images and details consistent with the aesthetics of your world? For example: consider this passage from Catherynne M. Valente’s </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9591398-the-girl-who-circumnavigated-fairyland-in-a-ship-of-her-own-making"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Girl Who Circumnavigated Fairyland in a Ship of her Own Making</span></i></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">in which our protagonist, September, and her wyvern companion, A-Through-L, are waking up to embark on their journey.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">September bit into a fat, juicy persimmon. Well, something like a persimmon. Rather larger, greener, and tasting of blueberry cream, but it looked terribly </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">like </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">a persimmon, and so September had resolved to call it that. A-Through-L still worried a poor tree, which was so tall and stubbornly thick that no small girl could ever have hoped to climb it, even if she had known that there was a fruit up there in its yellowy-silver branches… September insisted she was full between peals of laughter, but the Wyverary seemed to delight in charging the tree with a cheerful snarl and smacking into it full force until the helpless fruit gave up and came tumbling down. After each blow, A-Through-L sat back on his enormous hanches and shook his head, sending his whiskers a-flying. The sight of it kept September laughing, helplessly, her skirt tumbling-full of oozing, green-orange, blueberryish persimmons. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sun hitched up her trousers and soldiered up into the sky. September squinted at it and wondered if the sun here was different than the sun in Nebraska. It seemed gentler, more golden, deeper. The shadows it cast seemed more profound. But September could not be sure. When one is traveling, everything looks brighter and lovelier.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this passage we see the descriptions of fruit and nature, including details like laughter, clothing, taste, and body language and actions. These images work together to contribute to a bright, quirky, whimsical aesthetic which romanticizes travel, adventure, and the “other world.” When romanticizing elements of real life, we can use those same tactics to romanticize elements of fictional lives and create enticing fictional worlds. While romanticization in the real world is often negative, it is a core element of fantasy and can be incorporated into writing as such. Next time you see a sunrise, think of September and ask yourself if it looks gentler, more golden, deeper. Next time you write a sunrise, remember that feeling.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
