<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>What&#8217;s in a Fairy Tale? &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/whats-in-a-fairy-tale/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 19:30:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Review of Disfigured: On Fairy Tales, Disability, and Making Space</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-of-disfigured-on-fairy-tales-disability-and-making-space/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathrin Hagey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 11:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[What's in a Fairy Tale?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amanda Leduc’s Disfigured: On Fairy Tales, Disability, and Making Space is an outstanding addition to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-19504" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Disfigured_Cover-190x300.jpg" alt="fairy tales and disability" width="190" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Disfigured_Cover-190x300.jpg 190w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Disfigured_Cover-649x1024.jpg 649w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Disfigured_Cover-768x1213.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Disfigured_Cover.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 190px) 100vw, 190px" />Amanda Leduc’s <em><a class="ek-link" href="https://chbooks.com/Books/D/Disfigured" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">Disfigured: On Fairy Tales, Disability, and Making Space</a> </em>is an outstanding addition to the already wonderful collection of books about fairy tales and related topics. I was shaken and lifted up by what she has achieved with integrating disability justice with memoir, fairy tale studies, pop culture, and other fantastical and historical elements.</p>

<p><a class="ek-link" href="https://amandaleduc.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Leduc (opens in a new tab)">Leduc</a>, a disabled Canadian novelist and essayist, prefers identity-first language. In describing her own love of fairy tales and the negative impact of realizing, at a very young age, that fairy tale princesses don’t walk with a limp, she is candid, funny, brilliant.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">But it is never society that changes, no matter how many half-animals or scullery maids are out there arguing for their place at the table. It is almost always the protagonists themselves who transform society in some way&#8211;becoming more palatable, more beautiful, more easily able to fit into the mould of society already in place. The intervention is magical rather than surgical, but one can imagine the writers of these tales arguing in favour of the medical model [of disability]: the <em>life-saving</em> surgery, where <em>life</em> is synonymous with social standing and regard. The child who has surgery to repair their club foot is the same child who, in a fairy tale, would likely be visited by a fairy godmother or an evil witch, the gift of able-bodiedness dangled in front of them in a way that’s entirely irresistible.</blockquote>

<p>We’ve come to associate the term <em>Fairy Tale</em> with a story that ends happily, for those who are deserving. Not just any story will do, as is the tradition. We have well-groomed expectations, going back hundreds, if not thousands, of years, about a fairy tale’s archetypal components: magic, wise women, villains, animal helpers, beautiful heroines, etc.</p>
<p>Disney has attempted to rectify the classic narrative arc of fairy tales in which an attractive, healthy, white hero or heroine achieves their happily ever after. But we need more than bandages and skin grafts to repair the damage done by excluding most of humanity. Nothing less than an entirely new body of literature will suffice.</p>
<p>Disability is a way of moving through the world, Leduc argues. Disability is not metaphor or a symbol for something else. Since the 1990s, the motto for the disability justice movement has been “Nothing about us, without us.”</p>
<blockquote>Put another way: the medical model celebrates an individual’s triumph over disability, while the social model celebrates society’s collective power and responsibility to consider the needs of all, thus making disability an integrated element of the society in which we live.</blockquote>
<p>We like to put ourselves in boxes, but life doesn’t really allow for it. Happiness, disability, illness, poverty and wealth: these things are inconstant, changeable. No one can survive without the collective efforts of society. Each of us requires practical/social/environmental adjustments in order to live our lives as we see fit. My happy ending likely doesn’t look like your happy ending, just as my body is also different from yours. So be it.</p>
<blockquote>Sometimes, when happy endings and obvious villains are all that you’re fed, it becomes difficult to square your own experience of the world with that story. If you’re shown the different body as other over and over as a child, it becomes hard to see your own different body as something that might, in turn, belong.</blockquote>
<blockquote>This goes for bodies and children of all kinds. For myself, as a disabled child, it had a particular kind of staying power. Sometimes I feel like the bright colours and bright bursts of song in Disney films are as delicious and as deceptive as the witch’s candy cottage hidden deep inside the woods.</blockquote>
<blockquote>You might eat, but this kind of candy will never fill you up.</blockquote>
<p><em data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">Disfigured</em> has made me rethink my childhood reaction to the event in the <a class="ek-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heidi" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="children’s classic Heidi  (opens in a new tab)">children’s classic <em>Heidi </em></a>when the disabled girl Clara is forced to walk when her wheelchair is smashed. The upshot is <img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-19653 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/clara-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/clara-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/clara-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/clara-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/clara-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/clara-550x550.jpg 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/clara.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />that the real barrier to Clara being a “normal” girl was in her mind all along. Of course we were meant to cheer Clara on as she took her first, tentative steps. But what a different story it would be if Clara was perceived to be whole and well, as she was, wheelchair and all.</p>
<blockquote>As with the charity model, psychological approaches to disability work to take the blame away from society and put it on the individual—to make disability not a lived, mundane reality but a temporary struggle that can be overcome if one has the inner and outer strength to do it.</blockquote>
<p>Amanda Leduc not only mines traditional tales from the likes of the Brothers Grimm and Hans Christian Andersen but also analyzes the influence of pop culture on our collective thinking. She offers an illuminating look at the facial scars of <a class="ek-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_James_Bond_villains" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Bond villains (opens in a new tab)">Bond villains</a>, the limitations of <a class="ek-link" href="https://princess.disney.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Disney princesses (opens in a new tab)">Disney princesses</a>, and the more contemporary hero narratives found in the <a class="ek-link" href="https://www.marvel.com/explore" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Marvel Universe (opens in a new tab)">Marvel Universe</a>.</p>

<p>While doing a surgical investigation of fairy tales and their ilk, this author has whipped up some magic of her own. <em>Disfigured</em> goes to the heart of the stories we tell ourselves, whom we accept, and whom we other. It is both far reaching and deeply intimate&#8211;a book I highly recommend.</p>


<hr class="wp-block-separator" />


<h4 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Disfigured: On Fairy Tales, Disability, and Making Space</em> by Amanda Leduc <a href="https://chbooks.com/Books/D/Disfigured" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">can be purchased here</a>.</h4>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Amanda Leduc&#8217;s novel, <em>The Centaur’s Wife</em>, is <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.ca/books/551899/the-centaurs-wife-by-amanda-leduc/9780735272859" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">forthcoming with Random House Canada</a> in the spring of 2021.</h4>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Faerie</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/faerie/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathrin Hagey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 10:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[What's in a Fairy Tale?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the time I was two years old, I weighed thirteen pounds and was too&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-19198" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/The-Hairbell-Fairy-featured-in-Conan-Doyles-The-Coming-of-the-Fairies-1922-226x300.jpg" alt="Faerie" width="226" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/The-Hairbell-Fairy-featured-in-Conan-Doyles-The-Coming-of-the-Fairies-1922-226x300.jpg 226w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/The-Hairbell-Fairy-featured-in-Conan-Doyles-The-Coming-of-the-Fairies-1922.jpg 540w" sizes="(max-width: 226px) 100vw, 226px" />By the time I was two years old, I weighed thirteen pounds and was too weak to walk or even sit up for very long. My parents were troubled folk who finally took me to the hospital where I was diagnosed with celiac disease, a now well-known chronic condition. Fortunately, one of the attending doctors had a cousin recently diagnosed with the same problem and he recognized the symptoms where others had not. I imagine that if I’d been born a hundred or so years earlier, my parents—of mainly Celtic and Germanic descent and sickened by alcoholism (him) and intermittent psychosis (her)—might have concluded that I was not the child originally born to them, that I was from the realm of Faerie.</p>
<blockquote>Although [<a href="https://www.irishcentral.com/roots/history/bridget-cleary-last-witch-burned-in-ireland" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bridget Cleary’s</a>] was the most flamboyant case of changeling-murder in the Victorian press, sadly it was not the only account of brutal mistreatment of those deemed to be fairies. Usually the poor victims were children, born with physical deformities or struck by sudden wasting illnesses. It wasn&#8217;t until the 20th century that reports of fairy abductions began to dwindle&#8230;
<h5>From &#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://endicottstudio.typepad.com/articleslist/fairies-in-legend-lore-and-literature-by-terri-windling.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Fairies in Legend, Lore, and Literature (opens in a new tab)">Fairies in Legend, Lore, and Literature</a>&#8221; by Terri Windling</h5>
</blockquote>

<p>Faerie is a dangerous state, a country ruled by capricious characters, amoral beings who care nothing for us and are ill-equipped to fathom the stormy seas of human emotions. That being said, every so often they condescend.</p>



<p>Windling states that fairies went out of fashion again—after reaching peak popularity during the reign of Victoria—in the first half of the twentieth century, a span of time that saw two world wars and a world-wide depression that partially collapsed the economic dreams of the burgeoning middle class. But when J.R.R. Tolkien’s LotR trilogy hit, elves and dwarves and hobbits and their fantastical realm returned for good. The twenty-first century has also witnessed the rise in popularity of <a class="ek-link" href="http://www.ghibli.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Studio Ghibli (opens in a new tab)">Studio Ghibli</a> and the enchanting storytelling of creators Hayao Miyazaki and Isao Takahata who have brought to cinematic life many elements of Japanese Faerie: fish-girl Ponyo (<em>Ponyo</em>), forest spirit Totoro (<em>My Neighbor Totoro</em>), No-Face the mirror demon (<em>Spirited Away</em>), river dragon Mizuchi (<em>Spirited Away</em>), and many more.</p>



<p>Faerie has always been a world-wide phenomenon. In her article, Windling lists no less than fifty-eight of its denizens, including Manitou (Algonquin), Hotots (Armenia), Peri (Persia), Oakmen (British Isles), Gandharvas (India), Aziza (west Africa), Shinsen (China), Rusali (Romania), and Bela (Indonesia). She states that her list is by no means complete.</p>

<p>It’s often remarked that fairies rarely appear in fairy tales, despite the moniker. If by fairy we mean a tiny winged being, fleet of mind and body, then yes, they are few and far between. But if, instead, we refer to beings whose name is derived from the the Latin fata (“the fates”), we see that fairy tales are rife with them. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-full wp-image-19199" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Chiostri-pinocchio.jpg" alt="Blue Fairy" width="198" height="296" />Perhaps the most familiar to those of us who grew up with western literature: the fairy with turquoise hair in Carlo Collodi’s <em>The Adventures of Pinocchio</em>; Cinderella’s fairy godmother; the woman at the well in “Diamonds and Toads”; Thumbelina in the story of the same name by Hans Christian Andersen; Pan in <em>The Wind in the Willows</em>; the good fairies and the bad fairy in “Sleeping Beauty”; and Tinkerbell in <em>Peter Pan</em>.</p>

<p>Less familiar, but just as thrilling, two little-known tales featuring fairies:</p>



<p>From the <a class="ek-link" href="https://archive.org/details/chinesefairybook00wilh/page/n141/mode/2up?q=flower+elves" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Chinese Fairy Book (opens in a new tab)"><em>Chinese Fairy Book</em></a> (Wilhelm and Martens), &#8220;The Flower-Elves&#8221; tells the story of a scholar who, world-weary and seeking &#8220;hidden wisdom,&#8221; takes refuge in a country house surrounded by flowers and bamboo. A neighbor introduces herself.</p>

<blockquote>She made a deep courtesy (sic), greeted him and said: &#8220;I am your neighbor. We are a company of young maids who are on our way to visit the eighteen aunts. We should like to rest in this court for awhile, and therefore ask your permission to do so.&#8221;</blockquote>
<p>The scholar is taken by these women, to the point of being bewitched.</p>
<blockquote>They were charming, with delicate features, and slender, graceful figures. When they moved their sleeves, a delightful fragrance was exhaled. There is no fragrance known to the human world which could be compared with it.</blockquote>
<p>After being joined by the aunts, the scholar dines with the ladies and watches them sing and dance. He is &#8220;so overpowered with delight that he no longer knew whether he were in heaven or on earth.&#8221; The young ladies are the flowers and the aunts are the winds that threaten their existence, but also hasten their development when they are being gentle and thoughtful. The scholar comes to the aid of the flower-elves by controlling the winds. The flowers are content and he grows in wisdom until he becomes a wise old sage. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-19200" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/TurkishTales-e1595784753100-242x300.jpeg" alt="Turkish fairy tales" width="242" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/TurkishTales-e1595784753100-242x300.jpeg 242w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/TurkishTales-e1595784753100.jpeg 447w" sizes="(max-width: 242px) 100vw, 242px" /></p>
<p>In <a class="ek-link" href="https://publicdomainreview.org/collection/forty-four-turkish-fairy-tales-1913" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Forty-Four Turkish Fairy Tales by Ignácz Kúnos (opens in a new tab)"><em>Forty-Four Turkish Fairy Tales</em> by Ignácz Kúnos</a>, &#8220;The Padishah of the Thirty Peris&#8221; is the story of a princess who one day encounters a dove who steals her ring and, by some deep instinctual recognition, falls so in love with the bird that it breaks her heart. The bird returns twice more, stealing her things, and even more of her heart.</p>
<p>The padishah tries to trick his daughter into revealing the source of her pain. He provides a healing bath for all the people who, before partaking, must reveal the reason for their troubles. The padishah believes his daughter will thus declare herself. As so often happens, the padishah unleashes a series of events that will bring salvation to his daughter and to the bird, who is really a prince enchanted by thirty peris who keep him captive as padishah of a separate, parallel realm. Two lands are united when the princess and the dove/man finally wed.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll give the final words to the master himself:</p>
<blockquote>Faerie contains many things besides elves and fays, and besides dwarfs, witches, trolls, giants, or dragons: it holds the seas, the sun, the moon, the sky; and the earth, and all things that are in it: tree and bird, water and stone, wine and bread, and ourselves, mortal men, when we are enchanted.
<h5>From &#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="http://heritagepodcast.com/wp-content/uploads/Tolkien-On-Fairy-Stories-subcreation.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="On Fairy Stories (opens in a new tab)">On Fairy Stories</a>&#8221; by J.R.R. Tolkien</h5>
</blockquote>
<hr />
<p>All images are in the public domain.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Frogs</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/frogs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathrin Hagey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 11:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[What's in a Fairy Tale?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18979</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My last post was about water in fairy tales, with a particular emphasis on wells.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-18981" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/frog-5073324_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="frog prince" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/frog-5073324_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/frog-5073324_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/frog-5073324_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/frog-5073324_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/frog-5073324_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />My last post was about <a class="ek-link" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/water/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="water in fairy tales (opens in a new tab)">water in fairy tales</a>, with a particular emphasis on wells. It seems natural to focus this time on frogs, those liminal beings that exist where land and water meet, and require both.</p>
<p>An obvious place to begin would be with the Grimms&#8217; &#8220;The Frog King, or Iron Heinrich,&#8221; also frequently referred to as &#8220;The Frog Prince.&#8221; I will get to it in a moment. Before doing so, I would like to divert your attention to &#8220;Briar Rose,&#8221; the Grimms&#8217; version of a story also known as &#8220;Sleeping Beauty in the Wood.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p>Long, long ago there lived a king and a queen. Day after day they said to each other: &#8220;Oh, if only we could have a child!&#8221; But nothing ever happened. One day, while the queen was bathing a frog crawled out of the water, crept ashore, and said to her: &#8220;Your wish shall be fulfilled. Before a year goes by, you will give birth to a daughter.&#8221;</p>
<h6>From <em>The Annotated Brothers Grimm</em>, Maria Tatar</h6>
</blockquote>
<p>Tatar states that the desire for a child can also be interpreted as a phase of &#8220;renewal, transformation, and rejuvenation.&#8221; She cautions against putting too much emphasis on the appearance of the frog in the queen&#8217;s bath, mainly because earlier versions had a talking crab. However, one could argue that the Grimms&#8217; final edits reflect long and widely held beliefs about frogs, creatures that &#8220;kept popping their heads out of wells, springs, rivers, woods, and so on to announce a forthcoming pregnancy. That is, they were often symbols of fertility.&#8221;<sup>1</sup></p>
<p>&#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://etc.usf.edu/lit2go/175/grimms-fairy-tales/3122/the-three-languages/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The Three Languages (opens in a new tab)">The Three Languages</a>&#8221; is another fairy tale collected by the Grimms. In this, a count, dismayed by the stupidity of his only son, sends him to three wise men. The first teaches the boy the language of dogs, the second&#8211;the language of birds, and the third&#8211;that of frogs. Enraged, the count orders his servants to kill the hopeless son. They take pity on him, and the young man makes his way through the world, using, in succession, each of the three languages in three different circumstances, gaining good fortune along the way.</p>
<blockquote><p>Frogs are a form of life developed earlier in the evolution of animal life than either dogs or birds &#8230; Thus, while at the deepest level frogs may symbolize our earliest existence, on a more accessible level they represent our ability to move from a lower to a higher stage of living. If we want to be fanciful, we could say that learning the language of the dogs and the birds is the precondition for gaining the most important ability: to develop oneself from a lower into a higher state of existence. The frogs may symbolize both the lowest, most primitive, and earliest state of our being, and the development away from it.</p>
<h6>From <em>The Uses of Enchantment: The Meaning and Importance of Fairy Tales</em>, Bruno Bettelheim</h6>
</blockquote>
<p>Frogs begin life as water-borne eggs, hatching as tadpoles, sperm-like creatures that eventually sprout legs, become froglets, then lose their tails, becoming adult frogs. All but the final stage take place entirely in water. As a ubiquitous species, they have worldwide significance as symbols of metamorphosis. It isn&#8217;t exactly a gigantic leap to imagine a frog becoming a human being.</p>
<p>According to Zipes, &#8220;The Frog Prince&#8221; is &#8220;known and beloved throughout the world in many variants &#8230; We love this lascivious frog &#8230; Perhaps love is too strong a word. Let us just say that we have a fatal attraction to the frog and we don&#8217;t know why.&#8221;</p>
<p>For forty years the Grimms wrestled with how they wished to finalize the text, given religious and other social constraints. In similar stories, such as &#8220;The Well at the World&#8217;s End,&#8221; the princess cuts off the frog&#8217;s head. The Grimms settled on having her slam it against a wall, a rare display of rebellion in a fairy tale daughter. (The notion of kissing the frog to reveal the prince came later and is predominant in Anglo-American versions.)</p>
<p>&#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="http://www.eastoftheweb.com/short-stories/UBooks/FrogPrin.shtml" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The Frog Prince (opens in a new tab)">The Frog Prince</a>&#8221; goes like this: The youngest daughter of a king is bored. She goes to a well at the edge of a wood to play with her golden ball. When the ball falls in the water, her weeping alerts a nearby frog who promises to fetch it if she will love him, play with him, and take care of him for life. This she promises to do.</p>
<p>Once she has the golden ball in hand, the princess skips to the castle, ignoring the pleas of the jilted frog. Later that evening, the frog knocks at the castle door. When the princess expresses how disgusted she is by the slimy creature, the king says she must fulfill her promise. She does the bare minimum for as long as she can, putting him in a corner of her room.</p>
<blockquote><p>While she was lying in bed, he came crawling over and said: &#8220;I&#8217;m tired and want to sleep as much as you do. Lift me up into your bed or I&#8217;ll tell your father.&#8221;</p>
<p>The princess became really annoyed, picked up the frog, and threw him with all her might against the wall. &#8220;Now you&#8217;ll get your rest, you disgusting frog!&#8221;</p>
<h6>From <em>The Annotated Brothers Grimm</em>, Maria Tatar</h6>
</blockquote>
<p>The frog (a prince in disguise) is instantly disenchanted by the violence. And of course, they get married.</p>
<p>In &#8220;The Frog Prince: Tale and Toxicology&#8221;<sup>2</sup> David M. Siegel and Susan H. McDaniel share a biological argument for the why of the &#8220;special place&#8221; of frogs in fairy tales and folklore:</p>
<blockquote><p>Early storytellers, it seems, may well have had direct or indirect knowledge of the hallucinogenic effects of a small innoculum of bufotenin following contact with frog skin &#8230; It is also consistent with the role of the frog as a messenger from another world, a being between levels of consciousness, between the physical world and the spiritual world.</p></blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-18983" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/i-beg-your-pardon-927750_1920-300x199.jpg" alt="frogs" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/i-beg-your-pardon-927750_1920-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/i-beg-your-pardon-927750_1920-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/i-beg-your-pardon-927750_1920-768x510.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/i-beg-your-pardon-927750_1920-1536x1021.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/i-beg-your-pardon-927750_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Another interesting (and hilarious) point is made by Mari Ness in her piece &#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://www.tor.com/2016/05/26/wait-what-happened-to-the-kissing-part-the-frog-king-or-iron-henry/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Wait. What Happened to the KISSING Part? The Frog King, or Iron Henry (opens in a new tab)">Wait. What Happened to the KISSING Part? The Frog King, or Iron Henry</a>&#8221; for Tor.com. After pointing out that many versions of this fairy tale feature a violent act of rage on the part of the princess, she then states: &#8220;unless a frog flung against a wall counts as a marriage vow, the two are not exactly legally married. Also missing: the usual stuff about flowers, chocolates, that kinda thing.&#8221;</p>
<p>Just as a tadpole can&#8217;t help but become a frog (bearing hallucinogenic possibilities), the Grimms couldn&#8217;t bring themselves to nullify the passion and drive of their heroine, despite the theme of this amphibious tale, which many take to be: <em>Keep your promises</em>.</p>
<p>Frogs, it would seem, have the best of both worlds. As do princesses, some of the time.</p>
<hr />
<ul class="rich-text block-editor-rich-text__editable" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li>All images by Alexas_Fotos at Pixabay.com</li>
</ul>
<ol class="rich-text block-editor-rich-text__editable" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li>Zipes, Jack. 2008. &#8220;What Makes a Repulsive Frog So Appealing: Memetics and Fairy Tales,&#8221; <em>Journal of Folklore Research</em>, Volume 45, Number 2, May-August 2008: 109-143.</li>
<li>Siegel, David M. and McDaniel, Susan H. 1991. &#8220;The Frog Prince: Tale and Toxicology,&#8221; <em>American Journal of Orthopsychiatry</em>, 61 (4), October 1991: 558-562.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Water</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/water/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/water/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathrin Hagey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 11:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[What's in a Fairy Tale?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The banks of Sulphur Creek in southern Ontario were my childhood haunting grounds. The creek&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-18080" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/vintage-1721898_1920-200x300.jpg" alt="water" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/vintage-1721898_1920-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/vintage-1721898_1920-684x1024.jpg 684w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/vintage-1721898_1920-768x1150.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/vintage-1721898_1920-1026x1536.jpg 1026w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/vintage-1721898_1920.jpg 1282w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />The banks of Sulphur Creek in southern Ontario were my childhood haunting grounds. The creek lay at the bottom of a ravine, a beautiful place where a remnant of the old Carolinian forest of eastern America stretches into Canada. One of my favorite memories is being hot and sweaty on a summer’s day and taking a drink. Unknown to me then, the water was foul with toxic waste, two major steel factories and other mid-twentieth century industrial activities taking place nearby. But what did it matter? I believed that where the water bubbled, over logs and other debris, it was pure. And I longed to go to “the other side,” that magical realm of possibility.</p>
<blockquote>All running water, not just spring water, can prove to be the haunt of fairies, for crossing over (or through) running water is one of the ways to enter their realm.
<h4> </h4>
<h4>From &#8220;<a class="ek-link ek-link" href="https://www.terriwindling.com/blog/2013/06/into-the-woods-11-wild-waters.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Water, Wild and Sacred (opens in a new tab)">Water, Wild and Sacred&#8221; by Terri Windling</a></h4>
</blockquote>

<p>For most of human history, water has been drawn from wells. In many ancient stories (in the Bible and in fairy tales, for example) life-changing conversations take place near one. As a social gathering space that also holds the key to life, the well is a literal and figurative echo chamber where your true voice is magnified and your intentions cannot be hidden. A visit there might be a blessing, or a curse.</p>



<p>Charles Perrault&#8217;s fairy tale “<a class="ek-link" href="http://www.surlalunefairytales.com/diamondstoads/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Diamonds and Toads (opens in a new tab)">Diamonds and Toads</a>” begins with a mother and her two daughters. The mother and the eldest daughter are miserable people and they force the youngest, who is mild-tempered in comparison, to work like a beast. One of her tasks is to fetch water from a well a great distance from their home.</p>



<p>One day, when the youngest daughter is filling her bucket, an old woman appears and begs for a drink. She is a fairy in disguise, and very pleased with the girl’s fine manners, rewarding her by turning every word she speaks into a precious jewel or a delicate blossom.</p>





<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18081 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Lesfees-237x300.jpg" alt="Diamonds and Toads" width="237" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Lesfees-237x300.jpg 237w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Lesfees-768x972.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Lesfees.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 237px) 100vw, 237px" /></p>



<p>Of course, we know what happens next: the mother wants to ensure that her wicked daughter will meet the fairy at the well and receive the same treatment. The fairy rewards <em>her</em> with toads and other foul creatures for every syllable she speaks.</p>

<p>“<a class="ek-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Well_of_the_World%27s_End" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The Well of the World’s End (opens in a new tab)">The Well of the World’s End</a>,” an Anglo-Scottish fairy tale collected by Joseph Jacobs, tells the story of a girl sent to the well of the world’s end to collect water with a sieve, and told by her step-mother not to return until she does. A frog finds her weeping beside the well, and he says that he will help her if she will do anything he asks for one night. She takes his advice, covers the sieve with moss and mud, collects the water, and returns home. The step-mother is not amused, and for a punishment insists that the girl keep her promise to the frog, who turns out to be a handsome prince in disguise.</p>

<p>&#8220;<a href="http://www.authorama.com/grimms-fairy-tales-51.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Water of Life</a>&#8221; is a German fairy tale recorded by the Grimms. A king has grown old and weary, the fire of his life dying. Ironically, it’s the water of life that will bring the renewal he desires. And it’s the youngest son, the king’s own intuition, and his deepest instincts that will guide him back to the source.</p>





<p>From a spiritual and/or psychological perspective, water symbolizes purification and renewal (baptism), and also power (Holy Spirit). It is reflective, and being the first mirror, sometimes a means of predicting the future (hydromancy; Galadriel’s mirror). Water symbolizes healing, knowledge, wisdom, and transformation.</p>

<p>Water can even capture the fire of the cosmos. In his essay “<a class="ek-link" href="https://parabola.org/2018/05/16/the-heights-of-machu-picchu-by-j-m-white/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The Heights of Machu Picchu (opens in a new tab)">The Heights of Machu Picchu</a>,” J.M. White describes a surprising discovery about ancient Incan astronomers:</p>
<blockquote>Ruben took us across the plaza through a complex of buildings into a large room that has two stone cylinders carved out of the bedrock of the floor. They are about four inches tall and fifteen inches wide with a lip about a quarter inch tall around the top-edge. They were full of rain water when we first came upon them &#8230; He said these were used as reflective mirrors for watching the sky, that the room was an observatory where, by comparing the images in the two cylinders, the ancient astronomers made calculations charting the movement of the stars, planets, sun and moon. Then he instructed us to stand where we could see the sun reflected in the shallow pool of water. I shifted around until I had the gleaming light of the sun reflected in the center of the pool. As I stared at the reflection, I noticed there was a perfect circle of smaller suns reflected over and over around the outer lip in a radiant parhelion of gem-like points of light &#8230; He said that in the Andean traditions there is a color spectrum that runs through the body and each part of the body is associated with a color &#8230; It was a marvelous room with an esoteric technology uniting the above and the below, reflecting outward to the distant stars and inward to the inner state of the body.</blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-18082" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/glitter-1575596_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="Sunlight on Water" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/glitter-1575596_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/glitter-1575596_1920-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/glitter-1575596_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/glitter-1575596_1920-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/glitter-1575596_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Sunlight on water is a primal delight—two life essentials coming together, reassuring us that everything we need is there for us, in abundance. Our bodies contain within them both the fires and waters of life, in delicate balance.</p>
<hr />
<ul class="rich-text block-editor-rich-text__editable" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li>First Image: Prawny at Pixabay.com</li>
<li>Second Image: CC BY-SA 3.0</li>
<li>Third Image: MabelAmber at Pixabay.com</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/water/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dogs</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dogs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathrin Hagey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 10:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[What's in a Fairy Tale?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dogs are descendants of one of the most feared beings on earth: From the diminutive&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17843 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_20190902_223821297-225x300.jpg" alt="dog" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_20190902_223821297-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_20190902_223821297-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_20190902_223821297-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_20190902_223821297-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/IMG_20190902_223821297-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />Dogs are descendants of one of the most feared beings on earth:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">From the diminutive dachshund to the massive Saint Bernard, all dogs are descended from the European grey wolf. At some point in the past, humans and wolves crossed paths, and then somehow, somewhere, the wolf began to change.  
<h4> </h4>
<h4>From &#8220;<a href="https://lithub.com/did-dogs-choose-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Did Dogs Choose Us</a>?&#8221; by Helen Pilcher for Literary Hub</h4>
</blockquote>
<p>There are more questions than answers here, but that’s going to be the case for some time. The depth of our bond with dogs means sorting out the ground zero events of their domestication will take all the resources we can muster.</p>
<blockquote>If current divisions between species are murky, the past lies in deep darkness. Scientists generally agree that there is good evidence that dogs were domesticated around 15,000 years ago. By 14,000 years ago, people were burying dogs, sometimes along with humans. But some biologists argue, based on DNA evidence and the shape of ancient skulls, that dog domestication occurred well over 30,000 years ago.</blockquote>
<blockquote>And as to where the process occurred, researchers studying dog and wolf DNA — most of it modern but some from ancient sources — have argued in recent years that dogs originated in East Asia, Mongolia, Siberia, Europe and Africa.</blockquote>
<blockquote>One reason for the conflicting theories, according to Greger Larson, a biologist in the archaeology department at the University of Oxford, is that dog genetics are a mess. In an interview at his office here in November, he noted that most dog breeds were invented in the 19th century during a period of dog obsession that he called “the giant whirlwind blender of the European crazy Victorian dog-breeding frenzy.”</blockquote>
<blockquote>That blender, as well as random breeding by dogs themselves, and interbreeding with wolves at different times over at least the last 15,000 years, created a “tomato soup” of dog genetics, for which the ingredients are very hard to identify, Dr. Larson said.  </blockquote>
<blockquote>
<h4>From “<a class="ek-link" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/01/19/science/the-big-search-to-find-out-where-dogs-come-from.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The Big Search to Find Out Where Dogs Come From (opens in a new tab)">The Big Search to Find Out Where Dogs Come From</a>” by James Gorman, New York Times</h4>
</blockquote>
<p>In folklore, dogs have second sight (Scotland), have been steeds for fairy riders (Wales), and have the ability to heal human wounds with their tongues. According to Marie-Louise von Franz in <em>The Interpretation of Fairy Tales</em>, the dog is “the essence of relationship.” But not all relationships are positive. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17845 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Giuseppe_Arcimboldo_-_Sketch_for_a_Cerberus_-_WGA00875-300x220.jpg" alt="cerberus" width="300" height="220" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Giuseppe_Arcimboldo_-_Sketch_for_a_Cerberus_-_WGA00875-300x220.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Giuseppe_Arcimboldo_-_Sketch_for_a_Cerberus_-_WGA00875-1024x752.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Giuseppe_Arcimboldo_-_Sketch_for_a_Cerberus_-_WGA00875-768x564.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Giuseppe_Arcimboldo_-_Sketch_for_a_Cerberus_-_WGA00875.jpg 1089w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>The hell hound of British folklore haunts the moors and is associated with the devil, the likely inspiration for J. K. Rowling’s Sirius Black and Sir Arthur Conan Doyle’s Hound of the Baskervilles. And let’s not forget Cerberus, the three-headed dog of ancient Greece, guardian of Hades, the dreaded underworld (also appearing in the Harry Potter series as Fluffy).</p>

<p>In the western canon, the following are the most familiar fairy tales featuring dogs:</p>



<ul>
<li>From Andrew Lang’s <em>Green Fairy Book</em>, “<a class="ek-link" href="http://www.mythfolklore.net/andrewlang/396.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The Three Dogs (opens in a new tab)">The Three Dogs</a>” tells the story of a poor shepherd who, upon dying, leaves his son and daughter with only a small house and three sheep. The humble son trades the sheep for three mysterious dogs: Salt who will bring him food, Pepper who will protect him, and Mustard who can chew through iron. The dogs guide the boy to his happily ever after&#8211;marriage to a princess.</li>
<li>The Grimms “<a class="ek-link" href="http://www.authorama.com/grimms-fairy-tales-8.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The Dog and the Sparrow (opens in a new tab)">The Dog and the Sparrow</a>” is a dark tale and, despite the title, is really more about the bird. The poor dog belongs to a shepherd who rarely feeds him. The sparrow comes to the rescue, until a brute of a carter, despite the bird’s warning, runs over the dog in the street. The rest of the story is about the horrific ways in which the bird avenges the dog’s death. (Maria Tatar doesn’t even bother to include this one in <em>The Annotated Grimm Brothers</em>.)</li>
<li>Also from the Grimms, “<a class="ek-link" href="https://germanstories.vcu.edu/grimm/bremereng.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The Bremen Town Musicians (opens in a new tab)">The Bremen Town Musicians</a>” is a reverse <em>Animal Farm </em>in which a donkey, a dog, a rooster and a cat unite harmoniously to defeat a band of witless robbers to take over a hideout and make it their home.</li>
<li>From Hans Christian Andersen, “<a class="ek-link" href="https://www.storynory.com/the-tinderbox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The Tinderbox (opens in a new tab)">The Tinderbox</a>” is a brutal story about a soldier returning from battle, a witch who guides him to riches, and three dogs&#8211;one with eyes as big as teacups, another with eyes as big as millwheels, and a third with eyes as big as round towers&#8211;who guard treasures of copper, silver, and gold. The soldier fetches the riches for himself and the tinderbox for the witch. When the old woman won’t reveal why she wants the box, the soldier chops off her head. After the soldier spends all his coin, he quickly learns that the tinderbox can summon the dogs and replenish his riches, forever. After defeating the king and queen, the soldier gets his happily ever after with the princess and the dogs.</li>
</ul>

<p>On December 3rd, 2015 <a href="https://windling.typepad.com/about/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Terri Windling</a> gave us the dog girl illustration, because it was her birthday and she wanted to follow what is a tradition for many indigenous cultures: the giving of birthday gifts by the birthday person. She indicated the illustration could be <a class="ek-link" href="https://www.terriwindling.com/blog/2015/12/the-dog-child.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="downloaded (opens in a new tab)">downloaded</a> and printed out from her website <em>Myth and Moor</em>. And she encouraged us to write a dog girl story of our own. This is mine.</p>
<hr />
<p>Once upon a time there was a dog child who lived in a tiny little house on a tiny little hill in a tiny little village on Dartmoor&#8230;</p>

<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17844 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/TheDogChild-172x300.jpg" alt="dog girl" width="172" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/TheDogChild-172x300.jpg 172w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/TheDogChild.jpg 530w" sizes="(max-width: 172px) 100vw, 172px" />But before she became a dog child she was a small girl from a large family, whose mother, due to the worries of finding food to eat and fuel for the fire, had spoken sharp, hurtful words. Upon receiving her mother’s rebuke, the girl turned and ran farther and faster than she had ever done in the whole of her life. And before long she was alone and lost on the darkening moor.</p>



<p>The season was spring, but the night air was crisp. As the last slip of sunlight disappeared, the stars began to come out of hiding, one by one. The girl shivered.</p>



<p>Something stirred in the bracken. The moor was vast, with hidden dangers her mother had warned her about. All she could do was lay down where she was, wrap her arms around her knees, and hope for sleep to arrive.</p>



<p>When morning came, the sun blazed, warming the girl from head to toe, awakening her to the sweet breeze and the soothing sound it made.</p>



<p>“I wonder if mama will ever find me,” said the girl to the nearest being, a blush-pink spindle tree. The spindle replied, “Do you wish to be found?”</p>



<p>The girl was so puzzled by what it said she forgot to be amazed that it could say anything at all.</p>



<p>“Of course I do,” said the girl.</p>



<p>“Then so be it,” said the spindle, and then it shuddered and grew silent.</p>



<p>A granite tor in the distance caught her eye, and the girl spent most of the morning walking to the place, which, on arrival, loomed like a mountain. She found shelter in a place carved by wind and rain and settled in to rest. But she was not alone.</p>



<p>“What are you doing in my cave?” said a voice both soft and scratchy, like wool.</p>



<p>“I’m lost,” said the girl.</p>



<p>“That’s not an answer.”</p>



<p>“I don’t have another.”</p>



<p>“Well then,” said the voice, “I suppose you can stay a little while.” This was followed by other, softer voices that made the girl long to see what made them.</p>



<p>In time, the girl’s eyes grew adjusted to the light in the cave. And as they did, she saw shapes that slowly became a creature with a long snout and an even longer tail, and five smaller creatures lying alongside it. At the sight of the creature mother and her children, the girl’s heart grew soft as honey. They were strange beasts, yet also familiar. The young ones, she could see now, suckled while their mother lay on her side, a grin of contentment puckering the skin at the edges of her snout.</p>



<p>More time passed and the creature mother rested while her children slept, all but one who had climbed into the girl’s lap and was stroking her hands with its tongue.</p>



<p>“Do you hear that?” the creature mother said to the girl after a while. “Someone is out on the moor calling for you.”</p>



<p>The girl tilted her head to listen, but all she could hear was the wind.</p>



<p>“Whoever it is smells like you,” said the creature mother.</p>



<p>The girl left the cave, and when she saw her mother, ran to greet her. They embraced, and then the girl brought her mother into the cave to meet the creature mother and her young. The creature told them she was a dog and that her children were puppies. She invited the girl to return in the future to visit her again. “You’ve been a good guest,” she said to the girl. “I will miss you.”</p>



<p>Back home the girl did what she had always done: tended the sheep, carded wool, helped her mother bake rye bread, and watched over her younger siblings. But nothing could stop her from longing to visit the dogs. She had left a part of her heart back in the cave. In fact, the girl’s desire to hear the dogs’ voices on the wind and to smell their approach was so great that, in time, she grew dog ears and a dog nose.</p>



<p>Then one day, while the girl was rounding sheep into the pen for the night, a brown creature crept out from the gorse. It was the puppy who had stroked her hands with its tongue, now a fully grown dog. The girl greeted the dog with hugs. The dog greeted the girl with tail wags. They would never be parted again.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center" style="text-align: center;">The End</p>
<hr />
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-17846" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/bremen-town-musicians-1651945_1920-214x300.jpg" alt="Bremen Town Musicians" width="214" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/bremen-town-musicians-1651945_1920-214x300.jpg 214w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/bremen-town-musicians-1651945_1920-731x1024.jpg 731w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/bremen-town-musicians-1651945_1920-768x1076.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/bremen-town-musicians-1651945_1920-1097x1536.jpg 1097w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/bremen-town-musicians-1651945_1920.jpg 1371w" sizes="(max-width: 214px) 100vw, 214px" /></p>
<h4> </h4>
<h4 class="has-text-align-center" style="text-align: center;">&#8220;Everything I know I learned from dogs.&#8221; &#8211;Nora Roberts</h4>



<ul class="rich-text block-editor-rich-text__editable" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li>First image: Photo of Chip by Cathrin Hagey</li>
<li>Second Image: Sketch for a Cerberus by Giuseppe Arcimboldo in the Public Domain via Wikimedia Commons</li>
<li>Third image: Dog Child by Terri Windling</li>
<li>Fourth Image: Bremen Town Musicians by TeeFarm at Pixabay.com</li>
</ul>
<hr class="wp-block-separator" /><!-- /wp:quote -->]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cats</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/cats/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathrin Hagey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 17:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[What's in a Fairy Tale?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the European witch hunts and trials, thousands of cats were put to death, accused&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_17488" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17488" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-17488 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/cat-746242_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="cats" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/cat-746242_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/cat-746242_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/cat-746242_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/cat-746242_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/cat-746242_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17488" class="wp-caption-text">By LisaRedfern at Pixabay.com</figcaption></figure>
<p>During the European witch hunts and trials, thousands of cats were put to death, accused as they were alongside their human &#8220;familiars.&#8221; The legacy of this tragic era is still with us, even though we tend to jest about Halloween cats and the old superstitions. But this negative view of cats contradicts their actual role throughout human history. Cats have almost always symbolized protection and good fortune.</p>
<blockquote>In the earliest feline images found on cave walls and carved out of stone, wildcats are companions and guardians to the Great Goddess—often flanking a mother goddess figure in the act of giving birth. Such imagery has been found in ancient sites across Europe, Africa, India, and the Middle East.
<h4>Terri Windling, &#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://www.terriwindling.com/blog/cats-cat-lore/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Feline Folklore (opens in a new tab)">Feline Folklore</a>&#8220;</h4>
</blockquote>

<p>Cat is <em>mau</em> in Ancient Egyptian, <em>mao</em> in Cantonese—alliterations and imitations of the sound a domestic cat makes, and, as Windling notes in the article cited above, &#8220;a mother-syllable.&#8221;</p>



<p>Long before cats featured in folklore and fairy tales, they rose to phenomenal status in Ancient Egypt, progressing from rodent-killing protectors of grains to household pets to god/dess. Cats transformed Egyptian culture and were transfigured by it—shaped, physically, and metaphorically, into the cozy, domestic creatures we know and love today. Or so we thought.</p>

<figure id="attachment_17489" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17489" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-17489 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mcbabayaga-200x300.jpg" alt="fairy tale cat" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mcbabayaga-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/mcbabayaga.jpg 547w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17489" class="wp-caption-text">Illustration by Adrienne Segur (public domain)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The latest research provides evidence that cats and humans coexisted even earlier than previously believed. Thousands of years before their arrival in Egypt, cats in the Near East protected stored crops and conquered the hearts of the farmers who grew them.</p>
<blockquote>One striking example is a 9,500-year-old cat that was buried in a human grave on the island of Cyprus, where cats are not native. Some 6,000 years ago, after Neolithic farming practices began spreading, it seems that these people-friendly felines foraged northward and westward with humans into Bulgaria and Romania.
<h4>Maya Wei-Haas, &#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/science-nature/how-cats-conquered-world-180963749/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="How Cats Conquered the World (opens in a new tab)">How Cats Conquered the World</a>&#8220;</h4>
</blockquote>
<p>Domestic cats in Ancient Egypt represented a &#8220;second wave&#8221; of feline dominance over humankind.</p>
<blockquote>The researchers even found evidence of these human-loving cats at the Viking port of Ralswiek on the Baltic Sea, says Geigl, and the Iranian port of Siraf, confirming that the faithful mousers commonly joined sailing crews. And the cats’ venture didn’t end there: for thousands of years, these furry globetrotters have followed humans wherever they went, conquering every continent except for Antarctica.
<h4>Maya Wei-Haas, &#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/science-nature/how-cats-conquered-world-180963749/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="How Cats Conquered the World (opens in a new tab)">How Cats Conquered the World</a>&#8220;</h4>
</blockquote>
<figure id="attachment_17490" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17490" style="width: 233px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-17490 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ftkip-233x300.jpg" alt="Kisa Cat" width="233" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ftkip-233x300.jpg 233w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/ftkip.jpg 303w" sizes="(max-width: 233px) 100vw, 233px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17490" class="wp-caption-text">Illustration by Adrienne Segur (public domain)</figcaption></figure>
<p>According to Marie-Louise von Franz in <em>The Interpretation of Fairy Tales</em>, animals feature in our oldest, deepest stories. We project onto them our own &#8220;archetypal&#8221; tendencies. As intimate as we have been with cats for a very long time, it comes as no wonder then that we have so many stories about them, including a long list of feline fairy tales. Perhaps the best known from the European fairy tale canon is &#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/free-spirits/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Puss in Boots (opens in a new tab)">Puss in Boots</a>.&#8221; There are, however, many other cats to consider:</p>
<ul class="rich-text editor-rich-text__editable block-editor-rich-text__editable is-selected" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li>&#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://etc.usf.edu/lit2go/139/the-brown-fairy-book/4318/kisa-the-cat/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Kisa the Cat (opens in a new tab)">Kisa the Cat</a>&#8221; in which a young princess&#8217;s long-lost companion, in the form of a cat, rescues her from a menacing giant. Kisa the cat is then released from an evil enchantment and returned to her original form as a princess. The two young women will be inseparable for the rest of their lives.</li>
<li>&#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://www.therussianstore.com/blog/tale-of-baba-yaga-the-russian-witch" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Baba Yaga (opens in a new tab)">Baba Yaga</a>&#8221; is the Russian tale of a terrifying, iron-toothed witch outwitted by her niece with the aid of a black cat.</li>
<li>Countess d&#8217;Aulnoy&#8217;s &#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Fairy_Tales_by_the_Countess_d%27Aulnoy/The_White_Cat" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The White Cat (opens in a new tab)">The White Cat</a>&#8221; in which an aging king sets his sons to the task of earning their right to rule by procuring the handsomest dog in the world. The story focuses on the youngest who amasses a collection of dogs in all shapes and sizes. Concerned that he hasn&#8217;t yet found the best dog, he sets out into the woods where he finds a castle so fine it defies imagination. Disembodied hands guide him inside to a blazing hearth where he is disrobed and put into new clothes. Disoriented, he wanders into a room where an orchestra of cats is playing: &#8220;Suddenly each began to mew in a different tone, and to scratch the strings of their guitars with their claws. It was the strangest music that had ever been heard.&#8221; Then the mistress of the castle appears, a lovely white cat who extends her hospitality to the prince in the form of a grand feast. &#8220;You, madam,&#8221; says the prince, &#8220;are a cat of very rare description.&#8221; The white cat is really an enchanted princess who wins the throne for the youngest son and unites his family in the process.</li>
<li>&#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://www.sacred-texts.com/neu/eng/meft/meft32.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="The King of the Cats (opens in a new tab)">The King o&#8217; the Cats</a>&#8221; is an ancient tale from the British Isles in which the sexton and his wife discover the truth about their old tom in a most surprising fashion.</li>
</ul>
<p>The world is full of lucky cats, artful cats, traveling cats, sassy cats . . . I invite you to get your fill <a class="ek-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_fictional_felines" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="here (opens in a new tab)">here</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fraud, Part Two</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fraud-part-two/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathrin Hagey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[What's in a Fairy Tale?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tabitha &#8220;Tabby&#8221; Aykroyd  was servant and friend to Anne, Emily, Charlotte and Branwell Bronte for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="ek-link ek-link" href="https://www.bronte.org.uk/the-brontes-and-haworth/family-and-friends/tabitha-aykroyd" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Tabitha &quot;Tabby&quot; Aykroyd (opens in a new tab)" data-rich-text-format-boundary="true"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17282 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/the-witch-647537_1920-300x146.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="146" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/the-witch-647537_1920-300x146.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/the-witch-647537_1920-1024x497.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/the-witch-647537_1920-768x373.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/the-witch-647537_1920-1536x746.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/the-witch-647537_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Tabitha &#8220;Tabby&#8221; Aykroyd</a>  was servant and friend to Anne, Emily, Charlotte and Branwell Bronte for more than thirty years. Having been born in Yorkshire in the late 1700s, she was a faith-filled Christian woman with at least one foot deep in the lore of moor and wood. Her fireside tales enriched the lives of her brilliant young audience. (We have her to thank for adding fairy tale zest to their future literary works.) Tabby was an eager storyteller from a county brimming with tales to share.</p>
<blockquote><p>According to some, every dale in North Yorkshire had its own hobgoblin. These small, furry creatures of semi-human form were thought to attach themselves to a particular location, or particular family. Sometimes they could be helpful, carrying out household tasks or farm work in return for a daily jug of fresh cream.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A well-known story from Hart Hall Farm in Glaisdale tells how one such creature worked through the night to complete a task that had defeated the farm workers earlier in the day. It unloaded an entire hay cart that had become wedged between stone flags and was too heavy to move. When the creature was spied working naked at midnight, the workers left clothing out for it. But the clothing was refused and, offended, the hob disappeared forever. Hobs had to be placated but could easily become malicious if slighted. If that happened they could transform into a boggart.</p>
<h5>Katherine Clements, <a class="ek-link ek-link" href="https://www.foyles.co.uk/blog-Folklore-of-the-Yorkshire-Moors" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="&quot;Folklore of the Yorkshire Moors&quot; (opens in a new tab)">&#8220;Folklore of the Yorkshire Moors&#8221;</a></h5>
</blockquote>
<p>Then, as now, women past their sexual prime were too easily dismissed. But as Tabby toiled by the fireside she also wielded a powerful weapon: the spell that is cast by a well-told tale. It could be argued that she had the greatest influence on the children, Emily in particular. In pre and semi-literate places and times, women, and their voices, were a potent force.</p>
<blockquote><p>Spinning a tale, weaving a plot: the metaphors illuminate the relation; while the structure of fairy stories, with their repetitions, reprises, elaboration and minutiae, replicate the thread and fabric of one of women&#8217;s principal labours&#8211;the making of textiles from the wool or the flax to the finished bolt of cloth.</p>
<h5>Marina Warner, <em>From the Beast to the Blonde</em></h5>
</blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17283 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/vintage-1652574_1920-300x210.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="210" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/vintage-1652574_1920-300x210.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/vintage-1652574_1920-1024x718.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/vintage-1652574_1920-768x539.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/vintage-1652574_1920-1536x1078.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/vintage-1652574_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Documenting the history of the fairy tale has proven to be thornier than expected. Literary fairy tales owe their existence to the people, mainly men, who gathered story crumbs from previous publications, friends, family, neighbors, or by way of serendipitous chats with spellbinding people. The age of these tales has also been in question. But the evidence suggests the phrase &#8220;Tale as old as time&#8221; is apt.</p>
<blockquote><p>Using techniques normally employed by biologists, academics studied links between stories from around the world and found some had prehistoric roots.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>They found some tales were older than the earliest literary records, with one dating back to the Bronze Age.</p>
<p>The stories had been thought to date back to the 16th and 17th centuries.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Durham University anthropologist Dr. Jamie Tehrani said &#8220;Jack and the Beanstalk&#8221; was rooted in a group of stories classified as The Boy Who Stole Ogre&#8217;s Treasure, and could be traced back to when Eastern and Western Indo-European languages split more than 5,000 years ago.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Analysis showed &#8220;Beauty And The Beast&#8221; and &#8220;Rumpelstiltskin&#8221; to be about 4,000 years old.</p>
<h5><a class="ek-link ek-link" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/uk-35358487" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="BBC News (opens in a new tab)" data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">BBC News</a></h5>
</blockquote>
<p>A timeline (not necessarily <em>the</em> timeline) of recorded European tales is as follows:</p>
<ul class="rich-text editor-rich-text__editable block-editor-rich-text__editable is-selected" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li><strong data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">1550s Italy: Giovanni Francesco &#8220;Straparola&#8221;</strong> (stories include: &#8220;Sleeping Beauty,&#8221; &#8220;Puss in Boots,&#8221; &#8220;Beauty and the Beast,&#8221; &#8220;The Golden Goose&#8221;)</li>
<li><strong data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">1630s Italy: Giambattista Basile</strong> (stories include: &#8220;Rapunzel,&#8221; &#8220;Snow White,&#8221; &#8220;Sleeping Beauty,&#8221; &#8220;Cinderella&#8221;)</li>
<li><strong data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">1690s France: Charles Perrault</strong> (stories include: &#8220;Bluebeard,&#8221; &#8220;Cinderella,&#8221; &#8220;Sleeping Beauty,&#8221; &#8220;Little Red Riding Hood,&#8221; &#8220;Donkeyskin&#8221;) and<strong> Madame d&#8217;Aulnoy</strong> (stories include: &#8220;Cunning Cinders,&#8221; &#8220;Princess Rosette,&#8221; &#8220;The Little Good Mouse,&#8221; &#8220;The Imp Prince&#8221;)</li>
<li><strong data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">1819 Germany: Jacob and Wilhelm Grimm</strong> (stories include: &#8220;The Twelve Brothers,&#8221; &#8220;Rapunzel,&#8221; &#8220;Hansel and Gretel,&#8221; &#8220;Cinderella,&#8221; &#8220;Snow White,&#8221; &#8220;Briar Rose&#8221;)</li>
<li><strong data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">1888-1916 Britain: Joseph Jacobs</strong> (stories include: &#8220;Jack and the Beanstalk,&#8221; &#8220;The Three Little Pigs,&#8221; &#8220;Mr. Fox,&#8221; &#8220;The Fish and the Ring&#8221;)</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>Scholarly ambitions and patriotic zeal may have guided the Grimms in the early stages of collecting, but once their tales were in print they began to modify their vision for the collection. As reviewers weighed in, the brothers began to realize that what they had produced had a limited popular appeal in market terms. One early critic lamented the vast amounts of &#8220;pathetic&#8221; and &#8220;tasteless&#8221; material&#8230;By 1819, the date of the second edition, the collection had received more than a face-lift. Eighteen tales had been so heavily revised, redacted, and rescripted that they were almost unrecognizable&#8230;</p>
<h5>Maria Tatar, <em>The Annotated Brothers Grimm</em></h5>
</blockquote>
<p>&#8220;<a class="ek-link" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/fraud-part-one/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Fairy Tale Fraud, Part One (opens in a new tab)" data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">Fraud, Part One</a>&#8221; examines fraud within story content: some characters are fraudsters while others become their victims. In the case of earlier tales being censored and edited by literary masters, the net of victims is perhaps more widely cast, the persons caught once flesh and bone, like us.</p>
<blockquote><p>This is how many women&#8217;s teaching tales about sex, love, money, marriage, birthing, death, and transformation were lost. It is how fairy tales and myths that explicate ancient women&#8217;s mysteries have been covered over too. Most old collections of fairy tales and myths existent today have been scoured clean of the scatalogical, the sexual, the perverse, the pre-Christian, the feminine, the Goddesses, the initiatory, the medicines for various psychological malaises, and the directions for spiritual raptures.</p>
<h5>Clarissa Pinkola Estes, <em>Women Who Run With the Wolves</em></h5>
</blockquote>
<p>Straparola&#8217;s prince impregnates sleeping beauty; Perrault&#8217;s chaste nobleman doesn&#8217;t even kiss Beauty&#8217;s still lips. Different times and places call for different measures of blood and bone, lust and ecstasy, death and rebirth. It isn&#8217;t necessarily bad, as long as we are free to indulge in a reclamation of sorts. And we are living in a fairy tale Renaissance: spin new tales, re-wind old ones; the magic sweeps up people of all walks.</p>
<blockquote><p>Fairy tales give voice to unspecifiable longings for happiness, growth, success, justice. They reflect deeply rooted psychological aspects of existence, such as the attitudes that many have towards their parents and siblings, such as the relations between men and women (i.e., who is the rescuer, and who is rescued), such as the place of humans within their environments, within those selfsame woods. They have served as a medium for some of the greatest creative endeavors of the human imagination: in literature, art, music, dance, and other forms. Yet they have stood the risk of being abandoned not only because Disney and others pushed them into the nursery, but because a facile examination of them will not, cannot satisfy the longings that they evoke.</p>
<h5>Helen Pilinovsky, &#8220;<a class="ek-link ek-link" href="https://endicottstudio.typepad.com/articleslist/spells-of-enchantment-the-fairy-tale-cycle-ll-by-helen-pilinovsky.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Spells of Enchantement: The Fairy Tale Cycle (opens in a new tab)">Spells of Enchantement: The Fairy Tale Cycle&#8221;</a></h5>
</blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17284 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/forest-4700071_1920-300x188.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="188" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/forest-4700071_1920-300x188.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/forest-4700071_1920-1024x643.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/forest-4700071_1920-768x482.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/forest-4700071_1920-1536x965.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/forest-4700071_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Don&#8217;t be deceived: familiar fairy tales are more mysterious than you think. Dig a little deeper, into the leaf litter, and you&#8217;ll find a smudge in the earth, the remnant of an ancient path. Follow it a while and when you come to a fork, choose wisely. In one direction, brightly lit, a golden carriage awaits to help you on your way; the other is dark and smells of fungi and rotting matter and you will have to traverse it foot by weary foot. Both will reward, but in different ways. And both will take you somewhere new, though, perhaps, only one will take you where you need to go.</p>
<p><em>First Image by Pezibear at Pixabay.com</em><br />
<em>Second Image by Prawny at Pixabay.com</em><br />
<em>Third Image by addesia at Pixabay.com</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fraud, Part One</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fraud-part-one/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathrin Hagey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[What's in a Fairy Tale?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2019 was, in many ways, the year of the fraud. A case in point: the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17034 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735406_1920-210x300.jpg" alt="fraud" width="210" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735406_1920-210x300.jpg 210w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735406_1920-718x1024.jpg 718w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735406_1920-768x1095.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735406_1920-1078x1536.jpg 1078w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735406_1920.jpg 1347w" sizes="(max-width: 210px) 100vw, 210px" />2019 was, in many ways, the year of the fraud. A case in point: the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2019_college_admissions_bribery_scandal" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="college admissions scandal (opens in a new tab)">college admissions scandal</a> wherein Hollywood celebrity parents used fraudulent means (test taking trickery, mock photos, etc.) to get their youngsters into highbrow universities. Another: William Morrow editor and best-selling author <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/02/11/a-suspense-novelists-trail-of-deceptions" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Dan Mallory lied (opens in a new tab)">Dan Mallory lied</a> about his personal circumstances and took credit for the work of others. More: two documentaries were released about the infamous <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fyre_Festival" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Fyre Festival (opens in a new tab)">Fyre Festival</a>, a brutal failure of a music event dreamed up by “serial fraudster” Billy McFarland. Less publicized: actor <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/01/08/us/jussie-smollett-chicago-google-search-warrant/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Jussie Smollett allegedly (opens in a new tab)">Jussie Smollett allegedly</a> staged his own beating, and <a href="https://www.thecut.com/2019/09/the-story-of-caroline-calloway-and-her-ghostwriter-natalie.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Instagrammer Caroline Calloway admitted to using Natalie Beach (opens in a new tab)">Instagrammer Caroline Calloway admitted to using Natalie Beach</a> to create a huge share of her content, without credit or reasonable compensation. More unsavory frauds: Harvey Weinstein, Jeffrey Epstein, Prince Andrew, and the pres&#8230;never mind.</p>
<p>According to Merriam-Webster, fraud is the “intentional perversion of truth in order to induce another to part with something of value or to surrender a legal right.” Fraud and its perpetrators have, unfortunately, been with us longer than memory can stretch. But hey, they make for great storytelling material. In fact, many fairy tale villains are fraudsters. Let&#8217;s explore:</p>
<ul class="rich-text editor-rich-text__editable block-editor-rich-text__editable is-selected" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17037 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735367_1920-182x300.jpg" alt="rapunzel" width="182" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735367_1920-182x300.jpg 182w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735367_1920-622x1024.jpg 622w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735367_1920-768x1264.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735367_1920-934x1536.jpg 934w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/fairytale-1735367_1920.jpg 1167w" sizes="(max-width: 182px) 100vw, 182px" />Rapunzel’s captor is willing to destroy the one she claims to love in order to keep her from moving on. This is a pattern of domestic abuse all too familiar. The witch might be lonely, but she is pathologically controlling, dependent on her “daughter” to the point of denying the young women even an iota of agency. In order to maintain the status quo, she has convinced Rapunzel that she is, indeed, her mother, that the world beyond the tower is a dangerous place, and that only she, the witch-mother, can make her happy. The witch not only misrepresents herself and her intentions, she also recreates the world in her own image.</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Guilty as charged: Mother Gothel</h3>
<ul class="rich-text editor-rich-text__editable block-editor-rich-text__editable is-selected" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li>What do little girls and baby goats have in common? They’re all kids. All kidding aside, Red Riding Hood and the seven little goats had the misfortune to come into contact with a hungry wolf (this guy really gets around). In Red’s story, the wolf impersonated her sweet old grandmother by donning that woman’s gown, cap and glasses. The seven little goats were left at home while their loving mother went out in search of food, saying of the wolf, “If he manages to get into the house, he’ll gobble you up, skin, hair, bones, and all. The old scoundrel often disguises himself, but you won’t have any trouble recognizing him, because he has a gruff voice and black feet.”<sup>1</sup> But the crafty old fraudster used chalk to smooth his voice and the miller’s flour to whiten his feet. He fooled the wee ones and gobbled them up, all but one.</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Guilty as charged: The big bad wolf</h3>
<ul class="rich-text editor-rich-text__editable block-editor-rich-text__editable is-selected" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li>Of course, it’s the nature of all fraudsters to be selfish, but some are so greedy they’re willing to dupe their own flesh and blood. Take the case of Hansel and Gretel’s father and mother, for instance. Like other fairy tale parents, they abandoned their children; but this pair pretended to be concerned for their offspring during two treks deep into the woods, built them a reassuring fire, and promised to return by dusk.</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Guilty as charged: Mr. and Mrs. Woodcutter</h3>
<ul class="rich-text editor-rich-text__editable block-editor-rich-text__editable is-selected" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17038 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vintage-1653147_1920-210x300.jpg" alt="Puss in Boots" width="210" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vintage-1653147_1920-210x300.jpg 210w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vintage-1653147_1920-718x1024.jpg 718w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vintage-1653147_1920-768x1095.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vintage-1653147_1920-1078x1536.jpg 1078w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/vintage-1653147_1920.jpg 1347w" sizes="(max-width: 210px) 100vw, 210px" />Though the advertising industry became a powerful force in the twentieth century, people (and fairy tale characters) have been making false claims forever. One of the clearest cases is that of the wily feline who sold a king a bill of goods in the form of a poor miller&#8217;s youngest son, a simpleton, around whom the cat created a fanciful tale of wealth and good fortune. Thereafter, the king&#8217;s daughter married the boy, whose worldly goods before marriage consisted of nothing more than the cat, a handsome face, and a good temperament.</li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Guilty as charged: Puss in Boots</h3>
<ul class="rich-text editor-rich-text__editable block-editor-rich-text__editable is-selected" role="textbox" aria-label="Write list…">
<li>Ill-gotten gains are at the heart of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/spinning/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="a story that springs from many locations. (opens in a new tab)">a story that springs from many locations.</a></li>
</ul>
<blockquote>What makes &#8220;Rumpelstiltskin&#8221; particularly troubling for those who seek moral guidance for children in fairy tales is the way in which its plot turns on deception and greed. The miller tricks the king into thinking his daughter can spin straw into gold; the miller&#8217;s daughter misleads the king; the king marries because he lusts after gold. Finally, the queen not only dodges the terms of the contract&#8230;but also engages in a cruel game of playing dumb as she rehearses various names&#8230;
<h5> </h5>
<h5>From <em>The Annotated Brothers Grimm</em>, edited by Maria Tatar, 256-257</h5>
</blockquote>
<h3 style="text-align: center;">Guilty as charged: The miller, and the king and queen</h3>

<p>&#8220;Fraud, Part Two&#8221; will explore how the Grimm brothers, and other recorders of our most well known fairy tales, deceived us all. Coming in March, 2020.</p>


<hr class="wp-block-separator" />


<ol>
<li><em>The Annotated Brothers Grimm</em>, edited by Maria Tatar. (W.W. Norton &amp; Company: New York), 31.</li>
</ol>



<ul>
<li>All Images by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/Prawny-162579/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=1735406">Prawny</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=1735406">Pixabay</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mermaids</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/mermaids/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathrin Hagey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 11:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[What's in a Fairy Tale?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thousands of years since the first fish goddess emerged from the primordial human collective unconscious,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16648 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/mermaids-swimming-ship-GraphicsFairy-768x511.jpg" alt="mermaids" width="768" height="511" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/mermaids-swimming-ship-GraphicsFairy-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/mermaids-swimming-ship-GraphicsFairy-768x511-300x200.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></p>
<p>Thousands of years since the first fish goddess emerged from the primordial human collective unconscious, countless women pine to be mermaids. Hans Christian Andersen and Disney merely exploited the contents of this particular Pandora’s box. It is thought that Andersen used the archetype in order to submerge unrequited desires. Disney turned Andersen’s tortured protagonist into a powerless, lovesick girl. Both infantilized what &#8220;&#8230;has traditionally been framed as a &#8216;seductive and impenetrable female representative of the dark and magic underwater world from which our life comes and in which we cannot live&#8217;.&#8221; (From <em>The Annotated Hans Christian Andersen</em> by Maria Tatar)</p>
<p>Though the little mermaid and Ariel continue to strike horror into the hearts of many, they provide some with the fuel to fantasize about <em>actually</em> being a mermaid. (More on that later).</p>
<p>At <em>Luna Station Quarterly,</em> we’ve received plenty of mermaid stories over the years. I had one of my own published in <em><a href="http://www.newfairytales.co.uk/pages/issuesix.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">New Fairy Tales</a></em> eight years ago. My first encounter with a mermaid came via a book passed down to me by my father: <em>The Children’s Hour</em>, edited by Marjorie Barrows. Tom and Elizabeth Orton Jones wrote one of the tales: “Minnie the Mermaid,” first published in 1939. (Elizabeth won the 1945 Caldecott Medal for U.S. picture book illustrations).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16649 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Untitled-design-1-300x300.png" alt="minnie the mermaid" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Untitled-design-1-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Untitled-design-1-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Untitled-design-1-768x768.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Untitled-design-1-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Untitled-design-1.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />The story of a boy named Mick who meets a young mermaid while swimming in the sea, it stood out for me mainly because of Elizabeth Orton Jones’ lovely line drawings of the impish Minnie. As a child, I was struck by Minnie’s nakedness, which both horrified and thrilled me, and her total freedom to swim alone in a vast ocean. She was spunky and had all sorts of games to play and songs to sing, while Mick tried his best to keep up.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cathrinhagey.com/fish/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Fish (opens in a new tab)" data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">Fish</a> symbolize abundance, wealth, creativity, rebirth, transformation, wisdom, sincerity, and more. We may well ask: what <em>don’t</em> they represent? Dagon, the first human-fish chimera and deity of ancient Mesopotamia (circa 2500 BCE), is often portrayed as a fish from the waist down. He was a god of fertility: fish and grain, his purview. In that era, most depictions of human-fish hybrids were of men. The concept of fish-women seems to have burgeoned around 1000 BCE, in Assyria.</p>
<blockquote><p>The goddess Atargatis, mother of Assyrian queen Semiramis, loved a mortal (a shepherd) and unintentionally killed him. Ashamed, she jumped into a lake and took the form of a fish, but the waters would not conceal her divine beauty. Thereafter, she took the form of a mermaid—human above the waist, fish below—although the earliest representations of Atargatis showed her as a fish with a human head and arm, similar to the Babylonian god Ea.<sup>[9]</sup> The Greeks recognized Atargatis under the name Derketo.<sup>[10]</sup> Sometime before 546 BC, Milesian philosopher Anaximander postulated that mankind had sprung from an aquatic animal species. He thought that humans, who begin life with prolonged infancy, could not have survived otherwise. (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mermaid#Etymology" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)" data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mermaid#Etymology</a>)</p></blockquote>
<p>The seas gave birth to all life on earth. In utero, the amnion holds us in its warm, oceanic embrace. Leaving it is usually the first trauma we experience. Thrust as we are into the atmosphere, where light is less filtered and our tiny lungs must cope with deadly gases, is it any wonder that deep inside some of us long for the sea?</p>
<blockquote><p>From earliest times and throughout much of human mythology, the element of water has been viewed as feminine. Beginning with the ﬁrst stories written down in Mesopotamia six thousand years ago, the primal waters were portrayed as goddesses. To the Sumerians, she was Nammu and later Tiamat, from whose body all of earthly creation was formed. Many of the major rivers of Europe and Asia are given the names of female deities. (From <a href="https://parabola.org/2018/10/23/the-rusalki-by-jane-l-mickelson/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="&quot;The Rusalki&quot; by Jane L. Mickelson (opens in a new tab)">&#8220;The Rusalki&#8221; by Jane L. Mickelson</a>)</p></blockquote>
<p>It may be that our connection to the sea, combined with our two-legged insufficiency to meet its demands, is what makes the mermaid archetype so powerful. Having the freedom to course vast oceans under our own strength is a tantalizing prospect for many women. In addition, despite mermaid sensuality, sex and childbirth aren&#8217;t the main aspect of their story. Well-placed seashells and glorious hair be damned, mermaids are independent, assertive, athletic, adventurous, and sociable on their own terms. They are both supremely feminine and hugely powerful. As mermaids heed their own counsel, is it any wonder so many girls and women dream of being one?</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*****</p>
<p>The mermaid fantasy complex is a growing industry. There are real life mermaids, books, websites, spirituality to be reclaimed. Here’s a brief sample:</p>
<p><a href="https://iamamermaid.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="I am a Mermaid (opens in a new tab)" data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">I am a Mermaid</a>: &#8220;A delicate, ladylike blog for mermaids and the humans who love them.&#8221;</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="AFRICAN SPIRITUALITY: The Mami Watas" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v7mc5LfyBDo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Hannah Mermaid swims &amp; ocean animals" width="730" height="548" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/SaZ4wv8VyVM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Nadia Vessey a Real Life MERMAID!" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jnGIvWeM9wQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Forsaken Trailer" width="730" height="548" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mG0q99OvjkU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h5>First Image courtesy of thegraphicsfairy.com<br />
Second Image taken by Cathrin Hagey from <em>The Children&#8217;s Hour (Public Domain)</em></h5>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fox</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fox/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cathrin Hagey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 10:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[What's in a Fairy Tale?]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A mother fox dug under the old barn now used as a storage shed. Some&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-15401" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fox-3707653_1920-300x214.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="214" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fox-3707653_1920-300x214.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fox-3707653_1920-768x548.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fox-3707653_1920-1024x731.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/fox-3707653_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />A mother fox dug under the old barn now used as a storage shed. Some of us think she has eight kits; one person counted nine. She’s raising her little ones beside a well-used path to the arena where riders on horseback pass several times a day. The boldest of the kits sun themselves as we stare, mystified that their mother isn’t threatened by us or our massive, stomping companions. She quietly leads them to the automatic watering bowl of the mini horses, who watch, stupefied, while the red-brown troupe marches past.</p>
<p>She has given me a lot to think about. One thing that comes to mind is the infamous story of an American girl who traveled to Italy and became, by way of the tragic fate of another girl, the pariah of a nation. “Foxy Knoxy,” the seldom used childhood nickname of <a href="http://www.amandaknox.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Amanda Knox (opens in a new tab)">Amanda Knox</a>, was recycled in order to demonize her in the press. I was one of those obsessed with the case for a while. The regular mansplaining of Amanda’s “behavior,” the magnification and analyses of her facial expressions and vocal tones (so reminiscent of the treatment of Lindy Chamberlain, the Australian woman whose infant was taken by a dingo), and the cocksure misogyny of the public discourse surrounding the case all contributed to a personal feeling of loss that I could barely articulate at the time. The Foxy Knoxy headline contributed to an image that was brazen, beautiful, and deadly. It had done its job.</p>
<blockquote>&#8230;foxes in Korean folk tales are not always female, but they are predominantly so, and almost always evil. They are generally seductive creatures that entice unwary scholars and travelers with the lure of their sexuality and the illusion of their beauty and riches. They drain the men of their yang &#8212; their masculine force &#8212; and leave them dissipated or dead&#8230;In Korean the term for fox, &#8220;yowu,&#8221; also refers to a conniving and cunning woman, quite similar to the term &#8220;vixen&#8221; in English, which is not quite as pejorative. Although Americans will use the modifier &#8220;foxy&#8221; to describe an attractive woman, Koreans would only use that term for its negative connotations.
<h5> </h5>
<h5>Heinz Insu Fenkl, <a href="https://endicottstudio.typepad.com/articleslist/fox-wives-and-other-dangerous-women-by-heinz-inzu-fenkl.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">&#8220;Fox Wives and Other Dangerous Women&#8221;</a></h5>
</blockquote>
<p>The Italian press were pejorative as hell. They understood, whether consciously or not, the potential of fox power for good or ill, casting Ms. Knox as both dangerously attractive and conniving&#8211;like a witch.</p>
<blockquote>There is a general belief in witches taking the form of foxes. Witches are said to go out at night as fox souls, do much mischief in this form, and then return to their bodies, which have lain as if dead on their beds meanwhile.
<h5> </h5>
<h5>Marie-Louise von Franz, <em>The Interpretation of Fairy Tales</em></h5>
</blockquote>
<p>In real life, foxes have both doglike and catlike qualities, masculine and feminine aspects, making them perfect archetypal material. Foxes are rarely neutral in fairy tales and folklore; indeed, they appear as tricksters or, more commonly in European and Asian fairy tales, as vampiric characters taking either masculine or feminine form.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.authorama.com/english-fairy-tales-29.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="&quot;Mr. Fox&quot; (opens in a new tab)" data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">&#8220;Mr. Fox&#8221;</a> is an ancient example of one such tale. English in origin, it was collected by Joseph Jacobs and is a kind of anti-tale to &#8220;Bluebeard&#8221; (I urge you to real <a href="https://mrpond47.wordpress.com/2011/03/30/bluebeard-mr-fox-and-harald-silkenhair/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Katherine Langrish’s wonderful article</a> about this). It tells the story of Lady Mary, a young woman who chooses Mr. Fox from among a group of suitors. He appears to her as a wealthy gentlemen with fine manners and a wonderful castle as his dwelling. One day, while Mr. Fox is away and her brothers are otherwise occupied, Lady Mary, driven by curiosity, seeks out and finds the abode of her intended. On the gate is written: <em>Be Bold, Be Bold</em>. Over the doorway she reads: <em>Be Bold, Be Bold, But Not Too Bold</em>. Upon entering the house and mounting the stairs, she comes to a door on which she finds the words: <em>Be Bold, Be Bold, But Not Too Bold, Lest That Your Heart’s Blood Should Run Cold</em>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-15402" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Mister-Fox-202x300.png" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Mister-Fox-202x300.png 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Mister-Fox-768x1142.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Mister-Fox-689x1024.png 689w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Mister-Fox.png 1712w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" />Lady Mary is a cool customer. She enters the room and finds a bloody chamber full of the remains of young ladies. When she tries to leave, Mr. Fox appears in the yard, dragging the body of yet another girl. Lady Mary hides and while she watches, Mr. Fox attempts to remove a ring from the dead girl’s finger. When he can’t do that, he cuts off her hand, which flies into Lady Mary’s lap. When Mr. Fox fails to find the ring, or Lady Mary, the latter rushes home, carrying the evidence of Mr. Fox’s crime. Later, at a supper laid by Lady Mary’s family, she confronts her betrothed with the evidence by telling a story about a dream she had in which he had killed and dismembered a young lady, and when he denies it, producing the hand! Lady Mary’s father and brothers immediately kill the murderer. Mr. Fox is cunning and deadly, but Lady Mary is more than his match.</p>
<p>Heinz Insu Fenkl recounts a tale from Korea (by way of China)&#8211;”The Fox Sister.”</p>
<p>A man with three sons dearly wishes for a daughter, “even if she is a fox.” His wish fulfilled, the baby girl is the darling of all the household. When she is six years old, horror befalls them when one of their cows is killed each and every night. The father sends his eldest son out to keep watch. The young man tells a terrible tale: “It is our little sister who is killing the cattle. She came out in the middle of the night and I followed her to the cattle shed. By the moonlight I could see her as she did a little dance. Then she oiled her hand and her arm with sesame oil. She shoved her whole arm into the cow&#8217;s anus and pulled out its liver. She ate it raw while the cow died without a sound.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-15403" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/moon-4068925_1920-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/moon-4068925_1920-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/moon-4068925_1920-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/moon-4068925_1920-768x767.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/moon-4068925_1920-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/moon-4068925_1920-550x550.jpg 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/moon-4068925_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />The father banishes his son for his lie, and when the cattle slaughter continues, he sends his second son to watch. This young man tells a similar story and is also banished. The third son, keen to remain with his family, declares that the full moon is killing the cows and that his sister is innocent. The delighted father rewards him, declaring, “You shall inherit my lands when I have gone to join our ancestors.”</p>
<p>The two elder brothers wander until they are taken in by a Buddhist master. After years of study, the master tells them their sister is likely a fox demon. He gives them three bottles&#8211;white, blue, and red&#8211;and instructs them on their use. When the brothers finally reach their old home, they find it utterly destroyed. All that remains is their sister. When they attempt to leave, she serves a sumptuous meal, which leaves them lethargic. The eldest awakens in the night to hear his sister chomping on the bones and slurping up the blood of his brother. He flees in terror and the girl gives chase. It is only when he remembers the master’s instructions that he uses the three bottles to finally defeat the fox.</p>
<p>I am in awe of the mother fox under the barn. She is at once familiar and mysterious, coming and going as silently as the breeze. And though her choice of abode seemed foolish to me at first, I now realize it was perfectly sound. The cat is lazy and so there are plenty of mice. Pigeons abound. Horses don’t mind foxes. And the people seem hardwired to admire her, or fear her, depending on the watcher.</p>
<hr />
<p>Some extra Foxy reads:</p>





<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.poetryarchive.org/poem/fox" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="&quot;Fox,&quot; a poem by Adrienne Rich (opens in a new tab)">&#8220;Fox,&#8221; a poem by Adrienne Rich</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.jabberwocky-magazine.com/2011/08/%E2%80%98kitsune%E2%80%99-fox/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">&#8220;&#8216;Kitsune&#8217;, Fox,&#8221; a short story by Brittany Warman</a></li>
<li><a href="http://test.foxsister.com/archive.php" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label=" (opens in a new tab)">&#8220;The Fox Sister,&#8221; a web comic by Christina Strain</a> (currently on hiatus)</li>
</ol>
<ul class="block-editor-rich-text__editable editor-rich-text__editable" role="textbox" data-is-placeholder-visible="false" aria-label="Write list…">
<li><em data-rich-text-format-boundary="true">Fox image by werner22brigitte at Pixabay.com</em></li>
<li><em>Mister Fox image by Joseph Jacobs [Public Domain], via Wikimedia Commons</em></li>
<li><em>Moon image by mikhsan at Pixabay.com</em></li>
</ul>
<hr class="wp-block-separator" />]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
