<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lady Morse Code and the League of Extraordinary Authoresses &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/lady-morse-code-and-the-league-of-extraordinary-authoresses/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:29:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Superblog Issue #6: She&#8217;s a Nonfiction Extraordinary Authoress</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/superblog-issue-6-shes-a-nonfiction-extraordinary-authoress/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jody Morse]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 17:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lady Morse Code and the League of Extraordinary Authoresses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7730</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to the new year, Extraordinary Authoress Leaguers and beloved civilian readers! I,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Hello and welcome to the new year, Extraordinary Authoress Leaguers and beloved civilian readers!</strong></p>
<p>I, Lady Morse Code, thought we might kickoff 2017 with something, or well someone, out of our normal box. Most of the members of the League of Extraordinary Authoresses are fiction writers but there have been a few nonfiction gals to eek their way into the guild over the years. Today’s guest is one of those … a nonfiction writer. Be kind to her please; she’s not used to all this fantastical attention.</p>
<p>May I introduce you to – drumroll – Penelope the Provocateur aka The Great Believer. Yes folks, she’s so out there that her supername has a supername. Love it!<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Penelope-the-Provocateur-photo.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-7733" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/Penelope-the-Provocateur-photo-300x300.jpg" width="249" height="249" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Lady Morse Code: Welcome to the blog world … can I call you PP? No, shouldn’t do that. Um. Maybe Penny? No, makes you sound cheap. How about I go with Provocative Believer? Too long and oddly erotic. Penelope it is! That okay with you?</strong></p>
<p>Penelope the Provocateur/The Great Believer: Lady Morse Code, you may call me whatever you wish. Names are not important to me.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: Then why do you have two supernames and a cover name?</strong></p>
<p>PPGB: Sometimes all cannot be encompassed within the bounds of our mortal understanding.  We are complex creatures needing to embrace simple notions.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: I see. Did you actually answer my question? I’m not quite sure but your lulling tone and velvety voice make me not care. Well played. Moving on. Before we get into our usual rift of questions, I notice that you’re not wearing a costume of any sort. No cape, no mask, no red cowgirl boots. Just slacks, pearls and a fashionable, yet causal blouse and blazer. What’s up with that? </strong></p>
<p>PPGB: I have no need for elaborate costuming or common avenues of superego trickery. To do my work, I have many costumes that I wear so that I may walk among the average citizens undetected.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: Alrighty then. You definitely have the whole Zen, woowoo thing going on. I like it. Just different than my normal interviews with over the top, drama queen, out of this world superwriters. Maybe I&#8217;m just not used to the nonfiction vibe. I&#8217;ll get used to it, I&#8217;m sure. Tell us about your superpowers, Penelope.</strong></p>
<p>PPGB: My power resides in questioning, challenging and blowing up common assumptions. As well as, boiling complex things down into simple distinctions. And, of course, helping people get things they never knew they wanted, faster than they ever thought possible. Making the impossible possible and the possible routine.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: Readers, we’re going to take a quick recess for me to wrap my head around what she just said and decide whether or not those are legit superpowers. Please stand by.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>(4 hours later)</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC: Okay, we’re back and I can officially say that I’m a convert. I’ve seen the light, the error of my ways and will be buying this superwriter’s books today. As well as paying her whatever she wants in order to have tea with me once a week. Who knew I had my priorities and concepts so screwed up?!? Wow! Mind blown. Well, Penelope, I feel like stopping the interview here and writing my eighty-thousand-word memoir in a day but if I do that, my blog editor would have a fit and readers might be disappointed. So, as not to incur the wrath of Cheryl or upset our fans, let’s continue. Do you have a sidekick? </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong>PPGB: Everyone and no one.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: Hell yeah! I knew she’d say something like that. That’s so you, Great Believer. Any weapons or supergadgets?</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong>PPGB: Curiosity, clarity, and acknowledgement. As well as, of course, my portable technology, complete with electronic mail and calendar.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: Again, such a Zennish answer. Stellar! And nobody can live without portable technology these days, so that’s not a weakness on your part, Penelope. No worries. You’re still super beyond understanding and humanity in my mind’s eye. I’m dying for you to tell me, I  mean our readers, about your lair. </strong></p>
<p>PPGB: Because four walls and a physical structure aren’t of utmost importance, Greystone Guides World Headquarters is located in an unassuming 1950’s brick ranch. What is more important are the beings that inhabit a building, like my voracious, people-pleasing rescue bullies.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: Are you telling me that your HQ is guarded by former bullies, like jocks and mean girls? Bullies you’ve converted to your meditative, alternative-thinking ways? </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong>PPGB: No, grasshopper, don’t get ahead of yourself. We rescue <a href="http://www.pbrc.net/">Staffordshire Terriers</a> and give them a forever home.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: Well, that’s not as dramatic as my idea but I like the notion that you give discarded and abandoned dogs a home. That’s sweet and now that I think about it, makes sense. Do you have any female superwriter heroes?</strong></p>
<p>PPGB: Mother of “The Work”, <a href="http://thework.com/en">Byron Katie</a>, and <a href="http://www.danpink.com/">Dan “The Motivator” Pink</a> are never far from the heart of my consciousness.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: I think Dan Pink is a guy, isn’t he? We’re pretty estrogen-focused around here.</strong></p>
<p>PPGB: Oh, my friend, you have so much to learn—as do we all. What is gender, really, other than a way for us to separate ourselves and cause division and strife? Let go of this habitual mind trap you’ve fallen into. What does it matter if Dan is a man or a woman?</p>
<p><strong>LMC: I feel a bit woozy, like when <a href="http://starwars.wikia.com/wiki/Rey">Rey</a> uses the force on her captors. Yes, Penelope, I will let go of this habitual mind trap and move on. Dan’s gender is not important. Whew! That was intense but we need to press on. I seriously doubt you have any but I always ask; archenemies?</strong></p>
<p>PPGB: Assumptions and unquestioned thoughts.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: Ha! Saw that one coming. Zentastic! Do you have a catch phrase? Wait, let me guess. Something like “Bow to the master of your uber-awareness” or “Wake up to the clarity of the moment”?</strong></p>
<p>PPGB: Actually, it’s “Bamaste, the badass in me recognizes the badass in you.”</p>
<p><strong>LMC: What! No way! Just when I was getting a bit over-zenned, you brought me totally back with that badass catch phrase. Penelope, you are truly a wonder of the superwriter world. I don’t even know what to say. I swear I feel like Oprah out under the trees of her ranch during <a href="http://www.supersoul.tv/">Super Soul Sunday</a>. Well, I’ve gushed and had my mind blown enough for a life-time of interviews. How do our readers find you and your books? </strong></p>
<p>PPGB: <a href="http://www.mattisongrey.com/">www.mattisongrey.com</a> as well as, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/mattisongrey?fref=ts">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/MattisonGrey">Twitter</a> under my cover name. Let me say, Lady Morse Code, I have thoroughly enjoyed our time together today. Thank you for inviting me.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: Shut the front door! That’s my line. How did you know I was going to say something like that next? Are you a mind-reader too? Just stop. If my mind blows again, they’re going to have to find another superwriter to run the League and write this blog column. Go. Just go away, I can’t be exposed to your awesomeness any longer. But we are having chai lattes tomorrow morning together, right?  </strong></p>
<p>PPGB: Yes, we will come together again soon. Do not be surprised if my cover writing persona resonates differently than the one you’ve met in this interview. Here, I have let myself venture into superextremes, a somewhat fictionalized version of myself. In my books, some of this must be held back and tempered to stay true to the Work and my faithful readers.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: I understand. I think. Maybe. Who cares? Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Well, folks, I don’t know about you but I’m going to draw myself a hot bath laced with lavender and chamomile and soak  by candlelight for a few hours while I contemplate all the ways I plan to improve myself and my writing. Until next time … I hate to even say it now …</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Up, Up and Cliché!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Lady-Morse-Code-Headshot.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-6867 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Lady-Morse-Code-Headshot-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="265" /></a></strong></p>
<p><strong> * </strong><strong>For more information about Lady Morse Code and the League of Extraordinary Authoresses, check out the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/tag/lady-morse-code/">past five issues</a> or visit Jody&#8217;s cover website <a href="http://www.bountifulbalconybooks.com/">www.bountifulbalconybooks.com</a>. </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Superblog #5: The Queen of Shadows Rages</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/superblog-5-the-queen-of-shadows-rages/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jody Morse]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 17:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lady Morse Code and the League of Extraordinary Authoresses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7592</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello once again, faithful and loyal extraordinary authoresses and league supporters!  Today I, your fearless&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Hello once again, faithful and loyal extraordinary authoresses and league supporters! </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Today I, your fearless leader Lady Morse Code, am a little weary about our interview guest, as I&#8217;m not 100% sure which side of the fence she plays on&#8211;hero or villain. She&#8217;s bit gruff and grumbly, but all in all I think she has a good heart. So, hang in there with us and if you get too bummed or on edge during the interview, take a break to lay in a hammock, sing a happy song or eat something sweet then come back when you&#8217;re ready. Curling up the fetal position to cry is acceptable too. I&#8217;m not saying that&#8217;s what I did after the interview but I might have done something close to that. Okay, without further adieu, take a deep breath because here&#8217;s today&#8217;s guest&#8230;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Queen-of-Shadows-Edited-Headshot.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-7593 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Queen-of-Shadows-Edited-Headshot-225x300.jpg" alt="queen-of-shadows-edited-headshot" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Lady Morse Code: Queen of Shadows, welcome to the League of Extraordinary Authoresses! May I call you Queen or Shadow?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Queen of Shadows: You will address me as Queen of Shadows.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: Well, guess not. That&#8217;s okay. My feelings aren&#8217;t hurt. Alrighty, so Queen of Shadows, do you have a cover name?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: Ceanmohrlass.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: That&#8217;s an unusual name. Would you like to tell us how you came to use either your cover name or your superhero name?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: <em>(silence, she refused to look at me and just stared out the window)</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: Well, this interview isn&#8217;t going so well, is it? Going to be a short one, I&#8217;m afraid. Would you be willing to maybe tell me about your powers?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: What? Are you not from this universe? My superpower is the ability to read the minds of the good, and steal important information. My master plan is to take over every library in the universe! I twist and devour others&#8217; secrets, turning them into multi-genre blockbusters!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: Wow! I&#8217;m not quite sure how to respond to that. I think you were being rude but at least you&#8217;re talking. That&#8217;s progress. Let&#8217;s see if we can keep it going but maybe just a little bit less aggressive. Shall we? Do you have a sidekick, Queen of Shadows?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: I do, her name is Aurora Phoenix and she has the power to control fire and heat <em>(then she whispered).</em> She&#8217;s my daughter-in-law and I absolutely adore her.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: Happy day! How unexpected. That was a lovely answer. I do find it surprising that you have offspring and that they survived to adulthood but that aside, I like this new version of you. Thank you for coming around. Who are some of your favorite female superhero writers and why do you admire them?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: <a href="http://www.pameladaniell.com/">Pamela Daniell</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Michele-Morrell-438547769669768/">Michele Morrell</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/T.M.-Cromer/e/B011QK3WXY">Tara Cromer</a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: A little backslide to a short, clipped answer but that&#8217;s alright. These are fantastic authors, I get why you like them without you having to explain. Tell me about your lair and feel free to elaborate as much as you&#8217;d like. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: In a deep dark forest in Texas. It&#8217;s surrounded by sound waves and hidden behind the cloak of night. Actually, it’s just Magnolia <em>(then she laughed uncontrollably and somewhat hysterically).</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: Oh my. Well, that wasn&#8217;t really elaborate, however, I&#8217;m willing to move on. Are you okay, Queen of Shadows? Good. We&#8217;re almost done, please hang onto your sanity just a little longer. Stay in the light, please, and tell me about your weapons or supergadgets.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: Now if I told you, you would have an advantage over me wouldn’t you &#8230; Queen of Shadows divulges nothing!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: Alright, alright. Sit back. Calm down. We&#8217;re good. We&#8217;re on the same side. I think. Right? Good. Um. Can you describe your supercostume for my readers? That&#8217;s not too personal, is it?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: Be gone with you peasant. Everyone knows of my luscious lavender and teal locks that seize the hearts of men! But my SpongeBob pajamas will do if you must know something. Why should I wear a mask? <em>(she then paused for a long time and appeared to be thinking, channeling an unholy spirit or sleeping with her eyes open, I&#8217;m not sure which)</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: Queen of Shadows? Can we go on? I&#8217;ll take your blood curdling glare as a yes. Do you have a catch phrase?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: I must have my Frappe!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: That&#8217;s unexpected. I guess even those who walk on the weird side need their caffeine to get through long days of writing, especially during NaNoWriMo. Now, this next question might trigger some feelings or pent up frustrations that I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m equipped or willing to deal with but I&#8217;m going to take a risk and ask anyway. Do you have an archnemisis?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: Prince Penguin. Our epic battles of the mind have come close to leveling large cities, and he has always managed to escape me using trickery. Then I go and cry to my son &#8230; he will seek justice for me!</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: Didn&#8217;t see that one coming and still stunned by the fact that you have offspring. Anyway, we&#8217;ll be sure to add Prince Penguin to our enemy log right away. Last question for you today, thank goodness. Should literate citizens want to reach you or learn more about your superwriting, how can they do that?</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">QOS: Only if they dare come hither:  <a href="http://ceanmohrlass.weebly.com/">ceanmohrlass.weebly.com</a>.  Oh, yes, do join me &#8230; <em>(I should divulge that an evil grin spread across her face at this point then she vanished)</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>LMC: Well, I would say thank you to our bizarre guest but she disappeared without so much as an acknowledgement or a goodbye. Guess she was done. A huge thanks to you, our readers and wonderful supporters, for tuning in once again. If you want to know more about me, you can check out the first post of this series&#8211;I interviewed myself, quite well, I must say. And if you would like to be an interview guest on this blog, please leave a comment or send an email to <a href="mailto:Jody@BountifulBalconyBooks.com">Jody@BountifulBalconyBooks.com</a>. Until next month, remember to keep writing and as I always say, &#8220;Up, Up and Cliche!&#8221;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Lady-Morse-Code-Headshot.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-6867 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Lady-Morse-Code-Headshot-225x300.jpg" alt="Lady Morse Code Headshot" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>The League of Extraordinary Authoresses motto: Dots and Dashes Unite, Together we will Write!</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Superblog #4: The Bayou Kraken Reaches Out!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/superblog-4-the-bayou-kraken-reaches-out/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jody Morse]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 16:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lady Morse Code and the League of Extraordinary Authoresses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back, SuperReaders! ************************************************************************************ As always, I am your ever-so-humble SuperHostess, Lady Morse Code, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Welcome back, SuperReaders!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">************************************************************************************</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">As always, I am your ever-so-humble SuperHostess, Lady Morse Code, and this is the League of Extraordinary Authoresses interview series. Today we have a tentacled, top hat-wearing SuperWriter to introduce you to&#8230;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Bayou-Kraken.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7436 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Bayou-Kraken-300x225.jpg" alt="bayou-kraken" width="300" height="225" /></a>The Bayou Kraken!!!!!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">So, we&#8217;re just going to jump right into the murky waters of this interview.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">LMC: Welcome, Bayou Kraken! I&#8217;ve been such a huge fangirl since you rescued me from drowning during that kayaking trip through the underbelly of downtown Houston.  Who knew that my cowgirl boots weighed so much when filled with water?!? So, let me start with a public thank you.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">BK: You&#8217;re most welcome, Lady Morse Code. Anyone with tentacles would have done the same.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">LMC: Yes, true. Normally we start with a different line of questioning but since you brought them up. Tell us more about your tentacles.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">BK: Tentacles are amazing things! I&#8217;m able to write poetry, fiction, and non-fiction all at once, participate in multiple critique groups, and take a wide variety of workshops at <a href="http://www.writespacehouston.org/">Writespace</a> Houston, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/grackleandgrackle/">Grackle and Grackle</a>, and <a href="http://inprinthouston.org/">Inprint</a>! Now I’m working on pulling time out of thin air and actually getting projects done, but you know, I’m running out of tentacles.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">LMC: How exciting! I&#8217;m so jealous! In addition to your extra limbs, I also love your top hat, humidity-resistant goggles and bullet-proof corset that protects you from rejections and excuses for not writing! Such an amazing look! Okay, enough fawning over your getup. Let&#8217;s move on. Give me the scoop on your sidekicks and superwriting heroes.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">BK: Well, as for sidekicks, there are two small, white dogs that follow me around on adventures on the bayous. But mostly they lounge around and look cute while I write. Cuteness is a powerful weapon they brandish mercilessly. As for heroes, I&#8217;d have to say the Woman of the Earth Sea, aka <a href="http://www.ursulakleguin.com/">Ursela Le Guin</a>, and the Queen of Avalon, aka <a href="http://www.mzbworks.com/">Marion Zimmer Bradley</a> are top picks for me.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">LMC: Oh, speaking of cover names, I haven&#8217;t even asked yours yet! So, tell us what your cover name is, please.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">BK: Jennifer Stephan Kapral. Catchy, huh?</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">LMC: It is! Almost as catchy as your catch-phrase&#8211;Release the inner editor! I love when you finish a rough draft and shout it full voice and it echoes through the tunnels and water pipes. So fun! I bet the readers are all going to start using your phrase to inspire their own inner editor. Love it! Tell us about your lair.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">BK: <span style="font-weight: 400;">I lurk underneath the bayous of Houston, favoring the cloak of the murky waters. If anyone possesses a threat to my lair, a swarm of blood-thirsty fairies (aka mosquitoes) drives them away. For friends, a bayou mermaid welcomes them with fresh caught fish (jaw to table) and the friendly neighborhood alligator makes frozen margaritas, pre-crushing the ice with his teeth to give it a mouth-crafted touch. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">LMC: Party at the bayou this weekend! Sounds like a super fun place. Hey, what about super gadgets&#8211;do you have any?</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">BK: <span style="font-weight: 400;">I have a finely tuned sensing device that locates exactly where a story </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">should</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> start (hint: it’s not where you started it). I also have a Super Special Pen filled with Kraken Ink (not mine, don’t be silly!) that allows me to rewrite the opening sentence of a story over and over and over until it pops out of the page and grabs hold of the reader. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">LMC: Can I borrow your super-story-starting sense? That is something I surely struggle with! Well, sadly, it&#8217;s about time for us to wrap up. My fingers are getting pruney and I think there might be a leech in my boot. I love you but this bayou life is &#8230; never mind. How can the literate citizens of the world reach you, if they need you?</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">BK: <span style="font-weight: 400;">They can find me on a run, bike ride, or kayak trip down the bayou (just ignore the white plastic bags and random pieces of furniture), look at my past musings about Houston at </span><a href="http://lifeinsidetheloop.blogspot.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">http://lifeinsidetheloop.blogspot.com/</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and follow me on twitter at <a href="https://twitter.com/BayouKraken">@bayoukraken</a>. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;">LMC: Thank you so much for being with us today, Bayou Kraken, and I can&#8217;t wait to pop down to your lair for a murky, mermaid-served margarita! Until next time, this is Lady Morse Code signing off. Dots and dashes unite, forever we will write!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Lady-Morse-Code-Headshot.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6867" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Lady-Morse-Code-Headshot-225x300.jpg" alt="Lady Morse Code Headshot" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<ul>
<li style="text-align: left;">If you&#8217;re new to Lady Morse Code&#8217;s superblog, check out issues #1-3 here at Luna Station Quarterly.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Superblog #3: Introducing Harley &#8220;I Told You So&#8221; Harbinger</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/superblog-3-introducing-harley-i-told-you-so-harbinger/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jody Morse]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 16:31:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lady Morse Code and the League of Extraordinary Authoresses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Superwriters unite! ********************************************************************************************* &#160; We&#8217;re back for another gathering of the League of Extraordinary Authoresses&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Superwriters unite!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">*********************************************************************************************</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Harley-Harbinger.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7323 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Harley-Harbinger-262x300.jpg" alt="harley-harbinger" width="262" height="300" /></a>We&#8217;re back for another gathering of the League of Extraordinary Authoresses with me, Lady Morse Code, and today we have a stellar guest! (If she behaves herself.) No need to beat around the bush, tree or Batmobile today. I&#8217;m ready to jump straight into the interview! How about you? Let&#8217;s do this!</p>
<p>Oh, one note. Getting together in person wasn&#8217;t such a good idea, since Harley and I tend to rub one another the wrong way. We&#8217;re friends but more of the long distance variety and with the restraining order&#8230;</p>
<p>Anywho. So, we&#8217;ll be conducting today&#8217;s interview via SuperType &#8211; the superhero version of Skype instant messaging. Enjoy!</p>
<p><strong>Lady Morse Code:</strong> For the record, please state your name.</p>
<p><strong>Harley Harbinger:</strong> Seriously? For whose record? Morse Code, are you messing with me?</p>
<p><strong>LMC:</strong> Calm down, Harley. This is merely a formality. Just play along. Amuse me. Please.</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Fine. My name is Harley Harbinger. Happy?</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Yes. Very. Thank you. What an unusual superhero name, how did you come up with it?</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>I thought about it. Really? Is this how all of the questions are going to be? I&#8217;m outta here.</p>
<p><strong>LMC:</strong> No, Harley. Don&#8217;t forget, you owe me! Get your cape out of a wad. We&#8217;ll move on. How about your cover name?</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Are you seriously still on the name game? <a href="http://www.hlwalrath.com/">Holly Lyn Walrath</a>. That&#8217;s my cover. Okay?</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Yes, I am okay but you might need a chill pill, Har.</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Don&#8217;t call me &#8220;Har&#8221;. Sorry, I can&#8217;t help the way I am. When you have a backstory like mine, life&#8217;s tough. Yes, that may be cliche but it&#8217;s true. I&#8217;ll try to calm down and be polite. I do owe you for the only time Dr. Deadline has ever cornered me. You had to be the one to come along, didn&#8217;t you? Alright. Go on with your stupid questions, Morsey.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Thank you. And we&#8217;ll discuss you calling me &#8220;Morsey&#8221; later. What are your superpowers?</p>
<p><strong>HH:</strong> As a Harbinger, my superpower is foretelling the future. I trap my victims with logic like the great Spock, except my logic calculates the possibilities of disaster. Much like the Cassandra of Greek mythology, I see a bad idea coming from a mile away. This superpower is super-helpful in writing because it allows me to immediately tell when a story is going sideways. However, I am also cursed by my power, as no one ever seems to listen. Particularly my cover husband.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: T</strong>hank you for more of a full and straightforward answer lacking hostility, sort of. I would have never guessed that getting people to listen to you would be your superweakness. Maybe your hubby and I should grab a drink sometime and chat about this quality of yours further.</p>
<p><strong>HH:</strong> What did you say about my husband?</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Nothing. Never mind. Moving on. Do you have a sidekick you&#8217;d like to tell us about?</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Who&#8217;s &#8220;us&#8221;? Oh, wait, your silly, little readers. That&#8217;s right, I forgot. Yeah. So, sidekick. My sidekick is Cutting Cleo the Cunning Cat, whose superpower is purring. And cuddles. And distracting writers during writing so they don’t take themselves too serio—HEY STOP STEPPING ON THE KEYBOARD#072@$ad;9@&amp;DFAJ08%CVslk df&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Harley! This is a PG-rated blog. Didn&#8217;t I tell you to go to a room by yourself for the interview?</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Who are you? My mother. Hang on, I&#8217;ll put Cleo out.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Thank you, Harley.</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Reluctantly, I&#8217;m back. What&#8217;s your next lame question?</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Female superwriting heroes. Who&#8217;re yours?</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>All joking aside, there are so many great female writing heroines I admire! Angel Catbird (aka <a href="http://margaretatwood.ca/">Margaret Atwood</a>) is one of my favorites. She’s got a keen eye, a killer prose style, and a wit sharp enough to impale the lowliest troll. Sergeant Samatar (aka <a href="http://www.sofiasamatar.com/">Sofia Samatar</a>) is another superheroine who is an expert at multi-genre mythos, writing across poetry, short stories, and novels. Plus her hair is basically fabulous. And those boots!</p>
<p><strong>LMC:</strong> Harley Harbinger! I have never known this side of you. Fangirling and using the phrase &#8220;basically fabulous&#8221;!?! Folks, you read it here first &#8211; Harley Harbinger is out of the fangirl closet! On my blog column! Even if you did get Margaret Atwood&#8217;s superwriter name wrong. She&#8217;s just The Catbird. Star Phantom mentioned her<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/superblog2-meet-star-phantom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> last episode</a>.</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Wait. What? Erase! Delete! Where&#8217;s the damn undo button? I wasn&#8217;t fangirling. I hate the Sarge&#8217;s boots. They&#8217;re atrocious! Fashion is lame. Plus, what does SP know about Angel Catbird?</p>
<p><strong>LMC:</strong> I&#8217;m guessing you have a fabulous relationship with Star Phantom too. Hard to be the rebel of the superwriter world, isn&#8217;t it? That&#8217;s what you get for writing all that creepy, poetic stuff. Nobody gets you, Har.</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Lots of highly intelligent readers love my work. It just goes over your head, Morsey. Are we done yet?</p>
<p><strong>LMC:</strong> No, we&#8217;re not. Next topic: your lair. Tell us about where you&#8217;re SuperTyping from right now.</p>
<p><strong>HH:</strong> My secret lair is hidden in the salt-soaked Gulf Coast of Texas, just five minutes from NASA. They’ve called me in for many a secret mission to communicate with aliens. In fact, there was this one time they brought an alien back to earth and we had a long conversation regarding the future of their species over a pint of suds at the local pub. I told him, her, whatever that it was a bad idea to come to earth, but did they listen? Well, I shouldn’t say more, but let’s just say there’s a coffee shop at the end of the galaxy that went missing last year and I don’t want to say I told you so but I TOLD YOU SO.</p>
<p>Anyway I probably shouldn’t tell you and your readers more about my secret lair because the aliens might be on to us. Let’s just say there are plenty of squishy couches and a lot of lemon tea here.</p>
<p><strong>LMC:</strong> Again, shock and awe from the Morse Gallery! I believe you about telling off an alien&#8211;sounds like you&#8211;but squishy couches and lemon tea. Would never have guessed. Honestly. Never.</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Shut up, Morsey! Whatever works, right? Maybe frolicking around to disco music with your hummingbirds and Chai Lattes works for you but for me it&#8217;s layin&#8217; around on my sofas and sipping lemon tea with my cat. So what?</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>You&#8217;re right, Har. We shouldn&#8217;t let our differences divide us. We should support one another, as superheros, women, and writers by celebrating our unique qualities. Even if they are squishy lemons and boot fetishes (laughter, lots of laughter).</p>
<p><strong>HH:</strong> That&#8217;s it, Morse! I&#8217;m done. Debt paid. I need more tea!</p>
<p><strong>LMC:</strong> I&#8217;m sorry, Harley. No. I&#8217;m done teasing you. Only a few more questions. Please?</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Fine. But hurry it up. I&#8217;ve got to feed Cleo.</p>
<p><strong>LMC:</strong> Of course. Weapons or supergadgets. Have any?</p>
<p><strong>HH:</strong> Okay I shouldn’t mention this but between friends&#8211;did you catch the dripping sarcasm in that word, Morsey?&#8211;my super-secret weapon is my Quill of Invisibility. It’s invisible, but if you could see it you’d see that it’s beautiful, topped with a phoenix tail feather. Anything you write with it comes out perfect, error-free, and immediately published at a top-tier journal. Now if I could just remember where I left it . . .</p>
<p><strong>LMC:</strong> If I had to guess, I&#8217;d say Cleo, your deaf cover husband or the aliens took it. I do have to admit that your writing is pretty super. Quill of Invisibility would explain your seeming abilities. Not that I&#8217;m saying I don&#8217;t think&#8230;never mind. Hurrying along! Next question. How do the literate citizens of the world reach you?</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>NASA just installed a truth-beacon over my house so anytime the people of the galaxy need me they can just push a button and I’ll come running, ready to give them writing and editing advice, or sometimes even relationship advice for lonely Martians. Or, if it’s a cloudy night, you can hit me up at <a href="http://www.hlwalrath.com/">www.hlwalrath.com</a> or @hollylynwalrath.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Relationship advice to lonely Martians. Have to keep that in mind. Being the fashion maven that I&#8217;ve learned you are, tell us about your costume.</p>
<p><strong>HH: </strong>Well, first off, I wouldn&#8217;t call it a costume. That&#8217;s lame. But, if you must know, I wear a black cape, black mask, and nerdy t-shirt paired with blue jeans. They’re terribly comfortable and practical for fighting the evils of the future-tense. I’ve also been known to don a bit of truth serum. It makes a beautiful perfume &#8211; smells like chocolate, which very few villains seem to realize. I also carry binoculars so I can spot a problem passage a mile away.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>I like the binoculars idea, I never understand your t-shirts but that&#8217;s okay. Variety is the spice of the superlife. Right? Superwriter catch phrase or motto, do you have one?</p>
<p><strong>HH:</strong> I don’t like to say “I told you so” because that’s just rude but I have been heard to mutter, “That’s a horrible idea, don’t go upstairs!” during horror movies and in the midst of editing manuscripts.</p>
<p><strong>LMC:</strong> You? Judgey or rude? I just can&#8217;t envision that. No surprised look on this face right now (wink, wink). With phrases like that, I&#8217;m sure you don&#8217;t have an arch nemesis but I have to ask, do you have an arch nemesis, Harley?</p>
<p><strong>HH:</strong> My arch nemesis is the one and only, ever-present DPV &#8211; Dreaded Passive Voice. It had been everywhere and then I was meaning to delete it but it had been cropping up again and then I had been thinking of how to destroy it but there it was again, in everyone’s writing. . . There it was again! Curse you Dreaded Passive Voice!</p>
<p>The only way to fight passive voice is with the power of verbs. I load them up in my quill of invisibility and splat! Bam! Boom! Passive voice cowers before them!</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Wow, Harley, I love you like this! Getting all worked up over the DPV! Wow! Unexpected. On that note, I think we should end the interview. You might need a cold shower or another cup of tea. So, on behalf of the League of Extraordinary Authoresses, thank you to our guest, Harley Harbinger. I&#8217;m Lady Morse Code and we&#8217;ll be back next month with another edition of our Superblog. Our next interviewee is the amazing Bayou Kraken! You won&#8217;t want to miss her &#8211; she has tentacles!</p>
<p>For past interviews, visit <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/columns/">https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/columns/</a> and search for &#8220;Lady Morse Code&#8221;.</p>
<p>Until next time&#8230;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>&#8220;Dots and Dashes Unite, Together We Will Write!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Lady Morse Code and the League of Extraordinary Authoresses</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Lady-Morse-Code-Headshot.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6867" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Lady-Morse-Code-Headshot-225x300.jpg" alt="Lady Morse Code Headshot" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Superblog#2: Meet Star Phantom</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/superblog2-meet-star-phantom/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/superblog2-meet-star-phantom/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jody Morse]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 15:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lady Morse Code and the League of Extraordinary Authoresses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back fans of female superhero writers! ************************************************************************************************** If this is your first time to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Welcome back fans of female superhero writers!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>**************************************************************************************************</strong></p>
<p>If this is your first time to visit the League Of Extraordinary Authoresses, have no fear! You can go back to visit the first issue by following the link at the bottom of this post or just start by reading this one. No backstory or prologue really needed. I’m Lady Morse Code and I showcase the members of my League here at Luna Station Quarterly. That pretty much sums it up.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Star-Phantom-1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6983 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Star-Phantom-1.jpg" alt="Star Phantom" width="295" height="274" /></a>So, without further delay, let’s meet today’s featured split infinitive slaying femme fatale…</p>
<p>Whose cover name happens to be <a href="http://www.cassandraroseclarke.com/">Cassandra Rose Clarke</a>, but don’t tell her arch nemesis.</p>
<p>That’s one of the rules of the League. No revealing our covers to our enemies.</p>
<p>Now on with the interview!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>****************************</strong></p>
<p><strong>Lady Morse Code: </strong>Welcome to my bountiful balcony lair, Star Phantom. Oh, and don’ t mind the hummingbirds, they won’t attack unless I sing a high C. Which I won’t. But they do occasionally get tangled in long hair, so you might want to ponytail up. Great. That settled, on to superhero business. Tell us about your main superpower.</p>
<p><strong>Star Phantom: </strong>I can cross between the different universes that comprise the multiverse. A cool side effect of this is that I can make myself invisible to the people in one universe while still being able to observe what’s happening around me.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>That is amazing, Star! Can I call you Star? Good. Okay, what about a sidekick? Do you have one?</p>
<p><strong>SP: </strong>Yes. He’s a sentient black cat who accompanies me on all of my adventures. He used to be a king in another universe (which is represented in our universe by a popular fantasy book series and TV show), but when he died he became a cat in our world. His name is Robert Barcatheon.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Robert Barcatheon!?! Fascinating and clever! Oh, I wish you had brought him with you today! Although he might have gotten hungry and decided to eat one of my hummers, maybe best that he didn’t come. Could you name drop a bit and tell us who a couple of your female superwriter heroes might be?</p>
<p><strong>SP: </strong><a href="http://margaretatwood.ca/">Margaret Atwood</a>, also known as The Catbird, and <a href="http://kellylink.net/">Kelly Link</a>, aka Fusion Lass.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>One of my all-time favorite quotes from The Catbird is “A word after a word after a word is power.” Any mention of power, super or not, gets me going! Words are super powerful. Am I right? Of course, I am. Moving on. Back to you, Star. Tell me about your lair.</p>
<p><strong>SP: </strong>Located in the heart of the Pacific Northwest, my lair is a secret underground cavern filled with soft lighting, espresso steam, and tasteful wooden interiors. I call it the Star Cave. There are entrances everywhere, across all the universes in the multiverse. Plus, it’s warm in the winter and cool in the summer, and I never run out of snacks and caffeine to fuel my missions.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>I hear you about the snacks and caffeine! Don’t get me started about popcorn, almonds and Sparkling Chai Lattes. Do you have any weapons or supergadgets?</p>
<p><strong>SP: </strong>All I need to cross dimensions is a trusty Pilot Precise rolling ball pen, with a super-fine point and black ink. The super-fine point allows me to rip holes in the fabric of space-time and cross over in a flash!</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Write me jealous! I’m going to have to get a pen like that! Wow! Okay, well, tell the literate citizens of the world how they can reach you, if in need of your superediting or superwriting skills.</p>
<p><strong>SP: </strong>I stole Batman’s Bat-signal from the DC universe and brought it here for this exact purpose! Or, if they are uncomfortable shining a giant ill-gotten bat symbol into the night sky, they can visit my cover identity’s website at <a href="http://www.cassandraroseclarke.com/">www.cassandraroseclarke.com</a>, go to the “Bio and Contact” page, and choose their preferred method of contact.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>You stole Batman’s Bat-signal?!? How brilliant and on-the-verge-of-evil of you! Star Phantom, you are full of surprises! Since this is a written blog, not video, we will post your head shot but tell the readers what you’re wearing today. I’m assuming this is your crime fighting costume.</p>
<p><strong>SP: </strong>Yes. I’m wearing a black cocktail dress stitched with sparkling jewels to look like the night sky, black boots, black gloves, and a veiled fascinator &#8211; to hide my identity.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>Well, of course, there’s no reason to hide your identity from me but I love the look! Sexy and universe-bendingly mysterious. Perfection! Alright, well we’re almost done. One last question. Star, do you have a superwriter catch phrase or symbol?</p>
<p><strong>SP: </strong>Whenever I catch a bad guy, I give them a starlight kiss as my calling card.</p>
<p><strong>LMC: </strong>What?!!? A starlight kiss. Makes my dots and dashes seem kind of lame. But, this isn’t a competition. And it is <em>my</em> blog, so no reason to get jealous. Right? Right. Well, Star Phantom, it has been a pleasure getting to know you better and introducing you to our LOEA readers. Thank you for coming and happy multiverse travels. Until we meet again…Up, up, and cliché!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>****************************</strong></p>
<p>If you would like more information about Lady Morse Code, her main cover name is Jody T. Morse and you can visit her site below.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bountifulbalconybooks.com/">http://www.bountifulbalconybooks.com/</a></p>
<p>Don’t forget to check out Star Phantom’s cover site, as well…</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cassandraroseclarke.com/">www.cassandraroseclarke.com</a></p>
<p>And if you’d like to become a member of the League of Extraordinary Authoresses and be interviewed by Lady Morse Code, please send her a message through her cover site or email <a href="mailto:Jody@BountifulBalconyBooks.com">Jody@BountifulBalconyBooks.com</a> with the subject line “League Member Interview”.</p>
<p>Thanks for tuning in and be sure to check back next month when LMC will be interviewing a superhero of speculative fiction prowess with superwriter powers beyond measure. She’s recently compiled and edited an anthology from the in-between, visits her favorite Black Hole on a regular basis and has been a crucial help in getting Lady Morse Code’s fiction-writing butt in gear. That’s all we’re leaking. You’ll have to come back to see us next month to learn who she is.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>**************************************************************************************************</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>“Dots and Dashes Unite, Together We Will Write!”</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>**************************************************************************************************</strong></p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="tKEDKfnHKu"><p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/superissue-1-meet-lady-morse-code/">Superissue #1: Meet Lady Morse Code!</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;Superissue #1: Meet Lady Morse Code!&#8221; &#8212; Luna Station Quarterly" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/superissue-1-meet-lady-morse-code/embed/#?secret=M0vybrAS1Z#?secret=tKEDKfnHKu" data-secret="tKEDKfnHKu" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/superblog2-meet-star-phantom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Superissue #1: Meet Lady Morse Code!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/superissue-1-meet-lady-morse-code/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/superissue-1-meet-lady-morse-code/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jody Morse]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 15:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lady Morse Code and the League of Extraordinary Authoresses]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a world where superheroes are scarce, Luna Station Quarterly brings you, the one, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">In a world where superheroes are scarce,</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> brings you, the one, the only&#8230;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Lady Morse Code!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">******************************************************************************************************</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Hello literate citizens of the world, I am Lady Morse Code. Welcome to my Superblog!</p>
<p>In this blog series of heroic proportions, I&#8217;ll be introducing you to the amazing members of my League of Extraordinary Authoresses &#8211; one in each illustrious issue. These transmissions could potentially get hijacked by a villain or arch nemesis but the plan is for us to focus on women who write for the liberty and justice of all writers. Only time will tell how well our defenses will hold.</p>
<p>In this initial edition, I&#8217;d like to introduce myself, if that&#8217;s not too presumptive.</p>
<p>As I will be the interviewer and the interviewee, I will mark the questions I ask with <em>LMC#1</em> and the answers with <strong>LMC#1.5</strong>. (I couldn&#8217;t seem to label myself #2. Superflaw, I guess.)</p>
<p>On with the interview!</p>
<p><em>LMC#1: Lady Morse Code, tell me about your names. What is your superhero name and what is the cover name you go by when trying to blend into the milieu? </em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Well, you just addressed me by my superhero name so the question is rather moot. I&#8217;m Lady Morse Code, of course. My main covers are Jody T. Morse, Jody Townsley Morse and J.T. Morse but I also answer to Mommy, Macushla (my cover husband&#8217;s nickname for me) and Hey Lady In The Red Cowboy Boots.</strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1: That&#8217;s a lot of cover names. Why so many?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Oh, young lady, because I&#8217;m so multi-genre. Plus, I&#8217;m too much superwriter for just one cover name, so I have given myself many to choose from. All the super-authoresses are doing it these days.</strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1:</em> <em>Ah, I see. Thank you for the compliment to my age. Moving on.</em> <em>What are your superpowers?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Echo Vision, which entails being able to see annoying echoed words and phrases in other people&#8217;s writing, and the power of Multi-Genre Mythos. That&#8217;s what we, superwriters call the ability to not allow critics and naysayers to box us in to one genre, M-GM. A power worth invoking, if you can handle it. Honestly, I&#8217;m so multi-genre that I&#8217;m all over the place!</strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1:</em> <em>Yes. I&#8217;d definitely agree with that last statement. You are all over the place. Can you find echoes in your own writing as well as in the writings of others?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Of course not! That would be something akin to a super-super power. Unheard of! </strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1: Sorry to offend, your Superness. I&#8217;m guessing you&#8217;re not a friend of the self-editing mastermind known as Editina Selforo.</em> <em>How sad for you. Speaking of Editina, she has a lovely sidekick named Proofreading Penny,</em> <em>do you have a sidekick or superpartner?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Not yet but I hope to someday. Would you like to audition for the role? I think we&#8217;d be great together. Honestly, with my good looks and your writing abilities, we could take over the world.</strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1:</em> <em>Um, I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s possible to be your own sidekick. Let&#8217;s discuss that later and in private. Question number five: who are a few of your female superwriting heroes?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Oh, I have so many. Let&#8217;s see. There&#8217;s the Magical Moss Maven, aka <a href="http://www.elizabethgilbert.com/">Elizabeth Gilbert</a>; the Divergent Diva, cover name <a href="http://theartofnotwriting.tumblr.com/">Veronica Roth</a>; and the never-to-go-hungry-again superwriter who publishes as <a href="http://www.suzannecollinsbooks.com/http://www.suzannecollinsbooks.com/">Suzanne Collins</a>.</strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1:</em> <em>How funny! I love all of those super-authoresses too! Maybe we&#8217;re not so different after all. Tell me about your secret lair, Lady Morse Code.</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: OMC! The Bountiful Balcony is such an amazing place, if I do say so myself! Hidden in the Piney Woods of Texas, the BB is raised over 10 feet in the air and guarded by my flock of totes adorable hummingbirds and flesh-eating foliage. </strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1:</em> <em>What is OMC?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Oh My Code, of course!</strong></p>
<p>LMC#1: <em>Right. Makes sense. Don&#8217;t know how I missed that one. Are hummingbirds scary enough to thwart invaders? And where did you find flesh-eating foliage this time of year?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Who said I use the birds to thwart invaders? I just think they&#8217;re so cute and they come when I sing for them in a shrill upper register. As for the plants, I bought them online and they really only eat the flesh of flies and mosquitoes. But that&#8217;s scary, right?</strong></p>
<p>LMC#1: <em>Well, maybe. Are they, by any chance, Venus fly traps ordered from the educational children&#8217;s section of Amazon.com? If so, then not scary at all. Sorry. </em></p>
<p><strong>(LMC#1.5 is unable to speak, due to being overcome by emotion. She closes her eyes, shakes her head, and purses her lips tightly before releasing a supersigh.)</strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1: Let&#8217;s take a break for a message from our sponsors while Lady Morse Code collects herself. Wait, I just remembered that we have no sponsors. Right. Then I guess were back to the questions. </em><em>Do you have any special weapons or gadgets you use when fighting the evils of the dreaded Dr. Deadline, the ever-mocking Writers Block or the pesky Procrastination Prankster?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Of course! I have a supersonic alarm that tells me when Dr. Deadline is approaching, a laptop disguised as a book about ancient Greece and a Morse Code decoder ring that I found in a cereal box.</strong></p>
<p>LMC#1: <em>Is the alarm just an app on your smart phone, by any chance?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Um, yes, it is. But the ringtone is extra super. Wanna hear? </strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1: No. No, I don&#8217;t.</em> <em>I&#8217;m not superimpressed right now. That said, how do the literate citizens of the world reach you when they might be in need of your superservices?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: They SOS me with a flashlight or write three dots, three dashes then three more dots on a building, paper or any other flat surface. Or, of course, they can always visit my cover site </strong><a href="http://www.bountifulbalconybooks.com/"><strong>www.bountifulbalconybooks.com</strong></a><strong> and send me an SOS message there.</strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1:</em> <em>Excellent answer, Lady Morse Code! You&#8217;ve turned the tides. I enjoyed how you slid that discreet and shameless self-plug into the interview. I would actually deem that move to be supersmart. Good job. Could you describe your superwriter costume for our readers?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Yes. I wear a black mask donned with the letters L-M-C, as well as, the dots and dashes for Superhero. Also, I have a pair of black silk PJs, red cowgirl boots, and a red cape covered in black dots and dashes.</strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1:</em> <em>Silk PJs?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Yes, I find the standard superhero bodysuit-leotard thingy way too constricting and crotch pinching. Plus, I do my most productive writing in my jammies. Seemed like as good of a costume as any. Roll out of bed and straight to writing and/or crime fighting. Oh, did I mention the fake beauty mark I wear over the left side of my lip?</strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1:</em> <em>No, no you didn&#8217;t. And I wish you wouldn&#8217;t have. Yes, folks, now I am shaking my head in shame. Thank goodness we have come to our last question. Do you have a superwriter catch phrase or symbol?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: Well, the League&#8217;s motto is &#8216;Dots and Dashes Unite, Forever We Will Write&#8217;. But my personal signature is leaving a series of random dots and dashes in red permanent marker on evil doer&#8217;s foreheads.</strong></p>
<p>LMC#1: <em>Why random? Wouldn&#8217;t it be more meaningful if the code spelled out something?</em></p>
<p><strong>LMC#1.5: No! I don&#8217;t want to be a comic book cliche&#8217;. How lame and expected! Honestly, who do you think you are interviewing here?</strong></p>
<p><em>LMC#1:</em> <em>Myself. That&#8217;s part of the problem.</em> <em>Well, thank you, Lady Morse Code, for this not-my-best-but-not-my-worst interview ever. I&#8217;ll be going back to your subconscious now. Thank you to our readers for reading and, until next time, keep putting your superwriter powers to good use. Up, up and cliche&#8217;!</em></p>
<p>Tune in next time for an adventurous interview with an actual writing superhero who pens under the cover name <a href="http://www.cassandraroseclarke.com/">Cassandra Rose Clarke</a>. Find out what writing superpowers she wields and how she feels about Lycra bodysuits.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;d like to join the League of Extraordinary Authoresses, get in touch with Lady Morse Code via her cover site <a href="http://www.bountifulbalconybooks.com/">www.bountifulbalconybooks.com</a></p>
<p>Thanks for visiting the Luna Station Quarterly and well be back with Superissue #2 soon. I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ll be waiting on dots and dashes.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Lady-Morse-Code-Headshot.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="center-image aligncenter wp-image-6867 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Lady-Morse-Code-Headshot-225x300.jpg" alt="Lady Morse Code Headshot" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/superissue-1-meet-lady-morse-code/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
