<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>On the Books &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/on-the-books/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 04:29:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Permissions and Your Publisher</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/permissions-and-your-publisher/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 12:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anyone who has signed—or considered signing—a publishing contract has probably come one or more clauses&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anyone who has signed—or considered signing—a publishing contract has probably come one or more clauses about obtaining permission for the use of other people’s work. These are pretty standard publishing contract provisions, and I’ve written about <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/when-to-pay-for-copyright-permissions/">permissions in this column previously</a>, largely with respect to how to obtain permissions to use other people’s photographs and artwork.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28985 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />As I’ve had several questions about permissions lately, and, in particular, how permissions clauses in publishing contracts operate in practice, I thought it would be worth setting out some basics. Of course, my usual disclaimer applies: nothing in this column is intended as formal legal advice and if you are facing a legal question about permissions it may be worth consulting an agent, attorney, or other expert.</p>
<p>Important issues to consider when entering into a publishing contract for a project where you intend to copy/quote other people’s work is to think about:</p>
<ul>
<li>what work you want to use (text, images, art, photographs);</li>
<li>who holds the copyright (if anyone) in that work; and,</li>
<li>how difficult it would be to obtain/afford permission from the copyright holder(s) for your proposed use.</li>
</ul>
<p>Bear in mind that more than one person can hold copyright in the same work: for example, co-authors of a book or song lyric you want to quote may jointly hold copyright. Even copyrights in images and photographs can be jointly held if the image in question is the product of a collaboration between two or more creators. It is important to obtain permission from all the copyright holders if you want to use a copyrighted work in your own project.</p>
<p>I should also note that I’m confining my discussion here to situations where permission is required, either because your proposed use of the work is not a fair use, or where the publisher insists on a record of permission being granted regardless of whether the use is a fair use or not. If you’re interested in learning more about fair use, I’ve written about it <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/fair-use-101/">here</a>.</p>
<p>Publishers tend to be risk averse and frequently want to ask you to obtain permission for most copyrighted material you plan to re-use in your own work. As noted above, there may be several clauses in your contract about permissions, one of which is likely to be in the “representations and warranties” section: you will be promising the publisher that your work doesn’t infringe anyone else’s copyright and that, where other people’s material is used, you have obtained permission.</p>
<p>The contract will probably also specify that you, the author, are responsible for securing and paying for permissions. It’s often a good idea when negotiating the publishing contract to make sure that the publisher has a permissions form you can use so you know exactly what they require in terms of permission: for example, if the publisher’s print run is likely to be more than 10,000 copies, your permission (or license) has to cover a print run of that size. If, say, you want to use someone else’s photograph in your work, and the publisher intends it to be a full color reproduction of the photograph in a particular size, you need to ensure that the permission allows full color reproductions in that size. You also want to ensure that the permission doesn’t limit the time period of the license for a term that is less than the time the publisher plans to sell your book. (In that case, it may be necessary to renew the license at some point post-publication.)</p>
<p>The other question that comes up with respect to obtaining permissions is cost. Sometimes a copyright holder will give you a license to use their work for free, but usually there is a fee attached, and fees can range from very minimal to pretty exorbitant depending on the circumstances. If you are using a lot of, say, photographs or quotes from other people’s work and the permissions costs are likely to be significant, you might want to try negotiating a “permissions budget” with the publisher so they will assist in the cost of obtaining permissions up to a certain amount. If you know you have a project that relies pretty heavily on permissions to re-use others’ work, you may want to discuss a permissions budget upfront with your publisher before it becomes an issue.</p>
<p>Other publishing contract clauses may state that where permission to reproduce another’s work cannot be obtained, the publisher can decide to either remove that material from the book or, in circumstances where the material in question is integral to the project, the publisher might have the right terminate your contract. These are not common situations, but they can arise so it is worth looking out for these clauses in your publishing contract and making sure you understand them, including what happens to, say, your advance if your publisher terminates the contract for failure to obtain necessary permissions.</p>
<p>The legal stuff, particularly with respect to rights in other people’s work, can be scary and confusing, but if a publisher does want to publish your book, it is worth making sure that you’re on the same page about permissions and costs. Where permissions can’t be obtained for whatever reason, it may be possible to insert something from the public domain in lieu of the copyrighted material, or to claim fair use. But it’s always a good idea to have the permissions discussions early in the negotiating process to avoid misunderstandings or problems down the line.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marketing Your Books: What to Expect</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/marketing-your-books-what-to-expect/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 11:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28546</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many authors prefer pursuing the path of traditional publishing with an established publishing house rather&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28554 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/thought-catalog-o0Qqw21-0NI-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/thought-catalog-o0Qqw21-0NI-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/thought-catalog-o0Qqw21-0NI-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/thought-catalog-o0Qqw21-0NI-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/thought-catalog-o0Qqw21-0NI-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/thought-catalog-o0Qqw21-0NI-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Many authors prefer pursuing the path of traditional publishing with an established publishing house rather than delving into indie publishing because of the belief—or maybe hope—that a traditional publisher will do the bulk of marketing for the book. While there are lots of reasons to prefer traditional publishing over indie publishing or vice versa, this view seems to be one that many writers hold so I thought it would be worth sharing some thoughts on it. These thoughts are less about the law than about business strategies but may be helpful to those choosing which publishing path to follow. And I must start out by acknowledging that I am not a marketing expert myself!</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also important to appreciate that every book is different, every author is different, and many authors successfully navigate a hybrid publishing path with some of their work published traditionally and some indie published. And sometimes the decision between indie or traditional publishing for a particular project may be influenced by concerns about how to market the piece.</p>
<p>Whether you are traditionally published or indie published, it is VERY likely that you will have to do significant marketing of your own if you want the book to be successful. Unfortunately, the dream of most authors—that their publisher will arrange a multi-city book tour and pay for featured tables at B&amp;N stores around the country—is not usually the reality, especially post-pandemic. Publishing houses have whole lists of books coming out in each season and they have limited PR/marketing budgets and people. They will have a marketing plan for each book and they will typically be sending books to the lead reviewers and other magazines, media outlets etc to see if the book gains traction, but whether they do a lot more will depend on the book, the publisher, the publishing season, the budget etc.</p>
<p>So it’s a good idea to think about your own marketing/PR strategies regardless of what the publisher does and, if you can work in concert with the marketing/PR team at your publishing house, so much the better.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28552 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Authors can do a lot themselves at very little cost by utilizing social media tools, reaching out to local bookstores to offer events and/or to offer to sign copies that may already be in the store. Independent bookstores are usually very receptive to these initiatives but don’t be shy about walking into your local B&amp;N or Chapters because you may be surprised how keen they are to feature local authors and to have you sign copies of your book.</p>
<p>You can certainly think about hiring your own marketing/PR consultant, but this can be very pricey and of course even the best PR consultant can’t guarantee significantly increased sales so if you’re thinking about hiring someone to help, talk to them first and make sure you understand precisely what they’re offering to do at what cost (and importantly what they’re not offering to do). Whether it’s a publishing house or a PR consultant sending your book out to review outlets, there is no guarantee that anyone will actually review the book. So go into those discussions with your eyes open and don’t shell out a lot of money unless you’re sure that a particular person or strategy will be helpful for you.</p>
<p>The sad truth is that there is no magic bullet to make books sell in the market. For authors with a traditional publishing contract, it often feels like success is just around the corner as soon as you sign the deal. But convincing readers to buy books is a whole ‘nother piece of the publishing puzzle. The main advance I can give is to make sure you know exactly what your publisher is, and isn’t, going to do and figure out ways to supplement their efforts through the most cost-effective means you can find. Asking other authors for advice is a great idea, and coordinating efforts with other authors writing in your genre can save time and money and avoid re-inventing the wheel</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monopsony and the Publishing Industry</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/monopsony-and-the-publishing-industry/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 11:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a break from my usual focus on contracts and intellectual property law, I’ve decided&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28402 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-768x1151.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-1025x1536.jpg 1025w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-1367x2048.jpg 1367w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1709w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />In a break from my usual focus on contracts and intellectual property law, I’ve decided to delve into a little antitrust law for this month’s column. Many authors have been watching with interest the Department of Justice’s (DOJ) attempt to prevent Penguin Random House (PRH) from acquiring Simon &amp; Schuster (S&amp;S) on antitrust grounds. Some helpful background to the case can be found <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/publisher-news/article/87783-doj-sues-to-block-prh-acquisition-of-s-s.html">here</a> and <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/publisher-news/article/89932-doj-vs-prh-and-s-s-book-biz-legal-showdown-of-the-century.html">here</a> as reported in Publishers Weekly.</p>
<p>For those who don’t know, and in extremely over-simplified terms, antitrust law is largely aimed at preventing a corporate entity or group of entities from exerting too much control in a market in a way that may create economic harm. The focus of the harm is usually on consumers—in terms of the aggregation of control of an industry leading to artificially increased prices because of lack of competition in the market.</p>
<p>Claims of monopoly in the publishing industry are not new, and have intensified both as a result of the entry of large digital players (like Amazon and Apple) on the sales and distribution side of publishing around 2010 and as a result of increasing consolidation of the major publishers. If the acquisition goes through, the “Big 5” publishers will become the “Big 4” and it’s not all that long ago that we were talking about a “Big 6” (i.e. before Penguin merged with Random House). Recently HarperCollins also acquired Houghton Mifflin Harcourt which, while not one of the largest houses, certainly boasted significant lists of its own. The HMH logo and corporate identity have been fully retired since the merger.</p>
<p>Obviously monopolies in publishing have the potential to harm the market for books and associated products and services. However, as a bit of a law geek, what is interesting to me (and to many watching the current litigation) is that the case between the DOJ and PRH/S&amp;S is not predominantly framed in monopoly terms, emphasizing costs to the ultimate consumers of books.</p>
<p>Instead, the more significant legal claim seems to be a <strong>monopsony </strong>argument. Unlike a monopoly, a monopsony refers to a situation where there is only one or a limited number of <strong>buyers</strong> in a market, as opposed to sellers. Publishers both buy literary works from authors and sell them to consumers and this case seems to focus on the former part of the equation in large measure. The DOJ is arguing that with increasing consolidation of publishers as <strong>buyers</strong>, less competitive deals will be made to authors who will have less choice in terms of bargains for the sale/licensing of their work. It’s an interesting twist on the usual legal narrative about aggregation of power in publishing. Of course there are also concerns about the consolidation of selling power of what would be the ”Big 4” post-merger, but it is interesting to watch the situation of authors being brought to the fore in this case.</p>
<p>The links to PW coverage (above) go into more detail about the nature of the arguments and how a monopsony differs from a monopoly in terms of market concerns so I won’t go into more detail here, particularly as I’m not an antitrust expert. But it is interesting to see the DOJ put its emphasis on the position of authors at a time when there are increasing concerns about whose voices are represented in the publishing industry, the ability of mid-list creatives to make a living from their work and the cost structures within publishing houses themselves.</p>
<p>When economies of scale are created through acquisitions and mergers, it has been far from<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28404 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-768x509.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-1536x1017.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-2048x1356.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> clear that those benefits are passed on to the authors who create the works that fuel the business. It’s also not clear the benefits are passed on to workers at the organizations in question. A significant number of editors and other staff members<a href="https://www.themarysue.com/march-2022-leaving-publishing-exodus/"> have been leaving the larger publishers</a> due to concerns over unsustainable conditions in terms of salaries, workloads and living expenses (particularly for those expected to work in expensive locations like NYC). In fact, the unionized HarperCollins staff organized <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/publisher-news/article/89825-hc-union-sets-july-20-strike-date.html">a strike on July 20</a> to protest their working conditions.</p>
<p>The case is set to be argued in August and the results will be fascinating to follow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Agency Agreements: Single versus Multiple Project Contracts</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/agency-agreements-single-versus-multiple-project-contracts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Writers thinking about signing with an agent for the first time, or when switching agents,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Writers thinking about signing with an agent for the first time, or when switching agents, are often faced with decisions about agency agreements that only cover a single project (and might, after that, operate on a project-by-project basis or simply terminate) versus more general agreements that cover multiple projects. Because agency agreements are contracts, supplemented by some fiduciary duties that I won’t go into in this column, they can be drafted in many different ways. Some agents operate without written contracts at all—this is perfectly legal, but it’s always a better idea to have something in writing in case confusions or misunderstandings arise down the line. All of this throat-clearing is to say that I’m writing here in generalities and every contract will have its own specifics, so it’s important to understand what you’re signing in any given situation and ask the agent or an outside expert if there is something you don’t understand.</p>
<p>The good news is that agency contracts—whether for single or multiple projects—are typically pretty simple, usually no more than a couple of pages that set out the relatively standard duties/responsibilities of the agent, along with the basis for the agent’s compensation (usually a standard commission).</p>
<p>So what are the pros and cons between signing a single project agreement versus a multiple project agreement? Often there isn’t much difference between the two in practice. Many agencies offer single project agreements for the first project and then go on to rep many more projects for the same client, while those that offer multiple project agreements may end up terminating the contract if they fail to sell the first project, or if they sell, say, one project but find themselves unable to sell anything else.</p>
<p>While some authors become anxious when faced with a single project agreement (<em>What about my other work? Aren’t you invested in my long-term career?</em>), others might feel worried about a contract that covers all their work (<em>What about small publishing gigs I get myself?</em> <em>What about my poetry and those song lyrics in my bottom drawer? Are you going to claim commission on stuff you don’t even represent?</em>)</p>
<p>There really isn’t a good way to draft a “one size fits all” agency contract without having to renegotiate the contract for each client, so often the author is presented with the agency’s standard agreement and occasionally a small revision might be made e.g. a multiple project agreement might be limited to a particular genre or market.</p>
<p>Some agencies offer authors a choice between a single project agreement or a multiple project agreement. If you have the choice, think about what you want from the agent in question. Are you likely only to write a single project in the area they represent? If so, the single project arrangement might be right for you. Single project contracts allow you to be free of the agreement outside that project, although many agencies that offer single project agreements are prepared to continue representing your work as long as you are productive and continue writing things they can sell.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s theoretically easier to part ways with an agent representing you for a single project because you have only given that agent authority to work on that one project and, whether or not they sell it, that’s the limit of your contractual arrangement, subject to any termination formalities set out in the contract e.g. notice by either party to the other that the arrangement is coming to an end. However, it’s generally not particularly difficult to terminate a multiple project agreement either—usually there’s a termination period of around 30 days (often less; sometimes more) to allow the agent to close of the administration of your work and then you go your separate ways.</p>
<p>Bear in mind that regardless of whether you signed a single project or a multiple project agreement, your agent will likely continue to receive commission on any deal(s) they brokered for you during the course of the agency. That’s pretty standard practice whatever the scope of representation under the initial agreement.</p>
<p>As with any contractual issue, the pros and cons really come down to understanding your needs as an author and the nature of the agreement being offered to you. While agency agreements tend to be pretty simple, it’s usually worth having another set of eyes—a contract consultant or publishing attorney or other expert—look over the agreement for you before you sign to help make sure you fully understand the agent’s rights and obligations.</p>
<p>And as with everything in this column, nothing written here is intended as legal advice but hopefully it is helpful information in navigating agency agreements.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trademarks and the Writing Life</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/trademarks-and-the-writing-life/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For this month’s column, I&#8217;m delving into an area I don’t often talk much about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27504 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/badge-gcd514c570_1920-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/badge-gcd514c570_1920-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/badge-gcd514c570_1920-1024x1024.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/badge-gcd514c570_1920-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/badge-gcd514c570_1920-768x768.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/badge-gcd514c570_1920-1536x1536.png 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/badge-gcd514c570_1920-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/badge-gcd514c570_1920.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />For this month’s column, I&#8217;m delving into an area I don’t often talk much about in the publishing context: trademarks. The reason I don’t often delve into it is that trademark law only affects authors in very limited circumstances. There is not much that authors can trademark and most of the trademarks that appear on books belong to the publisher, e.g., “HarperCollins” is a trademark belonging to the publisher that will appear on its books.</p>
<p>So what is a trademark anyway?</p>
<p>As the reference to HarperCollins suggests, it is a source indicator—a signal to consumers of the source of a product or service they may want to buy. It’s a shorthand way to indicate something to purchasers about the quality/consistency of the product or service: for example, if you see McDonald’s golden arches on a building, you know exactly what to expect when you go inside the restaurant—a budget priced menu of fast food including familiar items like Big Macs and Fries.</p>
<p>Because a key purpose of trademark law is to protect this ability of consumers to associate certain products/services with their manufacturers, trademarks really serve a commercial identification function. Rather than protecting creativity, they protect consumer associations (although the creative aspects of some trademarks—like a distinctive graphic design—may be protected by copyright law as well).</p>
<p>Understanding the rationale for trademark law will probably help explain the answers to the two main questions authors typically ask about trademarks:</p>
<p>1/ Can I trademark my name (including a pen-name) and/or book title?</p>
<p>2/ Can I refer to someone else’s trademark in my own work?</p>
<p><u>Trademarking Authors’ Names and Book Titles</u></p>
<p>You typically cannot claim a trademark in your name as an author (even a pen-name) or in your book title. This is because, unlike the publisher’s mark—HarperCollins, Simon &amp; Schuster, etc.—your personal name and book title don’t tell consumers anything about the source of the book in a trademark sense. If the purpose of trademark law is to support consumer associations between producers/manufacturers and their customers, it’s really the publishers’ marks that serve that function.</p>
<p>The book’s title doesn’t tell consumers anything about the source of the book—it just identifies the book and distinguishes it from other books.</p>
<p>Your name as an author is a form of source identifier (for example, readers will expect different things from a Stephen King book than they will from a Janet Evanovich book), but the law treats this kind of source differently from the consumer associations protected by trademark law. The Supreme Court made this clear some years ago in the case of <em>Dastar v 20<sup>th</sup> Century Fox</em> when it held that trademarks protect the producer of physical items (in that case video cassettes, but the same would apply for books), rather than the original creator of the works. <em>Dastar</em> was an unusual case and this explanation is an oversimplification, but the main point is that <em>copyright</em> law is supposed to protect those who create original works like books, movies, music, etc., and trademark law protects the source of production of the physical items that go out into the marketplace.</p>
<p><u>Using Someone Else’s Trademark in Your Work</u></p>
<p>The second question about using other people’s marks in your writing is more complicated. Generally, if you are simply referring to someone else’s mark in the course of your short story, novel, memoir, etc., that’s not a legal problem. This result makes sense if you think about the<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27505 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/registered-g3c65fba98_1280-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/registered-g3c65fba98_1280-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/registered-g3c65fba98_1280-1024x1024.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/registered-g3c65fba98_1280-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/registered-g3c65fba98_1280-768x768.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/registered-g3c65fba98_1280-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/registered-g3c65fba98_1280.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> purposes of trademark law—to identify the source of a product in the commercial sphere. If you happen to refer to a character who likes to drink Coke, or likes to drive a Porsche, in the course of your novel, you are obviously not suggesting that Coke or Porsche is the producer of your book.</p>
<p>However, problems can arise where you use someone else’s trademark so prominently in your own writing that consumers may be confused about whether that trademark holder actually is affiliated with your work in some way. For example, if you write a book about how to become a better Scrabble player and you prominently use the Scrabble trademarks throughout the book, it may be unclear to readers whether the makers of the game are the producers of, or in some other way affiliated with, your book. Even in a situation like this, you can usually avoid infringing the trademarks if you make it clear that your book has not been authorized by Hasbro (the U.S. owner of the mark).</p>
<p>Of course, there’s the additional wrinkle that whether or not your book actually DOES infringe a trademark, nothing stops the trademark holder from threatening legal action, which is why many publishers will avoid publishing books that prominently use highly protected marks unless they have permission. They just don’t want to take the risk. A lot of the books you see on the shelves that prominently feature trademarks (like LEGO and Barbie) are published under a license from the trademark holder, and often those projects are initiated by the trademark holder, working together with a publisher, and hiring authors and illustrators on a work for hire basis.</p>
<p>The bottom line is that if you’re writing a standard novel, memoir, short story, etc., you are unlikely to be infringing someone else’s mark even if you refer to it in the text. So there’s very little to worry about unless you get into the kind of writing where your work suggests an affiliation with a trademark holder; and then you should probably seek expert advice before publishing. If you approach a publisher, they will probably ask you about existing trademarks that may impact publication.</p>
<p>As always, this column is not intended as formal legal advice, so if you are concerned about uses of a trademark that may be problematic, you should seek advice from an expert.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What if My Publisher Cancels My Book?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-if-my-publisher-cancels-my-book/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve heard a lot of questions lately about what happens if your publisher decides not&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27312 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/green-chameleon-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/green-chameleon-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/green-chameleon-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/green-chameleon-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/green-chameleon-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/green-chameleon-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I’ve heard a lot of questions lately about what happens if your publisher decides not to publish your book after signing a contract with you. While this is obviously a matter of contract law—and contracts vary between publishers and between projects—the following is an overview of the types of situations that can arise and the issues you should check in your contract, preferably before you sign it!</p>
<p>There are a number of reasons why a publisher may decide not to publish your work, even after signing a contract for it. The main situations are:</p>
<p>1/ the publisher goes out of business or is acquired by another company and the new owners don’t want to proceed with publication;</p>
<p>2/ the publisher is not satisfied with the final draft of your manuscript; or,</p>
<p>3/ the publisher is concerned about market factors that might lead to poor sales or reputational harm.</p>
<p><em>Publisher Goes out of Business or is Acquired by Another Company</em></p>
<p>While it is extremely unfortunate if your publisher goes out of business prior to publishing your book, it does happen and there are usually contract clauses that provide for who gets what rights and what money if this does occur. Your contract may include a termination clause that reverts all rights in the book to you on the publisher’s bankruptcy and you want to check that you get to keep any advance monies already paid in that situation.</p>
<p>There will likely also be a clause in your contract about what happens if the publisher is acquired by another company—usually the publisher gets the right to transfer your contract to the new owners. If the new owners don’t want to proceed with your book, their right to terminate your contract will likely be governed by the provisions of your original contract. That contract should contain clauses that explain what happens if the publisher decides not to proceed and who gets what rights/money in that situation. You should get your rights back to allow you to sell the manuscript elsewhere—so it’s a good idea to make sure there’s a clause to that effect in the original contract.</p>
<p><em>Unsatisfactory Manuscript</em></p>
<p>A publisher usually has the right to terminate your contract if you fail to deliver a final manuscript that is editorially satisfactory within the time specified in your contract for final delivery. The idea of a “final delivery” date may sound odd to authors who have sold completed drafts of books to publishers, but remember there is always some editing to be done after you sell the manuscript so there is typically a “final delivery date” specified in the contract that is later than the date you actually signed the contract. When you negotiate the contract it is important to check that the final delivery clause contemplates the work being “editorially” satisfactory rather than generally satisfactory to the publisher. If the contract’s “satisfactory delivery” concept is too broad, theoretically a publisher could claim that they decided they just didn’t like the contents of what you wrote, rather than that there was too much editorial work to do to make it worth continuing with the book.</p>
<p>Court cases have been argued about what it means for a manuscript to be “satisfactory” or “editorially satisfactory” under these kinds of clauses, and how much work a publisher should be doing to help get the manuscript into an editorially satisfactory state. Make sure that when you sign a publishing contract you understand the kinds of situations in which the publisher could claim that your work isn’t satisfactory to them, as the contract will typically give them a right not to proceed with the book if they are not satisfied with your final manuscript.</p>
<p><em>Market Factors</em></p>
<p>A publisher may also decide not to proceed with your book because the market has changed since they signed your book and they don’t think they can sell it anymore. This can be because there are suddenly too many similar books on the market or because social or political circumstances have changed which make your book potentially less appealing to the target market. It could also be because you have engaged in conduct that the publisher thinks might negatively impact sales of the book or harm their reputation.</p>
<p>These situations are probably the most challenging in legal terms. Publishers will try to draft their contracts so they have as much discretion as possible about whether to publish the book so it’s important to read your contract carefully and understand the kinds of situations in which the publisher might decide not to proceed and, importantly, what you get in those situations—hopefully a full reversion of your rights in the book and an entitlement to retain any advance monies paid to you.</p>
<p>One clause that’s become more common in publishing contracts in recent years to give the<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27313 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gaman-alice-ZpnVeCKf6KM-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gaman-alice-ZpnVeCKf6KM-unsplash-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gaman-alice-ZpnVeCKf6KM-unsplash-678x1024.jpg 678w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gaman-alice-ZpnVeCKf6KM-unsplash-768x1160.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gaman-alice-ZpnVeCKf6KM-unsplash-1017x1536.jpg 1017w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gaman-alice-ZpnVeCKf6KM-unsplash-1356x2048.jpg 1356w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gaman-alice-ZpnVeCKf6KM-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1696w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /> publisher more discretion is the morality clause. The Author’s Guild has some useful information on morality clauses <a href="https://www.authorsguild.org/industry-advocacy/why-we-oppose-morals-clauses-in-book-contracts/">here</a>. These clauses are a phenomenon borrowed from other sectors of the entertainment industry, like film/TV contracts where, say, an actor can be replaced from a project if they behave in a manner likely to harm the project. While there may be good reasons for publishers to want to include these clauses, they do give publishers a lot of discretion in deciding what kinds of conduct are immoral or objectionable, giving rise to their right to terminate the contract. The Author’s Guild article includes some examples of the typical wording of these kinds of clauses and explains why those clauses can be so problematic for authors.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hopefully none of your books ever get cancelled for any reason, but before you sign a book contract, it is important to understand the situations in which a publisher might decide not to proceed with publication and what rights/money you will receive in which situations. As always, this column is not intended as formal legal advice, and if you are concerned about how your particular contract works, and what might happen if it is terminated, you should seek advice from an expert.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Publishing Contracts: The Dreaded Option Clause</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/publishing-contracts-the-dreaded-option-clause/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 11:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve written previously in this column about option clauses in publishing contracts, focusing on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve written previously in this column about <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/option-and-non-compete-clauses/">option clauses</a> in publishing contracts, focusing on the pros and cons of options versus multi-book deals, but in this column I want to look at how option clauses work on a more nuts and bolts level: how they impact authors thinking about their next work. Not all publishing contracts have option clauses, and not all option clauses are the same.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27094 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash1-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash1-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash1-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash1-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />If you’re worried about what you can do with your next project—when you’re already under contract for an earlier project—check to see if your contract <em>has</em> an option clause and, if so, what is the scope of the option. For example, if you have a romance novel under contract, your option (if there is one) might say that you have to give the publisher a first right of refusal over your next romance novel, or your next novel, or even your next “work.” Obviously, the more limited the option clause, the more leeway you have to share work outside those limits with another publisher, so if your option is limited to romance novels and you have written a picture book, you can send the picture book to whoever you want—provided you are not restricted by any other clauses in your contract (e.g. a non-compete clause).</p>
<p>But what about the situation where you are ready to share your next work that falls <em>within</em> the option clause? Does the option mean you have to sell your next romance novel to the first publisher? Or that the publisher can sit on your next manuscript as long as they want without giving you an answer about whether they want to publish it?</p>
<p>Generally not.</p>
<p>Because options are creatures of contract, you have to look at the exact terms of your contract to see what your specific rights and obligations. However, most publishing contracts do not <em>require</em> you to accept an offer made by the publisher on your option manuscript. They generally specify only that you and your publisher will negotiate in good faith over the new project to see if you can come to agreeable terms. If you cannot come to an agreement, the option ends and you can send your work to other publishers.</p>
<p>Some option clauses additionally say that if you fail to come to terms with the original publisher and you pursue other publishers, the first publisher will have the right to match terms offered by another publisher; or, that you won’t accept an offer from another publisher on less favorable terms than the first publisher had offered you.</p>
<p>If you do come to an agreement with your original publisher for your option book, then the contract for the new book is a whole new contract with its own terms—which may also include another option on your <em>next </em>book. So there will be a new advance figure, new royalty terms, etc.</p>
<p>There is also the question of <em>when</em> you can submit your option book to your publisher. Most publishers will not look at an option book before “delivery and acceptance” of the final revisions on your first book. This term is very common and very confusing because many authors assume that “delivery and acceptance” means the point in time when the author is happy with the manuscript, when the author has responded to editorial suggestions, and/or when the delivery date for the manuscript in the contract occurs. Technically, none of this is “delivery and acceptance.” It may be “delivery,” but we often forget about that important term “acceptance.” The editor has to formally sign off on the manuscript: that is, agree that what has been delivered is satisfactory for the piece to go into production (or to go to an illustrator if it’s a picture book, graphic novel, or other illustrated work).</p>
<p>An editor should tell you when the first book has been “accepted,” and, if they fail to do that, and <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-27095 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/olia-gozha-J4kK8b9Fgj8-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/olia-gozha-J4kK8b9Fgj8-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/olia-gozha-J4kK8b9Fgj8-unsplash-1024x680.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/olia-gozha-J4kK8b9Fgj8-unsplash-768x510.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/olia-gozha-J4kK8b9Fgj8-unsplash-1536x1020.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/olia-gozha-J4kK8b9Fgj8-unsplash-2048x1360.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />you believe you have satisfied all of your contractual obligations, you should ask for that assurance. This sign-off will indicate both that you should be receiving any portion of your advance that was due on “delivery and acceptance” and that you should be in a position to submit your option manuscript.</p>
<p>Your contract will probably provide a deadline for the publisher to decide on the option manuscript once it is submitted: maybe 30 days, 45 days or 60 days. At the expiration of that time, if there is no agreement on a new contract, you will generally be free to take the manuscript to another publisher.</p>
<p>Options can be confusing and challenging and I know I’m not giving particularly precise answers here to common questions. The problem is that, like all issues arising from a contract, the terms vary between publishers and over time, so it is important to understand what your publishing contract says before you sign it in relation to options. If you have thoughts at that time about what your next project is likely to be and when it’s likely to be ready, it may be worth discussing with your editor to see if it is possible to draft the contract accordingly. And sometimes it is possible to tweak an agreement down the line if you are ready earlier than planned with a new manuscript and if the editor has the bandwidth and ability to consider it earlier than the contract specifies. But as with all contract issues, an ounce of understanding at the outset can be worth a pound of cure down the track.</p>
<p>As always, this column is not intended as formal legal advice, and if you are concerned about how your particular contract works, you should seek advice from an expert.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Publishing Contracts in the Real World</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/publishing-contracts-in-the-real-world/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 11:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26762</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s often difficult for non-lawyers (or really anyone who doesn’t think about contracts regularly) to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s often difficult for non-lawyers (or really anyone who doesn’t think about contracts regularly) to fully appreciate that contracts do not necessarily cover every eventuality that could arise between the parties and, even when they do, they can be revised if both parties need to make a change.</p>
<p>Why is it worth making this point in a column on laws related to publishing? Because so much writers do revolves around contracts: contracts with agents and publishing houses, and perhaps also with marketing and PR firms.</p>
<p>As someone who has taught contract law for many years, one of the first things I always say about contracts is to bear in mind that they are basically a risk management tool—a document agreed between the parties to explain what each has agreed to do, and to predict what could go wrong and set out how those potential future problems will be handled.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26859 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/romain-dancre-doplSDELX7E-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/romain-dancre-doplSDELX7E-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/romain-dancre-doplSDELX7E-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/romain-dancre-doplSDELX7E-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/romain-dancre-doplSDELX7E-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/romain-dancre-doplSDELX7E-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />So, for example, in a publishing contract, the author is agreeing to write and deliver the work described in the contract, and is agreeing to give certain rights to the publisher to publish and distribute (and sublicense etc.) the work. The publisher is agreeing to publish the work, usually within a certain period of time from receiving a satisfactory manuscript. Then there are a bunch of clauses about what might happen if something unexpected occurs for example, if either or both parties are sued with respect to the contents of the work; if a force majeure event occurs (an unforeseen event that prevents one of the parties, typically the publisher, from fulfilling its contractual obligations in a timely manner); if the work goes out of print; if the publisher goes out of business etc. If you think about it, these are all issues that may or may not arise, but the parties are trying to manage what will happen in terms of the risks if those circumstances do occur.</p>
<p>Because no one can see into the future, circumstances could arise that are not contemplated in the contract. One of the parties may find it is unable to fulfill one or more contractual obligations, but neither party wants to terminate the contract or sue for breach. For example, if the author is sick and needs more time to deliver the final manuscript, many publishers will prefer to update the contract to give the author extra time than to cancel the contract altogether, depending on the circumstances.</p>
<p>It is important to understand that, while both parties are doing their best (at least we hope they are) at the time they enter into the contract, situations could occur that would technically be grounds to terminate the contract, but the author and publisher prefer to revise their contract than to cancel everything. That’s the reality of a contract. It can be amended if both parties agree to it. This doesn’t mean that it shouldn’t be as comprehensive and accurate as possible to begin with, but it is important to appreciate that in practice deadlines get missed and situations change and as long as people work cooperatively and transparently, many of these circumstances can be handled without too much trouble.</p>
<p>Of course, it is also important to appreciate—and many writers already do—that even though contracts are basically a risk management tool, the parties generally do not have equal bargaining power when entering into the contract. Many debut authors without a proven sales track record will often have a lot less bargaining power than the publishing house they are dealing with. On the other hand, bestselling authors at the top of their game might have a lot more bargaining power than they did earlier in their careers. A publishing house may also be taking more risk than the author because it is investing the money in the book to begin with so it arguably has more to lose if the book does not make money or if something goes wrong, and books have to be removed from the shelves as a result of a legal claim about the contents of the book, e.g. copyright infringement.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, the point of this column is to make authors aware that the text of your <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-26861 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/mari-helin-ilSnKT1IMxE-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />publishing contract, be it your first or your forty-first book, is not likely to be the be-all and end-all of your commercial relationship with your publisher. There will likely be practical changes, which may necessitate legal updates to the contract, as a result of circumstances that were not foreseen at the time of contract or that were foreseen as a possibility but have to be dealt with in reality when they happen (like a book not doing as well as expected, the publisher getting sued over the book, a paper shortage as a result of a pandemic etc.) As an attorney myself, I’m <strong>never</strong> going to say “ignore your contract and go with the flow”, but I am going to remind people that contracts are imperfect risk management tools and parties who want to have a long term commercial relationship ultimately may have to be flexible to obtain the most effective benefits of working together.</p>
<p>As always, this column is not intended as formal legal advice, and if you are concerned about signing a publishing contract, or about a problem that has arisen under a contract, you should seek advice from an expert such as a literary agent or publishing attorney.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fair Use 101</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fair-use-101/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 11:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26498</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the last couple of columns, I’ve focused on how not to infringe other people’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the last couple of columns, I’ve focused on how <span style="text-decoration: underline;">not</span> to infringe other people’s copyrights so I knew the day would come when I would have to tackle fair use. That time is now!</p>
<p>Most authors know that fair use is a defense to copyright infringement. However, few people have a clear sense of how fair use really works, which is not surprising given that Congress, when adding the defense to the copyright act, intended to maintain flexibility for courts to adapt fair use for new copying technologies and circumstances. The American fair use model is intentionally more flexible and amorphous than similar defenses in other countries. Even the term “fair use” is largely American; many other countries use the term “fair dealing” for activities like reproducing other people’s work in the context of journalism, research, criticism, or commentary.</p>
<p>A (hopefully) fun way into thinking about fair use law is to consider some common misconceptions. How many of the following statements have you heard are true?</p>
<p>1/ If I credit the original author of the work I re-use in my own writing, it’s fair use.</p>
<p>2/ It’s okay to copy someone’s poem or song lyric in a chapter heading/epigraph of a book, but not in the body of a chapter.</p>
<p>3/ All educational uses are fair uses.</p>
<p>4/ All fanction and retellings of popular stories are fair use.</p>
<p>5/ Journalists cannot be sued for copyright infringement</p>
<p>Does it surprise you to learn that NONE of these statements is unequivocally true? Some are <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-26688 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-L4YGuSg0fxs-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />true in some contexts, but none of them is absolutely true all the time. And that’s because fair use is intended to flexible, to balance competing interests in the copyright holder’s rights to their work, and the need for new creators to repurpose existing works in their own.</p>
<p>I’ll come back to the above statements shortly, but, before we consider why they’re not always true, let’s look at what copyright law actually says about fair use, so we can understand how it applies to these statements.</p>
<p>Congress added the fair use defense to the copyright act in 1976, wanting to retain flexibility and balancing of competing interests that the courts had developed before then. The fair use defense now appears in §107 of the copyright act (aka “Title 17 of the U.S. Code”). For those who don’t want to read actual laws—and who can blame you?—avert your eyes from the next bit, but here’s what §107 actually says:</p>
<p><em>[T]he fair use of a copyrighted work … <u>for </u></em><em><u>purposes such as </u></em><em><u>criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching (including </u></em><em><u>multiple copies </u></em><em><u>for classroom use), scholarship, or research,</u></em><em> is not an infringement of copyright. </em></p>
<p><em>In determining whether the use made of a work in any particular case is a fair use the factors to be considered shall include—</em></p>
<p><strong><em>(1)</em></strong><em> the purpose and character of the </em><em>use, including</em><em> whether such use is of a commercial nature or is for nonprofit educational purposes;</em></p>
<p><strong><em>(2)</em></strong><em> the nature of the copyrighted work; </em></p>
<p><strong><em>(3)</em></strong><em> the amount and substantiality of the portion used in relation to the copyrighted work as a whole; and</em></p>
<p><strong><em>(4)</em></strong><em> the effect of the use upon the potential market for or value of the copyrighted work.</em></p>
<p>[Emphasis mine, and I’ve also removed some words to make it easier to read, but this should get the main drift across.]</p>
<p>One of the biggest challenges in understanding § is understanding what it <em>doesn’t </em>say. If you read the first sentence of the section by itself, it would seem like it is saying that if you engage in any of the listed uses—criticism, comment, reporting, research—your work is a fair use. And that is what it would mean if not for the second sentence, which qualifies the first by instructing courts to look at the four factors listed to decide if any particular use is a fair use.</p>
<p>Congress did not to say, for example, that “all research uses are fair use.” What it actually did say is that some research uses are fair uses provided that, after consideration of the fair use factors, a court is convinced that the work meets the fair use criteria set out in factors one to four. These factors instruct the court to focus on issues like whether the person claiming fair use is making money from the work without compensating the original creator, what kind of use is being made, how much of the original work is being used, etc. It’s a complex set of questions in any given case.</p>
<p>It’s also important to note that the four factor test is an instruction by Congress to the courts deciding particular cases, which unfortunately means that unless and until you end up in court and the case is formally decided, you do not know for sure whether your use is a fair use or not. You can have an attorney give you an opinion—and reasonable attorneys differ in their answer to fair use questions—but you don’t know for sure unless a court decides.</p>
<p>Now let’s dive into those five statements and see if we understand why none of them are absolutely true.</p>
<p><strong>1/ If I credit the original author of the work I re-use in my own writing, it’s fair use. (Not true.)</strong></p>
<p>Giving credit to the original author has nothing to do with fair use. It is not relevant to any of the fair use factors. As I noted in my <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/if-i-give-credit-its-not-copyright-infringement-right/">last column</a>, credit is often given in practice, but usually as it’s a condition of a license (i.e. an authorization or permission to use the work provided attribution is given). These arrangements are matters of contract law, not fair use.</p>
<p><strong>2/ It’s okay to copy someone’s poem or song lyric in a chapter heading/epigraph of a book, but not in the body of a chapter. (Not true.)</strong></p>
<p>To figure out if using snippets of someone else’s poem or song lyric is fair use, it is necessary to look at the four fair use factors. It doesn’t matter <em>where</em> in your work you’re using the other person’s words (epigraph/chapter heading, or anywhere else). What matters if how the fair use factors play out. Think about things like how much of the original work you used. Also, are you negatively impacting the market for the original work? Could/should you have paid a license fee?</p>
<p><strong>3/ All educational uses are fair uses. (Not true.)</strong></p>
<p>While research and scholarship are identified by Congress as the kinds of uses that might be fair uses in the first sentence of §107, courts still have to consider the fair use factors in any particular case, including those involving research and teaching. For example, copyright cases involving digital course packs and other teaching materials have been in the courts recently. Even though this copying is for educational purposes, those purposes are also commercial (student fees subsidize the copying and distribution) and they arguably impact the licensing market for those materials negatively.</p>
<p><strong>4/ All fanction and retellings of popular stories are fair use. (Not true.)</strong></p>
<p>Again, whatever the context, courts are required to apply the four factor test to determine whether any particular use is a fair use. If you are writing fanfiction or a retelling based on a public domain work (see note below), you don’t have to worry about copyright at all, but if your work is based on a copyrighted work, and the copyright holder has a problem with it, you may end up with a court deciding whether your use is a fair use based on how much of the original story you used, whether your use was commercial or not, whether your use negatively impacted the value of the original work, etc. High profile cases involving fair use in the publishing context include an unauthorized retelling of <em>Gone With the Wind</em> told from the perspective of the slaves <em>The Wind Done Gone</em>) and an unauthorized <em>Harry Potter</em> lexicon.</p>
<p><strong>5/ Journalists cannot be sued for copyright infringement. (Not true.)</strong></p>
<p>While journalism, like educational use, serves an important societal function, any copying done by journalists theoretically needs to satisfy the fair use test to qualify as a fair use. That’s why journalists often paraphrase or, when copying, do so under license. Journalists and media outlets have been sued for copyright infringement for using copyrighted photographs without permission even though they used them in the context of publicly important media stories. One of the most well known fair use cases involved a popular magazine being sued for reproducing key sections of Gerald Ford’s forthcoming memoir without permission.</p>
<p><strong>A brief note on the public domain. </strong>Before I entirely freak everyone out, it is important to remember that you only need to worry about fair use (or alternatively getting permission) for <em>copyrighted</em> works. You are always free to use <em>public domain works</em> any way you want to. I’ve discussed the public domain—and how it differs from the creative commons—in more detail in a <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/avoiding-infringing-someone-elses-copyright/">previous blog post</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26687 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-6sl88x150Xs-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-6sl88x150Xs-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-6sl88x150Xs-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-6sl88x150Xs-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-6sl88x150Xs-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tingey-injury-law-firm-6sl88x150Xs-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />It’s difficult to explain fair use in any detail in a column like this, so of course the above contains generalizations and simplifications. And most fair use disputes don’t end up in court and the parties resolve them in other ways e.g. negotiated settlement. Going to court is the only surefire way to know if a particular use is a fair use, but because litigation is expensive, we don’t get a lot of case law determining whether particular uses are fair uses or not.</p>
<p>As always, this column is not intended as formal legal advice, and if you are concerned about infringing someone else’s copyright and fair use questions, you should seek advice from an expert.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>If I Give Credit, It’s not Copyright Infringement, Right?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/if-i-give-credit-its-not-copyright-infringement-right/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/if-i-give-credit-its-not-copyright-infringement-right/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 11:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26410</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In my last column I talked generally about how not to infringe other people’s copyrights.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In my <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/avoiding-infringing-someone-elses-copyright/">last column</a> I talked generally about how not to infringe other people’s copyrights. This month, I wanted to dive into a specific question that often confuses people on the copyright infringement front:</p>
<p><em>Is it copyright infringement if I give credit to the original creator?  </em></p>
<p>The surprising answer is “maybe.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26468 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/markus-winkler-9XfSFjcwGh0-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/markus-winkler-9XfSFjcwGh0-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/markus-winkler-9XfSFjcwGh0-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/markus-winkler-9XfSFjcwGh0-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/markus-winkler-9XfSFjcwGh0-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/markus-winkler-9XfSFjcwGh0-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />What many people don’t realize about copyright law is that copyright infringement is what lawyers call a “strict liability” tort; that means you can infringe copyright simply by copying or distributing someone else’s work without permission. Your intent doesn’t matter. So it doesn’t matter if you give credit and/or say nice things about the original creator, or if you weren’t planning to make money from your use (although commercial use is a part of the fair use test which I’ve discussed <a href="https://cynthialeitichsmith.com/2020/09/guest-post-jacqueline-d-lipton-on-images-law-writers/">elsewhere</a>). Strict liability legal wrongs are those where you are liable simply for engaging in the prohibited act (in this case, copying without permission), regardless of your intent.</p>
<p>So why do you see so many works of literature and art where the author or artist <strong>does</strong> give credit to the original creator? Why would they bother giving credit if it doesn’t help them escape legal liability?</p>
<p>Well, for one thing it’s a nice thing to do professionally and ethically.</p>
<p>More importantly—or at least more legally—giving credit to the original creator is typically a term of a license to use the original work. The original creator may say: “You can use my words/illustration/photograph etc, as long as you give me credit.” The original creator may also ask for payment, either a flat fee or a royalty or a combination, as a term of a license to use their work. But even if they don’t want money, the attribution will be a term of the license.</p>
<p>The license between the original creator and the new creator is the reason why there is no copyright infringement when the original work is re-used by a new author or artist. The license gives legal permission to use the work in the way agreed between the two creators provided that attribution is given. The new creator isn’t relying on fair use at all in this situation, but rather on permission to use the work.</p>
<p>Think back to what copyright law prohibits. You are not permitted to copy/distribute someone else’s work without authorization. The license provides that authorization. That’s why people with a license are not infringing copyright: because they have authorization to use the original creator’s work. The authorization can come with various other obligations attached (like a payment obligation, or a requirement that you attribute the original creator). But it’s the license that excuses the new creator from infringing the original copyright, not the fact that they gave credit to the original creator.</p>
<p>Because those of us reading the new work or viewing the new art out in the wild never SEE the license or evidence of the license—because it’s a private contract between the creator of the original work and the new creator—it’s easy to assume that merely giving credit to the original creator must be a fair use. It’s an easy mistake to make. But giving credit by itself does not excuse copying that would otherwise amount to a copyright infringement. Giving credit is good professional practice, but legally it does not excuse unauthorized copying without some kind of permission from the original creator.</p>
<p>The fair use defense to copyright infringement is not about attribution, but rather about the context in which you used the original work, whether or not you had a commercial profit motive, whether or not you negatively impacted the market for the original work, etc. Fair use is a complicated defense, but generally speaking, it has little to do with giving credit where credit is due. If you have fair use questions, make sure you talk to a copyright expert before relying on the defense!</p>
<p>As always, this column is not intended as formal legal advice, and if you are concerned about infringing someone else’s copyright, you should seek advice from a copyright expert. But hopefully this discussion at least sheds some light on a question that often confuses creators when repurposing other people’s words or art.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/if-i-give-credit-its-not-copyright-infringement-right/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
