<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lauren Orbison &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/lauren-orbison/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 01:18:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday, Patricia Wrede!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-patricia-wrede/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lauren Orbison]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 15:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4061</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I remember when I first discovered Patricia Wrede&#8217;s work. I was browsing through our local&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">I remember when I first discovered Patricia Wrede&#8217;s work. I was browsing through our local used bookstore, McKay Used Books, and I came across her book Dealing with Dragons. I was beginning to dabble in my own original fiction at the time and was enchanted with anything that had dragons. I was particularly interested in stories where dragons were sentient and good guys rather than evil.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I loved the book. Her characters were intriguing (the idea of a princess as a dragon&#8217;s chef amused me quite a lot) and the world building was excellent. It charmed me.</p>
<p dir="ltr">After I finished it, I was curious what other books she had written. I searched on Google and I found her world building guide. My eyes bulged. It was a comprehensive list of everything that the aspiring writer needed to create a living fictional world. I had never seen such a detailed guide before. I remember looking over the lengthy list of questions about building a world. I wondered how I could ever measure up. All I originally was interested in was the section on magic and magical system creation, but even that was far more detailed than I expected. I printed out a copy of the guide and put it in a yellow folder. I thought the brightness of the folder would help keep me from losing it as easily as I lose everything else.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It worked for awhile.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Then I lost it and reprinted. And found the old one eventually. I finally figured out that having it on paper wasn&#8217;t really necessary, but that having it saved in a file I could easily refer to was much better. So that&#8217;s where it is now.</p>
<p dir="ltr">From Ms. Wrede, I learned just how much thought, time, and effort goes into building the setting for the plot when more often than not, the plot receives the bulk of attention. I&#8217;m sure I&#8217;m not the only author she&#8217;s influenced.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Wishing you a happy birthday, Ms. Wrede! I hope it&#8217;s a great one!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
