<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Grey Lenswoman &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-grey-lenswoman/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 23:34:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How Dare They!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/how-dare-they/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a bone-deep Scorpio—and I’m talking Sun-sign, Moon-sign, street-sign and any other sign that can&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a bone-deep Scorpio—and I’m talking Sun-sign, Moon-sign, street-sign and any other sign that can possibly be construed as even faintly tinged with Scorpio—your Grey Lenswoman is an Olympic-level champion at holding grudges. I’ve held onto some of mine dating back to second grade, when that creep Robert lied about me talking in class—honestly, all I did was turn my head and hold my finger to my lips in time-honored shushing mode. Robert’s tattling resulted in me having to stay late after school. I had to walk home! Okay, I always walked home, but it’s the principle of the thing, am I right? And I almost missed <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/best-role-models-ever/"><em>Sheena, Queen of the Jungle</em></a>!</p>
<p>So, as you can see, when it comes to some of my favorite TV series of all time, it’s far <img decoding="async" class="wp-image-28774 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Fireflyopeninglogo.jpg" alt="" width="192" height="112" />from surprising that I can hold onto a how-dare-they-cancel-it grudge for literally decades. Yes, of course <em>Firefly</em> is one—fourteen episodes and done? Seriously? And sure, they tossed us hardcore Browncoats a bone with the <em>Serenity</em> movie, but then Whedon killed off some of the characters. No, I won’t mention who, for those three people who’ve not seen it, but Bad Joss, bad! Never, never, never kill dogs or my favorite characters, else you risk the wrath of Me.</p>
<p>Another TV series I loved and lost is <em>The Adventures of Brisco County, Jr</em>. A Western, I hear you gasp in amazement? Yes, a Western, with the delicious snark of Bruce Campbell, the delightful geekiness of John Astin—who, I will argue to the death, was the sexiest Gomez Addams—and the delectable delectableness of Julian Curry. Plus we had Billy Drago! That man’s face was<img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28773 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/TheAdventuresOfBriscoCountyJropeninglogo.jpg" alt="" width="203" height="154" /> created specifically to be the perfect villain. With amazing inventions, a glowing orb, lashings of steampunk, actors who appeared in classic Western shows dating back to the 50s—the twenty-seven episodes of this series had everything. Except a second season. Funny story: when <em>Brisco</em> debuted in ’93, it was expected to crush in the ratings a weird sci-fi-ish series that debuted at the same time. It didn&#8217;t. That other series went on for years and was recently rebooted. Sure, I liked it too and watched all the episodes. You may have heard of it: <em>The X-Files</em>?</p>
<p>Three science fiction series with single-word titles debuted in 2005; <em>Invasion</em>, <em>Surface</em> and <em>Threshold</em>. I watched all three, of course, being the card-carrying geek I am. <em>Invasion </em>was vaguely Body Snatchers-ish, with sea creatures washed in by a hurricane who began to take over/clone residents of a small Florida town, while <em>Surface</em> was also about an invasion of deep-sea creatures that want to take over the world, mwhahahaha!</p>
<p>But, like Dorothy did the Scarecrow, this is the series I miss most of all: <em>Threshold.</em></p>
<p><em>Threshold </em>was similar to the other two, but far more fascinating<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28775 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Threshold_Intertitle-300x187.png" alt="" width="300" height="187" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Threshold_Intertitle-300x187.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Threshold_Intertitle.png 400w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />. These aliens were from another dimension, see, and they plan to invade by rewriting human DNA to match their own. First contact is a weird, jagged fractal-folding-in-on-itself shape that appears over the ocean, making a noise like clashing knives; every crewmember on a nearby freighter who sees/hears it either dies, horribly disfigured, or is changed, i.e., his DNA is successfuly rewritten, and he then escapes to infect others. In other words: &#8220;we have met the enemy and he is us.&#8221;</p>
<p>Naturally, the government calls in a team of scientists to investigate this delicious weirdness. Carla Gugino, a crisis-management expert who’s written a protocol for ‘first contact’, assembles a team including a microbiologist (played by Brent Spiner, yay, Next Gen); an aerospace engineer; a muscle-with-a-gun; and my personal favorite, a linguistics and mathematics genius-with-an-attitude-and-an-alcohol-problem played by the amazing and Best-Cyrano-Ever Peter Dinklage. Amidst lots of bickering, they plunge into the investigation, and lots of fun ensues. Oh, and both Gugino and the Muscle watched a video one of the crewmen made back onboard the ship and are maybe sorta kinda possibly infected themselves.</p>
<p>This was a beautiful setup for a series, it had a strong cast and good writing, and it should, by rights, have lasted several seasons. In fact, the creators had planned more seasons, with proposed titles like <em>Foothold</em> and <em>Stronghold</em> giving us hints as to how they might go.</p>
<p>But how many episodes did I get of <em>Threshold</em>?</p>
<p>Thirteen.</p>
<p><em>Thirteen</em>, I tell you!</p>
<p>How dare they!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Baldies and Commies and Ashe and Murdock and Fox: Andre Norton’s Time Trader series</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/baldies-and-commies-and-ashe-and-murdock-and-fox-andre-nortons-time-trader-series/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 10:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the highlights of my very earliest voracious reading—I’m thinking third grade here—was the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the highlights of my very earliest voracious reading—I’m thinking third grade here—was the discovery of the concept of sequels! And prequels! And characters appearing in more than one book! (Okay, other than Dick and Jane and their bratty little sister Sally, I mean. And if you don’t get that reference, you’re obviously not as ancient as your Grey Lenswoman: congrats. I guess.)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28472 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/norton-1950-1-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/norton-1950-1-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/norton-1950-1.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>I discovered the sequel, this glory of civilization, this ultimate joy, by checking out GALACTIC DERELICT (pub. 1959) from my grammar school library one day. I devoured it, as one would expect, and happened to read in the front matter of the book—because I read every word in a book, then and now—the most beautiful of all possible words in any language: <em>Sequel to THE TIME TRADERS </em>(pub. 1958).</p>
<p>Wait, what? How long has this been going on, why did no one tell me, and where do I lay my grubby mitts on THE TIME TRADERS? I did find it, luckily for my perennially delicate sanity, and this series became one of my earliest favorites, right up there with Heinlein’s juveniles and Jules Verne.</p>
<p>Remind me to tell you how much Verne I’ve read sometime. I still have fond memories of my third-grade teacher seeing me reading TWENTY THOUSAND LEAGUES UNDER THE SEA and asking me, with some wonder I recognized later, “Are you <em>enjoying </em>that?” which in my opinion did NOT deserve a reply. I just shrugged and returned to Captain Nemo.</p>
<p>But back to THE TIME TRADERS, first in the series (!!!) by the ever-delightful Andre Norton…who had to change her name from Mary Alice since no <em>boy </em>would ever read a science fiction adventure by a <em>girl</em>, am I right? <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28473 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheTimeTraders-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheTimeTraders-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheTimeTraders.jpg 258w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" /></p>
<p>Our young hero Ross Murdock has been a bad boy and his judge gives him two choices: go straight to jail or sign up for a superdupersecret government project. Naturally, Ross signs up, hoping to pull a quick runner on the way to the project and disappear into the huge city. But the major in charge fools him, takes him straight from the courtroom to the roof of the building and slaps him in a helicopter…and from it to a supersonic jet of a design he’d never seen. Before Ross can say “This ain’t what I signed up for” he’s at a hidden base in the Arctic. There he meets Dr. Gordon Ashe, archaeologist, and a bunch of other guys dressed in historic attire: there are Mongols and Vikings and guys in furs with bronze knives—all of them speaking pretty much like Ross.</p>
<p>It turns out that the Commies—height of the Cold War, remember?—have retrieved some cool new tech from an ancient alien ship they found buried in a glacier, and much of the tech involves time travel. Our good guys managed to grab some of the tech, at least enough to construct our own portals-to-the-past, but we naturally want to find our own crashed ship on our side of the Iron Curtain to scavenge. Thus, these teams of Vikings/Mongols et al are training to fit into their time periods so they can set up bases there to look for a ship of our own to scavenge.</p>
<p>Ross trains with Dr. Ashe to pass as a Beaker tradesman and it’s off to the past for adventure and danger and everything I love. Run-ins with dastardly Commies and pissed-off aliens ensue.</p>
<p>Book two in the series, GALACTIC DERELICT, move the story to the American West and introduces a new character, Travis Fox, a Native American who was training to become an archaeologist before a run-in with a racist professor. He meets our Ross and Ashe in a canyon, where they discover Travis has an unusual talent: he can tell between an actual Clovis point as opposed to a good copy, just by holding them. Then Ashe hands him a high-tech ray gun. Travis looks confused: how can this obviously advanced tech be older than the Clovis point, used by the original North American tribes to hunt mammoth?<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28474 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/GalacticDerelict-202x300.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/GalacticDerelict-202x300.jpg 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/GalacticDerelict.jpg 262w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" /></p>
<p>Travis is sworn into the secret and joins Ross and Ashe on an important trip to the past, where a team has found a nearly intact alien scout ship on our side of the world. While setting up a time transport grid around the ship to bring it to the future/their present, thus ensuring no problems with stone age tribe members and woolly mammoths, there’s a convenient volcanic eruption—don’t you hate it when that happens? Our guys tumble into the ship, which gets energized by the time travel transportation, and takes off. Luckily, a science tech happens to be onboard, one who’s been studying what info they have on the ship.</p>
<p>Unluckily, the ship had already come into the present moment before it takes off. Now they have to follow a pre-programmed flight path…to planets fifty-to-a-hundred-thousand years-ish <em>after </em>it was originally built.</p>
<p>Norton wrote two more books in the series herself, THE DEFIANT AGENTS and THE KEY OUT OF TIME, and collaborated on several more in the next decades. But the first two are my favorites, and I’ve been in love with Dr. Gordon Ashe since I was eight.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-28475" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheDefiantAgents-193x300.jpg" alt="" width="193" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheDefiantAgents-193x300.jpg 193w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheDefiantAgents.jpg 255w" sizes="(max-width: 193px) 100vw, 193px" /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28476 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/KeyOutOfTime-201x300.jpg" alt="" width="201" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/KeyOutOfTime-201x300.jpg 201w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/KeyOutOfTime.jpg 261w" sizes="(max-width: 201px) 100vw, 201px" /></p>
<p>Time travel AND space travel? Yes, please!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SFF Movies &#8216;Based On&#8217; Books I love</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/sff-movies-based-on-books-i-love/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 10:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Movies &#8220;based on&#8221; books. Oh, as a confirmed SFF geek, where do I begin? So&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Movies &#8220;based on&#8221; books. Oh, as a confirmed SFF geek, where do I begin? So many, many bad movies made from good books. Okay, I get it: every movie can’t achieve the utter worshipful perfection of Peter Jackson’s THE LORD OF THE RINGS. But some could definitely try harder is all I’m saying.</p>
<p>Let’s start with the inimitable Andre Norton. In 1959 she published THE BEAST MASTER, book one in the tale of Hosteen Storm, a Navajo who was telepathic with several genetically-modified animals. They all get sent to an alien planet and the usual Norton hijinks ensue. Good, classic Andre Norton, am I right?  <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28582 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Beast_master-212x300.jpg" alt="" width="170" height="241" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Beast_master-212x300.jpg 212w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Beast_master.jpg 269w" sizes="(max-width: 170px) 100vw, 170px" /></p>
<p>Then why, pray tell me, oh why did the screenwriters for the 1982 THE BEASTMASTER even suggest that they &#8220;based&#8221; their story on Norton’s book? I mean, what the who? Now suddenly we have the barbarian Dar—brilliantly portrayed by Marc Singer’s pecs—who as a fetus gets magically transferred from his mama’s womb into a cow—dazzling special FX here as the cow’s belly swells—and grows up into the aforementioned bundle of pecs. Then there’s a &#8220;story&#8221; about how he meets and bonds with a big cat, a hawk, and a pair of ferrets—the ferrets being clearly the best actors in the entire movie, as I still remember their names: Kodo and Podo. There’s a big bad guy—Rip Torn in his best scenery-chewing mode—a noble black guy and a fur bikini filled with Tanya Roberts. Don’t get me wrong, I loved the movie, but it was obviously made by someone who had: 1. Never read Norton’s book, and 2. Only knew in the very vaguest fashion what constituted a good fantasy movie. Hint: it’s not pecs and a fur bikini.  <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-28584 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/TheBeastmaster-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="149" height="227" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/TheBeastmaster-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/TheBeastmaster.jpg 256w" sizes="(max-width: 149px) 100vw, 149px" /></p>
<p>However, any and all movies would be improved by the addition of a pair of ferrets—fact. TITANIC, for instance, badly needed ferrets.</p>
<p>Oh, yeah, and Andre Norton insisted her name be removed from the credits. Surprising, huh?</p>
<p>Next in this litany of infamy is the pair of movies based on John W. Campbell-writing-as-Don-A.-Stuart’s novella, &#8220;Who Goes There?&#8221; First was 1951’s THE THING FROM ANOTHER WORLD, starring pre-Gunsmoke James Arness as a vegetable alien—no, he’s not a confirmed plant eater, he’s an actual plant. The novella and the movie share a location—a claustrophobic base in the Antarctic—and a basic premise—alien ship frozen in ice inadvertently destroyed but inhabitant saved—but skips over most of the shapeshifting bit. Still, it does have a lovely sense of fear and danger and I adored it as a kid, as I uncritically adored anything faintly SFF.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28585 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who_Goes_There__John_Campbell_book_1st_edition_cover_art-205x300.jpg" alt="" width="185" height="271" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who_Goes_There__John_Campbell_book_1st_edition_cover_art-205x300.jpg 205w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who_Goes_There__John_Campbell_book_1st_edition_cover_art.jpg 263w" sizes="(max-width: 185px) 100vw, 185px" /></p>
<p>In 1982, John Carpenter directed THE THING, with a bearded Kurt Russell and a team of actors familiar from TV. This one was much, much closer to the original novella and, even though I was no longer in grammar school, I loved it. This time, as in the story, the alien can replicate others, leading to a growing sense of paranoia. Who’d human, and who’s not?</p>
<p>Great Carpenter-esque scenes of decapitated heads sprouting legs to run away from flamethrowers—honestly, does it get any better than that? And my favorite scene of all: a doctor is doing CPR and it goes terribly, terribly wrong, not only for the patient…but for the doctor. Watch it and see.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28587 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/The_Thing_1982_theatrical_poster-195x300.jpg" alt="" width="171" height="263" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/The_Thing_1982_theatrical_poster-195x300.jpg 195w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/The_Thing_1982_theatrical_poster.jpg 220w" sizes="(max-width: 171px) 100vw, 171px" /></p>
<p>Oh, and there’s a suitably depressing ending that leaves the viewer up in the air about who is still infected and who survives. Or doesn’t.</p>
<p>And finally, THE PUPPET MASTERS. Heinlein’s 1951 book is one of my favorites of his, full of thinly-disguised Commie obsession of that time period, but with some seriously kick-ass characters. And the movie wasn’t bad, don’t get me wrong. I mean, all Donald Sutherland needs to do is stand there and I’m agog. Hey, I even drop what I’m doing to listen—with varying amounts of drool—to that lovely, lovely voice pitch orange juice.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28583 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Thepuppetmastersposter-202x300.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Thepuppetmastersposter-202x300.jpg 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Thepuppetmastersposter.jpg 259w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" /></p>
<p>And Sutherland is not miscast as the head of a secret organization who’s the only one to realize Earth is being invaded and Earthlings being controlled by soul-sucking aliens that look like slugs with rather fetching whip-tails. In the book, though, one of his operators is his son, Sam, and another is a brilliant badass red-haired woman named Mary—who has an interesting backstory that plays into the denouement.</p>
<p>In the movie, Sam and Mary are played by, well, actors that don’t fit my image of the roles is all I’m going to say. Story doesn&#8217;t suck too much either.</p>
<p>Heinlein’s books deserve good movies. The closest I’ve seen is PREDESTINATION, based on his &#8220;All You Zombies.&#8221; It gets the twisty-turny-wibbly-wobbly time travel bits down. Go watch it if you haven’t seen it.</p>
<p>And watch the others too. After all, they are SFF…after a fashion.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Triffids and Krakens and Chrysalids and Cuckoos, Oh My!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/triffids-and-krakens-and-chrysalids-and-cuckoos-oh-my/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 14:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[John Wyndham Parkes Lucas Beynon Harris was an English science fiction writer who died in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://John/ Wyndham - Wikipedia">John Wyndham Parkes Lucas Beynon Harris</a> was an English science fiction writer who died in 1969. He started off writing for the pulps in the 1930s under a slew of pen names, mostly derived from his impressive and what must have been extremely useful selection of given names: John Beynon Lucas Parkes. He wrote as John B. Harris and Johnson B. Harris before finally publishing novels as John Wyndham.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-28345 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/John_Wyndham_Parkes_Lucas_Beynon_Harris.jpg" alt="" width="264" height="300" /></p>
<p>‘Cozy catastrophe’ was what Brian Aldiss termed a bunch of Wyndham’s books, meaning less Big Picture <em>boom boom Independence Day</em> <em>alien attacks end of the world aaah!</em> and more experiencing a catastrophe on an individual level and the long process of dealing with the aftereffects.</p>
<p>My first introduction to Wyndham’s work was in middle school with THE DAY OF THE TRIFFIDS, about ambulatory poison plants. Think big honkin’ Venus flytraps with an attitude: they have poison-tipped whip-like appendages and three thick roots they can scoot around on. Slow? You betcha. But if you’re trapped and can’t get away? Face it: you’re plant food.</p>
<p>Of course, when the triffids first appear, crafty corporations find out they’re useful sources of animal feed…so naturally, they start farming them, because fields and fields of six-foot tall poisonous walking plants is always a good idea. Sure, they start off removing the poison sacs…until they find out the quality of the feed declines, so they simply teach their factory farms how to ‘be careful.’ Because that always works for corporations. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28346 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/JohnWyndham_TheDayOfTheTriffids-202x300.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/JohnWyndham_TheDayOfTheTriffids-202x300.jpg 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/JohnWyndham_TheDayOfTheTriffids.jpg 259w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" /></p>
<p>But were acres of walking poison plants the catastrophe? Nah. The disaster really kicks in when the Earth enters a ‘meteor field’ that exposes everyone who’s watching to pretty green lights in the night sky. Ooh! Ahhh! Pretty lights!</p>
<p>Oops.</p>
<p>The next morning, everyone who watched the spectacle wakes up blind. The triffids escape. Cue the catastrophe.</p>
<p>THE KRAKEN WAKES is an alien invasion on a muted, very English scale. Balls of light are seen falling into the sea. A short time later, sea levels begin to rise, and heavy little armored tanks trundle onto beaches. It seems the lights were ships containing creatures that can only live under very high pressure, hence their descent into the deep sea. They’re invading to turn good old Terra into something more suitable for their needs. The protagonist is a reporter struggling to survive in a slowly flooding London.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28347 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Thekrakenwakes-202x300.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Thekrakenwakes-202x300.jpg 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Thekrakenwakes.jpg 261w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" /></p>
<p>THE CRYSALIDS is less about a catastrophe and more about its aftermath. Centuries after a nuclear holocaust, society has reverted to a medieval level, and anything mutated is considered evil-with-a-capital-E and either killed or banished—even a little girl with six toes on one foot. Pragmatically, huge horses are A-okay, as they’re useful around the farms.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28344 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Chrysalids_first_edition_1955-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Chrysalids_first_edition_1955-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Chrysalids_first_edition_1955.jpg 238w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></p>
<p>A group of children, however, have developed a mutation that isn’t visible—they’re telepaths. Cue the burning torches.</p>
<p>One of Wyndham’s most impactful books is THE MIDWICH CUCKOOS, turned to the movie(s) CHILDREN OF THE DAMNED and VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED…with varying degrees of success. Another alien invasion, but with a clever twist on the aliens’ part.</p>
<p>One day, an invisible dome settles over the small English village of Midwich. The people inside are all sprawled out as if dead, and anyone who steps inside the perimeter of the dome collapses. Twenty-four hours later, the dome dissipates and everyone who looked dead wakes up. Whew! They were just asleep all along.</p>
<p>Then every woman of childbearing age who’d been inside the dome find out she’s pregnant, regardless of her marital status…or even her virginity. Nine months later, they all give birth to eerily similar blonde kids with glowing eyes.</p>
<p>Awww, cute helpless children, right? Uh, not so much. The kids grow up fast, always travel together in a pack, show no emotions, and are able to protect themselves by mind-controlling anyone who messes with them. One guy who’d insulted them runs his car ‘accidentally’ into a tree.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28348 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheMidwichCuckoos-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheMidwichCuckoos-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheMidwichCuckoos.jpg 258w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" /></p>
<p>Oh, and apparently they can read humans’ minds. And Midwich wasn’t the only town this happened to: a native village in in the far north had stoned the mothers and their offspring as soon as they were born. And reports from Russia—the book takes place in the 1960s during the height of the Cold War—tell of a town nuked to nonexistence.</p>
<p>Neither of these would be typical English reactions to this little problem. But Wyndham’s protagonist manages to confront the issue.</p>
<p>Wyndham wrote other books, most of which I recommend mostly because I love his low-key, intimate and usually first person POV style. I think you might enjoy ‘em too. You can grab a bunch of his public domain work&#8211;Canadian public domain&#8211;at <a href="https://www.fadedpage.com/csearch.php?author=Wyndham%2C%20John">Faded Pages</a>.</p>
<p><strong>  </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keith Laumer’s Retief Stories: Why I Will Never Be Able to Stop Laughing</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/keith-laumers-retief-stories-why-i-will-never-be-able-to-stop-laughing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 10:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28144#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=28144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Keith Laumer was a science fiction writer who first started publishing in the late 1950s.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Keith Laumer was a science fiction writer who first started publishing in the late 1950s. Go check him out on Wikipedia if you need to know more: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keith_Laumer">Keith Laumer &#8211; Wikipedia</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-28148 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/KLaumerEB.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="297" /></p>
<p>It definitely had to have been Laumer’s time in the U.S. Foreign Service that primed him for what I consider one of the funniest, snarkiest, and pun-iest science fiction series ever. I laughed when I first read <em>Retief’s War</em> over fifty years ago, I laugh today when I reread it and I do not doubt, if someone is thoughtful enough to put in in my hand, I will laugh at it on my deathbed…and beyond.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Obviously, I’m here today to talk about the incomparable Jame Retief: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jame_Retief">Jame Retief &#8211; Wikipedia</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28150 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/If_196201-213x300.jpg" alt="" width="213" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/If_196201-213x300.jpg 213w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/If_196201.jpg 390w" sizes="(max-width: 213px) 100vw, 213px" /></p>
<p>Retief is the most capable, clever, and gorgeous galactic diplomat that can possibly be imagined. He was a low-level employee of the <em>Corps Diplomatique Terrestrienne</em>, the human diplomatic corps that represented Terra on dozens of both human-settled and completely worlds—and he stayed low-level throughout his service. Why, one can’t help but ask? Jame was smarter than literally everyone in the room—especially all his fellow diplomats—and was renowned for repairing the screw-ups so endemic in his organization. In stories called ‘Pime Doesn’t Cray’, ‘Retief and the Red Tape Mountain’ and ‘The Piecemakers’, he pulls figurative rabbits out of hats again and again.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">But whoa! Jame Retief never, ever, EVER gets credit for his dazzling legerdemain. His ‘superiors’ hog that, dislocating their shoulders as they pat themselves on the back. In one story called ‘Sealed Orders,’ Retief gets a sealed package of instructions from the ambassador and is sent off to clear up a snafu. Retief does, and the ambassador takes the credit, as it was obviously because his instructions were so precise and so perfect.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Retief nods, just before disposing of the—unopened—packet down the garbage chute.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28149 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/If_196207-215x300.jpg" alt="" width="215" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/If_196207-215x300.jpg 215w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/If_196207.jpg 393w" sizes="(max-width: 215px) 100vw, 215px" /></p>
<p>But my love for Retief does not include just the clever stories. As we are all well aware, I’m a sucker for puns and clever word play—and I will admit, the heavier-handed the better. How about military men named Colonel Trenchfoot and Major Faintheart? Ambassadors called Grossblunder, Gropedark, Lacklustre, Shortfall, and Swinepearl?</p>
<p>And even better, many of the stories begin with quotes from the official CDT handbook, which I picture as being a foot thick and full of the approved behavior in every conceivable situation and culture. Naturally, the handbook has a list of lettered-and numbered facial expressions and how they’re to be interpreted by colleagues. Read this quote—if you dare—and I can only hope you’re not drinking anything; I know to my keyboard’s detriment that snorted/spewed iced tea is not beneficial:</p>
<p><em>     “A most perceptive observation, Chester,” Ambassador Earlyworm said, bestowing a 24-w (Gracious Condescension) leavened with a hint of 7-y (Expectation of Great Things in Due Course) on the lucky bureaucrat, at which his fellow underlings around the table were quick to bombard him with approbation, ranging from Faintlady’s 12.7-x (Knew You Had It In You, Fella) to Felix’s more restrained 119-a (We’re All Pulling For You, Lad), to which he responded with a shy 3-v (Modest Awareness of Virtue).</em><br /><em>     “In fact,” Earlyworm interjected a Cold Return to Objectivity (91-s) into the lightning interplay of ritual grimacing…</em></p>
<p>So, political screw-ups abound. Cool aliens are either trying to run the Terries off their planet or soak them for all they can get. And the clueless CDT fall into every trap, even with their eyes wide open, since the service is full of professional butt-kissers and CYAs. Pretty much every one short of full Ambassador rank recognizes toadying as a basic survival skill. Retief&#8217;s inability to master this particular skill is one of the reasons he finds promotions so hard to come by.</p>
<p>So, get thee to some Jame Retief stories—there are several free at Gutenberg—and see if you’re made of stronger stuff than I and are able to keep from laughing.</p>
<p>I doubt it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Her Majesty the Queen of Space Opera: Part One</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/her-majesty-the-queen-of-space-opera-part-one/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/her-majesty-the-queen-of-space-opera-part-one/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Leigh Brackett will always be a name to conjure with, and not just because she&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-27711 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/WebsiteGraphic_WIDE_030521_1-300x140.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="140" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/WebsiteGraphic_WIDE_030521_1-300x140.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/WebsiteGraphic_WIDE_030521_1-1024x478.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/WebsiteGraphic_WIDE_030521_1-768x358.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/WebsiteGraphic_WIDE_030521_1.jpg 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Leigh Brackett will always be a name to conjure with, and not just because she wrote the first draft of a little movie you may have heard of called <em>The Empire Strikes Back</em>. Though she died before it went into production and hers was not the final filmed screenplay, she created many of the story beats that ended up in the movie. City in the clouds: check. Battle of Hoth: check. Deadly trip through an asteroid field: yep, it’s there. Love triangle between Luke, Leia and Han: check, check, and check.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> Brackett made her first sff sale to the Feb 1940 issue of <em>Astounding Science Fiction</em> and became one of the few—very few—big name female writers of science fiction at the time. One of the others was C.L. Moore, who’ll be the subject of a future column.</p>
<p>Leigh Brackett was born in 1915 in Los Angeles. Her father died when she was three, and Leigh and her mother moved back in with her grandfather. She described her education as ‘rather haphazard’ and, although she was offered a scholarship to college, she had to turn it down to make money writing for pulps. In a 1944 autobiographical sketch for <em>Startling Stories</em>, Leigh listed her likes as ‘Anything to do with the sea…people, the genuine kind…dogs, horses, the theater, movies, books, beer and working hard at something I enjoy doing.’ She would describe her mother as a ‘feminine, helpless little person…a lady with a capital ‘L’, and Leigh obviously despised that attitude. In one of the last interviews before her death, Leigh said: ‘I didn’t believe that you were supposed to sit waiting for a man to come along and provide you with this, that and the other. I don’t need anybody to provide for me. I’ll provide for myself.’</p>
<p>You go, girl.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Brackett put science fiction aside for a while after she published her first detective story in 1943, followed by her first hard-boiled mystery novel in 1944. <em>No Time for a Corpse </em>so impressed acclaimed director Howard Hawks that he had his secretary call and request ‘that guy Brackett’ to help him with the screenplay for <em>The Big Sleep</em>, with William Faulkner as her cowriter, and Bogart and Bacall as stars.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-27713 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Bigsleep2-300x238.jpg" alt="" width="258" height="205" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Bigsleep2-300x238.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Bigsleep2-1024x811.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Bigsleep2-768x608.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Bigsleep2.jpg 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 258px) 100vw, 258px" /></p>
<p>In 1946, after Brackett married fellow pulp writer Edmond Hamilton—Ray Bradbury was their best man—Brackett left screenwriting for a while and returned to science fiction. She created Eric John Stark in 1949, a black-skinned orphan raised by an indigenous tribe on Mercury. Apparently, no cover artist read her descriptions of Stark: Erik John was consistently shown as the strapping Caucasian hero, par for the course in that time. After the Mariner Mission confirmed that Mars was not inhabited or inhabitable, Brackett didn’t even slow down on the Stark stories: she just transposed him to another solar system. Her last Stark, ‘Stark and the Star Kings’, put Erik John in the world created by her husband. Some of the Stark stories are: “Queen of the Martian Catacombs’, ‘City of the Lost’, ‘Black Amazon of Mars’, and ‘Enchantress of Venus.&#8217;<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27712 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/51F6Er4K4VL-210x300.jpg" alt="" width="210" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/51F6Er4K4VL-210x300.jpg 210w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/51F6Er4K4VL.jpg 350w" sizes="(max-width: 210px) 100vw, 210px" /></p>
<p>I defy you to think of pulpier titles. Go ahead and try. I’ll wait.</p>
<p>In the mid-1950s, Brackett returned to writing screenplays for TV and movies, including several westerns for Howard Hawks: <em>Rio Bravo</em>, <em>El Dorado</em>, and <em>Rio Lobo</em>. Later, she and Lawrence Kasdan shared credit for the screenplay of <em>Raiders of the Lost Ark. </em></p>
<p>Obviously, Brackett’s range was extraordinary. She was a member of the <em>Mystery Writers of America</em>, the <em>Western Writers of America</em>, and <em>the Science Fiction Writers of America, </em>plus the <em>Writers Guild</em> and the <em>Television Academy of Arts and Sciences. </em>Her novel <em>Shadow over Mars </em>won the Retro Hugo Award for 1945.</p>
<p>When George Lucas offered Brackett the screenplay for <em>The Empire Strikes Back, </em>she knew she was already dying from cancer. She put aside her final Eric John Stark novel to work on the screenplay. Frederik Pohl, science fiction writer and editor, speculated as to why:</p>
<p><em>    ‘I think she was aware that what Lucas was doing was taking the science fiction pulp stories of the 30s and 40s and putting them on the screen, and of course Leigh was there, she was part of that. The two things she was really good at: science fiction and screenwriting, and for the first time in her life, they went together.’</em></p>
<p>Yeah. They did.</p>
<p>Leigh Brackett, Queen of Space Opera. And mysteries. And westerns. A role model for the ages.</p>
<p>Next month I’ll do a deep dive into the Skaith/Eric John Stark stories.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/her-majesty-the-queen-of-space-opera-part-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Which Is the What of the I and the Me: Part Two</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/which-is-the-what-of-the-i-and-the-me-part-two/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last time, I discussed my love for the ‘Who am I, really?” theme in books:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last time, I discussed my love for the ‘Who am I, really?” theme in books: specifically, the Person One taking over the role of Person Two scenario, with varying degrees of success—success for the people doing the taking over, I mean, and not my description. I hope. This time, I’m going to talk about what I consider an offshoot of the ‘Who am I’ theme: a person waking up with amnesia and being immediately plunged into danger and excitement while struggling to keep up, find out stuff, and stay alive. Let’s call it Person One struggling to play the role of, well, Person One.</p>
<p>I’m a big fan of classic mysteries and one of my favorite writers in this field is Margery Allingham, often listed with Dorothy L. Sayers and Agatha Christie as one of the Queens of Classic Crime. Allingham had a long-running series about her detective Albert Campion, from the late 1920s to well after World War II; the series is still ongoing with a different writer. My favorite book in the series is TRAITOR’S PURSE. Albert often comes across in his early adventures as how he’s described more than once, a silly ass. Being a mystery, this façade just covers his real brilliance. But he does mature, and TRAITOR’S PURSE slams him slap into the Second World War. And I&#8217;m not talking the battlefields-and-weapons kind of war, but the secret, subversive, underground kind of war.  <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27456 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/TraitorsPurse-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/TraitorsPurse-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/TraitorsPurse.jpg 328w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" /></p>
<p>A man wakes in hospital with his head bandaged and no memory of who he is—just an intense feeling that he’s got to stop something seriously bad or England will lose the war. Also, he suspects he may have murdered someone. He blunders around, all his friends depending on him, while he gradually figures stuff out. Oh, and he’s pretty sure he’s lost the love of his life by being his usual, silly-ass self. It’s a good story, where the detective IS the mystery.</p>
<p>Another favorite writer of mine is Manning Coles. Adelaide Manning and Cyril Coles collaborated on a series of light-hearted—well, the first one was pretty intense—clever and snarky spy stories about Thomas Elphinstone Hambledon. Tommy pops up first in DRINK TO YESTERDAY—the intense one—then reappears in A TOAST TO TOMORROW.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27457 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/toast-211x300.jpg" alt="" width="211" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/toast-211x300.jpg 211w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/toast.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 211px) 100vw, 211px" /></p>
<p>Right before the end of World War One, a man is rescued from a burning German ship with the inevitable head wound. He’s wearing a high-ranking military uniform so gets sent to a Berlin hospital, wakes up with the inevitable amnesia and is sent out to the world. The Great War ends, he goes through the bad years and gets involved with a guy called Adolf Hitler—he doesn’t like the little creep, but he knows Germany needs a leader. After a few years, our amnesiac ends up as the Chief of Police in Berlin. Cue the Reichstag fire, which brings up a stressful moment in his past. The Chief of Police remembers who he is: Tommy Hambledon, a British agent. Woohoo, he thinks, this is wicked cool—well, he thinks it in much more 1930s British slang terms, like ‘By Jove!’ or some such. And he spends the rest of the book messing with England’s secret service while he works to take down Adolf and his buddies. I love this book and all the Hambledon stories.</p>
<p>By far my favorite amnesia stories is Roger Zelazny’s first book in his ten-volume epic fantasy series THE CHRONICLES OF AMBER. I know every self-respecting fantasy reader knows this series by heart, but bear with me.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27455 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Nine_princes_in_amber-191x300.jpg" alt="" width="191" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Nine_princes_in_amber-191x300.jpg 191w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Nine_princes_in_amber.jpg 253w" sizes="(max-width: 191px) 100vw, 191px" /></p>
<p>Book one in the Chronicles is NINE PRINCES IN AMBER. A man wakes in hospital—are we sensing a theme here?—with no memory of who he is or why he’s there. Luckily, his underlying subconscious sneakiness keeps him just barely in front of destruction as he lies to his captors and, later, his siblings. See, Carl Corey is really Corwin, a Prince of Amber. And Amber is the real world, of which Earth and all the other worlds are mere shadows.</p>
<p>Corwin manages to find a way to get his memories—all his memories—back and plunges into all sorts of other endeavors. This is volume one of a 10-part series, after all. But I love the way Zelazny shows us how, even with no memory, the original personality is there, submerged and directing things. Who are we without our memories? Corwin, for one, is the same person he is with his memories.</p>
<p>I don’t need to tell you what a brilliant writer Zelazny is, and I really like his other work, LORD OF LIGHT especially. But NINE PRINCES was my introduction to him, and I fell on it with glee, not only because it&#8217;s everything I love&#8211;1st person, snarky narrator with few redeeming social qualities&#8211;but also when I saw how it derived from some of my earlier favorite books.</p>
<p>So, have your main character lose her/his memory. I’m pretty sure amnesia would suck, but it makes for great storytelling.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Which Is the What of the I and the Me: Part One</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/which-is-the-what-of-the-i-and-the-me-part-one/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am a sucker for books that no one reads anymore, and I will doubtless&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am a sucker for books that no one reads anymore, and I will doubtless bend your ear in future about many of them. One of my particular favorite themes is a story about Person One taking the place of Person Two for some reason: to save the country; to save a life; or sometimes, just because they can. Though it usually turns out to be something more, or other than, fun. It’s what I call the ‘Who am I, really?’ theme.</p>
<p>First, Mark Twain’s <em>The Prince and the Pauper</em>. Set in England in the sixteenth century, it’s about a peasant boy swapping places with Prince Edward VI, Henry VIII’s boy. The real prince gets to dash about the countryside and have the adventures he’s always dreamed of, while Tom Canty gets to eat regularly and spends his time cracking walnuts with the Great Seal of England. Fun.</p>
<p>Next, we move to the nineteenth century and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthony_Hope">Anthony Hope’</a>s <em>The Prisoner of Zenda</em>. Adventure—sensing a theme here?—romance and derring-do. I am a sucker for derring-do and does it not sound cool? Okay, Zenda: it seems, back in the day, an Englishman had some adventures in Ruritania, an imaginary kingdom based on one of those European principalities which proliferated before the Franco-Prussian War gave Prussia the opportunity to corral them all into the German Empire. A descendant of that original roving Englishman ends up looking exactly like the crown prince of Ruritania and is cajoled, persuaded, and sweet-talked—“Consider your honor, sir!” harumph harumph—into standing in for the kidnapped prince at his coronation. “It’ll only be for a few days, honest,” the good guys tell him.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27248 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Zenda1_Gibson-191x300.jpg" alt="" width="191" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Zenda1_Gibson-191x300.jpg 191w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Zenda1_Gibson.jpg 323w" sizes="(max-width: 191px) 100vw, 191px" /></p>
<p>A few days stretch out a bit longer and our Honorable Englishman ends up having to marry the Princess Flavia. He and the princess then proceed to fall in love, but when the real prince finally shows up, she gives up her English love. For honor. Flavia, girl, what were you thinking? I mean, the real prince is a creep. But that’s honor for you, not to mention Englishmen during the Empire. In books, anyway.</p>
<p>On to our next Englishman: this book is set a bit later, as in right before The Great War. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/E._Phillips_Oppenheim">E. Phillips Oppenheim</a> wrote a bunch of adventure novels, of which his best known is probably <em>The Great Impersonation</em>. It’s 1913-ish and Everard Dominey—which I think you’ll agree is the most English name it’s possible to conceive—has left England for the wilds of Africa after an unmentionable badness happened back home. Yep. His honor again. He has seriously let himself go when he stumbles into the tent of a German and, vast surprise and plot twist: he and the German, Baron Leopold von Ragastein, who’s been exiled for killing his lover’s husband, could be twins.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27252 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gi-208x300.jpg" alt="" width="208" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gi-208x300.jpg 208w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gi.jpg 318w" sizes="(max-width: 208px) 100vw, 208px" /></p>
<p>The crafty Baron goes all broody and thoughtful and realizes this is an opportunity to insert himself into the middle of English society, sort of a sleeper agent in a country he knows will oppose his own if/when a big war starts. He consults with his doctor/secret agent buddy; they send poor Everard into the jungle, with plans to murder him so the German can take over his identity</p>
<p>Cut to England a few months later and, taa daa, Sir Everard has returned home. Everyone, friends and family, is surprised at how gosh darn good he’s looking, though he’s a bit stiffer and, uh, more military than they recall. Only his poor wife thinks he may be Someone Else, but she’s been in a sanitarium as a result of that aforementioned badness, so no one takes her seriously. Of course it’s Everard; who else could he be, right? Then all sorts of shenanigans—there’s a word we don’t use enough—ensue before the exciting denouement.</p>
<p>Now, lest you think I’ve forgotten about speculative fiction, which is in face impossible: my favorite of the Person-One-pretending-to-be-Person Two batch: Robert A. Heinlein’s <em>Double Star</em>, which won the Hugo for Best Novel in 1957. This book ranks high in my personal Heinlein pantheon, which consists of literally every Heinlein. Jo Walton says in her blog that Heinlein’s &#8220;ability to write a sentence that makes you want to read the next sentence is unparalleled&#8221; and lordy, lordy, as we say in the South, ain’t that the truth?<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27251 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Double_Star_first_edition_cover-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Double_Star_first_edition_cover-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Double_Star_first_edition_cover.jpg 259w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></p>
<p>In this jewel of a book, the not-as-good-as-he-thinks-he-is actor Larry Smythe aka The Great Lorenzo is asked to play the role of Joseph Bonforte, a political big wheel who’s been kidnapped right before an important meeting with some Martians. To miss that meeting could cause chaos in the solar system. Larry agrees, even though he has this horrible aversion to the way Martians smell. Getting that little problem solved is one of my favorite parts.</p>
<p>Adventure, romance, and an interesting ending, which I won’t spoil for you. Actually, yes I will; if you haven’t read <em>Double Star</em> yet, then why shouldn’t I add to your overwhelming burden of shame? See, they get Bonforte back but the stress is too much for him, and Larry has to take over the role again. Permanently.</p>
<p>It’s a beauty of a book and go read it right now. I’ll wait.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best Role Models Ever</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/best-role-models-ever/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/best-role-models-ever/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a child growing up in the fifties—yes, I am officially an old lady or,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a child growing up in the fifties—yes, I am officially an old lady or, as I prefer to think of myself, a quantum crone—I didn’t have any progressive female role models on TV or in the movies. I was an early reader: Jules Verne in the third grade, followed by Andre Norton’s Time Traders and Heinlein’s juveniles right afterwards, not to mention every single comic book and science fiction mag I could con my folks out of. So, there I was, reading voraciously and all primed and ready to go forth and conquer the Universe, while still getting home before dark, and what do I see in the media? Nice ladies in dresses and white gloves, doing…housework. Huh. Something was wrong here, I thought.</p>
<p>Then, they appeared, those glorious goddesses who still influence me to this day. The two most powerful women of 50s TV: strong, smart, competent, intelligent, and taking no crap from anyone, anywhere, even if he had superpowers or wore a pith helmet.</p>
<p>The two women who made me what I am today: Lois Lane. And Sheena, Queen of the Jungle.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27156 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/1607661771_6c15534_Sheena_Queen_of_the_Jungle1955_1252-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/1607661771_6c15534_Sheena_Queen_of_the_Jungle1955_1252-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/1607661771_6c15534_Sheena_Queen_of_the_Jungle1955_1252-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/1607661771_6c15534_Sheena_Queen_of_the_Jungle1955_1252-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/1607661771_6c15534_Sheena_Queen_of_the_Jungle1955_1252.jpg 1252w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><em>Sheena, Queen of the Jungle</em> had a brief, single season run in 1955-56, based on the Fiction House comic of the same name that began publication in 1938. Sheena was played by statuesque—that’s what they called it, back in the day—blonde actress <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Irish_McCalla">Irish McCalla</a>. Sheena swung through trees. She had a pet chimp. She rescued her ‘boyfriend’ Bob almost every week. Hey, she carried a knife in her belt and her bikini was made of skins. So, basically, the perfect woman, or so my five-year-old self thought. This was what I wanted to be when I grew up. So intensely did she influence me, I still make most of my main characters tall and blonde and powerful, nearly seventy years later. They seldom wear skin bikinis, sure, leaning more towards brooding black leathers and bristling with blades. Or ray guns. But the concept holds: strong women.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-27157 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/images-1.jpg" alt="" width="260" height="194" /></p>
<p>Oddly, my mom wouldn’t get me my requested skin bikini for Christmas—though I did get a cowboy hat and guns with holsters, since Westerns were big in the 50s.</p>
<p>But hold the phone; not so fast. Sure, Sheena could handle herself in a fight. Okay, she could whip anyone, anywhere. And did I mention: chimp? But her conversational style ranged from ‘Men bad.’ To ‘Bob safe?’ While pithy and to the point, her repartee didn’t exactly dazzle, and recall, I was a brainy reader as well as an adventure-loving…okay, reader. What about my more cerebral side?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-27158 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Noel_Neill_Superman_1948.jpg" alt="" width="220" height="194" /></p>
<p>Enter <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noel_Neill">Lois Lane</a>. Sure, she’d been in the comics I’d been devouring from the time I could only look at the pictures, i.e., the age of two, but to see her, in all her glory as depicted by Noel Neill in both the two serials with Kirk Allyn and the TV series with George Reeves…well. Here was a role model for the ages. Smart, sassy, spunky, surpassing every male around her in wit, style, and sheer ability, Lois Lane was a true goddess in a perky hat and a business suit. And you cannot convince me that she seriously never really figured out Clark and Supe were two separate guys, never connected the two. No way, no how; she just played along with the guy, helping him believe he was clever enough to pull the wool over her eyes. Lois: clever, competent, <em>and </em>kind. <em>That</em> is what we all should aspire to be.<em> That</em> is something to strive for.</p>
<p><em>Adventures of Superman</em>—yes, I can recite the words to the intro at the drop of Lois’s hat—was on TV from 1952 to 1958. In the first season Lois was played by Phyllis Coates, but Noel Neill took over in all succeeding seasons, no doubt because she had originated the role in the two prior Columbia Pictures serials.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-27159 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/images-2.jpg" alt="" width="256" height="197" /></p>
<p>So, whatever you may have heard about the dearth of strong female role models in the 1950s, that’s not technically true. Yes, women in commercials wore heels while mopping their kitchens and worried a little too much about their husbands’ collars—the dreaded ‘ring around’, for example—but not all women had such concerns. Sheena was busy saving Bob and outwitting poachers, with a chimp on her hip and a knife in her hand. Lois was girl-reportering left, right, and center, and messing with Clark about how dreamy Superman was, always with a knowing twinkle in her eye.</p>
<p>I can’t see either Sheena or Lois holding a mop or worrying about collars. Must be why I never have.</p>
<p>I still haven’t got my chimp, though…</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/best-role-models-ever/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
