<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>YA Girl &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/ya-girl/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 04:02:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tickled Pink for Turning Red</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/tickled-pink-for-turning-red/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 10:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[YA Girl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I will admit: when the trailer for Pixar&#8217;s new movie Turning Red came out, I was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I will admit: when the trailer for Pixar&#8217;s new movie <em>Turning Red </em>came out, I was less than enthused. I just didn&#8217;t see the appeal of yet another movie where a character of color turns into an animal. But I&#8217;m so glad I gave this movie a chance, because I absolutely loved it and I do not vibe with all the criticism it&#8217;s been getting. <em>Turning Red </em>has an all-women leadership team; it&#8217;s the <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27282 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/joshua-j-cotten-e8t9o3eJ36o-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/joshua-j-cotten-e8t9o3eJ36o-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/joshua-j-cotten-e8t9o3eJ36o-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/joshua-j-cotten-e8t9o3eJ36o-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/joshua-j-cotten-e8t9o3eJ36o-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/joshua-j-cotten-e8t9o3eJ36o-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/joshua-j-cotten-e8t9o3eJ36o-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1706w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />first of Pixar&#8217;s films to be directed solely by a woman, Domee Shi, who also wrote it. A Women&#8217;s History Month win! We need to uplift marginalized voices, not criticize them for not being &#8220;perfect.&#8221; In my opinion, <em>Turning Red </em>is perfect anyway.</p>
<p>For all those who say this movie is not relatable, I ask, haven&#8217;t you ever been thirteen? Haven&#8217;t you ever gone through the experience of growing up? It shouldn&#8217;t matter if you&#8217;re not a Chinese-Canadian girl. Maybe we haven&#8217;t all turned into giant red pandas, but aside from that, Meilin&#8217;s story is one of the most relatable I can think of. She loves her mom and loves spending time with her, but she&#8217;s growing up. She wants to spend more time with her friends and she&#8217;s developing interests and ideas that her mom doesn&#8217;t approve of. It&#8217;s normal for kids to feel confused about who they&#8217;re becoming, wanting to be their own person but still wanting their family&#8217;s approval.</p>
<p>For all those who say this movie is cringe, again I ask, haven&#8217;t you ever been thirteen?? Teenage girls are often ridiculed by society (hence the criticism of this movie&#8230;) but there&#8217;s something so joyful in seeing them geek out about what they love. In <em>Turning Red</em> Meilin and her friends are obsessed with the boyband 4*Town and will stop at nothing to make it to their concert. It brought me so much joy to see them fangirl so hard because I fangirled about stuff just as hard when I was that age. Heck, I still go hard for the stuff I love. There shouldn&#8217;t be an age limit on being an avid fan. Meilin and her friends are totally justified in their love for 4*Town, anyway. I can&#8217;t stop jamming to their songs, and if 4*Town was real I would be dying to go to one of their concerts.</p>
<p>As for Meilin turning into a red panda, I think there&#8217;s a difference from other media with this trope because at least Meilin doesn&#8217;t stay a panda for the majority of the movie. The backstory behind the red panda transformation is pretty awesome, too. A certain part at the end having to do with the red panda transformation actually moved me to tears. And you know what&#8230;red panda Meilin is just really cute!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Re-Review: Edward Scissorhands</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/re-review-edward-scissorhands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 11:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[YA Girl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Edward Scissorhands takes place around Christmas, so it&#8217;s technically a Christmas movie, right? Not that I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26541 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/naomi-o-hare-ZxrKugW-6Eg-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/naomi-o-hare-ZxrKugW-6Eg-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/naomi-o-hare-ZxrKugW-6Eg-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/naomi-o-hare-ZxrKugW-6Eg-unsplash-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/naomi-o-hare-ZxrKugW-6Eg-unsplash-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/naomi-o-hare-ZxrKugW-6Eg-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Scissorhands">Edward Scissorhands</a> </em>takes place around Christmas, so it&#8217;s technically a Christmas movie, right? Not that I need an excuse to watch this old favorite, but that&#8217;s what I told myself as I decided what to watch the other night. I&#8217;ve loved this movie since I was a kid, seeing a little bit of myself in Edward, forever out of place with the cookie cutter suburbia he inhabited. And I still really enjoy it, from the brilliant acting to the perfect costume designs and spot-on social commentary. Now that I&#8217;m older, and know more about writing, I have a new appreciation for the fairytale elements of the film. However, there are two things that really bothered me after my recent rewatch: the romance and the ending.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll start with the romance. It&#8217;s no surprise <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/keep-your-amatonormativity-away-from-my-dragon/">how I feel about amatonormativity</a>. Is there anything wrong with Edward falling in love with Kim? No, of course not. But really, what was the &#8220;love&#8221; built on? Her beauty? When Edward first sees Kim&#8217;s picture, we, the viewers, automatically know he&#8217;s fallen in love with her because he can&#8217;t tear his eyes away from her image. There&#8217;s also the romantic music that accompanies the scene. So what we&#8217;re meant to wonder for the rest of the movie is: will this outcast get the girl? Except my question this time around was, <em>why </em>did he get the girl? Kim was never really nice or welcoming to him until after he was caught &#8220;breaking into&#8221; her boyfriend Jim&#8217;s house. That&#8217;s the turning point in their relationship, where she starts to be kinder to Edward and sees Jim for the selfish jerk he really is. But they never actually talk much, and when they do they never have an actual conversation. So what does Edward love about Kim? And what does Kim love about Edward? She doesn&#8217;t like him at first, asking her mom why he has to live with them. Also, she&#8217;s seventeen. I suppose it doesn&#8217;t have to be realistic, but the romance didn&#8217;t convince me the second time around.</p>
<p>I was much more interested in the relationship between Edward and Peg, and I wish the movie had explored that more. Peg is a housewife in this boring suburban community, but in a way she&#8217;s a little bit of an outsider herself. No one wants to buy any of her Avon products, and they either don&#8217;t answer the door when she comes calling or straight up tell her to go away. Then we have Edward, whose first words to her are &#8220;Don&#8217;t go.&#8221; She&#8217;s the first person he&#8217;s come into contact with since his creator died, and she&#8217;s the one person who, in my opinion, truly cared about him. No one would have blamed her for running for the hills after encountering Edward in his dark, desolate attic, but instead she gently applied astringent to his face. While the rest of the neighborhood saw him as a shiny new toy, she was always encouraging his happiness and insisting he was special not because of his scissor hands, but because of who he was. When the rest of the neighborhood turned on Edward, Peg stood by him, insisting on having a Christmas party and acting like everything was normal.</p>
<p>What struck me the most, though, was the scene where Peg and Kim are sitting on the couch together, waiting for Peg&#8217;s husband Bill to come home with runaway Edward. She says,</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;You know, when I brought Edward down here to live with us, I really didn&#8217;t think things through. And I didn&#8217;t think about what could happen to him, or to us, or to the neighborhood. You know, I think that maybe it might be best if he goes back up there. Because at least there he&#8217;s safe, and we&#8217;d just go back to normal.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>This scene reveals that, although Peg does care about Edward, she still sees him as an oddity, something that can just go away and be forgotten. Her suggestion that he just go back to his dusty mansion to be alone, so that he can be &#8220;safe&#8221;, seems really unfair to me. I guess that&#8217;s the point of the movie&#8217;s theme, that in such a conformist society those that stick out must be punished, but I can&#8217;t help but wish for a better ending for Edward. All he wanted was to be loved and accepted. He&#8217;s not a bad person. In fact, he&#8217;s a better person than the people living below<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26542 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/matt-forster-fJ4LbppCkn4-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/matt-forster-fJ4LbppCkn4-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/matt-forster-fJ4LbppCkn4-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/matt-forster-fJ4LbppCkn4-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/matt-forster-fJ4LbppCkn4-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/matt-forster-fJ4LbppCkn4-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> him in the neighborhood. So why does he have to be alone? Because he&#8217;s different? Because he has to carve ice sculptures and make it snow for eternity?</p>
<p>I still have a soft spot for this movie, but I don&#8217;t know if I can watch it again without feeling confused about its narrative. Edward&#8217;s mansion is a constant, looming presence over the neighborhood, so I don&#8217;t see how anyone could forget about him just because he went away. Nothing was stopping Kim, or even Peg, from going up there to see him. What do you think? Did Edward deserve a better ending? Or should I just be quiet and accept the fairytale-esque story the movie tried to tell? No matter what, I&#8217;ll always be wishing for more Peg/Edward platonic love forever.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hazel&#8217;s Theory of Hitting Me in the Feels</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hazels-theory-of-hitting-me-in-the-feels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[YA Girl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s no secret that asexual representation in media is few and far between. Ace characters&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_25835" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25835" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-25835 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Asexuality_Pride_Library_Logo-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Asexuality_Pride_Library_Logo-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Asexuality_Pride_Library_Logo-1024x1024.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Asexuality_Pride_Library_Logo-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Asexuality_Pride_Library_Logo-768x768.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Asexuality_Pride_Library_Logo-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Asexuality_Pride_Library_Logo.png 1250w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25835" class="wp-caption-text">Hafuboti, CC BY-SA 4.0 <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0</a> via Wikimedia Commons</figcaption></figure>
<p>It&#8217;s no secret that <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/asexual-main-characters-in-speculative-fiction/">asexual representation</a> in media is few and far between. Ace characters tend to be on my radar, yet somehow I went into my most recent read completely oblivious as to what was in store. Yes, <em><a href="https://lisajennbigelow.com/books/hazels-theory-of-evolution/">Hazel&#8217;s Theory of Evolution</a> </em>by Lisa Jenn Bigelow is categorized under the asexual tag on Goodreads, but somehow I missed that. Going in unaware of Hazel&#8217;s asexuality made my reading experience that much better, though. It made the story more authentic and relatable for me. When Hazel begs her moms to sign the waiver for sex ed because she feels uncomfortable at the thought of ever having sex someday, I thought, this can&#8217;t be what I think it is? One of her moms gives Hazel a significant look, and at the end of the book the topic is revisited in such a heartwarming and validating way that I may have shed a few tears. In this middle grade realistic fiction book with sapphic mothers and a trans girl, I never expected there to be a conversation about being valid for not wanting to date, have sex, or get married when you grow up. As someone who didn&#8217;t realize I was ace until I was in my 20s, I can&#8217;t help but wish this book had been around when I was 13, like Hazel. It might have helped me realize what I was feeling, or wasn&#8217;t feeling, a lot sooner. But I am grateful this book exists now, for all the ace kids on the cusp of puberty and all the messy, confusing feelings that come with it. It&#8217;s so easy to get caught up in what the other kids around you are feeling that your own feelings can end up getting mixed up, too. Having a character like Hazel, who sticks to her own convictions and doesn&#8217;t try to change who she is to fit in, is an important character for kids to have.</p>
<p>The ace and other queer representation in this book wasn&#8217;t the only thing I loved about it, of course! Ace or not, Hazel&#8217;s story was super easy for me to relate to. At her old school, Hazel was seen as the weird &#8220;Goat Girl&#8221; (because she lives on a goat farm) with only her best friend Becca on her side. When she&#8217;s forced to go to a new school for eighth grade, the only thing she has to look forward to is hers and Becca&#8217;s sleepover traditions. But as Becca&#8217;s social life starts to blossom and Hazel&#8217;s family&#8217;s situation takes a toll on her emotions, the two girls begin to drift apart. I may have shed some more tears when Hazel and Becca have a particularly brutal conversation, where Hazel reminds Becca that she promised they&#8217;d always be best friends, and Becca admits maybe she shouldn&#8217;t have promised that. Society places a large emphasis on how much breakups suck and how to move on, but no one ever talks about friendship breakups.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25836 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/bailey-mahon-AlfgSap679Y-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/bailey-mahon-AlfgSap679Y-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/bailey-mahon-AlfgSap679Y-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/bailey-mahon-AlfgSap679Y-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/bailey-mahon-AlfgSap679Y-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/bailey-mahon-AlfgSap679Y-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> Losing a best friend is just as painful as the end of a romantic relationship, and while I wasn&#8217;t glad the two girls in the book were losing their precious friendship, I am glad that this book touched on that topic.</p>
<p><em>Hazel&#8217;s Theory of Evolution </em>has ups (Hazel makes some new friends, and they are funny and caring and awesome) and downs (Hazel spends the whole book repressing her emotions because she&#8217;s terrified that one of her mothers, who&#8217;s pregnant, might have another miscarriage) and touches on topics that real kids experience but that we don&#8217;t often see in media. Hazel&#8217;s voice comes across as authentic, too. Some middle grade can read as though the reader is being talked down to, but Bigelow really nailed the perspective of a thirteen-year-old girl in an emotional tumult. If you&#8217;re looking for more ace representation, or even if you&#8217;re not, this is a great book to add to anyone&#8217;s reading list!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: The Kyoshi Novels</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-kyoshi-novels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 16:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[YA Girl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last summer I wrote about how underrated I felt Suki is in Avatar: The Last Airbender.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/avatars-underrated-mvp/">Last summer</a> I wrote about how underrated I felt Suki is in <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender</em>. Fearsome<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25364 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/julius-yls-5wRzDAuhLR4-unsplash-300x201.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="201" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/julius-yls-5wRzDAuhLR4-unsplash-300x201.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/julius-yls-5wRzDAuhLR4-unsplash-1024x685.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/julius-yls-5wRzDAuhLR4-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/julius-yls-5wRzDAuhLR4-unsplash-1536x1027.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/julius-yls-5wRzDAuhLR4-unsplash-2048x1369.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> leader of the Kyoshi Warriors, she proved that girls can be tough and soft at the same time. She and the other Warriors leave a lasting impression, with their dramatic white and red makeup, heavy outfits, and unique style of fighting with fans. All of these traditions are modeled after Avatar Kyoshi, their namesake and founder of their home island. Not much is known about her in the show, aside from the fact that she singlehandedly created an island while protecting her home from a tyrant, who then fell to his death, leading people to believe she was a cold-blooded murderer. She also gave the advice to Aang that only justice will bring peace, and that she would have done whatever it took to protect her home. This led to her reputation in the fandom as being a tough as nails, no-nonsense Avatar who would rather aim a flying rock at your head than try to negotiate.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve always wanted to know more about Kyoshi, since I&#8217;m a sucker for large women who kick ass. Thankfully, there are <a href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/series/2436">two novels</a> that tell her origin story: <em>The Rise of Kyoshi</em> and its sequel <em>The Shadow of Kyoshi</em>, both by <a href="http://www.fcyee.com/">F.C. Yee</a>. The first book follows Kyoshi&#8217;s path to discovering she&#8217;s the Avatar, and the second follows her path to finding her own Avatar way, while also dealing with consequences from her past lives. Yee worked closely with Michael Dante DiMartino, one of the creators of <em>Avatar</em>, so the series felt true to the source material. It was also really cool to see how the world of <em>Avatar </em>looked before Aang&#8217;s time, well before the Hundred Year War and demise of the Air Nomads. Every mention of flying bisons threw me for a loop because everyone was so casual about it, but during Kyoshi&#8217;s time, of course it wouldn&#8217;t have been rare to see them.</p>
<p>What really kept me hooked was seeing how Yee took what we already knew about Kyoshi (her makeup, outfit, fans, etc.) and crafted their origins in ways I never would have expected. Her iconic makeup wasn&#8217;t even her idea; it came from a band of criminals that doubled as opera performers. Who would have guessed that? After parting ways with the criminals, she keeps using the makeup and feels that she can only truly do her Avatar duties while wearing it. Something that was passed down through history to the Kyoshi Warriors began as a way to hide the Avatar&#8217;s insecurities.</p>
<p>Which is probably what I liked best about these books: Kyoshi is far from perfect. In the show, the glimpses we get of Kyoshi are that of a confident, powerful, established Avatar. In the books, she starts off timid and tries to shrink herself down to attract less attention. It&#8217;s gratifying to see her come into her own, embrace her full height and power and start to become the fierce Avatar we know she ends up becoming. But still, she messes up a lot. As much as I enjoyed seeing her threaten the lives of horrible world leaders who definitely deserved it, those kinds of actions hold consequences, even for the Avatar. I liked following her journey from becoming a clueless kid who thinks she can brute force her way through any situation, into a thoughtful Avatar who comes up with clever plans (while still relying on brute force to get results, of course!).</p>
<p>Oh, and a nice bonus: Kyoshi is canonically bisexual!</p>
<p>Any fans of <em>Avatar </em>will definitely enjoy this series, and the two books make for an excellent quick summer read!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wolfwalkers!!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/wolfwalkers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 12:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[YA Girl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This one&#8217;s for all the wolf girls out there. A lot can be said about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This one&#8217;s for all the wolf girls out there.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24346 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/federico-di-dio-photography-9y-XkkOk2XI-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/federico-di-dio-photography-9y-XkkOk2XI-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/federico-di-dio-photography-9y-XkkOk2XI-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/federico-di-dio-photography-9y-XkkOk2XI-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/federico-di-dio-photography-9y-XkkOk2XI-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/federico-di-dio-photography-9y-XkkOk2XI-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>A lot can be said about the overabundance of streaming channels nowadays, but I recently came in to a free year of Apple TV+ and of course I had to immediately watch <em>Wolfwalkers</em>. <a href="https://www.cartoonsaloon.ie/">Cartoon Saloon</a> is an Irish animation studio that&#8217;s constantly on my radar. They produced one of my all-time favorite movies, <em>Song of the Sea</em>, and consistently deliver with stories that are entertaining, emotional, and well-written, as well as visually stunning. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolfwalkers"><em>Wolfwalkers</em></a>, the newest addition to their lineup, is no exception. Set in Kilkenny, Ireland, in the 1650s, the plot follows young English girl Robyn Goodfellowe adapting to the strict rules of her new home while her father Bill is tasked with exterminating the wolf pack outside of town. The only problem is that Robyn isn&#8217;t content to be a scullery maid; she&#8217;s imaginative, adventurous, and wants nothing more than to help her father hunt the wolves. So she does what any rebellious young adventurer would do: sneaks out of town into the woods. There she learns that there&#8217;s more to this wolf pack than meets the eye.</p>
<p>One of this movie&#8217;s strong suits is the contrast between the settings. We have the strict, regimented Kilkenny, where Robyn is forced to be someone she doesn&#8217;t want to be. She and her father are looked down upon because they&#8217;re English, the Lord Protector is a colonizing asshat, and Robyn isn&#8217;t listened to because she&#8217;s a girl. Then there&#8217;s the forest, where everything is beautiful and magical. Robyn is free and happy, and accepted by her new friend Mebh. This is even reflected in the animation itself. Everyone and everything associated with the town is drawn with crisp, rigid lines, while the forest is blurred and soft, with the sketch lines still showing. As the story progresses, Robyn herself becomes softer as she embraces her new wilder, freer self.</p>
<p>Another win for this movie is Robyn and Mebh&#8217;s friendship. Despite the fact that they should be enemies, Mebh actually wins Robyn over pretty quickly and shows her that she can have a life free of society&#8217;s constraints. In Kilkenny, Robyn is a girl who has to do what she&#8217;s told, which definitely does not include going on adventures or telling fairy tales. She&#8217;s English, an outsider, and therefore unwelcome. But Mebh lives outside of all that. She doesn&#8217;t care that Robyn&#8217;s English&#8211;she doesn&#8217;t even know what or where England is. She likes Robyn for who she is, and as it&#8217;s revealed that Mebh has been living without her mother for so long and her loneliness becomes apparent, we see that Mebh is getting just as much out of the friendship as Robyn. The scene where Mebh tells her mother&#8217;s sleeping form all about Robyn and how she brushed and wove flowers into her hair was so touching. The rest of the world in <em>Wolfwalkers </em>is hard and strict, but at least these two lonely girls were able to find each other and leave it all behind.</p>
<p>And of course, <em>Wolfwalkers </em>is great for wolf and werewolf fans. Whereas wolves are usually depicted as wild, aggressive, and scary, Mebh&#8217;s pack is friendly and fun-loving. They only attack when threatened, just as any wild animal would do. And the concept of wolfwalkers turns the werewolf trope on its head. Usually werewolves change on a full moon, and it&#8217;s often painful and involuntary. Being a wolfwalker is quite the opposite. There isn&#8217;t any actual shapeshifting going on; instead, their spirits leave their bodies when they&#8217;re asleep, and manifest as wolves. Totally voluntary (for the most part) and no full moon needed. There are some pitfalls to the process, but I&#8217;ll stay away from spoiler territory.</p>
<p><em>Wolfwalkers</em> is a fantastic film that I didn&#8217;t want to end. If you&#8217;re craving an adventure, which we probably all are right now, then definitely check this one out if you can!</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Wolfwalkers — Official Trailer | Apple TV+" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/d_Z_tybgPgg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Characters Who Deserved Better: Ashi from &#8220;Samurai Jack&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/characters-who-deserved-better-ashi-from-samurai-jack/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[YA Girl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I suppose it says something that, after years and years of waiting for the final&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22139 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/krys-amon-eAAR-0iDhic-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/krys-amon-eAAR-0iDhic-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/krys-amon-eAAR-0iDhic-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/krys-amon-eAAR-0iDhic-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/krys-amon-eAAR-0iDhic-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/krys-amon-eAAR-0iDhic-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I suppose it says something that, after years and years of waiting for the final season of <em>Samurai Jack</em>, I barely even think about the show&#8217;s finale. It&#8217;s not that the final season was terrible; I just thought everyone&#8211;Jack and the viewers alike&#8211;deserved better. At least Jack got a bittersweet ending, but I think that finally defeating the evil incarnate that is Aku after decades of hopelessness warrants a happier ending! Maybe that&#8217;s just the idealist in me. Maybe I&#8217;m tired of stories being unfair. And mostly, I am tired of female characters always getting the short end of the stick.</p>
<p>Throughout the series, Jack made many allies, but always traveled alone. Until the final season introduced Ashi, one of the seven Daughters of Aku who were born and raised with the sole purpose of killing Jack. There are things I like about Ashi&#8217;s character, but unfortunately she was born sexy yesterday. The YouTube channel Pop Culture Detective has a video called &#8220;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0thpEyEwi80">Born Sexy Yesterday</a>&#8221; about this troubling trope involving mostly female characters. In the video description, he explains:</p>
<blockquote><p>It&#8217;s a science fiction convention in which the mind of a naive, yet highly skilled, girl is written into the body of a mature sexualized woman. Born sexy yesterday is about an unbalanced relationship, but it’s also very much connected to masculinity. The subtext of the trope is rooted in a deep seated male insecurity around experienced women and sexuality.</p></blockquote>
<p>Yes, readers, this does mean that Jack and Ashi (needlessly, in my opinion) fall in love. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/keep-your-amatonormativity-away-from-my-dragon/">Amatonormativity</a> strikes again. Fortunately, Jack is a good person and in no way tries to take advantage of Ashi&#8217;s inexperience. He&#8217;s not exactly the most experienced when it comes to romance, either, but he&#8217;s also much older (mentally&#8211;Jack&#8217;s body doesn&#8217;t age) than Ashi. Like the examples in the video, there are times when Ashi&#8217;s nakedness embarrasses Jack and he has to explain to her that &#8220;private parts are private.&#8221; As they travel together, the tension between them builds, and I could see their inevitable romance coming from a mile away.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I don&#8217;t think Jack falling in love after decades of being alone is a bad thing. There has been proof in the show that he&#8217;s attracted to women, and if it makes him happy then he definitely deserves to be happy! But why does his love interest, who is actually a well-fleshed out character, have to be reduced to just his love interest?</p>
<p>Ashi has lots of great moments throughout the final season. She overcomes the lies and abuse of her childhood and learns to see the beauty in the world; she&#8217;s able to become her own person and choose freely to help Jack in his quest to destroy Aku; she even does one of the most important things of all, which is to show Jack that things aren&#8217;t hopeless and that he has an entire army of allies willing to fight with him because of the positive way in which he impacted the Aku-ravaged world. These moments of character development make the male gaze-y-ness of her character even harder to swallow. In the scene where she rids herself of the clingy black bodysuit <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22140 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/daniel-lincoln-xm49F658RyM-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/daniel-lincoln-xm49F658RyM-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/daniel-lincoln-xm49F658RyM-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/daniel-lincoln-xm49F658RyM-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/daniel-lincoln-xm49F658RyM-unsplash-1228x1536.jpg 1228w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/daniel-lincoln-xm49F658RyM-unsplash-1638x2048.jpg 1638w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/daniel-lincoln-xm49F658RyM-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2047w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />she wears, it&#8217;s revealed that apparently that was just her own charred skin and she was naked the whole time? And then somehow fashions herself a skimpy outfit made of leaves, because fashion design was definitely part of her relentless warrior training? Her silhouette from behind a waterfall in which she&#8217;s all curves with just a pencil-thin torso, and also of course she falls in love with Jack immediately after being un-brainwashed to hate him and think he&#8217;s the root of all evil. Then, after finally defeating Aku and returning to Jack&#8217;s proper time period, they get married and she instantly fades from existence because without Aku, her existence is null.</p>
<p>If Jack&#8217;s &#8220;reward&#8221; for saving the world is returning home and instant marriage, then what is Ashi&#8217;s reward? It would have been better if she hadn&#8217;t fallen in love with Jack, not been Aku&#8217;s actual daughter (because gross) and not traveled back to the past with Jack. Let her be her own person and avoid the born sexy yesterday trope.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Mood-Boosting Must-Watch Fall Shows</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/4-mood-boosting-must-watch-fall-shows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 10:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[YA Girl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s autumn here in the Northern Hemisphere, and it&#8217;s my absolute favorite season. It&#8217;s no&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s autumn here in the Northern Hemisphere, and it&#8217;s my absolute favorite season. It&#8217;s no longer <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-20271 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ricardo-gomez-angel-4hhP-Ud4e84-unsplash-300x235.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="235" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ricardo-gomez-angel-4hhP-Ud4e84-unsplash-300x235.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ricardo-gomez-angel-4hhP-Ud4e84-unsplash-1024x804.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ricardo-gomez-angel-4hhP-Ud4e84-unsplash-768x603.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ricardo-gomez-angel-4hhP-Ud4e84-unsplash-1536x1206.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ricardo-gomez-angel-4hhP-Ud4e84-unsplash-2048x1608.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />grossly hot and humid, but not yet cold enough for the winter coats. The leaves are changing colors, the squirrels are frolicking, there are spooky decorations in people&#8217;s yards&#8230; the list goes on! Aside from the chilly nights being perfect for curling up with a good book, it&#8217;s also a perfect time to curl up with some good TV. There are plenty of anxiety-inducing factors in our daily lives right now, so allow me to recommend some cartoons I guarantee will boost your mood!</p>
<p><strong>1. <em>Over the Garden Wall</em></strong></p>
<p>This is an absolute must-watch for the fall! My best friend and I watch it together every year around Halloween, which makes for an excellent tradition. The show is about two brothers, Wirt and Greg, and their frog of many names, lost in the woods. It&#8217;s the perfect fall show, from the scenery to the spookiness. It&#8217;s not overly scary, though, so anyone who&#8217;s not a fan of creepy stuff would probably still enjoy it. Although the show has a dark undertone, the humor, mostly thanks to Greg being such a goofball, keeps it fun and pleasant. There&#8217;s a snarky bluebird named Beatrice, a town full of people wearing pumpkins, a school for animals, a riverboat cruise for frogs, and so many more whimsical situations. Watching <em>OtGW</em> will make you feel like you&#8217;re a kid pumpkin picking on a crisp, sunny day, with a haunted hayride to follow up. Definitely one of the best shows to watch any time, but I highly recommend watching during the fall for maximum enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>2. <em>Gekkan Shoujo Nozaki-kun</em></strong></p>
<p>OK, so this one isn&#8217;t fall-specific, but if you want to laugh your head off and feel absolutely delighted, this is the show for you. The story follows Chiyo Sakura and her attempts at telling her crush, Umetarou Nozaki, that she likes him. However, Nozaki is one fry short of a Happy Meal, so her message never lands. Instead, she finds out he&#8217;s the creator of a highly popular shoujo manga called <em>Let&#8217;s Fall in Love</em>, and he recruits her as one of his art assistants. Chiyo quickly learns that, even though his manga is about high schoolers falling in love, Nozaki has zero experience in the romance department and spends a lot of time doing &#8220;research.&#8221; As the series progresses, more characters join the cast, and together they all have about one brain cell between them. If there&#8217;s one thing we all need right now, it&#8217;s an anime about a bunch of high schoolers being dumb and drawing manga together. It&#8217;s currently on Netflix, so do yourself a favor and add this one to your watchlist.</p>
<p><strong>3. <em>Hilda</em></strong></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-life-of-an-adventurer/">I wrote about <em>Hilda </em>before</a>, so I won&#8217;t go on about it too long, but I think it&#8217;s the perfect show to watch right now. For one thing, we can all live vicariously through Hilda and her adventures while we&#8217;re stuck at home. Just a sweet little show about a girl and her pet deerfox having adventures in the magical wilderness and the charming yet mysterious city of Trolberg. The second season comes out this December on Netflix, so catch up now and get ready!</p>
<p><strong>4. <em>Song of the Sea</em></strong></p>
<p>To wrap up this list I have not a show, but a movie! <em>Song of the Sea</em> is about Ben, the son of a selkie, and his selkie sister Saoirse on a quest to help Ireland&#8217;s faeries return to Tír na nÓg. Most of the story takes place on Halloween, when the veil between worlds is thinnest, making it the last night Saoirse has to sing her song and save the faeries from Macha, the Owl Witch, who&#8217;s been draining them of their emotions and turning them to stone. Aside from an enchanting story and the very well-written sibling relationship between Ben and Saoirse, the animation in this movie is absolutely gorgeous. If you&#8217;ve seen <em>The Secret of Kells </em>or <em>The Breadwinner</em>, then you know you&#8217;re in for a treat. <a href="https://www.cartoonsaloon.ie/">Cartoon Saloon</a>, the animation studio behind these films, always does amazing work. <em>Song of the Sea</em> is like watching a watercolor painting for an hour and a half. Here&#8217;s the trailer, so you can see for yourself:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Song of the Sea Official US Release Trailer - Irish Animated Movie HD" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HgbXWt8kM5Q?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>So here we have a good mix of comedy, fantasy, adventure, and a dash of spookiness to absorb us for a little while. If you decide to watch any of the shows on this list, I hope you enjoy them as much as I did!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Rise of Queer Cartoons</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-rise-of-queer-cartoons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 11:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[YA Girl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a kid, finding out that Uranus and Neptune from Sailor Moon were lesbians was quite&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19619 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/uranus-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/uranus-198x300.jpg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/uranus.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 198px) 100vw, 198px" />As a kid, finding out that Uranus and Neptune from <em>Sailor Moon </em>were lesbians was quite the scandal. In the American dub, they were <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nHzjXrEiQqQ">cousins</a>, because of course blushing is a natural reaction for the characters to have when they&#8217;re told these two girls are &#8220;cousins.&#8221; At the time, this revelation of their true relationship was treated like a joke among my friends who liked the show. Uranus and Neptune were no longer the cool, collected, older Sailor Scouts we thought they were. Now they were something else, something we didn&#8217;t understand and were taught was wrong and weird and not to be taken seriously. After all, if being a lesbian was OK, then why would the American dub try to hide it?</p>
<p>In 2014, I watched the finale of <em>The Legend of Korra </em>feeling absolutely giddy. The last scene showed Korra and Asami walking hand-in-hand toward a portal to the spirit world, turning to face each other in the very last moment before the show ends. The music track called &#8220;The Avatar&#8217;s Love&#8221; played over the scene. My friend and I couldn&#8217;t contain ourselves. &#8220;Did that really just happen? Are Korra and Asami canon? Did Nickelodeon let these women be bisexual?&#8221; And I lost it again when <em>Adventure Time </em>ended in 2018 and, after hinting at a romantic connection throughout the series, it finally culminated in a kiss between Princess Bubblegum and Marceline. These moments were important to me as an adult who craves non-heterosexual representation, and I could only imagine how life-changing this representation could be for the kids watching. If I had grown up seeing butt-kicking girls who kiss girls in the cartoons I watched, maybe I wouldn&#8217;t have thought for so many years that being gay was something to whisper and laugh about. Of course, this is exactly why there were no significant queer characters who weren&#8217;t derogatory stereotypes in the cartoons of the past. If children saw positive representation like that, it would turn them all gay! Couldn&#8217;t impose that kind of sexuality on children! Let&#8217;s just keep imposing heterosexuality on them instead, because it&#8217;s normal! *eye-rolls myself into the sun*</p>
<p>Now that queer characters have finally started popping up in cartoons, it looks like there&#8217;s no going back. There&#8217;s <em>Steven Universe</em>, <em>The Dragon Prince</em>, <em>She-Ra and the Princesses of Power</em>, and <em>The Owl House</em>, just to name a few. I will give the biggest shout-out to Benson from <em>Kipo and the Age of Wonderbeasts </em>for being the first and only cartoon character I&#8217;ve ever encountered to state, in no uncertain terms, the words &#8220;I&#8217;m gay.&#8221; And what happened after that? Nothing, <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19618 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/sharon-mccutcheon-sMnoDBdC1tE-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/sharon-mccutcheon-sMnoDBdC1tE-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/sharon-mccutcheon-sMnoDBdC1tE-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/sharon-mccutcheon-sMnoDBdC1tE-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/sharon-mccutcheon-sMnoDBdC1tE-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/sharon-mccutcheon-sMnoDBdC1tE-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />really. Kipo felt a little embarrassed for having a crush on him, but she quickly moved on and held nothing against Benson for being who he is. Which is another thing that&#8217;s so great about these characters and the shows they&#8217;re in; they&#8217;re queer and it&#8217;s not a big deal. It doesn&#8217;t define them as characters; they&#8217;re just normal people, just like in real life.</p>
<p>I know TV executives and the like didn&#8217;t just wake up one day and say, &#8220;Ah, yes, we could use some more queer representation in our shows.&#8221; The showrunners had to fight for these characters, and I am so grateful that they were able to win those fights. The response to these characters has been overwhelmingly positive, so I hope from now on the queer representation keeps on coming.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Avatar&#8217;s Underrated MVP</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/avatars-underrated-mvp/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/avatars-underrated-mvp/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 10:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[YA Girl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Avatar: The Last Airbender is back on Netflix after what feels like 84 years, and I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Avatar: The Last Airbender </em>is back on Netflix after what feels like 84 years, and I immediately said, &#8220;Ah, yes, my emotional support cartoon.&#8221; Rewatching it has been a blast, and solidified its spot as one of the greatest shows ever, in my eyes. Something I always appreciated about it was that they let girls be fighters, too. <em>Avatar </em>kicked it up a notch in that respect, though. They were like, &#8220;oh, you want to see girls being awesome strong fighters? What if we made them even more <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19331 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vino-li-of-0z-W4w_c-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vino-li-of-0z-W4w_c-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vino-li-of-0z-W4w_c-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vino-li-of-0z-W4w_c-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vino-li-of-0z-W4w_c-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vino-li-of-0z-W4w_c-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vino-li-of-0z-W4w_c-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />badass than you ever could&#8217;ve expected?&#8221; By the end of the series, Katara has gone from barely being able to create a wave, to being probably the most powerful waterbender in the show. Toph was awesome from the start, what with using her blindness to amplify her earthbending senses, but goes on to create metalbending and being even more awesome. Then there&#8217;s Princess Azula, with her one-of-a-kind, super-hot blue flame firebending and being one of the few people who can lightningbend, and her friend Ty Lee who can render any bender helpless with the use of her chi-blocking techniques. This time around, though, I realized there was one character who never really got her fair share of recognition: Suki, the leader of the Kyoshi Warriors.</p>
<p>Suki first appeared in the fourth episode of the first season. She won my heart by putting Sokka and his casual sexism in his place. Before the end of the episode, Sokka apologizes for treating her &#8220;like a girl&#8221; instead of a warrior, to which she says, &#8220;I am a warrior, but I&#8217;m a girl, too.&#8221; In that one simple statement, Suki actually says a lot. You can be a great fighter and kick ass, but you don&#8217;t need to harden yourself or suppress your emotions; you can protect your village from invaders while having a crush on the cute guy who just blew into town, and these things are not mutually exclusive.</p>
<p>Her first appearance was originally supposed to be her last, but Suki was brought back later in the second season. At first it seemed like the writers only brought her back as Sokka&#8217;s love interest, and to show that he was still grieving the loss of Princess Yue from the the season one finale. Thankfully, this wasn&#8217;t the case, and Suki goes on to play an important role in the plot from then on. She&#8217;s usually left out when people talk about or depict Team Avatar, but she was absolutely an irreplaceable part of the team. Without her compassion and gentleness, Appa wouldn&#8217;t have had the strength to continue his search for Aang. If not for her quick thinking and physical prowess, Sokka and Zuko would&#8217;ve had a much harder time escaping from the Boiling Rock prison. In the series finale, Suki plays an integral role in taking down Ozai&#8217;s fleet of airships. I haven&#8217;t read many of the <em>Avatar </em>comics, but I know Suki&#8217;s in them, and I&#8217;m glad her story got to continue. I hope, now that there&#8217;s somewhat of an <em>Avatar </em>resurgence happening, that Suki finally gets the love and recognition she deserves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/avatars-underrated-mvp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Villains and Otherness in Cartoons</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/villains-and-otherness-in-cartoons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[YA Girl]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I recently read this comic by Alex Graudins that&#8217;s been making the rounds across social&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I recently read <a href="https://medium.com/@thenib/you-can-be-a-patriot-without-loving-america-afe4a08e2eaf">this comic</a> by <a href="http://toonyart.com/">Alex Graudins</a> that&#8217;s been making the rounds across social media, about how you can be a patriot without being proud of or loving your country. Graudins makes excellent points, but being the cartoon-lover that I am, the panel that struck me the hardest was the sixth panel. It points out how lots of villains in American cartoons are given foreign accents, with Mojo Jojo from <em>The Powerpuff Girls </em>pictured. While it&#8217;s true that Mojo speaks with what&#8217;s <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19117 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/woman-dark-eye-spooky-25757-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/woman-dark-eye-spooky-25757-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/woman-dark-eye-spooky-25757-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/woman-dark-eye-spooky-25757-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/woman-dark-eye-spooky-25757-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/woman-dark-eye-spooky-25757-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/woman-dark-eye-spooky-25757.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />supposed to pass as a Japanese accent, I never thought much of it before. Then I realized, maybe that&#8217;s the point. We&#8217;re not supposed to think about why the villains have foreign accents, or even what those accents are supposed to be; we&#8217;re just supposed to recognize that they&#8217;re not like us, not American. Even in cartoon universes where America doesn&#8217;t exist, this trope still stands. In the <em>Avatar: The Last Airbender</em> episode &#8220;The Blind Bandit,&#8221; there&#8217;s a character called Fire Nation Man, a heel who speaks with a fake Russian-esque accent to indicate that he&#8217;s a &#8220;bad guy,&#8221; despite the fact that actual Fire Nation citizens don&#8217;t have accents that set them apart from the rest of the world. His accent only serves to let us, the viewers, know that he&#8217;s Not Like the rest of the people in this Earth Kingdom town.</p>
<p>This othering of villains doesn&#8217;t stop just with their accents; it&#8217;s also coded in their appearances. Let&#8217;s look at Scar from <em>The Lion King</em>. He&#8217;s Mufasa&#8217;s brother, yet he looks absolutely nothing like him, or the other lions. His mane is black, his fur is darker than the golden color of the other lions, <em>and </em>he&#8217;s got a British accent, to boot. And it&#8217;s definitely been pointed out many times how Ursula from <em>The Little Mermaid</em> is the only fat character in the movie, who proceeds to become even bigger at the pinnacle of her villainy.</p>
<p>Of course, not every villain has an accent or strays from what&#8217;s typically considered attractive or desirable. Personally, I think villains that <em>are </em>what society considers &#8220;desirable&#8221; are much more insidious and convincing. The best example I can think of is Darla Dimple from <em>Cats Don&#8217;t Dance</em>. She&#8217;s a &#8220;sweet&#8221; little blonde-haired, blue-eyed girl who has Hollywood wrapped around her finger. No one would ever think she had an evil bone in her body, right? But at the thought of a bunch of animals coming to town to become actors and upstage her, she absolutely snaps and tries to sabotage them in the worst ways possible. The new season of Netflix&#8217;s <em>Kipo and the Age of Wonderbeasts </em>has kind of a double whammy; one villain is Scarlemagne, a British-accented mandrill who makes a truly awesome villain, but given his backstory, one that we, or at least I, would really like to see redeemed. The other is Dr. Emilia, an evil scientist, and one of the few white characters in a show that has no white characters at all in the main cast.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s easy to fall back on the stereotypes of &#8220;otherness&#8221; when it comes to creating villains. We&#8217;re already conditioned to hear a foreign accent or see someone with a different skin tone or a physical disability and think, &#8220;this person is not like me.&#8221; But it&#8217;s so much more challenging, and rewarding, to portray villains as those who hold power in society. Maybe instead of seeing the &#8220;other&#8221; as villainous, it would do society some good to see the &#8220;desirable&#8221; ones as bad for once.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
