<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tara Lindsey &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/tara-lindsey/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 03:54:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Nobody Reads Poetry, and That&#8217;s Okay. Really.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/nobody-reads-poetry-thats-okay-really/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tara Lindsey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 16:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Poetic Life]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5488</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More often than not, when I tell people I am a poet, in those rare&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/poetry-sm.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5500 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/poetry-sm-300x197.jpg" alt="poetry-sm" width="300" height="197" /></a>More often than not, when I tell people I am a poet, in those rare moments when I leave The Womb and actually interact with strangers, I am greeted with a polite smile, which is another way of saying, &#8220;I don&#8217;t read poetry and I have no idea why you would write it because <i>nobody</i> reads poetry, didn&#8217;t you get the memo?&#8221; I want to tell them that it doesn&#8217;t have to be that way, but they are right, and I am oddly fine with it.</p>
<p>I look at pop stars and politicians, I look at social media and our endless news cycle, and I see no place for poetry. I see <i>louderfastermoremoremore</i>, none of which has anything to do with where poetry comes from, which in my experience has everything to do with <i>quieterslowerlesslessless</i>. So how do you move forward when you understand that your life&#8217;s work is essentially a culturally dead art form?</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t speak for other poets, far more ambitious than I, some of whom I know are still hustling to be read, to be <i>relevant</i>, to (god forbid) make a living through their writing. But for me, the fact that no one is looking, that no one cares, is a tremendous relief in a world where the phrase &#8220;this is why we can&#8217;t have nice things&#8221; has entered the smarmy vernacular. I have very little faith that the culture as it stands can bear the weight of what poetry is capable of.</p>
<p>I am writing, first and foremost, for myself. Because I have to. Because it is a vocation. It is spiritual practice. Secondarily, and it is a distant second, I am writing to share what I see / hear / feel with a select group of people who have communicated with me that my poems have affected them. Their letters, which arrive out of the blue every so often, are always a surprise. They renew my faith in individual people to share genuine moments of grace with each other.</p>
<p>Emily understood what I am talking about, as did Blake in his own way. Writing for eternity, not posterity. Giving yourself permission to be utterly yourself, to have no influences other than every breath of human (and non-human) existence. To reject all poses and schools of thought / writing. Understanding that poetry is without question one of the most transformative art forms, and that the best of it is waiting out there, patiently, for the right soul to find it.</p>
<p>I meant to write about artifice, about personae &amp; parallel selves, but this happened instead. Hopefully next month. Until then, may <i>quieterslowerlesslessless</i> visit you, even if only for a few moments. You might be surprised how much you like it &#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where Language Cannot Go</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/language-cannot-go/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tara Lindsey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 16:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Poetic Life]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oh, Luna Station Blog, I’ve missed thee! It’s been 11 months since my last confession&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oh, Luna Station Blog, I’ve missed thee! It’s been 11 months since my last confession &#8230;</p>
<p>So, where was I? Ahhh, yes. Baseball.</p>
<p>As a general rule, I don’t like talking about poetry (or writing about it or even thinking about it too much, if we’re being honest). But when the right person catches me in the right mood and we start talking about what a poet actually <em>does</em>, rather than start in with the usual cliches about looking out windows for hours on end, I often make a baseball analogy.</p>
<p>If you’re not familiar with the rules &amp; standards of the game, a baseball player is considered (if you are primarily a hitter) to be above average if your batting average is .300. If you think about it, that means you are an elite player, and could theoretically get in the hall of fame<em> for failing 7 out of 10 times</em>! Ohhh, if all life was measured thusly!</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/images1.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5392 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/images1.jpg" alt="images" width="225" height="225" /></a>Writing poetry feels similar to me, though maybe not for the same reasons (I suppose prose writers will notice a bit of resonance here as well, though I can’t speak to their experience). For me, a poem nearly always begins with a feeling, an image, a juxtaposition of seemingly disparate things. In other words, it begins anywhere <em>but</em> the realm of expository language.</p>
<p>The challenge comes, of course, when trying to bend our 26 letters to the will of the ineffable feeling that is the engine and essence of the poem. Or to put it another way, “How do I put into words these things that I’m feeling/seeing/sensing that are at the edge of what it’s possible to say?” Think about that for a second&#8230;</p>
<p>Poets are uniquely suited to this task, unencumbered as we are by the constraints of narrative. If you are an adventurous poet, one who is not averse to improvisation and happy accidents, you go in open to the idea that you might fail spectacularly, quite possibly 7 out of 10 times, and those failures may lead to new combinations of sensation that you never imagined.</p>
<p>Even if you manage to get onto the page a rough facsimile of the ineffable engine, there is another failure of language waiting to waylay you. If your poem is to be read by someone else, it is more than possible that what the poem “means” to you could be different than what it “means” to the reader.</p>
<p>(This, of course, accounts for the pain &amp; discomfort that arises when schools try to force one canonical interpretation of a poem onto young people, thereby robbing them of the opportunity to feel things for themselves, but that’s another essay&#8230;)</p>
<p>This gulf between what you write and what someone else reads is another gift that the failure of language provides. Sometimes I think that as much as I have a fondness for my words, the real poem resides in that alchemical space, the space <em>between the notes</em>, as I would say when I have my musician hat on.</p>
<p>If the poem is the ineffable feeling, as much as it is the words, then what is transmitted from poet to reader, across that gulf, will always be <em>true</em>, regardless of the particularities. That truth, that moment when the reader gasps and asks, “What did you do to me?” does more to convince me of our shared humanness, of our shared possibility for grace across time and circumstance, than anything else I know.</p>
<p>Of course, after all this talk about Truth with a capital T, next month’s column will be about artifice <em>(insert party favor sound here).</em> And with that, I bid you adieu, for now. Thank you for reading. And if someone tries to tell you what a poem means, smack them. Hard.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing Invisible Compositions</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/introducing-invisible-compositions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tara Lindsey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 18:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Poetic Life]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I just re-read my previous two Medium posts, the one that ended The 366 Day&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just re-read my previous two Medium posts, <a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://medium.com/@WordsMusicLife/day-366-d34da146c6ae" data-href="https://medium.com/@WordsMusicLife/day-366-d34da146c6ae">the one that ended The 366 Day Project</a>, and <a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="https://medium.com/@WordsMusicLife/squalor-glamour-a-true-story-fadde53c86dd" data-href="https://medium.com/@WordsMusicLife/squalor-glamour-a-true-story-fadde53c86dd">the one from when sQualor // gLamour came out</a>. In those, I talked about the experience of feeling like I had finally become a poet. I talked about magick and intimacy and the power of holding a physical book in your hands. I’ll try not to talk about those things again.</p>
<p>Last week, I wrote a first draft of this piece you are reading right now. I talked about how strange and disconcerting it often feels to be a creative person in the digital age, when we are all somehow expected to double as public relations / brand management experts. There was nothing untrue in it, but it felt negative. It didn’t dance. There was no uplift, no aspiration, in it.</p>
<p>That didn’t feel right. Poetry can be many things. For some people, it’s for saying the unsayable. For some, it’s for social change. For me, it’s always been about singing, dancing, mystery, curiosity, half-forgotten memories, pathways to other realities. It’s about Muses and Winter and the occasional grand staircase, sometimes bathed in light, sometimes the lone refuge from darkness.</p>
<p><a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/invisible-compositions/" rel="nofollow" data-href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/invisible-compositions/">Invisible Compositions</a>, this book that The 366 Day Project interrupted, has been a long time coming. I have been living with these images, these other selves, for the last few years, long enough to gain and lose friends, long enough be a successful musician, leave music, then think about returning, long enough to tell you that I am not the same person who began this book.</p>
<p>Flipping through the pages these last few weeks, while dealing with life stuff, while trying to care for my family, while pondering the future, while missing the person who will understand these poems the most, I felt tremendous gratitude. The vocation of Poet is an honourable one, if not a particularly valued one in the culture I live in, and to hear and see and feel the things I do, and to get to write them down, is a blessing.</p>
<p>If you choose to read these poems, I hope you’ll do so with your heart. Leave your mind, leave symbolism and allegory and all of that stuff they taught you in school, off to the side. You don’t need them. And if you’ve read <a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/the-esbat-sequence/" rel="nofollow" data-href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/the-esbat-sequence/">Esbat</a> or <a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/squalor-glamour/" rel="nofollow" data-href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/squalor-glamour/">s//g</a>, and loved them, I assure you, you will love this one too.</p>
<p><a class="markup--anchor markup--p-anchor" href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/invisible-compositions/" rel="nofollow" data-href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/invisible-compositions/">Invisible Compositions. In paperback &amp; hardcover from Luna Station Press.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A New Beginning &#8230;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-new-beginning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tara Lindsey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 19:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This was supposed to be the second part of my Poetic Pilgrimage essay, but something&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1">This was supposed to be the second part of my Poetic Pilgrimage essay, but something has come up.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I have been named the new Creative Director of this Quarterly&#8217;s parent company, <a href="http://lunastationpress.com/">Luna Station Press</a>, and I am kind of over the moon about it. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I don&#8217;t know how much you all know about The Press. Have you read the <a href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/castles-starships/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wonderful</a> <a href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/a-stirring-in-the-bones/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">space opera</a> books by your esteemed Editor In Chief, <a title="Jennifer Lyn Parsons" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/jennifer-parsons/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jennifer Parsons</a>? How about the sassy <i><a href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/elegantly-wasted/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Charlie&#8217;s Angels</a> <a href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/uncontrollably-wasted/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">meets assassins</a> <a href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/wasteland/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">meets lots of wine</a></i> books by Cara Vescio?</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Not ringing a bell? Maybe you might like to have a look at our brand new website, to see what I&#8217;m going on about? <a href="http://lunastationpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">http://lunastationpress.com/</a></span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">To celebrate this new era of Luna Station Press, we are launching two new books today; a young readers book called <a href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/david-a-rat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">David, A Rat by Elizabeth Hinckley</a>, and a <a href="http://lunastationpress.com/portfolio/ayahuasca-nights/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">memoir of a life in shamanism, by Dr. Jason Martin</a>, which inaugurates the Press&#8217; new metaphysical imprint, <a href="http://lunastationpress.com/chacruna-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Chacruna</a>.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">These two books, I hope, illustrate the wide swath of styles and subjects we will be publishing moving forward. (Yes, we will even publish the occasional male, god forbid!) We have another half dozen releases planned into 2015 (including a special surprise for fans of the Quarterly) and seeds planted for where we&#8217;d like to be in 2016 and beyond.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">In addition to Luna Station&#8217;s long standing partnership with Amazon, we will now be enjoying international distribution through Ingram, which means Luna Station&#8217;s books will be orderable at pretty much any bookstore in the world. Which is more than a little cool.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Even though it&#8217;s great that we&#8217;re all meeting here on the web, I&#8217;m a big believer in physical books, and an even bigger believer in local, independent bookstores, both of which will be the core of what I&#8217;ll be focusing on in the months to come.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I would be remiss if I didn&#8217;t thank Luna Station&#8217;s founder, and your faithful EIC, Jennifer Parsons, for giving me this amazing opportunity. Without her, Luna Station would not exist, and all of us would be the poorer. She will continue on with the Press, in an editorial and production capacity, while continuing to give her heart and attention to this Quarterly, and to the marvelous work you are all doing.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Thank you for letting me share this news with you. I hope you&#8217;ll check out the Press&#8217; new site, and that you&#8217;ll find something there that inspires you. Until next month, when part two of A Poetic Pilgrimage will finally appear, I wish for you a fabulous Autumn, full of wonderful things.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Tara Lindsey</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Creative Director</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Luna Station Press</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Poetic Pilgrimage : Part 1</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-poetic-pilgrimage-part-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tara Lindsey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 15:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Poetic Life]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am obsessed with the physicality of poetry. We’ve already talked about specific locations holding lines&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/IMG_5819.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-2868" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/IMG_5819-1024x768.jpg" alt="IMG_5819" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p class="p1">I am obsessed with the physicality of poetry.</p>
<p class="p1"><a title="Poemstalking" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/poemstalking/"><span class="s2">We’ve already talked about</span></a><span class="s1"> specific locations holding lines of verse, and the scavenger hunt that occurs when we try to find them. This month, ever so slightly more traditionally, let’s talk about visiting places that are associated with poets and poetry, from the past to the present.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I am not the first person who’s ever thought to visit the grave or birthplace or home of a favorite poet. There is power in these places that reaches just beyond our level of understanding. We go to these places in the hope that we’ll somehow see what they saw, or better still, feel what they felt.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">As someone who tries to focus on the present instead of the past or future, it felt right to make my own initial poetic pilgrimage to the childhood home of my favorite living poet, W.S. Merwin. The fact that said home is only half an hour from my Womb is a happy coincidence.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">For any of you who haven’t read Merwin, I cannot recommend highly enough his 2008 collection, </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3401950-the-shadow-of-sirius?ac=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="s2">The Shadow of Sirius</span></a><span class="s1">, which won the Pulitzer the following year. His clear, concise poems, evocative to the extreme, will draw in even the staunchest “I don’t read poetry” holdout.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I had learned that in 2006, the town of Union City NJ had changed the corner of Fourth Street and New York Avenue to W.S. Merwin Way. The house he lived in until age nine is still standing, complete with the large tree in the backyard that he apparently loved as a small boy.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Driving out there one morning this past April, it really did feel like a pilgrimage, an adventure, a place to visit to somehow offer gratitude to a poet whose work moves me deeply.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>Pulling up to the street, seeing the sign, I’m not ashamed to admit my heart skipped a beat.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I brought my copy of Sirius with me, stood on the corner beneath the street sign and read the poem <i>The Nomad Flute</i> while looking up at the house, imagining the five year old boy writing out hymns for his minister father. I wondered if he somehow knew, even then, that poetry would shape his life.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I wondered how many people cross that street every day, and if they look up at that sign and that house and wonder who Merwin is? I wondered if it would inspire them if they knew? I also wondered which houses, in Union City and elsewhere, were sheltering the poets of the future, whose names we don’t know yet, but who are destined to change the world?</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Next month I will continue with this theme, and tell you how I wrote five lines in maybe the most famous American poetry location of them all &#8230;</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">PS &#8211; For any of you that might be interested in being transported by the power and grace of fine conversation, I would direct you to </span><a href="http://www.pbs.org/moyers/journal/06262009/watch.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span class="s2">this discussion between Merwin and Bill Moyers</span></a><span class="s1">, from the Sirius period a few years ago. I re-watch this regularly. It’s a major touchstone for me.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Poemstalking</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/poemstalking/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/poemstalking/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tara Lindsey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 17:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Poetic Life]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve been writing five lines a day since last August. In four day&#8217;s time, as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6578.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-2521" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6578-1024x768.jpg" alt="IMG_6578" width="640" height="480" /></a><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6607.jpg"><br />
</a></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I’ve been writing five lines a day since last August. In four day&#8217;s time, as you read this, the year-and-a-day project will be complete. To say that I have been utterly transformed / transmuted by this intentional, magickal act would be an understatement.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">On the surface, writing five lines a day doesn’t sound like much. But writing five lines of verse, which you hope will breathe and dance and be true, is another thing entirely. As I said last month, writing poetry is actually about listening, about how you live. The lines on the page are the compressed, refined, yet still (hopefully) natural result of trying to <i>live</i> poetically. It’s a distinction worth lingering over.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">As you might imagine, getting the heart / soul / body to cough up lines with any sort of consistency has been the biggest creative / spiritual challenge of my life. There have been numerous occasions where just sitting here in The Womb was not going to be enough to get it done. Amidst the potency of your inner metaphors, outside stimuli can sometimes be your best friend.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">One morning, I woke up knowing where the days’ lines were hiding. There is an old canal where I used to live, a quiet place that I couldn&#8217;t appreciate in my twenties that I now visit all the time, even though I live a few hours away. I used to love biking or walking from my house to the bakery in the little town center, about a mile away, for the best chocolate chip cookie in existence. (If we ever meet, ask me, and maybe I&#8217;ll tell you where it is.)</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Stretched over the canal are a few crossings; a concrete noisy highway overpass, which is dark underneath and feels like there might be a troll lurking somewhere, and an old bridge made of wood and stone, with a bench upon the little span, where you can pass a moment&#8217;s rest just a bit closer to the sky. Even from afar these places are still so alive to me &#8230;</span></p>
<p class="p1">I took the extra long scenic route that morning, through the Delaware Water Gap, waving to Tammany &amp; Minsi, driving up and over the Blue Mountains, winding back down through a dozen little towns, past fields and quiet tributaries, and finally back to river level, to the final leg, along the river, down Route 32, full of memory.</p>
<p class="p1">After walking past my old house, which is now abandoned, as if I had dreamed the whole thing, I got on the canal path and started walking.</p>
<p class="p1"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6571.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-2523" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6571-1024x768.jpg" alt="IMG_6571" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p class="p1">Sure enough, when I got to the troll bridge, I heard the first line.</p>
<p class="p1">The old wood and stone bridge did not cough up her secret at first, even after I sat on the bench for awhile, but I had faith, so I climbed back down and headed for town, for my cookie, which you have to eat while sitting on a rock by the little waterfall. There&#8217;s a rule.</p>
<p class="p1"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6585.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-2520" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6585-1024x768.jpg" alt="IMG_6585" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p class="p1">On the way back, I asked very nicely, and the wood and stone bridge gave me lines two AND three, which was a real gift. That still left two more lines, though …</p>
<p class="p1">I started to wonder if the rest of the poem might be a bit further afield. Poemstalking is sometimes an inexact science, after all. Across the river on the New Jersey side, right where Washington famously crossed back in the day (I do have to tell you, folks … that painting is SERIOUSLY exaggerated. The river is not that wide.) there is another canal, and a small town that time forgot, and a friendly love wall. You don&#8217;t believe me?</p>
<p class="p1"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6599.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-2519" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6599-1024x768.jpg" alt="IMG_6599" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p class="p1">The fourth line came quickly, but I still didn&#8217;t know about the fifth. Then the phone rang. It was The Muse. I sat on the magic wall and we talked and time stopped and now there was no question where the fifth line would be. So I drove deeper into memory, walked past Old Nassau, and sure enough, there was line five, at the top of the steps, where she grew wings and we flew, in that poem/dream, long ago.</p>
<p class="p1"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6607.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-2522" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/IMG_6607-1024x768.jpg" alt="IMG_6607" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p class="p1">Poemstalking isn&#8217;t always this involved / intense. Sometimes the lines are five minutes away, around the lake right in town. Then again, sometimes they are on the roof of a museum, on the Summer Solstice, and you know you have to be there to receive them, or they&#8217;ll fly to someone else, lost forever.</p>
<p class="p1">No one ever told me poetry was a full contact sport. But I wouldn&#8217;t have it any other way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/poemstalking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Vastest Things Are Those We May Not Learn …</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-vastest-things-are-those-we-may-not-learn/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tara Lindsey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 17:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Poetic Life]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The vastest things are those we may not learn. We are not taught to die,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/IMG_4122.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-2026" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/IMG_4122-1024x768.jpg" alt="The Womb, Morning" width="640" height="480" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text"><span style="font-size: .8em;">Photo By: <a href="http://www.taralindsey.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tara Lindsey</a></span></figcaption></figure>
<p class="post-p"><em class="post-pEm"><em>The vastest things are those we may not learn.<br />
We are not taught to die, nor to be born,<br />
nor how to burn with love.</em></em></p>
<p class="post-p"><em class="post-pEm">How pitiful is our enforced return<br />
to those small things we are the masters of.</em></p>
<p class="post-p"><em class="post-pEm">-Mervyn Peake</em></p>
<p class="post-p">I haven’t read Peake. He’s an idea. A promise. Of another world, maybe.</p>
<p class="post-p">Gormenghast sits in the stacks up here in <strong class="post-pStrong">The Womb</strong> (part library, part sacred space, part Tardis) vying for my attention with hundreds of other friends I haven’t met yet.</p>
<p class="post-p">There’s something about that quote, just out of reach, that is bringing to mind two of my many lives, that of poet &amp; shamanic practitioner.</p>
<p class="post-p">I honestly don’t think one can be taught to be a poet. It is a self directed enterprise. Or obsession. You can’t learn it from a book. You can’t learn it in a classroom or workshop. You can’t be taught how to <em class="post-pEm">know</em>.</p>
<p class="post-p">Being a poet seems to be about listening, about inviting something in. It seems to be about how one lives. Done with intention, the words on the page cannot be wrong, even if their <em class="post-pEm">meaning</em> is not immediately apparent.</p>
<p class="post-p">Similarly, in shamanism, the people who have the hardest time are often those who need to impose <em class="post-pEm">meaning</em> on the experience, as opposed to simply sitting with things that may be confusing / chaotic / uncomfortable.</p>
<p class="post-p">The head / mind is important. Obviously. But it’s the heart, the senses, the ability to build bridges between metaphors, that seems to drive change. And as I was once told, once you <em class="post-pEm">know</em> something, you can’t un-know it.</p>
<p class="post-p paragraph--last">No matter how hard you try.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
