<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Rebecca Buchanan &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/rebecca-buchanan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:13:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Book Review: Undiscovered</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-undiscovered/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Buchanan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gods Among the Stars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Title: Undiscovered (Treasure Hunter Security Book One) Publisher/Author: Anna Hackett Pages: 248 pp Price: .99 cents (ebook) /&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/hackett.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-8324" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/hackett-187x300.jpg" alt="" width="187" height="300" /></a><strong>Title: <em>Undiscovered</em> (Treasure Hunter Security Book One)</strong><br />
<strong>Publisher/Author:</strong> Anna Hackett<br />
<strong>Pages:</strong> 248 pp<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> .99 cents (ebook) / $9.99 (paperback)</p>
<p>Layne Rush is an archaeologist: dedicated, smart, fearless, and driven to uncover the secrets of the past. Declan Ward is a former Navy SEAL; after barely escaping a dishonorable discharge for disobeying orders, he founded Treasure Hunter Security. When Layne is attacked at her dig site in Egypt and priceless artifacts are stolen, Ward and his team are hired to protect her and recover the relics &#8212; relics which may lead them to the fabled city of Zerzura, lost to the sands of the Western Desert millennia ago . . .</p>
<p>I have previously recommended Hackett&#8217;s wild science fiction adventure, <em>Among Galactic Ruins</em>. There is an interesting connection between the two books: <em>Among Galactic Ruins</em> is set on an alien world in the far future which the human colonists named Zerzura . . .  after a fabled lost city on Old Earth.</p>
<p>Hackett&#8217;s books are the literary equivalent of rocky road ice cream. And I mean that as the highest of compliments. They are pure escapist <strong>fun</strong>. Daring adventure, narrow escapes, muscular heroes, sassy heroines, nasty villains, lost treasure, booby traps, more narrow escapes, more lost treasure, and a much-deserved happily ever after.</p>
<p>Hackett does her homework, though, and that shows in <em>Undiscovered</em>. <a class="caption" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zerzura" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zerzura</a> is a &#8220;real&#8221; mythical city, and Hackett incorporates the various stories and symbols centered around it into her novel. Further, she ties it to the Egyptian god <a class="caption" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Set_(deity)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Set</a>, naming it as the location of a cult in his honor. There&#8217;s a whole mythological/theological and historical lesson cleverly hidden in these pages, as Layne explains to Ward (and the reader) the unification of ancient Egypt, the demonization of Set, his role as protector, and the resurgence of devotion to him in the New Kingdom.</p>
<p>If I have one complaint, it is that the action scenes tend to be very abbreviated. Sequences which should go on for several paragraphs (or even pages) are crammed into a few terse lines. Consider the (minor spoilers) scene featuring the set-animals; I had to fill in some of the gaps myself, adding sound and color to the oddly spare description.</p>
<p>If you are looking for a fun, fast read which treats Kemetic history and spirituality respectfully, check out <em>Undiscovered</em>.</p>
<p>Recommended to fans of Seressia Glass&#8217; <em>Seducing the Jackal,</em> the <em>Gods of Egypt</em> series by Veronica Scott, the <em>Eye of Odin</em> series by Dennis Staginnus, and <em>The Blades of the Rose</em> series by Zoey Archer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spotlight On: Retrotopia</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/spotlight-on-retrotopia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Buchanan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 11:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gods Among the Stars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Title: Retrotopia Publisher: Founders House Publishing LLC Author: John Michael Greer Pages: 264 pp Price: $15.99 (paperback) /&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/greer.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8327 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/greer.jpg" alt="" width="192" height="297" /></a>Title: <em>Retrotopia</em></strong><br />
<strong>Publisher: Founders House Publishing LLC</strong><br />
<strong>Author:</strong> John Michael Greer<br />
<strong>Pages:</strong> 264 pp<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $15.99 (paperback) / $5.99 (ebook)</p>
<p>The year is 2065. Economic failure and ecological collapse have combined to shatter the United States. In the wake of a Second Civil War, the old US has broken up into half-a-dozen smaller nations and on-going war zones. A new President is about to assume power in the Atlantic Republic and she is determined to establish relations with the Lakeland Republic. As such, she sends her trusted envoy, Peter Carr, to open negotiations and learn what he can about the once-isolated Lakeland Republic, which, rumor has it, has turned its back on modern technology, economic theory, and law. Carr is certain that he will find a nation of backwards-thinking, starving illiterates. In fact, much to his shock and consternation, Carr finds a thriving nation which has learned the lessons of the past and embraces a much different idea of &#8220;progress&#8221; and &#8220;prosperity&#8221; than the rest of the world . . .</p>
<p><em>Star&#8217;s Reach </em>is one of my favorite science fiction novels, ably combining Gaian spirituality, eco-consciousness, and political theory into an epic adventure. As such, I was thrilled when I discovered that Greer had recently published <em>Retrotopia</em>. I immediately ordered a copy and dove right in.</p>
<p>I can confidently say that <em>Retrotopia</em> will be one of my favorite novels, ever. There is a lot packed into this slim volume and it is all presented in an entertaining and conversational style. Using Carr as a reader surrogate, Greer introduces us to alternative(?) fringe(?) radical(?) old-fashioned(?) ideas in the fields of economics, law, education, and technology. In contrast to Carr&#8217;s own Atlantic Republic (which has carried forward many of the policies and attitudes of the old United States), the Lakeland Republic has completely transformed how it does business, how it governs, how it taxes, how it educates, how it develops new technology &#8212; well, pretty much everything.</p>
<p>There is not the space here to summarize the entire novel, and I would not want to spoil it anyway, so I&#8217;ll offer one example. In the Lakeland Republic, there are five tax brackets (or tiers) based on the technological level of a particular era. Tier One is 1840, Tier Two is 1870, Tier Three is 1890, Tier Four is 1920, and Tier Five is 1950. Each county determines for itself which tier it wants to be in, with taxes going to support that level of infrastructure. So, gravel roads and horse-drawn wagons in low-tax Tier One counties, but power plants and running water and trolley cars in high-tax Tier Five counties.</p>
<p>It gets more interesting: the taxes only determine the technological level of the <strong>infrastructure</strong>. If a family living in a Tier Two county wants a radio, they are free to buy one. When Carr visits a Tier One county, he is shocked to see paved roads in the town center; it turns out that a group of private citizens decided there was enough traffic and trade going on downtown that gravel was not good enough; so they formed a corporation, raised the money themselves, and paved the roads, and then dissolved the corporation.</p>
<p>OK, one more example: in the Lakeland Republic all creedal associations are taxed. Translation: religious groups are not tax-exempt. Second translation: no hiding behind a pulpit and calling for violence against those with whom you disagree. Any creedal association, any group of people bound by a common set of beliefs, is <strong>also</strong> bound by the same laws as everyone else; no discriminating based on race, religion, or sexual orientation, or sex; no slander or libel or calls for violence.</p>
<p>Unlike in <em>Star&#8217;s Reach</em>, religion plays a much smaller role in <em>Retrotopia</em>. Carr is an avowed atheist, and even attends two meetings of the Atheist Assembly while he is visiting the Lakeland Republic. Two Christian sects are introduced in the story, but there are otherwise no references to any religious group or spiritual path.</p>
<p>Perhaps that is appropriate. We made the mess that is the Atlantic Republic and the Confederacy and the Texas Republic and the on-going civil war in California and the melting ice caps and the flooding coastal cities and the falling satellites and the crashing economy . . . We cannot expect a God or Goddess or pantheon to intervene. We broke the world. We need to fix it ourselves.</p>
<p>Greer has introduced me to a lot of new ideas. He&#8217;s making me think some uncomfortable thoughts. <em>Retrotopia</em> is one of those rare novels which is both infuriating and enlightening, frightening and hopeful.</p>
<p>Highly recommended to fans of Greer&#8217;s other work, as well as <em>The Fifth Sacred Thing </em>by Starhawk, <em>Ecotopia</em><strong> </strong>by Ernest Callenbach, <em>Herland</em> by Charlotte Perkins Gilman, and the <em>California Trilogy</em> by Kim Stanley Robinson.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: The Metaphysical Detective</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-the-metaphysical-detective/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Buchanan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gods Among the Stars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Title: The Metaphysical Detective (The Riga Hayworth series) Publisher: misterio press Author: Kirsten Weiss Pages: 284 pp Price: free&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/weiss.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8041 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/weiss-187x300.jpg" alt="" width="187" height="300" /></a>Title: The Metaphysical Detective</b> (The Riga Hayworth series)</p>
<p><b>Publisher: misterio press</b></p>
<p><b>Author:</b> <a href="http://www.kirstenweiss.com/">Kirsten Weiss</a></p>
<p><b>Pages:</b> 284 pp</p>
<p><b>Price:</b> free (ebook) / $5.95 &#8211; $10.95 (paperback)</p>
<p>Riga Hayworth is many things: a witch, an interpreter of dreams, a reader of tarot cards, and a private investigator. She is also a doting aunt to a teen niece who idolizes her, and best friend to an ex-pat French gargoyle. And now she finds herself caught up in the strangest case of her strange career: trying to solve the murder of a woman who was apparently killed by her own long-dead husband, while trying to figure out how sexy and charismatic casino owner Donovan Mosse fits into the whole thing . . .</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13097234-the-metaphysical-detective?from_search=true"><em>The Metaphysical Detective</em></a> is one of those rare books that left me feeling ambivalent. Usually, I thoroughly enjoy a story, or I have serious problems with it. I prefer to write about only the books that I enjoy, and share them with other readers. <em>The Metaphysical Detective</em> . . . well . . .</p>
<p>The good points. Riga Hayworth is a fantastic character: smart, sassy, compassionate, determined, and powerful. (Yes, she&#8217;s in on the joke regarding her name.) She knows that magic is not something to trifle with, and is prudent in its use. She also understands that everything &#8212; absolutely everything &#8212; is connected, and everything is Myth. That&#8217;s why she is so low key in her advertising (just flyers and business cards); it&#8217;s part of the initiatory process and people have to find their own way to her. She also uses tarot cards to profile the players in the mystery she is trying to unravel, plotting out their relationships to one another and to her.</p>
<p>Riga is also a loving sister to her totally non-magical sister and (supposedly) non-magical niece, Penelope. Riga is careful to keep her niece out of her investigations, not wanting the girl to become capital-E Entangled in mythical, magical goings-on. But when Penelope suddenly develops the ability to exorcise ghosts with just a word, Riga flips out, desperately trying to save the girl from a weird and dangerous future.</p>
<p>Which ultimately brings us to the part of the story that left me ambivalent. I love the use of myth in the story, with actions and events and people in the mundane realm mirroring what is happening in the mythical realm; as below, so above. I even like Weiss&#8217; use of Archetypes. Here, they are not imaginary constructs, make-believe reflections of our own thoughts and desires. Rather, they are the fully-realized manifestations of the primal story-powers of creation; bound to follow the dictates of their nature (just as we are), they often appear in forms which we can understand and relate to, but they are also autonomous entities.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a complex equation, but one that works in <em>The Metaphysical Detective</em>.</p>
<p>What did not work for me was the conclusion to the mystery that Riga was investigating, and how that tied into the nature and being of the Gods/Archetypes. No&#8211;no spoilers here. I won&#8217;t give away the ending. I will say, though, that when the motivation and identity of the murderer was revealed, I was stunned and had to set the book aside for a few days. When I finally picked it up again to read the last few chapters, I was fascinated by what it meant for Riga (and Penelope and Donovan), but still irritated. Or more than irritated.</p>
<p>So . . . ambivalent.</p>
<p>Ultimately, I do recommend <em>The Metaphysical Detective</em>. I think fans of <em>The SPI Files</em> by Shearin, Devon Monk&#8217;s <em>Ordinary Magic</em> series, <em>The Marnie Baranuik Files</em> by Aalto, and <em>The Medusa Files</em> by Black will enjoy the characters and the mystery &#8212; with the caveat that parts of the story may leave readers deeply irritated.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Corrina Lawson</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-corrina-lawson/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Buchanan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Today, we sit down for a brief interview with author Corrina Lawson. A regular reviewer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/b2ap3_thumbnail_Warriors-of-Seneca-Generic.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10321 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/b2ap3_thumbnail_Warriors-of-Seneca-Generic-188x300.jpg" alt="" width="188" height="300" /></a>[Today, we sit down for a brief interview with author <a class="caption" href="https://corrina-lawson.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Corrina Lawson</a>. A regular reviewer and blogger in the romance, fantasy, science fiction, and mystery genres, Lawson is also the author of two alternate history romances &#8212; one centered on ancient Rome, the other on the ancient Norse. Here, Lawson discusses her writing, her research, and the intricacies of re-releasing her books.]</strong></p>
<p><em>Question: <strong>Carnal Blessing</strong> is a re-release of <strong>Freya’s Gift</strong>. Why did you decide to write a romance about Vikings, and what role does Freya play in the story?</em></p>
<p><em>Corinna Lawson:</em> The short answer: I like Vikings! The long answer: I started this story with an idea: a Viking swinging an ax to exhaustion. I wanted to know who he was and why he was so driven. That led me down the rabbit hole to this world.</p>
<p>So while <em>Carnal Blessing </em>is an erotic story, it’s also a story about grieving and finding a way to recover and live again. Freya is the Norse goddess of fertility, which means that she’s the one responsible for the beginning of new life, but she’s also the goddess of sex and death. It would only be natural for the Vikings to pray to her for guidance on what to do next and interpret those signs. The important part is not whether I believe the goddess is real, but that the <em>characters</em> believe in her.</p>
<p><em>Q: You are in the process of re-releasing your Seneca series. First, what is the premise behind the books?</em></p>
<p><em>CL:</em> That the Roman Empire survived another five hundred years and managed to establish several small colonies in North America. This allowed me to have Romans and Vikings in the same timeline, something that obviously didn’t happen in the real world. And since it’s been established that the Vikings reached North America, I placed both there.</p>
<p>The stories contain people who are a mix of Romans, Vikings, and the Native American tribes. The overreaching plot arc is how they come to co-exist. The characters, however, are what drive the story. The heroine of <em>Warriors of Seneca </em>thought she’d find a new beginning in a new world, but war comes to her again, all the same. She wants victory not only for herself, but also to have peace for the next generation.</p>
<p>The heroine of <em>Eagle of Seneca</em> is a Native American woman who’s poised to become the leader of her Lenape tribe. She must decide whether the Romans should be viewed as enemies or allies and, if allies, which faction?</p>
<p>Basically, I’ve recreated the British Empire’s colonization of North America but, this time, since the Romans were more about assimilation of cultures rather than the destruction of them, the Native American tribes have a stronger chance of survival. I wanted a world where they not only survived, but thrived.</p>
<p><em>Q: How much research went into the Seneca series? Were you surrounded by stacks of books, or did you spend a lot of time doing research online?</em></p>
<p><em>CL</em>: Online, mostly, though I do recommend the book <a class="caption" href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/mannahatta-eric-w-sanderson/1100867103?ean=9781419707483#/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Mannahatta: A Natural History of New York City</em>,</a>which was a terrific resource. It detailed the topography and history of the island of Manhattan before colonization. It’s like that book was made just for my research.</p>
<p>Children’s books on Roman history from <em>DK Publishing</em> were great because they had detailed illustrations of such things as weapons, towns, and Roman encampments.</p>
<p>I also interviewed a history professor, who’s somewhat of an expert in Roman history.</p>
<p>There was television watching, as well. The History Channel has some terrific documentaries on ancient weapons and warfare.</p>
<p>The hardest part was research on the Native American tribes. Their history was mostly oral history and since many of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/cayetano-gil-532119-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10492 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/cayetano-gil-532119-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>them were systematically destroyed, so was much of their history. Many of the words we use to refer to them, for instance, are English or French, such as Algonquin or Iroquois. I wanted to dig deeper, to find equivalent words that were of their origin, such as Lenape or Mahican, though, of course, they’re also English translations of Native American words.</p>
<p>Native American names and words are still all over the Northeastern United States, even if we don’t recognize them as such. For example, as I researched the ancient rivers of New Jersey, I wanted to find the original word for the Passaic River, which I assumed was a French word. Not so. It comes from a Pay-say-ack (roughly translated), a Native American name.</p>
<p><em>Q: Why did you decide to re-release your books, and — for the other writers out there — how did you go about doing it?</em></p>
<p><em>CL:</em> It took a while because, well, it’s a complicated process. Not so much the nuts and bolts, but the marketing decisions.</p>
<p>The KDP (Kindle/Amazon) dashboard allows anyone to upload a cover and Word document, so long as you create an account and have a blurb/description. That takes, oh, an hour. Similarly, Draft2Digital will do the same and then upload your book to all epublishing sites, such as Amazon, B&amp;N, Kobo, Google Play, and iBooks. They take a ten percent cut, but it does save time. For me, I uploaded direct to KDP so as to cut out the middleman, but used Draft2Digital for the other ebook stores.</p>
<p>The hardest parts all related to marketing. I needed new cover art and that cover art needed to attract attention and convey the genre, all in one glance. I relied on friends in the business to look over the draft covers before finalizing them.</p>
<p>Then there was deciding on genre. I write cross-genre books, so which category should they be placed? For the <em>Seneca</em> books, that meant a choice between romance, SF/F, alternate history, and romantic fantasy. Which label would be mostly likely to attract readers who might love the book?</p>
<p>For publicity, I looked at newsletters and other methods and finally punted on doing it on my own. I went to Writerspace.com and signed up for their PR package. Those who are good at it can save the money. For me, I tossed the money in their direction so I could spend my time writing instead.</p>
<p><em>Q: You write for the <a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/blog/sci-fi-fantasy/">Barnes &amp; Noble Sci Fi and Fantasy blog</a>. How did you come to do so and which favorite new authors have you discovered as a result?</em></p>
<p><em>CL:</em> Joel Cunningham, who runs the blog, saw my GeekDad and GeekMom articles and asked me to write for him, too. That was quite flattering, so thanks, Joel!</p>
<p>I’ve read more SF/F through writing the reviews than I have in years. I loved Fonda Lee’s <a class="caption" href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/jade-city-fonda-lee/1125984281?ean=9780316440868#/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Jade City</em></a> (I’ll read whatever she publishes next); <a class="caption" href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/an-excess-male-maggie-shen-king/1125363212?ean=9780062662552" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>An Excess Male</em></a> by Maggie Shen King, a chilling and yet heartwarming story of what may happen next in a society where there is such an imbalance between the number of men and marriageable women; and <a class="caption" href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/kings-of-the-wyld-nicholas-eames/1124068319#/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kings of the </a><a class="caption" href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/kings-of-the-wyld-nicholas-eames/1124068319#/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Wyld</a> by Nicholas Eames, which has great fun with the idea of the classic fantasy company as a washed-up rock band.</p>
<p>I’ve also reviewed several John Scalzi novels and have developed a serious love for his science fiction mysteries. The second one, <a class="caption" href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/head-on-john-scalzi/1126272818?ean=9781250188922#/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Head On</em></a>, is just out.</p>
<p><em>Q: What other projects are you working on?</em></p>
<p><em>CL:</em> I’m going to be re-releasing my superhero romance series, <em>The</em> <em>Phoenix Institute</em>, over the next six months, one per month, because doing it that way makes Amazon’s algorithm happy. (Meaning more people might stumble across my work.)</p>
<p>After that, <em>finally</em>, I’ll have the sequel to <a class="caption" href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/the-curse-of-the-brimstone-contract-corrina-lawson/1118069779?ean=9781619224735" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>The Curse of the Brimstone Contract</em></a>, my steampunk mystery, out late in the year. That’s titled <em>A Hanging at Lotus Hall</em>.</p>
<p>In the meantime, I just finished an urban fantasy with romantic elements that is heavy on the ghost stories, and I also have a BDSM paranormal menage story that may/may not be self-published, depending. It’s out on submission right now. BDSM erotica is not my usual thing (it’s the only one I’ve written), but I had characters who suited the genre, so . . .</p>
<p><em>Q: Which conventions, book fairs, or other events will you be attending in the foreseeable future?</em></p>
<p><em>CL:</em> I’ll be headed to Book Expo America in June, but only as a journalist/book blogger. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/263a.png" alt="☺" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I’ll also be attending the Romance Writers of America conference in Denver in July. I’m not signing, but if anyone wants to meet up, you can hit me up on Twitter @CorrinaLawson or on <a class="caption" href="https://www.facebook.com/corrina.lawson" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Facebook</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Sandi Leibowitz</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-sandi-leibowitz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Buchanan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Here we sit down with poet and author, Sandi Leibowitz. A widely-published poet, Leibowitz just&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/b2ap3_thumbnail_leibowitz.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10325 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/b2ap3_thumbnail_leibowitz-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>[Here we sit down with poet and author, Sandi Leibowitz. A widely-published poet, Leibowitz just released her first collection, <em>The Bone-Joiner, </em>with more collections planned for the future. Leibowitz will also be reading some of her poetry live, for those in the New York City area this summer<em>.</em>]</strong></p>
<p><em>Question: How do you define your personal spiritual path? Are you solitary, or eclectic, or part of a tradition?</em></p>
<p>Sandi Leibowitz: I don’t consider myself a very spiritual person. I don’t follow any religion. I jokingly refer to myself as a JAP — Jewish Atheist Pagan (I was just telling someone that I made this term up decades ago and have started to hear other people using it): Jewish by upbringing (kinda sorta, which means, only culturally, not religiously); atheist by belief system; and pagan by attraction to old goddesses and gods of different cultures, primarily Ancient Greece, since these are the first gods I read about. I often celebrate pagan rituals, but only in the privacy of my own home or at least my own company.</p>
<p><em>Q: You recently published your first poetry collection, The Bone-Joiner. First, congratulations! Second, what sort of poems are included in the collection and how did you decide what to keep and what to set aside?</em></p>
<p>SL: Thank you! The poems are all speculative fantasy poems, mostly steeped in myths and fairy tales, though many are based in nothing but something from my own fancy. Many are dark, because that’s often where my imagination leads me. Some are humorous. Some celebrate the beauty of the world.</p>
<p>The question about deciding what to put in and what to keep out is an interesting one. I wanted to create a book that didn’t have too narrow a focus (e.g., all fairy tale poems), and did have that balance between light and dark. I decided to start with the title and had a few contenders. I decided on “The Bone-Joiner” because I thought that would catch people’s notice and not sound like anyone else’s work. I picked some of my favorite of my poems — but not all; I’m saving them for other collections!</p>
<p>At the same time, I also created two other possible chapbooks — and I didn’t want the books to contain any of the same materials, so some of the poems slated for the chapbooks were removed from <em>The Bone-Joiner</em>. I then looked for similarities among the poems, ways to group them, and came up with five sections, each given a title from one of the poems from that section: 1) Witch-Love: primarily about sorcerers and witches, often spells; 2) Lady Mary Speaks of Dreams: poems that are about dreams or dream-like, and poems based on fairy tales, with their dream-like imagery and symbolism; 3) Awakened – about ghosts and other creatures awakened from the dead; 4) Invasion – about dangerous beings; and 5) Attic Dust – poems centered on inanimate objects (or are they?).</p>
<p><em>Q: What sort of research went into the poems? What does your writing space look like?</em></p>
<p>SL: Some poems are born of my imagination and require no research (“Island of Crows” is based on a dream I had); <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/rawpixel-633849-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10488 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/rawpixel-633849-unsplash-300x209.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="209" /></a>others are based on myths, stories, etc., with which I’m very familiar. If I need to do research (such as for “Rusalka,” “Kosode-no-Te,” and “Attic Dust”) I’ll either use the internet or the internet in combination with books of myth I own.</p>
<p>I work pretty much exclusively in my &#8220;library&#8221; (I hate to call it an office; that sounds too much like work). It&#8217;s a book-lined room with teal walls, a wonderful painting of dancing people and dogs and a cat, and odds and ends like a miniature brass cauldron, an Aladdin&#8217;s lamp, a tiny cloth mermaid sitting in a French turquoise glass cup, a dragon-handled hourglass, antique marionettes, and stuff like that. My desk is completely awash in papers that are in danger of sliding to the floor and causing me to scream and rend my hair. In other words, a freakazoid mess.</p>
<p><em>Q: Which poem was the most difficult to write, and why?</em></p>
<p>SL: Probably “Sycorax Awaits the Birth of Caliban” and “Lizzie Siddal’s Blessing” were the hardest to write because I wrote them both a long time ago (especially &#8220;Sycorax&#8221;). A <em>really</em> long time ago. So long ago I don’t remember how hard I might have worked on them back then. But when I finally figured out that I was a writer of speculative poetry (the term didn’t exist when I started writing as a kid, and probably didn’t exist — or, at any rate, I was unaware of it, when I first wrote &#8220;Sycorax&#8221;), I went back to these two and knew I could do a much better job on them. With &#8220;Sycorax,&#8221; I wanted to create a unique voice, especially considering she was not only a witch, but also lived completely alone for who knows how long. Plus I needed to alert readers that this is a Shakespearean character who is never seen onstage.</p>
<p><em>Q: Where can curious readers find The Bone-Joiner?</em></p>
<p>SL: Curious readers may find <em>The Bone-Joiner </em>on <a class="caption" href="https://www.amazon.com/Bone-Joiner-Sandi-Leibowitz/dp/0999883909" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a>.</p>
<p><em>Q: Which poems and collections and authors would you recommend to fans of speculative poetry?</em></p>
<p>SL: I have very specific tastes in my speculative poetry, so I will recommend the sorts of poets and writing I love. While I love science fiction movies and TV shows, I pretty much don’t like reading it, and I really dislike reading SF poetry. (Sorry!) My taste is for fantasy poetry that uses luscious language and vivid imagery, especially if it’s based on myth and fairy tale.</p>
<p>My favorite spec poetry web sites include: <a class="caption" href="https://mythicdelirium.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Mythic Delirium</a>; <a class="caption" href="http://www.liminalitypoetry.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Liminality</a>; <a class="caption" href="http://throughthegate.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Through the Gate</a> (which is either defunct or on hiatus, but still on-line); and <a class="caption" href="http://www.goblinfruit.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Goblin Fruit</a> (which seems to be permanently done but is still on-line).</p>
<p>Some print books:</p>
<p><em><strong>The Moment of Change: An Anthology of Feminist Speculative Poetry</strong></em> edited by Rose Lemberg</p>
<p><em><strong>The First Bite of the Apple</strong></em> by Jennifer Crow</p>
<p><em><strong>Ghost Signs</strong> </em>by Sonya Taaffe</p>
<p><em><strong>Songs for Ophelia</strong> </em>by Theodora Goss</p>
<p><em><strong>Hungry Constellations</strong> </em>by Mike Allen</p>
<p><em><strong>How to Flirt in Fairyland</strong></em> by C.S.E. Cooney</p>
<p><em><strong>The Honey Month</strong></em> by Amal El-Mohtar</p>
<p><em><strong>Orpheus and Company</strong></em> and <em><strong>The Poets’ Grimm</strong> </em>are just two examples of anthologies of non-genre writers who are writing speculative poetry (the one based on myths, the other on fairy tales).</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/robert-lukeman-128794-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10489 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/robert-lukeman-128794-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Some favorite speculative poets other than those listed above include: Ada Hoffman, Sara Cleto, Brittany Warman, M. Sereno, Lynn Hardaker,  Virginia Mohlere, Megan Arkenberg, Tim Pratt, Margaret Wack, Lynette Mejia, Alexandra Seidel. I am probably forgetting a whole bunch. Of course, these are only contemporary poets, and speculative poetry, like speculative fiction, has been around since humans have created art.</p>
<p><em>Q: Which book fairs, conventions, or other events do you plan to attend in the foreseeable future?</em></p>
<p>SL: In July I will be attending Readercon in Massachusetts and am waiting to hear if I will be presenting a poetry reading with a bunch of terrific poets (to be announced if and when it’s announceable).</p>
<p>On August 11, I’m moderating and reading at a wonderful event I’m titling “Poe’s Heirs: Contemporary Speculative Poetry” at the visitors’ center at <a class="caption" href="http://bronxhistoricalsociety.org/poe-cottage/history-of-the-cottage/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Poe’s Cottage in the Bronx</a>. We will have a panel discussion on speculative poetry; readings by each of the participants; a Q&amp;A session; and a signing and book selling. The incredible group assembled are: Brittany Warman, Sara Cleto, C.S.E. Cooney, Carlos Hernandez and (depending on availability) Mike Allen. I so love this line-up!</p>
<p>I plan to do a reading in Queens, either solo or with other Queens poets, and possibly in Manhattan, and even more possibly in New Jersey, hopefully soon, but haven’t gotten around to arranging that yet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quick Pick: &#8220;One Fell Sweep&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/quick-pick-one-fell-sweep/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Buchanan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 12:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gods Among the Stars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Title: One Fell Sweep (The Innkeeper Chronicles #3) Publisher: NYLA Author: Ilona Andrews Pages: 338&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/andrews.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8455 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/andrews-195x300.jpg" alt="" width="195" height="300" /></a>Title: <em>One Fell Sweep</em></strong> (The Innkeeper Chronicles #3)<br />
<strong>Publisher: NYLA</strong><br />
<strong>Author:</strong> <a class="caption" href="http://www.ilona-andrews.com/innkeeper-chronicles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Ilona Andrews</a><br />
<strong>Pages:</strong> 338 pp<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> $4.99 (ebook) / $13.99 (paperback)</p>
<p><strong>The Hook:</strong> Dina DeMille is an Innkeeper. She runs the Gertrude Hunt, a bed and breakfast in Texas. But Dina is a very unusual Innkeeper, and the Gertrude Hunt deals with a very select clientele: aliens. Extraterrestrials. Beings of whom most humans are, and must remain, ignorant. It is Dina&#8217;s sacred duty as an Innkeeper to safeguard her guests &#8212; even if that means taking on a psychotic alien mercenary and his entire clan to save another species on the edge of extinction . . .</p>
<p><strong>The Analysis:</strong> <em><strong>The Innkeeper Chronicles</strong></em> might be loosely classified as urban science fantasy, if any label can be applied at all. Magic is real, but it is science that is so advanced that it operates like magic. (For example, Dina can open gates, or <a href="https://myalberteinstein.com/2015/11/21/the-einstein-rosen-bridge-and-the-einstein-podolsky-rosen-paradox-er-and-epr-wormhole-and-entanglement/">Einstein-Rosen Bridges</a>, to other planets.) There are space ships and laser guns in abundance, but also swords and knights and, oh yes, werewolves and vampires &#8212; but the werewolves and vampires are alien species. And all aliens who visit Earth are bound by treaty to not expose their existence to humanity, and to respect the neutrality of the Inns.</p>
<p>Of course, not all aliens abide by the treaty, which puts Dina in a difficult position: the Hiru have come to her, hoping to use the Gertrude Hunt as neutral territory where they may consult with the Archivarius. The avian Draziri have declared a religious war upon the pacifistic Hiru: anyone who kills a Hiru guarantees a place for him/herself and their entire clan in heaven beside the Draziri god. The Hiru are desperate to find a new home where their remaining members &#8212; fewer than a thousand &#8212; can live in peace.</p>
<p>Religion has always played an important role in the <strong>Innkeeper</strong> books, but here it takes center stage. Religion &#8212; sometimes sincere faith, sometimes crass manipulation &#8212; is the driving force behind the plot. The Hiru would not be on the verge of extinction if not for the Draziri holy war.</p>
<p>Not so subtle commentary on current events? Possibly. Or maybe just a timeless story about the dangers of fanaticism &#8212; of any kind.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/ryan-hefner-190737.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9208 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/ryan-hefner-190737-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>The <strong>Innkeeper</strong> series is also quite polytheistic, and it is a very pragmatic and skeptical polytheism. Different species follow different traditions, and Innkeepers like Dina treat them all with equal respect. Vampires, for example, worship a goddess who demands a life of honor and combat from her followers; she also demands that they respect other species&#8217; traditions. (No, vampires are not afraid of crucifixes; they just back away out of concern that they might be interfering in a religious rite.) Walk through the bazaar on the planet of Baha&#8217;char and one will see the adherents of hundreds of different faiths. If you&#8217;re willing to risk it, you can even try to consult with the prophets who live behind the toothed walls of the Sanctuary of Eno; but if they don&#8217;t want you there, the walls will eat you.</p>
<p><strong>The Verdict:</strong> I adore this series. I have changed my mind: I no longer want to reincarnate as a library cat. I want to be an Innkeeper. If I could afford it, I would purchase the <a class="caption" href="http://www.ilona-andrews.com/book/innkeeper-chronicles-vol-i/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">illustrated hardcover ominous edition</a>. As it is, I&#8217;ll have to stick with checking them out from the library a few times a year.</p>
<p>I understand from her social media posts that Andrews plans to continue the series for a few more books.* I, for one, cannot wait to see what further adventures await Dina, Sean, Arland, Maud, and everyone else who calls the Gertrude Hunt home.</p>
<p>Highly recommended to fans of Devon Monk, Lisa Shearin, Seanan McGuire, CS MacCath, and Lois McMaster Bujold.</p>
<p>Also, um, <em>cough.</em> If either of the Andrews is reading this: any chance of a follow-up series about Helen? Or Klaus? Or Tony? &#8216;Cause, you know . . . that would be cool . . . Just saying.</p>
<p>*<strong>Yes</strong>, <em>The Innkeeper Chronicles</em> must be read in order. Each successive book references previous events and characters; even though summaries explain a bit of what has happened, jumping in at the mid-point is not recommended.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Addendum: On Stories Of Our Own</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/addendum-on-stories-of-our-own/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Buchanan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gods Among the Stars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8329</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every now and then, the algorithms used by Amazon and Barnes &#38; Noble and Overdrive&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every now and then, the algorithms used by Amazon and Barnes &amp; Noble and Overdrive and such actually work. I find a recommendation for a book that I might enjoy pop up on the side of the page or on a bar along the bottom or in my email, and I&#8217;ll click on the link and lo and behold! This looks interesting!</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/igor-ovsyannykov-223082.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8995 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/igor-ovsyannykov-223082-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Such was the case last week when <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Cold-Shot-Chesapeake-Valor-Pettrey/dp/0764211978"><em>Cold Shot</em></a>, the first volume in <a href="https://www.danipettrey.com/about/">Dani Pettrey&#8217;s</a> <em>Chesapeake Valor</em> series caught my attention. I read through the synopsis and was just about to download it from the library when I spotted the publisher.</p>
<p><a href="http://bakerpublishinggroup.com/">Baker Publishing Group</a>.</p>
<p>A Christian publishing house.</p>
<p>I admit it: I hesitated. I have virtually no interest in Christian fiction of any kind, no matter the genre or topic. But this was a murder mystery and I love mysteries and the characters and story did sound interesting . . .</p>
<p>I finally decided <em>what the heck</em> and downloaded <em>Cold Shot.</em></p>
<p>I have to say that, overall, I am thoroughly enjoying the story. The characters are sympathetic and engaging, the mystery is intriguing, and the villains are all appropriately vile (sex trafficking in children and murder&#8211;it doesn&#8217;t get much more vile than that).</p>
<p>So, why am I discussing a Christian mystery on a Pagan blog? Because of that first bit: Christian. This is a murder mystery with spirituality at its core. The characters don&#8217;t just mouth platitudes. They <strong>live</strong> their faith, every day. They pray when they are in danger. They ask their god to protect their loved ones. They recite lines from cherished hymns to comfort themselves when they are particularly frightened or depressed. They remind themselves that their savior is strong, and so they can be strong, too. And they use that faith to fight the horror and greed and misery that they find in the world, to protect the innocent and the helpless, and to offer compassion and love to those who so desperately need it.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve said it before and I&#8217;ll say it again: we need more of our own stories. A monotheist can walk into virtually any bookstore or library in the world and find books like this: novels which seamlessly weave (their) faith into a fantasy novel or a science fiction story or a murder mystery or a children&#8217;s book. Their lore is shelved in religion, a category of nonfiction. Our lore is shelved in mythology and fairy tales. Their prayer books and how-to manuals and spiritual biographies are, again, shelved in the mainstream, acceptable religion section. Our prayer books and how-to manuals and spiritual biographies usually end up in the catch-all, fringe New Age or Metaphysics section &#8212; assuming there even <strong>is</strong> such a section.<a class="right-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/inja-pavlic-351545.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-8996 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/inja-pavlic-351545-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>This is why we need stories of our own. We need examples of other people (however fictional they may be) living our faiths, praying to our gods, fighting the good fight. I want to read a thriller about an <a href="http://www.beliefnet.com/faiths/pagan-and-earth-based/2001/04/who-are-the-asatruar.aspx">Asatruar</a> Marine fighting corruption in the military, drawing on his faith in Tyr to help him through. I want a mystery about a Druid fighting to protect the environment while trying to figure out who murdered a fellow eco-warrior. I want a story about a college professor who honors the Sumerian pantheon by going on a grand adventure to save priceless antiquities from religious fundamentalists. I want a story about a devotee of Artemis struggling to rescue children from forced labor in sweatshops.</p>
<p>Oh, and also? Biblical epics. I have lost count of how many novels I have seen which retell and celebrate the lives of various Biblical heroes and heroines and prophets and generals and kings. All well and good for those who want those stories, but you know what I want? I want historical fiction with Jezebel as the heroine, not the painted harlot. I want an ancient espionage tale centered around Delilah which does not cast her as the villain. Beyond that, I want stories which celebrate the native Balts who defended their lands against Christian Crusaders in the 12th and 13th centuries, which honor Redbad of Frisia, and lament the horrible death of Raud the Strong.</p>
<p>We deserve our own stories. Our gods deserve to have stories written about them, to show acts of faith being performed in their names. But no one else will write them. We have to write them.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s stopping you?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quick Pick: Strange Magic</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/quick-pick-strange-magic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Buchanan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 17:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gods Among the Stars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Title: Strange Magic: A Yancy Lazarus Novel (Pilot Episode) Publisher: Shadow Alley Press Author: James Hunter&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/b2ap3_thumbnail_lazarus.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-7944" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/b2ap3_thumbnail_lazarus-188x300.jpg" alt="" width="188" height="300" /></a>Title: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23944302-strange-magic"><em>Strange Magic: A Yancy Lazarus Novel</em> </a>(Pilot Episode)</strong><br />
<strong>Publisher: Shadow Alley Press</strong><br />
<strong>Author:</strong> <a href="https://jamesahunter.wordpress.com/">James Hunter</a><br />
<strong>Pages:</strong> 221 pp<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> 99 cents</p>
<p><strong>The Hook:</strong> Yancy Lazarus is a mage &#8212; a chain-smoking, hard-drinking, foul-mouthed, blues-loving rambler of a mage. He also has a reputation for being something of a fixer, thanks in no small part to his tendency to help out folks caught up in nasty supernatural situations, when, really he should know better. Really, he should. But when innocent lives are on the line he can&#8217;t just stand by and do nothing. And when someone sends a hyena ninja hitman to take him out &#8230; well, he kind of takes that personally &#8230;.</p>
<p><strong>The Analysis: </strong>Hunter has a real gift for both world-building and creating complex characters. Allusions are made to a Guild which oversees magic-users, and that Lazarus does not get along with them particularly well (or at all). The drug-runners and gun-runners with whom Lazarus finds himself allied are definitely not nice people, but they are not presented as caricatures; they love their families and friends, and are fiercely loyal and protective of one another. The magic system itself is also explained, but in a conversational way, like Lazarus has sat down next to the reader at a bar and is spinning a tall tale.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve never encountered a magic system in an urban fantasy story quite like this one. Essentially, magic is a combination of life force (Vim) and potential energy (Vis), formed by will; and once that potential energy manifests in the physical world (as wind or fire or water or whatever), it must operate by the laws of physics. So, all mages are also physicists. Lazarus can summon fire if he wants, but, once it manifests, it will function just like any other flame; so, surrounding himself with a wall of fire might sound cool, but there&#8217;s a good chance he&#8217;ll burn himself to a crisp.</p>
<p>From a Pagan perspective, the theology could be described as polytheistic; maybe a variation on monolatry or henotheism. References are made to a capital-G God, and to a heaven and hell; but there an untold number of other gods, godlings, demigods, and assorted spirits running around. They play a significant role in <em><strong>Strange Magic</strong></em>, and I have a feeling that holds true for the rest of the series.</p>
<p><strong>The Verdict:</strong> This is a fun, fun, fun first volume. Hunter was right to subtitle it the &#8220;pilot episode,&#8221; because it  reads like a television show in my head. The dialogue is fast and loose and snarky, there are chase sequences and near misses, really awful monsters, an insane villain who thinks he&#8217;s the hero of the story &#8230; oh, and more monsters, plus lots and lots of guns and lots of explosions and some really cool magic.</p>
<p>Definitely recommended to fans of <em><strong>The Dresden Files</strong></em> by Butcher, the <em><strong>Daggers and Steele</strong></em> series by Berg, the <em><strong>Immortal</strong><strong> Vegas</strong></em> books by Stark, the<em> <strong>Twenty-Sided Sorceress</strong> </em>series by Bellet, the <em><strong>InCryptid</strong></em> books by McGuire, and the <em><strong>Hellblazer</strong> </em>comic and <em><strong>Constantine</strong> </em>television series.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Series Review: The Gryphonpike Chronicles</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/series-review-the-gryphonpike-chronicles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Buchanan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 17:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gods Among the Stars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7940</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Series Title: The Gryphonpike Chronicles Omnibus Edition: The Barrows Books: Witch Hunt, Twice Drowned Dragon,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/gryphonpike.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7941 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/gryphonpike-200x300.jpg" width="200" height="300" /></a>Series Title: <a href="http://anniebellet.com/series/gryphonpike/"><em>The Gryphonpike Chronicles</em></a></strong><br />
<strong>Omnibus Edition: The Barrows</strong><br />
<strong>Books: <em>Witch Hunt, Twice Drowned Dragon, A Stone&#8217;s Throw, Dead of Knight</em></strong><br />
<strong>Publisher: Doomed Muse Press</strong><br />
<strong>Author:</strong> <a href="http://anniebellet.com/">Annie Bellet</a><br />
<strong>Pages:</strong> Various<br />
<strong>Price:</strong> free to $3.99</p>
<p>Her name is Killer &#8212; or, at least, that is what people call her. Once, she was an Elemental Elf, one of the ancient beings who sang the world into being. Then grief and pride led her to corrupt her own song, and she brought misery and destruction to the elemental realm. As punishment, she was stripped of her voice and immortality and sent to the mortal realm. Now mute, she must perform one thousand heroic acts to regain her rightful place.</p>
<p>And so Killer finds herself part of a motley crew of adventurers: Makha, a human paladin; her half-winter orc husband Azyrin, the shaman; Drake, the swordsman who hails from southern lands; and Rahiel the pixie-goblin sorceress who flies around on a miniature unicorn named Bill. As they travel through The Barrows, they encounter cursed villages, ancient ruins, undead dragons, necromancers, ghosts, monstrous wolves, and plain folk just trying to survive and provide for their families. With each monster defeated and each life saved, Killer draws that much closer to her goal &#8230; assuming that she <strong>wants</strong> to return home &#8230;.</p>
<p>Bellet is a fantastic storyteller. There are fights aplenty and narrow escapes. The characters grow and change and discover new things about themselves and one another. I also love how she takes the tropes of D&amp;D and high fantasy &#8212; like the band of adventurers &#8212; and simultaneously exploits them and turns them on their head. Orcs, for example, are supposed to be bloodthirsty barbarians. In contrast, Azyrin is cultured and honorable, a devotee of the Storm God, bound to help any who need him. Rahiel, as a pixie-goblin hybrid, loves sparkles and glitter, but also likes to set things on fire and blow stuff up.</p>
<p>The theology of the series is also, not surprisingly, polytheistic. The Goddess Thunla and her unicorn consort Billarhian are widely worshipped, apparently by both humans and other species. Other Deities, such as the Storm Lord and the Summer Lady, seem to be specific to certain groups, but there is no evidence of religious jealousy or attempts as proselytization.</p>
<p>I first discovered Annie Bellet in the <em><strong>Nine By Night</strong></em> box set, which includes the first book in her <em><a href="http://anniebellet.com/series/twenty-sided-sorceress/"><strong>Twenty-Sided Sorceress</strong> </a></em>series. I loved it, and immediately began to look for more of her work. When I discovered that <em><strong>Witch Hunt</strong></em>, the first story in <em><strong>The Gryphonpike Chronicles</strong></em>, was free, I downloaded it, loved it &#8212; and then couldn&#8217;t find any more books in the series.</p>
<p>Happily, three more stories are now available, both as individual digital files and as an omnibus edition. The price is roughly equivalent, either way. If you&#8217;re curious, I recommend that you download the free edition of <em><strong>Witch Hunt</strong></em>. If you like it (and you will!), you can then either pick-up the individual stories or download the whole thing in the omnibus format.</p>
<p>I really really hope that Bellet writes more stories for these characters. I want to know more about all of them &#8212; and I want to know where they got that pearl, gosh darn it!</p>
<p>Highly recommended to fans of Shannon Mayer, CSE Cooney, Sarah Avery, Jolene Dawe, Juli D Revezzo, Lindsey Buroker, and Catherynne M Valente.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Series Review: Hexworld</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/series-review-hexworld/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rebecca Buchanan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gods Among the Stars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This blog was originally posted on witchesandpagans.com and was reprinted with permission of the author.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This blog was originally posted on <a href="http://witchesandpagans.com/pagan-culture-blogs/bookmusings/series-review-hexworld.html">witchesandpagans.com</a> and was reprinted with permission of the author. </em></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/b2ap3_thumbnail_hexmaker.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7609 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/b2ap3_thumbnail_hexmaker.jpg" alt="b2ap3_thumbnail_hexmaker" width="192" height="288" /></a></strong><strong>Series: Hexworld</strong><br />
<strong>Titles: The 13th Hex</strong>, <strong>Hexbreaker</strong>, <strong>Hexmaker</strong>, and <strong>A Christmas Hex</strong><br />
<strong>Author/Publisher:</strong> <a href="http://jordanlhawk.com/">Jordan L. Hawk</a><br />
<strong>Price:</strong> 99 cents to $4.99</p>
<p>It is the end of the 19th century. Commissioner Theodore Roosevelt oversees the vast police force of greater New York City, including the elite Witch Police. In a world where magic is the norm &#8212; used for everything from fire suppression to targeted advertising to surgery &#8212; the Witch Police are responsible for protecting the people against those who would use magic for nefarious purposes: including murder.</p>
<p>There are three elements to the Witch Police. The hexwo/men who create the beautiful sigils meant to harness arcane powers; the Familiar who channels the magic into the hex; and the Witch who activates the hex. The Witch and Familiar make a unique bonded pair, a harmonious whole. In theory, anyway. In reality, Familiars are treated as second-class citizens in American society; given their ability to assume animal form, they are considered barely human. Most are exiled by their families and stripped of their surnames. It is not uncommon for unbonded Familiars to be kidnapped, imprisoned, and starved until they agree to bond with a witch; the practice may be &#8220;unsavory,&#8221; but it is perfectly legal. As a result, feral Familiars have formed small self-sufficient communities, and some have become so radicalized that they want to tear down the existing society by any means necessary and create a new one, a therianthocracy.</p>
<p>And this where our heroes come in. The plot builds slowly over the course of the series as, in between investigating bank robberies and kidnappings and murders, more and more bits of the conspiracy are unveiled. At the same time, while those who are planning violent revolt <em>are</em> the villains, they are not wholly unsympathetic; considering the fact that many live in a constant state of fear, and are abused and starved, their desire for change is completely understandable. At the same time, the means by which they are trying to achieve that change &#8212; kidnapping and draining Familiars who do not agree with them, and mass murder of innocent civilians &#8212; are absolutely unacceptable.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/HexbreakerCov_200x300.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-7790 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/HexbreakerCov_200x300-200x300.jpg" width="200" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>I love <a href="http://jordanlhawk.com/books/hexworld-series/"><strong>Hexworld</strong></a>. Hawk has created an entertaining, engrossing series filled with detailed world-building and complex characters. For example, Tom Halloran in <strong>Hexbreaker</strong> is a former gang member desperately trying to make a normal life for himself; he did some bad things once upon a time, so now he keeps his head down and tries to do right by the people under his protection. In <strong>Hexmaker</strong>, Malachi is a fox Familiar who was thrown out by his family and now works as a thief; it&#8217;s something he&#8217;s actually good at, giving him a sense of purpose and accomplishment (and he only steals from people who can afford to lose a few pretty baubles). Then there is Owen  Yates, a child of privilege who is torn between family duty and serving his community, between the requirement that he marry to advance his family&#8217;s ambitions and his desire for Malachi. There&#8217;s also Augustus Cao in <strong>A Christmas Hex</strong>, a Witch of mixed Chinese and Irish descent; while he has some status as a Witch, he is simultaneously looked down upon due to his ethnicity.</p>
<p>The various statuses and relationships between Hexwo/men, Witches, and Familiars allows Hawk to explore racial and ethnic prejudice, gender construction, sexuality, socioeconomic status, the nature of terrorism, and religion not just historically, but, more importantly, in the modern world. Owen Yates&#8217; family, for example, is highly educated, Caucasian, and Protestant. They look down on Malachi because he is Irish <em>and</em> Catholic <em>and</em> a Familiar; so far as they are concerned, he will never amount to anything and should Know His Place. Catholicism is considered a heresy, due to its devotion to Mary Magdalene, Christ&#8217;s Holy Familiar. No doubt the Yates family and their ilk would be aghast if Augustus Cao were to explain that, in Chinese society, Familiars are <em>not</em> ostracized but remain with their families; bondings with Witches are even arranged and treated like marriages, with the ceremony performed in a temple and blessed by the Gods. (I&#8217;m curious as to how this ties in with the Chinese zodiac, and hope Hawk explores this further in future volumes.) Additionally, while women have few rights in mainstream society and homosexuality is never spoken of aloud, women are treated as equals in the Witch Police, and Familiars are almost all homosexual. Hawk even takes the opportunity to critique modern prejudices against the transgender community through the character of Nathan Yates, Owen&#8217;s younger brother; born female, he underwent hex-based gender affirmation surgery in France. Their parents, of course, thoroughly disapproved and have been reluctant to welcome Nathan back into the fold.</p>
<p>The <strong>Hexworld</strong> books are fun, fast, and highly entertaining, with hidden depths that will keep the reader engaged long after the last page. I can&#8217;t wait to read the next book, and the book after that, and the book after that.</p>
<p>Highly recommended to fans of Megan Derr, KJ Charles, Astrid Amara, Rhys Ford, Zoe Archer, and Thea Harrison.</p>
<p>[Note: <strong>The 13th Hex</strong> is available as part of the <strong>Charmed and Dangerous</strong> anthology, and as a stand-alone novella. If you are curious about <strong>Hexworld</strong>, this first story is a good place to start. <strong>A Christmas Hex</strong> is also an excellent stand-alone story; I hope Cao and his lupine Familiar appear in more stories.]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
