<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/enclaves-a-black-femme-dreams/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 10:57:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Beyoncé’s ‘Renaissance’ Album (2022)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/beyonces-renaissance-album-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 10:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28605</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A little over a year later, I’d like to return to the topic of Black&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_28606" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-28606" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28606" src="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/RENAISSANCE-DIGITALALBUM-BEYONCE-300x269.webp" alt="Album cover for Beyoncé’s 2022 ‘Renaissance’ album. Edited image shows Beyoncé atop a glowing, transparent horse." width="300" height="269" srcset="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/RENAISSANCE-DIGITALALBUM-BEYONCE-300x269.webp 300w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/RENAISSANCE-DIGITALALBUM-BEYONCE.webp 400w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-28606" class="wp-caption-text">Source: beyonce.com | <em>Renaissance</em> (2022)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A little over a year later, I’d like to return to the topic of </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/in-this-dancery-notes-on-the-magic-of-nightlife/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Black nightlife</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> — motivated by the recent release of Beyoncé’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renaissance </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">album. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This post isn’t meant to be a contrarian diatribe. I know Beyoncé is a talented musician and I admire her artistic accomplishments — especially her </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-spectacular-black-america-and-palestine/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">live performances</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It’s my admiration of her work that fuels my mild distaste for her latest project. Ultimately, I know Beyoncé can make more transcendent club music than the songs on </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renaissance </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">because she’s already done so throughout her career — especially from 2003-2013 (her pre-</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lemonade</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> era). </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renaissance </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is a smart album in theory, from a business mogul’s standpoint — it’s a conversation-starter, and it was a </span><a href="https://www.complex.com/music/beyonce-renaissance-three-act-project-album-message"><span style="font-weight: 400;">timely</span></a> <a href="https://www.wbur.org/cognoscenti/2022/08/03/beyonce-renaissance-album-covid-racism-harvey-young"><span style="font-weight: 400;">release</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> during the first pandemic summer when it seemed socially acceptable (if not safe) to dance amongst throngs of people. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renaissance </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">looks great on paper. But my interest in music is preoccupied by what it inspires within me, not by the claims it makes about itself. In its press coverage, its lyrics and its marketing, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renaissance </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">has announced itself as a rebirth of house music and club bops, but club music’s magic has historically arisen from its connection to specific locales, scenes, and underground circuits. When club music is made into pop music, the rough edges that allow it to enter our bodies are often smoothed out. I think that’s the case with this album.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Club music that truly </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">brings the house down</span></i> <a href="https://youtu.be/7UgIGVDEs_8"><span style="font-weight: 400;">isn’t Madonna’s “Vogue,”</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> which </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renaissance </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is openly in conversation with. It’s crafted by the queer street kids who pop icons are inspired by. How can I adore </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renaissance </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">when I’ve listened to Cakes da Killa, Quay Dash, Lagniappe, Abdu Ali, Kaytranada, Zebra Katz and LSDXOXO? It doesn’t compare. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renaissance </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">isn’t erratic or audacious enough to induce rabid -ussy-popping or trance-dancing. It’s pre-gaming music, not dancefloor music. It’s more suitable for instagram reels than electric, had-to-be-there nights. It feels like it should be in a museum, not playing at a basement party. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are at least a few past Beyoncé songs that have understood the house-music assignment. “Crazy In Love” and “Naughty Girl” (2003), the first songs on Beyoncé’s debut solo album, are well-situated within house and club music traditions — powerhouse vocals mingling with infectious, percussive beats. “Get Me Bodied” (2006), with its undeniable gospel influences and pulsating instrumentals, is also a child of house and club music — a spiritual experience that has inspired many a dance session in my lifetime. “Blow” (2013), too, offers a seductive dancing experience — vocals and instrumentals heightening each other into sonic euphoria. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renaissance</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has a fainter pulse than those earlier standouts. “I’M THAT GIRL,” “COZY,” “ALIEN SUPERSTAR,” “PLASTIC OFF THE SOFA” and “AMERICA HAS A PROBLEM” are intriguing tracks, but the singer’s voice and persona overwhelm them. Beyoncé’s vocal performance is the star of the album rather than one of its instruments. The songs’ hypnotic, subversive potentials are muffled by proclamations of material wealth and social mastery. And if house and club music are meant to get us free, what place does a singular, billionaire superstar’s narrative have within it? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My opinion of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Renaissance </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is not as easy as thinking it’s “bad.” I don’t think it’s a bad album. I think it’s a polished album that pales in comparison to its primary source material. I will listen to the future companion projects Beyoncé teased in </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cfb3ddsFe2S/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">an Instagram post</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, because I do care about what she makes. But I understand that I want more from music, and the world, than she alone can provide.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Further Listening:</b></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/4cuWLmE34YTJkiUgQVBeLv?si=4JsyGoLwRmqIupkiWN1mmw"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Qweendom</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> music compilation (2016)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nisi Shawl’s ‘Talk Like A Man’ (2020)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/nisi-shawls-talk-like-a-man-2020/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 10:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Talk Like A Man contains four short stories and two nonfiction pieces by Nisi Shawl,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_28280" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-28280" style="width: 201px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28280" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/pm_press_talk_like_a_man_nisi_shawl-201x300.jpg" alt="This is an image of the front cover of Nisi Shawl's collection of short stories, 'Think Like A Man.' It depicts the author holding a doll, in front of a backdrop of a forest." width="201" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/pm_press_talk_like_a_man_nisi_shawl-201x300.jpg 201w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/pm_press_talk_like_a_man_nisi_shawl.jpg 401w" sizes="(max-width: 201px) 100vw, 201px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-28280" class="wp-caption-text">Image Source: PM Press</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://pmpress.org/index.php?l=product_detail&amp;p=1050"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Talk Like A Man</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> contains four short stories and two nonfiction pieces by Nisi Shawl, all of which commemorate the author’s career as an Afrofuturist science fiction writer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The title </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Talk Like A Man</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> creates an expectation of gender play and subversion, but that was not what I experienced in my reading of it. Both the fiction and nonfiction in this collection seem far more invested in representing dominant gender dynamics than in disrupting them, rendering </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Talk Like A Man</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a project that mimics a man’s world without overtly suggesting another way of living.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first short story in the collection, “Walk like a Man,” features a far future world that might be considered post-black (in the sense that blackness no longer functions as a racial signifier and blackness is no longer an axis of oppression). This story also includes provocative considerations of how human bodies would be valued in a hyperdigital world with sentient, lifelike AIs; Shawl imagines that possessing a physical body would be a source of power in this setting, and AI families who could afford to have their children implanted in human bodies could become upwardly mobile. Although I enjoyed the premise of this story, I was often lost in its peppering of neologisms and its absence of exposition. The story dropped me in the middle of an ongoing world without grounding me in its history or quirks — which may partly be owed to the fact that this is one of the collection’s shorter pieces, clocking in at about 12 pages. I wanted more coherence, in plot or in sentiment, from the story that presumably inspired the collection’s title.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A pattern of vague language and over-abstraction continues throughout </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Talk Like A Man</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. “Women of the Doll,” the second short story, makes odd connections between sex work, trauma, and objectification. It follows a woman named Josette who belongs to a “hidden” coven called Women of the Doll. The coven appears to recruit women who experienced trauma, groom them into magical, ultra-alluring sex workers, and send them out into the world to seduce rich men, who are so entranced that they give up more money than they otherwise would. The women’s traumatized souls also happened to be placed in dolls so they wouldn’t be retraumatized by the sex work they engaged in, which gave me pause. I wondered why this story wasn’t more critical of the systems that made Josette so vulnerable, and why characters in this world weren’t more suspicious of Women of the Doll, which is apparently a known organization. I was also concerned that sex work was being portrayed as an occupation that only attracts terribly traumatized, exploitable people. The details of “Women of the Doll” weren’t always clear (why the organization exists, if their members’ souls are ever restored to their bodies, etc.), but it is apparent that Josette dreams of building a home, and retiring in it with “all the others”— who are presumably other dollified women. At over 30 pages long, this is one of the collection’s longer stories, but it feels incomplete.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The collection’s third story, “Something More,” takes us to an affluent corner of Britain. Unfortunately, I wasn’t quite convinced by the story’s setting. Its English slang was laid on too thick, and portrayals of antiblackness seemed unmoored from British history and culture. Part of the issue with the writing may be that there was too much plot for a less-than-40-page story. Allie, the protagonist, is a rich racist white English woman and musician who appears to be hashing out relationship drama and fleeing an evil wizard who possesses people’s bodies. While fleeing this wizard, Allie also travels to the future through a mirror and realizes, with shock, that her biological descendants will be magical black people. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There may be some self-insertion from the author when Allie laments, regarding criticisms of her obscure songwriting, that “if the meaning was known, the magic was lost.” (p. 71) I of course think it’s a fallacy that people can only be dazzled if they’re confused, as I often was while reading this collection. I believe the overall sensation of an artwork can be mysterious without all of its meaning being hidden. Accordingly, one element of this story I did appreciate was Shawl’s vision of a future with “white temples, Black poets, strange beasts.” (p. 80) Shawl teased a fantastical far-future where black people know they are powerful and use that power to stay connected to Earth instead of destroying it. I wish “Something More” had had enough room in it to comfortably house that concept.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The final short story in this collection, “An Awfully Big Adventure,” was underwhelming. It’s a two-and-a-half page flash fiction piece about phases of a person’s life, from birth to death, that reads like the result of a timed writing exercise. It moved far too fast for me to feel invested in it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The two nonfiction pieces that flank this collection were the most rewarding reads. “Ifa: Reverence, Science, and Social Technology” is an essay that was adapted from a talk Shawl gave at Stanford in 2004. It branches out from a definition of science fiction as “‘fiction that believes in science’” (p. 84) and makes the case for spiritual practices (particularly the Afrodiasporic practice of Ifa) as scientific processes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“‘The Fly in the Sugar Bowl: Nisi Shawl interviewed by Terry Bisson” is the final piece in this collection, and it showcases Shawl’s wit and eccentricity in addition to providing tidbits about their journey to becoming a science fiction writer. This piece also provides an important definition of Afrofuturism. Per Shawl, it “is not a subgenre of SFFH […] it’s a means of encompassing many different genres and subgenres. It’s an aesthetic movement rather than a set of guidelines for ways to construct or read a story.” (p. 103)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Talk Like A Man</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> isn’t one of my favorite collections, and it could have benefited from more curation (e.g. a foreword that ties the pieces together), it is a welcome introduction to Shawl’s work and concerns, which I’ll continue to explore. </span><a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781466837843/everfair"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everfair</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (2016) is next on my to-read list.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Black Feminist Serenades (A Song Playlist)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/black-feminist-serenades-a-song-playlist/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 11:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; If Black Feminist Love has core attributes, one of them must be feeling&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<figure id="attachment_28056" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-28056" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28056" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/The_Electric_Lady_Sam_Spratt-300x300.jpg" alt="Cover art for Janelle Monae's album, 'The Electric Lady.' Features multiple versions of Janelle Monae, all wearing black and white stripes." width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/The_Electric_Lady_Sam_Spratt-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/The_Electric_Lady_Sam_Spratt-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/The_Electric_Lady_Sam_Spratt-550x550.jpg 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/The_Electric_Lady_Sam_Spratt.jpg 720w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-28056" class="wp-caption-text">Album Cover: &#8216;The Electric Lady&#8217; by Janelle Monae (2013) | Source: Sam Spratt</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If Black Feminist Love has core attributes, one of them must be feeling out of this world. It must be a love that transports you to different social conditions than our current ones — conditions that affirm black gender rebellions and all around sweeter living. Black Feminist Love is not only love expressed by and for black women, but love that is capable of actively loving all black people—especially those who are neglected in popular discourses about black life and death. </span></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In my own attempt to think about what Black Feminist Love looks, feels, and sounds like, I’ve compiled a list of serenades that are suggestive of a black feminist spirit. I’m attracted to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">serenades </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">as emblems of Black Feminist Love because they are characteristically soft, romantic, and easy on the senses.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><b>“</b><a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/1m1bkkELiD3Nso6ctBLPLj?si=q6CI43JEQW6rIg-L4TGztQ"><b>Ghetto Woman</b></a><b>” by Janelle Monáe, from </b><b><i>The Electric Lady</i></b><b> (2013)</b></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is one of my favorite songs from </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Electric Lady</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in particular, and by Janelle Monáe more generally. Monáe’s own working class background permeates this tune, which is also influenced by Stevie Wonder’s “</span><a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/7wOKVOhqghB6rCyaPWVegJ?si=QbdaQAR1S8WCrLKglrZ5cA"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Boogie On Reggae Woman</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">” (1974).</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><b>“</b><a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/0ThY4m18BDygljq0qq0phK?si=-rwuv1o1TyudYhSieis2aQ"><b>Black Is the Color of My True Love’s Hair</b></a><b>” by Nina Simone, from </b><b><i>Nina Simone at Town Hall</i></b><b> (1959)</b></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This song is resoundingly tender, and written by a black lover for her black lover. It’s warm, and it melts me. Oh, to be black, and miraculously know who your true love is.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><b>“</b><a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/6pRo1ryP9N8aFCe1YpWQLj?si=oMDbJUZJR9GG9fo78kYIdg"><b>Borderline (An Ode to Self Care)</b></a><b>” by Solange &amp; Q-Tip, from </b><b><i>A Seat at the Table</i></b><b> (2016)</b></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is such a gentle song—brought to us by two of my favorite musicians, and inspired by </span><a href="https://www.refinery29.com/en-us/2021/05/10493153/reclaiming-self-care-audre-lorde-black-women-community-care"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Audre Lorde’s</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> conceptualization of self care. “Borderline” doesn’t pretend the world isn’t long-suffering, or that we aren’t actively fighting for it to be reborn. It does insist we need to rest in order to resist.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><b>“</b><a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/5n5Z1gVpQ51FOZp1MUHmV0?si=04fw1Kk3RmCHuZHnTKQUww"><b>Take A Little Trip</b></a><b>” by Minnie Riperton, from </b><b><i>Perfect Angel</i></b><b> (1974)</b></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a tough-love song. Minnie Riperton firmly and gorgeously encourages her addressee to get a grip, and think of people who don’t share their life experiences—which might make them a better person. Love and politics merge here.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><b>“</b><a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/2eOpW5DYOKUVYby95EUsWN?si=diWCblEQRJWUPwfmz3QDjw"><b>I Wonder U</b></a><b>” by Prince, from </b><b><i>Parade </i></b><b>(1986)</b></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.npr.org/2021/12/15/1064509418/bell-hooks-feminist-author-critic-activist-died"><span style="font-weight: 400;">bell hooks</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> might be considered a patron saint of Black Feminist Love, and so much of her work regards the cultivation of a deep curiosity that traverses gender binaries. This song is a short-and-sweet ode to curiosity in love.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><b>“</b><a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/0CSjMXDSJj5010AGSOqjpa?si=hrRIECjGSnumMgKAg7jZoQ"><b>Gigolos Get Lonely Too</b></a><b>” by Morris Day and The Time, from </b><b><i>What Time Is It?</i></b><b> (1982)</b></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to this song having a gritty </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">noir </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">persona, being wholly good to my ears (vocally, instrumentally), and being written by the </span><a href="http://princevault.com/index.php?title=Gigolos_Get_Lonely_Too"><span style="font-weight: 400;">late great Prince</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, I like its sex-positivity. The serenading character, a sex worker, doesn’t forgo his occupation in order to pronounce his love, and being a known gigolo doesn’t prevent him from acknowledging his desire for more than transactional relationships. He contains multitudes.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><b>“</b><a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/1RRzO2Ny0l17IiHcB6MKKo?si=mn65K9VpSCu7Vp_hDNeQ4g"><b>Love Song #1</b></a><b>” by Meshell Ndegeocello, from </b><b><i>Comfort Woman</i></b><b> (2003)</b></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sultry and affectionate, this is one of my favorite slow jams. I enjoy Ndegeocello’s music because she doesn’t shy away from being </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/love-letter-2/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">chivalrous</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or masculine, which lends itself to gender-play.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/2KlnDxr7nYOIffSKu6eDaR?si=KgUp2s4DRjypByA2bnpcxg"><b><i>Spotify Playlist</i></b></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Love Letter #2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/love-letter-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 10:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; Come live with me in comfort. — “Come Live With Me Angel” (1976,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<figure id="attachment_27692" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-27692" style="width: 225px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27692" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/208B577D-538D-4E23-9A97-A7BE8CF56B81-225x300.jpeg" alt="Author's photo of the beach" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/208B577D-538D-4E23-9A97-A7BE8CF56B81-225x300.jpeg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/208B577D-538D-4E23-9A97-A7BE8CF56B81-768x1024.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/208B577D-538D-4E23-9A97-A7BE8CF56B81-1152x1536.jpeg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/208B577D-538D-4E23-9A97-A7BE8CF56B81.jpeg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-27692" class="wp-caption-text">Photo taken by the author (Liza Wemakor) on March 3, 2022</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote><p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Come live with me in comfort.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">— “Come Live With Me Angel” (1976, song) by Marvin Gaye</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">My love is alive.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">— “Ain’t No Mountain High Enough” (1967, song) by Marvin Gaye &amp; Tammi Terrell</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I saw you and made up my mind.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">— </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jazz</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (1992, novel) by Toni Morrison</span></p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve told you about how my gender has something knightlike in it. Not for European antiquity’s sake, or for my dedication to any crown, but the one that culminates in a widow’s peak at the top of your head. It’s in my enduring spirit. Love seemed to have given up on me once, but I didn’t (couldn’t) give up on love, so I rode horseback into my own insides to find it (my love), and then I met you, and your love looked a lot like mine. Gallant, focused, intentional.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now we contemplate the notion of living together, and I can think of many reasons to, and no reasons not to. I think we are both who we say we are, and thankfully, those people go well together. And if we do live together in the near future, there will always be knickknacks on the tables, vinyl records and books on the shelves, fresh pickings from the garden on our plates, your handiwork (embroidery) on clothes and cushions. And if those things should disappear, there would still be you, Fantastic Person, who makes every place feel like a candlelit cottage on a cooling summer evening.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fiercest people are often so gentle, and you are living proof of that. A few months ago you drove me to the Pacific Ocean (my first time), and the water was so cold and choppy, but you probably would’ve gone deeper if I wasn’t afraid — even with the waves rising over our heads. And when we walked barefoot onto the rocks surrounding the tide pools, you didn’t flinch at the jagged edges. You taught me where to step, how to angle my feet, where to spot the fish and the turtles.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our kitten, Sweetness, may not share your name per se, but I did name them after you. So affectionate, yet a fighter, just like you: their unironic </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">pawther</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. I wanted to live with Sweetness so much, but I was also so afraid when we first got them. Truth be told, I was never much good at charming babies of any species — even when I adored them. I was too self-conscious to play, to gush, to be silly — things babies need to feel wanted. But you knew I could do it, and remembered that sometimes I need to be reminded </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I can do it</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. And now no one could tell me Sweetness isn’t our child, and I love them like I love you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve told you about how my gender has male R&amp;B singers in it: Babyface, Usher, Eric Benet — soft boys. Some time after that revelation, we watched </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hairspray</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (2007) and joked about how sensational it would be if Seaweed and Link were genderqueer. And maybe we decided they already were.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">READ: “</span></i><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/love-letter-1/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Love Letter #1</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">”</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: &#8216;The Memory Librarian&#8217; (2022)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-memory-librarian-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With six stories ranging from micro-fiction to novella in length, The Memory Librarian (2022) extends&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_27440" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-27440" style="width: 197px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-27440 size-medium" src="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/memory_librarian_harper_collins-197x300.webp" alt="Cover of 'The Memory Librarian' book (2022). Features an edited image of Janelle Monae in 'Dirty Computer' (2018)." width="197" height="300" srcset="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/memory_librarian_harper_collins-197x300.webp 197w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/memory_librarian_harper_collins.webp 425w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-27440" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Source: Harper Collins</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With six stories ranging from micro-fiction to novella in length, <em>The </em></span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Memory Librarian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (2022) extends </span><a href="http://www.transchordian.com/2013/10/metropolis-janelle-monaes-hidden-sci-fi-epic/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the dystopian world</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that thespian-musician Janelle Monae has been constructing for at least 15 years. Working with five acclaimed speculative fiction writers (Alaya Dawn Johnson, Eve Ewing, Danny Lore, Yohanca Delgado, and Sheree Renée Thomas), Monae weaves her own discography and the science-fiction classics that inspired it into a debut collection that insists upon black-queer politics and black-queer futurisms. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Librarian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">’s recurring theme is the importance of communal memory to political resistance, which is metaphorized through rebel characters who “remix” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nevermind </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">: a gaseous chemical that erases deviants’ memories in order to maintain the social order of New Dawn. New Dawn is a fascist metropolis, but it nonetheless contains pockets of resistance that thrive and survive in its neglected districts.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Librarian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">’s stories — namely “The Memory Librarian” (co-written with Johnson) and “Nevermind” (co-written with Lore) — representations of transness that were </span><a href="http://blackyouthproject.com/janelle-monaes-pynk-subtly-acknowledges-the-existence-of-trans-bodies-but-we-deserve-more-than-that/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">only alluded to</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Monae’s otherwise outspoken </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dirty Computer</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (2018) find rooting in principal, trans characters with complicated lives — lives that are touched by both pleasure and hardship. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The title story (“The Memory Librarian,” co-written with Johnson) was by far my favorite piece in the collection, both for its sensitive sketch of a rebellious, black trans woman (Alethia a.k.a. Lethe), and for its vivid depiction of New Dawn. This story seems to be the heart of the collection, dramatizing its revolutionary investments (see: protagonist Seshet’s gradual defection from New Dawn’s government), and fleshing out an exciting magic system (see: disc jockeys’ abilities to “remix” Nevermind into an intoxicant). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve been of two minds, however, about “Nevermind” (co-written with Lore). Not because of the quality of its writing or its story arc, which were fine (I enjoyed its considerations of non-punitive justice, and of the disappointments we face as we try to ‘find our people’). My issue with the story is that I suffer from a continued ambivalence towards </span><a href="https://youtu.be/PaYvlVR_BEc"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pynk</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which I see</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">as an essentialist feminist concept. Even with an explicitly nonbinary character (Neer) starring alongside Jane 57821 (one of Monae’s dirty-computer personae), and even with a sharp critique of transphobic feminists, by choosing to set this story in Pynk Hotel (a women’s commune depicted in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dirty Computer</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">’s </span><a href="https://vimeo.com/268498567"><span style="font-weight: 400;">emotion picture</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">), the writers confine the narrative to oversimplified conceptions of femininity and womanhood. This story suggests that anyone who identifies with womanhood is welcome at </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pynk</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but it doesn’t sufficiently (re)consider what womanhood is, or how </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">pynk </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">could be an alternative to normative gender categories. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The four stories that cushion the title story and “Nevermind” — “Breaking Dawn” (solely authored by Monae), “Timebox” (Ewing), “Save Changes” (Delgado), “Time Altar(ed)” (Thomas) — have promising moments, but they ultimately feel less grounded in the sleek aesthetics of New Dawn. They&#8217;re emotionally resonant, but lack the tightness and focus that could have turned a decent collection into an excellent one.  </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">**I received an Advance Reader Copy through NetGalley in exchange for a review.</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Black Girls and Mirrors: A Review of ‘Starkeisha’ (2022)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/black-girls-and-mirrors-a-review-of-starkeisha-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 10:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What’s on the other side of this will… it’ll ruin you forever. — Starkeisha’s Reflection&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_27238" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-27238" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27238" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Starkeisha_2022_Hulu-200x300.jpg" alt="This is a thematic poster of the 'Starkeisha' film. It shows mirror images of the main character, one with a short black afro and the other with straight, black hair. " width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Starkeisha_2022_Hulu-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Starkeisha_2022_Hulu.jpg 458w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-27238" class="wp-caption-text">Starkeisha (2022) | Source: Hulu</figcaption></figure>
<blockquote><p><strong>What’s on the other side of this will… it’ll ruin you forever.</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">— Starkeisha’s Reflection / Inner Critic</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few images of black girls looking into mirrors are prominent in my memory. Versions of Beyoncé dance-off in </span><a href="https://youtu.be/VVO9B-26oXM"><span style="font-weight: 400;">one of her</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Pepsi commercials (2013), </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/when-in-autumn-black-witch-sounds-an-album-playlist/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spellling reposes</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in a photo series by </span><a href="https://www.catalinaxavlena.com/filmphotography"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Catalina Xavlena</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (2018), Red and Adelaide face-off in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Us </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">(dir. Jordan Peele, 2019), and most recently, Starkeisha faces her inner self in a short film of the same name (dir. Mo McRae, 2022). Each of these mirror images is at once exhilarating and horrific, baptizing unexpecting black girls in darker, altered versions of themselves. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starkeisha</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> presents a young Black woman named Starkeisha Mary Jenkins (portrayed by debut actress Dom Chanel) who’s trying to assimilate to white corporate culture. She’s just finished psyching herself up for an interview at a ritzy law firm when a fall knocks her unconscious. At this juncture, she suddenly awakens in a room of mirrors — her sleek straight hair now transformed into a thick short afro, and her business-casual garb replaced by a fitted spacesuit. Two voices structure Starkeisha’s experience of her own internal universe: there is The Voice (provided by actress Vanessa Bell Calloway), a disembodied, godlike entity who offers cryptic guidance toward self-love, and there is Starkeisha’s reflection, a trickster-like presence who rallies for assimilationist dreams. With the sweetness of The Voice and the snark of her new reflection as foundations, Starkeisha eventually escapes the mirrored room by </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">being the magic — </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">embarking on an odyssey of personal growth and ancestral connection beyond the echo-chamber of her self-consciousness.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starkeisha’s reflection (a.k.a. her inner critic) repeatedly asks: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shouldn’t you be trying to get out of here instead of having all this fun?</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> But the short film takes this question as its point of departure rather than its thesis. McRae’s film suggests having fun is not mutually exclusive with getting free, and furthermore, one’s ability to have fun can lead to a higher capacity for freedom. Perhaps people who trust each other enough </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/in-this-dancery-notes-on-the-magic-of-nightlife/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">to have fun together</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are also better prepared to fight together. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The liberationist themes and representations of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starkeisha </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">align with Reverend Andrew Rollins’ description of Astroblackness. <em>Astroblackness</em> being an Afrofuturist movement “in which a person’s black state of consciousness [&#8230;] becomes aware of the multitude and varied possibilities and probabilities within the universe” (Anderson &amp; Jones, 2016, p. vii). I have my critiques of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starkeisha</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, for its oversimplified invocation of natural black hair as a symbol of black consciousness, for its over-reliance on Western space-opera aesthetics to establish Starkeisha as a futuristic character, and for its missed opportunities to build cinematic mood and tension, but I appreciate its reflection of a pivotal moment in Afrofuturism. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m inclined to note that it’s a bit too obvious that this film is a response to curated music compilations (see: the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Music For The Movement </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">EP series), as evidenced by how its narrative potential often loses out to its conceptual ambitions (which reify rather than reinvent cliches of Afrofuturism). But as Starkeisha herself comes to understand, there’s no harm in having fun. This film still offers poignant revelations along the way.</span></p>
<p><b>References / Further Reading:</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BOOK: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Afrofuturism 2.0: The Rise of Astro-Blackness</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, ed. Reynaldo Anderson &amp; Charles E. Jones (2016)</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/44489514?seq=1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ARTICLE</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">: “AFROFUTURISM 2.0 &amp; THE BLACK SPECULATIVE ART MOVEMENT: Notes on a Manifesto” by Reynaldo Anderson (2016)</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Love Letter #1</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/love-letter-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 11:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“But there are couples who find it sheer bliss to be spending a lifetime with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400">“But there are couples who find it sheer bliss to be spending a lifetime with one another. Their bonds are just as emblematic of what is real and possible as the reality of ruptured and broken bonds.” </span></p>
<p><strong>— bell hooks, “Introduction: love is our hope” from <i>Salvation</i></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">“&#8230;I believe utopia cannot be removed from the world in spite of everything…” </span></p>
<p><strong>— Ernst Bloch from “Something’s Missing: the Contradictions of Utopian Longing”</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">“love changed my face” </span></p>
<p><strong>— Jasmine Kabale Moore</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p></blockquote>
<figure id="attachment_26934" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26934" style="width: 352px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26934" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/StJuju_TheVerge_3-300x127.jpg" alt="Illustration of two people laying in a field of mushrooms, in a romantic embrace. The people are a monchromatic blue and the mushrooms are shades of pink." width="352" height="149" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/StJuju_TheVerge_3-300x127.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/StJuju_TheVerge_3-1024x434.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/StJuju_TheVerge_3-768x325.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/StJuju_TheVerge_3.jpg 1346w" sizes="(max-width: 352px) 100vw, 352px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26934" class="wp-caption-text">Source: The Verge | Artist: Allen Lasseter</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Like Howie says to Charlene in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Bringing Down the House</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> (2003): The cool points are out the window. If I wasn’t corny enough: my partner makes me softer. As if my body knows I’m in love, I’ve been waking up with rounded edges and mouthfuls of sweet-talk. There’s utopia between us. We’re people whose lives could so easily have kept us from each other, yet we’ve met without thread of loneliness, deceit or desperation. We’re not afraid of each other despite everything, and that is significant. Like Janelle Monae </span><a href="https://youtu.be/jLSEYYazmKc"><span style="font-weight: 400">sings</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> in “Mushrooms &amp; Roses” (2010): We’re all virgins to the joys of loving without fear. Through love I’ve broken one kind of innocence to reach another — exchanged the thrashing innocence of fear for the soothe of wondering, knowing, changing (repeat).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Sometimes my partner is a poem. We went to the movies; they laughed, at the movies, and their laugh shimmered across the theater, and people, not just me, smiled at the sound. I like the world when it notices the beauty of that laugh. Yes, a human voice can be windchimes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">We’re accidental. We wear the same colors accidentally. We bought each other the same Christmas present accidentally. We’re “cringe” together. We connect telepathically. We time-travel (it was 11 pm then suddenly 3 am!). If we’re possible, what else is? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">I’ve been thinking about a better world for a while now, as you know, but each tenderness I experience through love is another glimpse at “better,” another opening. I haven’t forgotten what I’ve been through, but I know, now, that there are different shores one can arrive at despite their disbelief. There is a world in which I hold, kiss, and serenade, and it is good, and my confessions are returned, and new rules are mutually set. There is work in which I am not alone. There is love in which I am not alone. The pushing did hurt, but it feels precisely good to be born. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Sometimes I am a poem. A pile of what I’ve learned. Broken stanzas made coherent together, loosely related ephemera. My partner is an archivist. Curious, gentle hands. Learning me and laying me back down. If they’re possible, what else is?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">My darling, my sweetheart, my goblin: I am an R&amp;B singer, and I want people to know how you make me feel, even if they don’t know you themselves. This love letter is not enough, but it’s only #1. </span></p>
<p><b>Further Reading / References:</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">SHORT FILM / SHORT STORY: “</span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/1/28/18139447/rivers-solomon-sci-fi-short-story-hound-mutants-better-worlds?_gl=1*790tpw*"><span style="font-weight: 400">St Juju</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">” by Rivers Solomon (</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">The Verge</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">, </span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/12/5/18055980/better-worlds-science-fiction-short-stories-video"><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Better Worlds</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> special issue, 2019)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">BOOK: </span><a href="https://monoskop.org/images/f/f7/Roland_Barthes_Roland_a_lover_s_discourse_1978.pdf"><i><span style="font-weight: 400">A Lover’s Discourse: Fragments</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400">  by Roland Barthes (1977 / 1978)</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: ‘Where the Rain Cannot Reach’ by Adesina Brown</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-where-the-rain-cannot-reach-by-adesina-brown/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 11:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26756</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Published by Atmosphere Press in December 2021. 318 pages. My personal notes for Where The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-26766 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_ABrown_frontcover-194x300.jpg" alt="Front cover of Adesina Brown's novel, 'Where The Rain Cannot Reach.' The image shows a dagger piercing a large, red sun. A smaller yellow sun is shown behind the dagger's hilt. The background is black." width="294" height="455" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_ABrown_frontcover-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_ABrown_frontcover-663x1024.jpg 663w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_ABrown_frontcover-768x1186.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_ABrown_frontcover.jpg 971w" sizes="(max-width: 294px) 100vw, 294px" /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-26767" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_Map.jpg" alt="Map of Gosso, a fictional continent. This is the setting of Adesina Brown's novel, 'Where The Rain Cannot Reach.'" width="295" height="456" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_Map.jpg 312w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_Map-194x300.jpg 194w" sizes="(max-width: 295px) 100vw, 295px" /></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Published by </span></i><a href="https://atmospherepress.com/books/where-the-rain-cannot-reach-by-adesina-brown/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Atmosphere Press</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400"> in December 2021. 318 pages.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">My personal notes for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Where The Rain Cannot Reach </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">(</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">WTRCR</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">) abound with direct quotes that either shifted or affirmed my understanding of freedom (which I’ll return to later). </span><a href="https://www.adesinabrown.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400">Adesina Brown</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">’s debut novel is remarkably wise and gentle, though it doesn’t exempt its characters from the inevitable hardships of resisting centuries-long oppression. This novel is rife with ruminations on love, relationships, identity and political struggles that are integral to its worldbuilding. Readers of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">WTRCR </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">will encounter a world that is reminiscent of Tolkien’s Middle-Earth, yet proves </span><a href="https://theconversation.com/was-tolkien-really-racist-108227"><span style="font-weight: 400">far more effective</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> at depicting </span><a href="https://nkjemisin.com/2013/02/from-the-mailbag-the-unbearable-baggage-of-orcing/"><span style="font-weight: 400">race</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> and gender in ways that diverge from real-world racism, patriarchy, and imperialism. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">WTRCR</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> is constructed around an epic, heroic journey. Tair, the protagonist, is introduced to us as a young, brown-skinned, displaced Human on the brink of adulthood. Her elders consist of a Dwarf (Shianna), an Elf (Silaa), and a Fel, or Faery-Elf hybrid (Alyn). These elders have raised Tair in the Elf-land of Mirte — alternately training her for and protecting her from the challenging future that lies ahead. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As an infant, Tair was abandoned in the Darkwoods that separate Human lands (Sossoa) from non-Human lands (Nossoa), on the continent of Gosso. As the prophesied “lost” Human child, Tair is destined to trigger the end of Sossoa’s fascistic regime, which perpetuates mass-murder and torture against all non-Human life (derogatorily referred to as </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">raiso</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">). Until the end of the novel, it isn’t clear </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">how </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">Tair will end this regime, but there’s no small chance that it will involve a great amount of self-sacrifice. Brown is deliberate about making readers wait to learn what Tair is truly capable of, and the drawn-out conclusion makes Tair’s journey all the more revelatory. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Tair’s perpetual alienation (as a multilingual Human raised by non-Humans) opens up </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">WTRCR </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">to many reconsiderations of Tair’s world specifically, and of life generally. In an attempt to avoid spoilers without withholding the author’s tender words, I’ll share bits of the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">wisdom </span><span style="font-weight: 400">I mentioned at the beginning of this review. Below are some chronological excerpts that strike me as wise and </span><span style="font-weight: 400">a</span><span style="font-weight: 400">ffective:</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“&#8230;she had been told that she was not unique in her responsibilities, her path, her life, but that she was precious all the same.” (p. 14)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“Shianna herself was rather averse to complacency [&#8230;] </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">It is in the refusal to defend others that one loses their ability to defend themself</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">, she had said on occasion.” (p. 19)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“There had to be something else lingering within her and other Humans that they had not yet been able to discover. Something that had perhaps laid dormant for generations.” (p. 118)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“In Sossoa, there were beings who looked like her, yet she was still unsure of whether or not simply looking like someone made anywhere feel like home.” (p. 205)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“‘Liberation may one day mean the ability to move freely between lands, to determine for oneself where they belong and what they will do with their lives once they get there,’ Rose continued on.” (p. 223)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“Both of them knew that something had changed in Tair. Something was different. Different, not wrong. Not wrong but changing. She could not place what it was, but she at least had a secret now— something she could not, and would not, allow Rain to see.” (p. 293)</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Having discussed what I enjoyed in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">WTRCR</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">, I’ll close this review with what left me wanting more. In the middle third of the novel (starting around Chapter 5, when Tair is troubled to learn more about what’s expected of her, or what her heroism entails), the story loses some of its emotional force — zipping through major events in Tair’s journey without allowing readers ample time and space to digest them. In this middle section, Tair’s reactions to her changing circumstances often felt like obligatory details as opposed to integral ones — quickly fading into the background to make way for another plot point. The final third of the novel ultimately won me over again, but there are missed opportunities, in the telling of this story, to elaborate upon Sossoa’s cruelty in relation to other realms and establish Tair’s personality beyond her pacifism, stubbornness, and youthful naivete. <em>WTRCR</em> is meant to be the first book in a multi-book series; I hope the subsequent volumes pick up on those missed opportunities.</span></p>
<p><em>*I was provided with an e-book in exchange for an honest review</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notes on Mermaids and Passing As Human</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/notes-on-mermaids-and-passing-as-human/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 11:47:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; Created half to rise, and half to fall; Great lord of all things,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<figure id="attachment_26615" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26615" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26615" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/passing-shortpedia-voices-300x225.jpg" alt="Promotional poster of 'Passing' (dir. Rebecca Hall, 2021); The image is split between black (left) and white (right), with Irene (played by Tessa Thompson) on the left and Clare (played by Ruth Negga) on the right." width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/passing-shortpedia-voices-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/passing-shortpedia-voices-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/passing-shortpedia-voices-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/passing-shortpedia-voices.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26615" class="wp-caption-text">Source: Shortpedia Voices</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote><p>Created half to rise, and half to fall;<br />
Great lord of all things, yet a prey to all;<br />
Sole judge of truth, in endless error hurled:<br />
The glory, jest, and riddle of the world!<br />
— Alexander Pope, “Essay on Man, Epistle II”</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s much to say about the allegorical potential of mermaids, given their hybridity of Human and Other. In this brief post, I’d like to consider how popular mermaid lore interacts with race, and specifically how the conundrum of “passing” as White continues to occupy a mythical place in American imaginations. Many (if not most) of us are familiar with <a href="https://muse.jhu.edu/article/688109/pdf">the story</a> of a young mermaid who exchanges her tail for two legs in order to assimilate to the human world. Struck by the mobility and luxury of (wealthy) humans, this maiden is compelled to become one of them, and thereby live what she understands as a proper (if not liberated) life. The two Black women who star in Nella Larsen’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passing </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">novel (1929) are mermaids in their own rights, gazing curiously upon Whiteness as an opportunity to become properly human, and enjoy the comforts that are entailed by White humanity. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passing </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">and stories like it that American authors such as Larsen, Jessie Redmon Fauset, Fannie Hurst, James Weldon Johnson, Iceberg Slim, and Brit Bennett have penned since the early twentieth century, Blackness may be conceptualized as a figurative marine animal — a low-hanging mermaid’s tail that must be </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tucking"><span style="font-weight: 400;">tucked</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or shed in order to pass as White. Whiteness, on the other hand, is the anthropomorphic upper body that makes passing possible. When Clare and Irene, the main characters in Larsen&#8217;s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passing</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, first encounter each other in their outwardly White forms, they are essentially poking their heads above water, convincing the White world they’re human by keeping their Blackness submerged. They’re not exactly lying to the people who presume they’re White — they’re simply putting on a (seamless) show for them by tucking their Blackness behind the curtain. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think the casting and cinematographic choices of Rebecca Hall’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Passing </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">film adaptation (2021) are inspired, and I enjoyed the film on both accounts. Rather than fixating on the inscrutability of White-passing characters’ Blacknesses (as filmmakers such as John Cassavetes, Larry Yust, and Douglas Sirk have done), Hall prioritizes the loving gaze of someone (perhaps a Black someone) who recognizes the fullness of who the mermaids are. The black-and-white lens of the camera functions not only to establish an antiquated New York City, but to render abstract the racial characteristics we use to code each other. Hall’s choices curiously reinscribe the mythicism of racial “passing” (and race itself). The ambient chatter that underscores the film often gave me the impression that I was sitting at a fanciful seaside, where the dark waves of an ocean regularly trouble the white sands of the shore.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><b>References / Further Reading:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_WcWHZc8s2I"><span style="font-weight: 400;">No Ordinary Love</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">” by Sade (Music Video)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><a href="https://www.shimajournal.org/issues.php#v15n2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crossing Merfolk Narratives of the Sacred: Nalo Hopkinson’s <em>The New Moon’s Arms</em> and Gabrielle Tesfaye’s <em>The Water Will Carry us Home</em></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">” by Jalondra A. Davis (from vol. 15, no. 2 of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Shima Journal</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">)</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Becoming Human: Matter and Meaning in an Antiblack World</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by Zakiyyah Iman Jackson</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sylvia Wynter’s </span><a href="https://trueleappress.com/2018/01/01/anti-copyright-wynter-info-drop/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">essays</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> — especially: “</span><a href="https://trueleappress.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/wynter-beyond-mirandas-meanings-unsilencing-the-demonic-ground-of-calibans-woman-1.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beyond Miranda&#8217;s Meanings: Un/silencing the ‘Demonic Ground’ of Caliban&#8217;s ‘Woman’</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><a href="https://datebook.sfchronicle.com/movies-tv/for-rebecca-hall-and-ruth-negga-the-racism-of-passing-is-a-culmination-of-personal-journeys"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Rebecca Hall and Ruth Negga, the racism of ‘Passing’ is a culmination of personal journeys</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">” by G. Allen Johnson</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><a href="https://www.screendaily.com/features/rebecca-hall-on-her-sundance-directing-debut-passing-identity-is-hopelessly-complex/5156593.article"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rebecca Hall on her Sundance directing debut ‘Passing’: ‘Identity is hopelessly complex’</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">” by Jeremy Kay </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><a href="https://www.okayplayer.com/culture/passing-movie-netflix-tessa-thompson-review.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Netflix’s ‘Passing’ Is a Gorgeous And Confounding Exploration Of Colorism</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">” by Jourdain Searles</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/02/t-magazine/passing-nella-larsen-brit-bennett.amp.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Performance of Racial Passing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">” by Brit Bennett</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short Films In The Criterion Channel’s Afrofuturism Collection</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/short-films-in-the-criterion-channels-afrofuturism-collection/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 11:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Criterion’s Afrofuturism collection (finely curated by Ashley Clark) has been on my to-watch list for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_26399" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26399" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26399" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Criterion_Afrofuturism_Banner-300x169.jpg" alt="Banner of the Criterion Channel's Afrofuturism Collection. A stylized collage of elements from various films in the collection." width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Criterion_Afrofuturism_Banner-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Criterion_Afrofuturism_Banner-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Criterion_Afrofuturism_Banner-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Criterion_Afrofuturism_Banner.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26399" class="wp-caption-text">Source: The Criterion Channel</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Criterion’s </span><a href="https://www.criterionchannel.com/afrofuturism"><span style="font-weight: 400">Afrofuturism collection</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> (finely </span><a href="https://youtu.be/ppNai6KOXyQ"><span style="font-weight: 400">curated</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> by Ashley Clark) has been on my to-watch list for a while now. Though </span><a href="https://hyperallergic.com/618690/afrofuturism-criterion-channel-streaming/"><span style="font-weight: 400">several titles have cycled out</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> of the collection, I’ve finally taken time to watch the short films that are still streaming. (I&#8217;m saving the feature-length films I haven’t viewed for another time.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">I’ve shared impressions of my ten favorite shorts below (ordered chronologically):</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote><p><b><i>Odds and Ends</i></b><b> (dir. Michelle Parkerson, 1993)</b></p></blockquote>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Duration: ~28 minutes </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Kitschy space-opera exposition informs viewers that this film is set in 2096, during an intergalactic war sparked by fascism, racism, and sexism. Lieutenant Loz Wayward (Latanya West) is the film’s lead character — a soldier who still finds her way to battle when her babylonmobile breaks down. Loz epitomizes 1990s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">black cool</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">, with her swagger, her smooth voice, and her ever-swooped hair. There’s a significant chance I would’ve wanted to be like Loz as a kid, if I’d known this movie existed. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">A grainy, stencil-like flashback, superimposed on a pink sunset, reveals that Loz is romantically involved with a somewhat older black woman, who outranks her. “God, I’m weak for a woman in uniform,” she remarks in the subsequent flashback scene, when she’s reluctant to leave her lover, Sephra (Cyndi James Gossett), in bed. Their rapport is sweet and poetic, even as sounds of war rage outside their apartment. Sephra tells her, “There’ve been a lot of lovers before you, Loz, but it’s the first time in a long time I knew I could count on love.” This is not only a </span><a href="https://lgbtqreads.com/2021/11/03/the-liberating-politics-of-queernorm-fiction-a-guest-post-by-where-the-rain-cannot-reach-author-adesina-brown/"><span style="font-weight: 400">queernorm</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> world, but a world where black women are (almost) everything. Most of this film’s sentient beings (including Loz’s spaceship) are imbued with black womanness, and white people only appear to contextualize black women’s systemic oppression. This is not a post-racial, post-gender fantasy of the future. It’s a black feminist projection (and critique) of the future Western civilization aspires to. It’s also a consideration of </span><a href="https://nyupress.org/9780814748336/queer-times-black-futures/"><span style="font-weight: 400">the loving future</span></a> <a href="https://www.press.uillinois.edu/books/?id=32ggx9gk9780252043963"><span style="font-weight: 400">black feminism could render</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><b><i>The Changing Same </i></b><b>(dir. Cauleen Smith, 2001)</b></p></blockquote>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Duration: ~9 minutes</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This film begins with an electronic exchange of two voices, presumably belonging to people (or perhaps a single person) who would be coded as black men. The authoritative voice questions and the submissive voice answers. The submissive voice is also more distorted than the authoritative voice, reflecting the submissive’s disorientation after an extended mission on Earth. Through this introduction, we learn that the humanoid subjects of this film are partly electronic in nature, and the submissive communicant (an extraplanetary agent) cannot return home until he’s collected certain data. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Cut to the first action scene, and a person coded as a young black woman evades the submissive agent we heard before, retreating to her private lair. If the chase scene didn’t give it away, we viewers ascertain that this woman has the aforementioned “data” when she feeds a printed scroll into a slot on her abdomen. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The woman continues evading the agent as he follows her, but she learns that he may not be as inimical as she believed. The two of them may even have a lot in common. (Suspense!)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This is an intriguing short with artful editing overall — and the music was apparently composed by David Bowie.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><b><i>The Becoming Box</i></b><b> (dir. Monique Walton, 2011)</b></p></blockquote>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Duration: ~16 minutes</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26472 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/becoming-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/becoming-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/becoming-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/becoming-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/becoming.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />The first scene is stunning. Through wilting tropical plants, a fixed shot shows Mark (Jeremy Gaines) sawing a cylinder of wood by hand. When Renée (Donna Duplantier), Mark’s sister, runs down a flight of stairs (from the inside of the house to the outside), he immediately chases her across the yard. At first, you might think they were playing a childhood game, but this isn’t the case.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The close-up is troubling. Mark grabs Renée as she struggles against his arms. Her family wants her to stay, but she wants to leave. They pull a ring of keys from her hand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Later scenes reveal that Renée came back to New Orleans from Washington D.C. when her mother went missing. Renée thinks their mother escaped into a locked, magical box in the yard of their family home (hence her desperation for the keys), but everyone else thinks her mother is dead. Renée’s insistence on getting into the box has life-altering effects on her.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This short is a compelling meditation on home, belonging, grief and identity — with suicidal allegory.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><b><i>Hasaki Ya Suda</i></b><b> (dir. Cédric Ido, 2011)</b></p></blockquote>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Duration: ~24 minutes</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Hasaki Ya Suda</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> is set in a near-future, multi-racial, climate-apocalyptic world — centered on exiles from the Global South. This short film follows Black African samurai and includes thrilling fight scenes with impressive choreography, acting, and special effects. As far as I can tell, it’s a one-of-a-kind, well-crafted film.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><b><i>Twaaga</i></b><b> (dir. Cédric Ido, 2013)</b></p></blockquote>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Duration: ~32 minutes</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In this short film, bodies are resilient, sacred, and spirited, while also vulnerable to war and conflict. Set in Burkina Faso during 1987, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Twaaga </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">ponders pan-Africanism, revolution, and the life that’s lost in political struggles. Here, the director (Cédric Ido) extends his commitment to exploring Global South subjectivities, and portraying the wondrous capacities of black/African people amongst themselves, ourselves. Interpolations of comic-book animations are part of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Twaaga</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">’s coherence.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The domestic scenes in this film are so beautiful — serene slice-of-life sequences that remind viewers, in part, of the everyday love that’s undermined by war. It’s delightful, and eventually heartbreaking, to watch 8-year-old Manu (Sabourou Bamogo) assume his superhero alter-ego.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><b><i>Afronauts</i></b><b> (dir. Nuotama Bodomo, 2014)</b></p></blockquote>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Duration: ~14 minutes</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Based on </span><a href="https://hyperallergic.com/515006/afronauts-nuotama-frances-bodomo-interview/"><span style="font-weight: 400">true events</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">, this short follows a group of Zambian outcasts’ attempts to reach the moon before the United States does. An implicit question it poses is what space travel might be like if it wasn’t tied to nationalist, capitalist, and patriarchal aims. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Rendering the film in black and white made its careful use of light and texture even more visceral — the color-contrast heightening its sensory effects. </span></p>
<blockquote><p><b><i>You and I and You </i></b><b>(dir. Terence Nance, 2015)</b></p></blockquote>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Duration: ~8 minutes </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Here, two adults and a toddler look behind themselves apprehensively as a trio of Africanist dancers follows them down a road. If we follow prevalent West African symbolism, the </span><a href="https://re-entanglements.net/chalk/"><span style="font-weight: 400">white chalk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> on their faces may signify spiritual rebirth and initiation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The headdresses the principal dancers wear, constructed from ochered brillo pads and sponges, subtly overturn </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2014/aug/04/black-hair-natural-get-over-it-beyonce-daughter"><span style="font-weight: 400">pejorative understandings of black hair textures</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> — all while heightening the film’s speculative sensibilities. More dancers join the cast as the film continues, portending both revelation and danger. The couple is changed by their encounters with these dancers, perhaps hinting at a reconfiguration of what it means to be a “family.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Terence Nance did his thing, as usual!</span></p>
<blockquote><p><b><i>The Golden Chain</i></b><b> (dir. Adebukola Bodunrin &amp; Ezra Claytan Daniels, 2016)</b></p></blockquote>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Duration: ~13 minutes</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In this animated short, a black scientist struggles with a common understanding in her world that not everything should be uncovered, and some matter is meant to be unknowable. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Dark ink blots that obscure the screen during the title sequence, accompanied by a rattling, liquid sound, suggest that parts of we viewers are also meant to be unknowable. We too are partially obscured, our interiors never fully in view.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">The Golden Chain</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> draws fascinating connections between our embodiments, our relationships, our technologies, and the fabric of the universe.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><b><i>1968 &lt; 2018 &gt; 2068 </i></b><b>(dir. Keisha Rae Witherspoon, 2018)</b></p></blockquote>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Duration: ~7 minutes</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">I’m excited by the theoretical work this film does — in concert with </span><a href="https://www.blackquantumfuturism.com/product-page/bqf-theory-practice-vol-i"><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Black Quantum Futurism: Theory and Practice</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400">, ed. Rasheedah Phillips. Contesting oppressive temporalities, this short film positions the linear “Western model of spacetime” as “a spell” that can be broken.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">In </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">1968 &lt; 2018 &gt; 2068</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">, Witherspoon splices together archival footage from a variety of sources (ranging from government programming to black community interviews) — interrupting and complementing them with overlays of text, sound and animation. This film conceptualizes </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">feeling</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> as an empirical, measurable practice.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><b><i>Zombies </i></b><b>(dir. Baloji, 2019)</b></p></blockquote>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Duration: ~16 minutes</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This short considers how technology has, in some ways, alienated us from each other, and in <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-26473 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/zom.jpg" alt="" width="183" height="275" />other ways, unleashed our star potentials. In the beginning, a man in a barbershop sings lyrics from his phone such as: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Light on face, oooh / Everybody shine, oooh</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> […] </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">People dance no more / Everybody got the spotlight</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">The Boy (musician/actor Popaul Amisi) and The Girl (actress Gaëlle Kibikonda) then lead us through futuristic scenes in Kinshasa, the capital city of the Democratic Republic of the Congo — enlivened by a soundtrack of rhythmic drum beats. Along the way, we see people who are physically frozen as they pose for selfies (stark light emanating from their screens), and club-goers dancing in isolation, sometimes donning VR headgear.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This is a riveting film.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Other Shorts in the Collection (also worthy of attention!):</strong></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Dark Matters </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">(dir. Monique Walton, 2010)</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Robots of Brixton</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> (dir. Kibwe Tavares, 2011)</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Native Sun </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">(dir. Terence Nance &amp; Blitz Bazawule, 2011)</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Jonah</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> (dir. Kibwe Tavares, 2013)</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Touch</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> (dir. Shola Amoo, 2013)</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">T</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> (dir. Keisha Rae Witherspoon, 2019)</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">I Snuck off the Slave Ship</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> (dir. Lonnie Holley &amp; Cyrus Moussavi, 2019)</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
