<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Salena Casha &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/salena-casha/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 04:51:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Lady Midnight by Cassandra Clare (2016)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lady-midnight-by-cassandra-clare-2016/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Salena Casha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 16:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ladies of the Light Saber and Sword]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone! I’d like to introduce you to my guest blogger (and sister), Nysa Casha.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Hi Everyone! I’d like to introduce you to my guest blogger (and sister), Nysa Casha. She’s an expert in female-authored young adult fantasy. She’s the one who recommended<a href="http://sarahjmaas.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> Sarah J Maas</a> to me and I couldn’t be happier to have her join us on my column. </em></p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Cassandra Clare knows how to craft a mesmerizing story. Her latest book in the Shadowhunter&#8217;s series and the first book in The Dark Artifices series, <em><a href="http://shadowhunters.com/book/lady-midnight/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lady Midnight</a>,</em> is one of those reads that, upon turning the last page, I was sad to return to reality. And frankly, this is simply because I don’t want to be in a world that is void of the shadowhunters Emma Cartstairs and Julian Blackthorn.</p>
<p>Want to know why? Well, think about this:</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/index.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-6293"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6293 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/index.jpg" alt="index" width="358" height="141" /></a>What if you and your best friend had lost your parents at the age of twelve? What if your best friend had to kill his father to protect his youngest brother? What if your best friend had four younger siblings he had to raise by himself, in an institute run by an uncle incapable of being a parent?  What if everyone claimed your parents died in a war but you knew that something very different was true?</p>
<p>Now, think about all of those pretty realistic questions under the gaze of someone who is half-angel half-human and you’ve got yourself a fantasy that tugs right at the centrality of human emotion.</p>
<p>But the reasons why I loved this novel weren’t because of the fantasy or the back story. What I can’t get my mind off of is the way the characters laced every step and spoke every word with power, love and courage. I breathed next to them as they raised Julian’s four younger siblings. I felt their love in the sacrifices they made for one another and their courage that radiated through intense battles and challenges.</p>
<p>And I longed to be able to fight in the same way fearlessly for those I love. I wished I could feel just as deeply as they did about all of life.</p>
<p>Well if you are wondering what happens, my simple answer to you is for you to become Emma Cartstairs. You make the hard choices when you are twelve. You eternally bind yourself to your other half, your best friend, to keep a family together and link yourself to a love so strong it surpasses anything humans could experience for lovers, friends, or family. Then you work tirelessly to create a home and a family from the ashes of a war. And you never stop searching for the truth behind your parents’ deaths. You train yourself beyond what is physically possible: by jumping from impossible heights even after continuous broken bones and brandishing a sword in bare feet on broken glass. And you do this because if anyone tries to hurt your family, you are certain you will be strong enough to endure anything and protect their safety at all costs. You become a girl who lives passionately, refuses to leave her friend&#8217;s side, and falls deeply in love with life and adventure.</p>
<p>I would recommend that you read <em>Lady Midnight </em>and lose yourself to the words of this story because the sort of love it embodies is one that can travel the Earth and move the heavens. I am so lucky to have experienced that kind of strength alongside these characters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Radiance&#8221; by Catherynne M. Valente (2015)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/radiance-by/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Salena Casha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 17:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ladies of the Light Saber and Sword]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I don&#8217;t read science fiction for a while, I forget how much I love&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/51EwU-9SrIL._SX329_BO1204203200_.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-6124"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6124 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/51EwU-9SrIL._SX329_BO1204203200_-199x300.jpg" alt="51EwU-9SrIL._SX329_BO1,204,203,200_" width="199" height="300" /></a>When I don&#8217;t read science fiction for a while, I forget how much I love it. How quirky it can be. How creative. I forget that science fiction doesn&#8217;t always have to be about space but can also be about time. That being said, a lot of the &#8220;interplanetary&#8221; novels I&#8217;ve read this year have found their main plot-line on Earth.</p>
<p><em>Radiance</em>, though, is an entirely other beast. First of all, if I had all the power in the world, I would nominate it for all the Nebulas and awards out there. I haven&#8217;t read a book so simultaneously innovative and nostalgic since<em> Ancillary Justice</em>, the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-review-of-ancillary-justice-2013-by-ann-leckie/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">first review I wrote on Luna Station Quarterly</a>. And the only reason I purchased it was because the back cover reminded me of<em> <a href="http://www.emilymandel.com/stationeleven.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Station Eleven</a></em>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s nothing like<em> Station Eleven</em>. And I still loved it.</p>
<p><em>Radiance </em>is a splintered narrative of spliced film. It&#8217;s made up of bits of script, bits of first-person narrations, bits of notebooks, bits of screen, bits of interviews, and bits of audio transcript. It offers a world that is a reflection of the real world, a better or worse version: it&#8217;s up to the readers to decide which. The novel itself is a movie about making movies. Set in the 1960s, <em>Radiance</em> is based on the assumption that interplanetary travel was made possible sometime in the 20s or 30s. The main characters are all heavily involved in filmmaking and the universe is ruled by major movie studios who travel across the planets to shoot their silents and talkies.</p>
<p>The main conflict of the film involves the femme fatale and film darling herself, Severin Unck, daughter of eccentric filmmaker Percy Unck. Her entire life is recorded, reshot and staged via film since her mysterious appearance on Percy&#8217;s doorstop. Her mothers are a revolving door of actresses, dancers, and setmasters, each providing Severin with a different role in her life. While her father emphasizes films shot about fantasy: noirs and vampire flicks, thrillers and mysteries, all more outrageous than the next, Severin rejects these for documentaries and makes a name for herself exposing the worst truths about the galaxy. And during her last film, she disappears. As such, the entire novel is spent trying to figure out where she has gone and who she really was. And many seem to argue that, if she wasn&#8217;t in front of a camera, she wasn&#8217;t real.</p>
<p>The austere is emphasized throughout the novel as filmmakers indulge in silent movies and an awe for the insane natural power of planets. The people involved in her disappearance and those who surround themselves with the mystery of who Severin was, devolve into dramatic characters cut from Greek tragedies and classical texts, tearing themselves a part to try and understand her. As a reader, you find yourself chasing after this slippery film of a girl, who traipses between the pages in black and white. You can smell burnt film and you question whether or not reality exists based on if it was filmed or not. And what exactly was Severin&#8217;s reality made from?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.catherynnemvalente.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Catherynne Valente </a>does a fantastic job world-building not just one, but at least five other worlds. She builds an entire civilization and then razes it to the ground using myth and superstition. No matter how advanced mankind becomes, we constantly succumb to what we do not know.</p>
<p>The characters are brilliantly developed, multi-faceted and mysterious. Some of the voices in the novel seem ownerless, like narrators of nature documentaries. Always operating behind the camera but never on scene. The novel is about the creation and destruction of art and also, the terribly selfish reasons behind why, sometimes, we create art.</p>
<p>This is a novel that forces you to turn the camera upon yourself and stand center stage to justify your existence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Razorhurst&#8221; (2014) by Justine Larbalestier</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/razorhurst-2014-by-justine-larbalestier/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Salena Casha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 17:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ladies of the Light Saber and Sword]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5866</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My last review was of a young adult fantasy novel so I&#8217;ve decided to follow&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/untitled.png" rel="attachment wp-att-5944"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-5944 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/untitled.png" alt="untitled" width="183" height="275" /></a>My last review was of a <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/5778-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">young adult fantasy novel</a> so I&#8217;ve decided to follow it up with a young adult paranormal novel. I don&#8217;t read ghost stories very often (unless you count those written by my writing group) and, frankly, I&#8217;ve read very few novels by Australian authors (although Justine categorizes herself as Australian-American). And I’ve read even less about Australia. Luckily, with this novel, I was able to get a bit of a history lesson in addition to exposure to literature coming out of Sydney. I think it would also be appropriate to acknowledge that, as a fangirl, one of the reasons I read Larbalestier was because she is married to <a href="http://scottwesterfeld.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Scott Westerfeld</a>, a favorite young adult author of mine.</p>
<p>Now, to the book in question. <em>Razorhurst </em>is set in the deadly Razorhurst neighborhood of Sydney in 1932. The novel follows two protagonists: Kelpie, an orphaned street urchin, and Dymphna Campbell, also known as the Angel of Death. Razorhurst is split between two crime bosses: Gloriana Nelson and Mr. Davidson &#8211; and the weapon of choice as suggested by the title of the neighborhood are knives/razors. Dymphna works for Gloriana Nelson and creates a plan with her latest man, Jimmy Palmer, to put her out of power. Then, without warning, Jimmy ends up dead. Kelpie discovers him. Taking pity on her, Dymphna decides to assume responsibility for the girl.</p>
<p>So where does the paranormal come in? Well, Kelpie sees and can interact with ghosts which is an unfortunate super power. She talks to them and while some of them torment her, they also keep her safe. She doesn&#8217;t have any personal haunters and instead interacts with ghosts that haunt people or parts of the neighborhood. She sees Jimmy Palmer&#8217;s ghost and converses with him throughout the novel. They provide her with wisdom about life but they also are fickle, tricky beings with only their own selfish motives at heart. Especially Jimmy. Most of the novel is spent trying to figure out if he is lying about who murdered him. While Dymphna isn&#8217;t forthright with the information, she too sees ghosts which creates a fascinating component of the dialogue that she has with Kelpie while Palmer is in the room. Larbalestier is a master of speakers just missing one another or talking on separate planes which really pulls readers into the novel.</p>
<p>One of the most engaging elements of the novel, however, is  Dymphna&#8217;s characterization. She is known as the angel of death because every person she &#8220;falls in love with&#8221; ends up dead. She originally works for Gloriana as a prostitute and it&#8217;s always slightly ambiguous whether she continues her duties even while she is with her other lovers. The reason I find Dymphna so intriguing is that she fits very well with a recent blog post I read about <a href="http://shannonathompson.com/2016/01/20/feminism-in-ya-knives-and-candy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Feminism in YA</a>. She&#8217;s a complicated character who experiences a lot of internal fear, pain, and sadness but who is very independent-minded and outwardly strong. She&#8217;s a fighter. She&#8217;s manipulative. She&#8217;s exactly what she needs to be in a world as dangerous as Razorhurst. She is very much a product of her environment. But like Celaena of <em>Thrones of Glass</em> or Kristin in <em>Station Eleven, </em>she experiences heartbreak, falls in love, and most importantly, demonstrates internal fear to the readers that she does not show to those in her external environment. To show fear in any of the situations above would be to forfeit her appearance and thus her life. I think this complicates all of the characters I&#8217;ve mentioned because the difference between how they should act to survive and how they actually feel adds a degree of relatability.</p>
<p>Kelpie is similarly a compelling character because of her lack of role models, her distrust of others, and the hardness of her soul that is a product of lack of love from the outside world. It&#8217;s amazing to watch her become more vulnerable as she learns to trust Dymphna without loosing the survival instincts she has learned throughout her short life. The book is technically told from her perspective and while Kelpie is young, she is worldly and street-smart in ways that make adults appear naive.</p>
<p>Overall, if you&#8217;re going to read this book for anything, read it for the characters. Both of them will steal your heart and make you wonder why there aren&#8217;t more like them in literature when we definitely know women like them in the real world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: The Red Queen</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/5778-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Salena Casha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 17:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ladies of the Light Saber and Sword]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5778</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I haven’t read any young adult novels in a while. This isn’t for any reason&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/RedQueen.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5764"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5764 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/RedQueen.jpg" alt="RedQueen" width="183" height="275" /></a>I haven’t read any young adult novels in a while. This isn’t for any reason in particular but I’ve been on a kick of literary novels recently and as much as I enjoy subtlety and pointedly difficult prose to parse out , I needed a break. So let me introduce you to <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/136452-red-queen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The Red Queen</em> </a> by Victoria Aveyard. It’s a bit <em>Hunger Games</em> meets <em>The Avengers</em> meets a bit of <em>The Gate Thief</em> by Orson Scott Card. It&#8217;s a pretty light read by ways of the fantasy, if not a little &#8220;been there, done that&#8221; by ways of premise. However, I have to say the execution and world building was pretty unique.</p>
<p>The story is based upon a world divided by the color of blood. &#8220;Reds&#8221; are the working class. The soldiers. The ones to die on the front lines and constantly serve the elite class of &#8220;Silvers.&#8221; The &#8220;Silvers&#8221; are not merely in control because of the color of their blood; their blood bestows upon them certain superpowers and fighting abilities beyond the scope of those who are Reds. The Silvers then can be seen as a class of almost demigods, using their powers to oppress and manipulate an entire legion of people below them. We follow the narrative of Mare, a girl of red blood born into poverty and known for being an expert pickpocket. Or at least until she gets both her sister and herself caught.</p>
<p>Her family has few means to make income and Mare is conscripted to work in the palace by a prince named Cal in disguise. During her visit, while she is serving the upper class during an &#8220;engagement ball&#8221;, she falls through a window and suddenly, her super powers manifest. She becomes the &#8220;little lightning girl&#8221;. The Silvers in power are worried about word getting out that a Red blood has super powers which would completely undermine their hold over all Reds in the land. So instead, they strike a deal with Mare: we will pretend you are a long lost Silver princess and take care of your family. She wears silver cover up to cover up the red-tinged tone of her skin and taught the ways of the elite classes. In the process, she is engaged to the ruling family&#8217;s youngest son, Maven.</p>
<p>As fate would have it, a group of Reds led by a masked woman decide to stage a coup/rebellion. They are able to recruit Mare into their ranks, seeing her as the perfect way to overthrow the Silvers from the inside. Mare has to navigate her new responsibilities as Silver royalty while also helping her family and anyone she has ever cared for from behind enemy lines.</p>
<p>That being said, the characters are relatively complex, especially the pair of princes: Maven and Cal. Maven demonstrates an aptitude for extreme empathy with Mare&#8217;s situation. Cal plays the part of risk-taking and self-indulgent (but smexy) love-interest for Mare (though I have to say, Cal trying to steal Maven&#8217;s wife-to-be is a bit strange even for YA). Mare is sassy and naive and makes more reckless mistakes than she does improvements all while trying to figure out her budding powers and deal with her own sense of place in a divided world. The queen (Maven and Cal&#8217;s mother) is reminiscent of Cersei from <em>Game of Thrones</em>: manipulative, all-seeing, and vindictive but her thirst for power and control is relatively compelling. The interplay between the Reds and Silvers is quite intriguing as well, providing a dystopian world in which the color of blood can separate human beings into entirely different classes (which, if you think about it, can also be applied to historical race relations as well as oppressive dictatorships in reality).</p>
<p>Yes, this is young adult. It has a love triangle. A lot of people have said that with the plot they&#8217;d &#8220;seen it before&#8221; but I have to say it had the opposite effect on me. It was like watching the new Star Wars and feeling that tinge of nostalgia when a favorite old character steps on the screen. Of course there are tropes and cliches, awkward dialogue. But despite all of that, or perhaps because of it, it was an enjoyable opening to the series.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August by Claire North (2014)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-first-fifteen-lives-harry-august-claire-north-2014/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Salena Casha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 16:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ladies of the Light Saber and Sword]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have been lucky, frankly, to be a member of a special sort of book club.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/20706317.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5575 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/20706317-200x300.jpg" alt="20706317" width="200" height="300" /></a>I have been lucky, frankly, to be a member of a special sort of book club. It&#8217;s small. It&#8217;s like-minded. It&#8217;s opinionated. And it&#8217;s fiercely intelligent. Its members care deeply and strongly about literature. Normally, the book clubs in which I engage often operate on the following schedule: 20 minutes of book talk (normally of a shallow nature) and followed by the liberal pour of wine and gossip. I love those book clubs for what they are but the singular club of which I speak is sacred to me and has expanded my reading mind in ways I can&#8217;t even begin to articulate.</p>
<p>So instead, I shared with you one of our recent finds: <a href="http://www.harryaugust.net/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August</em> </a>by Claire North. I feel as though it&#8217;s a bit sacrilegious of me to discuss the novel before my book club has had a chance to meet, but in doing so, perhaps I can organize my own insights before I engage in a deeper discussion with them of the novel in question.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s begin.</p>
<p>The novel is categorized on Amazon as metaphysical and occult horror. I don&#8217;t entirely agree with either categorization. It&#8217;s definitely a meta novel and there are horrific scenes of torture throughout. But I wouldn&#8217;t necessarily define it as occult. It&#8217;s fantastical in a spiritual way that reminds me a lot of Lev Grossman&#8217;s <em><a href="http://levgrossman.com/magicians-trilogy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Magicians</a>. </em>The novel&#8217;s plot follows Harry August, a Brit born at the turn of the 20th century who finds that, after he lives out his life and subsequently dies, he is reborn as himself and goes on to live a slightly different life again although he always remains as himself. It&#8217;s a twist on reincarnation where the reincarnation itself provides a limited time and space in which to operate; Harry can only move about through time in his own life span, hardly ever making it too far into the 21st century. A crucial element however is that he retains all memories of past lives. The cycle continues and the novel, as the title makes obvious, follows the first fifteen of his lives.</p>
<p>As the novel suggests, people with an endless loop of freedom and time could potentially intervene in major events. Want to assassinate Hitler or stop the atomic bomb from dropping on Japan? Unfortunately, no can do. All major events in history remain relatively unchanged, though it&#8217;s not clear if this is due to the unspoken rules of a secret club of these immortals of time called the Cronus Club (of which Harry is a member). And, if we really think about it, every time Harry dies, the world resets (though it&#8217;s ambiguous whether or not it&#8217;s the same world or same dimension). So how much intervention can one person do in a lifetime that will effect anyone or anything at all? What&#8217;s the point of it all?</p>
<p>For Harry, it&#8217;s all about learning. He is a mnemonic, someone with a perfect memory, who can recall every detail of each of his past lives. As such, he has copious knowledge about history, religion, politics, science, and languages. When you have almost a 1000 years to do whatever you want, learning to keep boredom at bay is a must (although he does dally a bit in addictive drugs for fun).</p>
<p>Now, how can a novel like this have a conflict? I have to say, I didn&#8217;t recognize the conflict until about halfway through the book: someone decides to begin picking off these immortals of time. The world &#8211; during each of Harry&#8217;s lives &#8211; accelerates to an end. Someone who is an immortal of time themselves has taken it upon themselves to end the world and those who can survive in a small loop of time as well. And of course, Harry knows exactly who it is. These immortals of time have a difficult time truly dying since physical death, for them, is merely a reset button. However, death is possible if a murderer goes back to their origin, the beginning of their life and abort them in their mother&#8217;s womb. This completely prevents someone like Harry from returning to life ever again. Morbid, I know.</p>
<p>The main themes that I noticed in the novel were two-fold: the consequences of progress and the desire of humans for immortality.</p>
<p>On the first front, I think North makes an argument that progress, in the technological sense, has a terrible price and that it is our ultimate demise. However, we can never shake progress&#8217; hold on us and our desire for better weapons, faster technology, and more &#8220;advanced&#8221; world views. For normal mortals, technology is as close as they will ever come to being a god of some sort. Creating scientific innovation shows that we have a bit of a god complex within all of us. As the novel demonstrates, technology does get the characters dangerously close to the answers of all creation though it is at an absolutely terrible price. Essentially the universe has two controls: progress and time. You can slow progress down or speed it up but you can never stop it. Progress is our master and by succumbing to it in greater and greater measures, we lose a bit more of our humanity. And, as a terrible side effect, we destroy the world (environmentally speaking) in which we operate and thus end ourselves.</p>
<p>Second, if you look at Harry as a mortal human being which I did in moments throughout the book, you can&#8217;t help but notice his coldness.  He murders people throughout his many lives both in war and for personal reasons. He does so without a guilty thought. Even though he worries about the end of the world, everything operates on a personal level for him: he has an agenda that does not necessarily relate to a &#8220;greater good&#8221; for the rest of humanity (i.e. all mortals who are unlike him). He is selfish. He is the complete definition of a man who plays god. Or even worse, he is god.</p>
<p>I think that North&#8217;s argument is that even Harry August (a &#8220;good&#8221; man), who I do come to empathize with throughout the novel, is given something that the rest of us do not have and it changes him, I think, for the worse. He is given time. He is given a life essentially free of consequences (omitting the minor detail of the villainous man who goes about destroying the world). His only penance is that he must carry the knowledge of all his past lives with him. I think he is essentially the embodiment of a present, but unmoved and apathetic god. He cares only for himself and for the perpetuation of his existing loop.</p>
<p>However, even though he does play god with those around him, Harry is still ruled by time. It frees him and imprisons him. By enabling him to forget his mortality, I think it also begins to fade his humanity. When he murders a fellow immortal of time, she begs him by saying she isn&#8217;t ready to die even though she has lives many lives past the one many are given. The lack of threat of death also bequeaths a degree of unaccountability which I find fascinating.</p>
<p>This novel is engrossing. It&#8217;s meta. It&#8217;s heavy on the physics and religious spirituality. It&#8217;s a bit repetitive in style which I think was done purposely to denote the circularity of time and human moral compass. It&#8217;s pretty morbid. As a result, I highly recommend it because it forces you as a reader to look into your own quantum mirror and define what is important for yourself and what questions exist that will vex you for the rest of your time. It also forces you to acknowledge what it is that moves you through time. If it&#8217;s progress, does it have a cost? And why are we all so willing to pay it?</p>
<p>Or really, do we have any other choice?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: &#8220;A Court of Thorns and Roses&#8221; (2015) by Sarah J. Maas</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-a-court-of-thorns-and-roses-2015-by-sarah-j-maas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Salena Casha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 16:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ladies of the Light Saber and Sword]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I almost cried when I found out we were nearly done with summer (mainly because, as a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1417961340l/16096824.jpg" alt="" width="228" height="350" />I almost cried when I found out we were nearly done with summer (mainly because, as a New Englander, I just survived a horrific winter). But this realization was made all the more bearable with a great summer read by one of my favorite authors, <a href="http://sarahjmaas.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sarah J. Maas</a>. If you don&#8217;t know her, you need to go and read her <em><a href="http://sarahjmaas.com/throneofglass/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Thrones of Glass</a></em> fantasy series because it&#8217;s got a bad-ass female protagonist named Celaena (aka, how you pronounce my name) who is an assassin who also loves wearing pretty dresses and looking hot AF. She&#8217;s like Arya Stark just a bit older, bolder, and, I&#8217;ll put the argument forward, more brutal.</p>
<p><em>A Court of Thorns and Roses</em> is a loose retelling of Beauty and the Beast (and I&#8217;d argue, with a spot or two of Cinderella thrown into it). Now, I <em>love </em>retellings of the mythological and fairy tale persuasion but I have to say, as of late, I have been unimpressed by the current lit. For example, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11235712-cinder" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Cinder</em> </a>by Marissa Meyer promised us a completely fresh retelling of Cinderella (with cyborgs and aliens and a futuristic setting in China) but it failed to deliver as it focused too much on an unbelievable romance and a far-fetched, poorly developed conflict that didn&#8217;t seem to be a dire enough concern of the protagonist. Also, I have no alliance to weak main POV characters with shaky voices.</p>
<p><em>A Court of Thrones and Roses</em> was exactly what I needed to restore my faith in retellings, because, really, it isn&#8217;t a love story at all (or maybe not in the traditional sense). The entire novel is based on the premise that Feyre (pronounced Fair-uh), youngest daughter of a disabled merchant, murders a Faerie in cold blood. Her action sets into motion events that change her family&#8217;s fortunes as well as her own attitude toward the world around her. I have to say this is one of the few books where I can legitimately say the main character truly developed and grew through her journey. Honestly, I didn&#8217;t like the version of her we were introduced to in the beginning of the novel. She was full of hatred and bitterness toward the world around her and, while this didn&#8217;t qualify her as a bad character in herself, it was a bit off-putting. By the end of the novel, she grew exponentially in strength, confidence in herself and overcame/recognized the fault in her hatred of the Faerie race. So props to her.</p>
<p>As part of a treaty created between Faeries and Men after a series of brutal wars, Feyre must journey with the High Fae and live with them as a hostage for the rest of her mortal life on the other side of the wall that separates the human and faerie world. Due to her hatred of magical creatures and her duty to her impoverished family, her kidnapping doesn&#8217;t go very well. That being said, she is no match for Tamlin and Lucien, the High Fae that transport her to the Spring Court. They keep her as a prisoner, but do not mistreat her. Their only real requirement is that she is never allowed to return to the lands of Men.</p>
<p>Feyre gets herself into quite a bit of trouble as she traipses around the grounds of Prythien. As she explores the world of the fae, she discovers that a &#8220;blight&#8221; on magic has overtaken the land. Both Tamlin and Lucien are required to wear elaborate metal masks at all times to prevent the blight from spreading to the rest of their bodies. As such, Feyre never sees their true faces. The masks make her curious as she tries to come to terms with the fact that the pair are not the monsters she believed all faeries to be.</p>
<p>Now, I won&#8217;t give anything away but I have to say, Sarah Maas is a genius when it comes to plotting. The twist that she offers at the end of the novel isn&#8217;t one I saw coming. Dear reader, you&#8217;re definitely in for a treat of games, of the mind, heart, and physique if you open these pages.</p>
<p>While Feyre is definitely a badass when it comes to female leads in fantasies, she is easily differentiable from Celaena of <em>Thrones of Glass</em>. It&#8217;s always nice to see authors able to write beyond their own prescriptions. Feyre is definitely her own woman and the pain she suffers from broken hearts (and perhaps even broken limbs) is tangible. Maas is a fabulous writer and I think we all need to steal a little bit from her.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: &#8220;The 100&#8221; by Kass Morgan (2013)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-the-100-by-kass-morgan-2013/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Salena Casha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 17:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ladies of the Light Saber and Sword]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4628</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi All, We&#8217;re back into science fiction and I have to say, Silvia Moreno-Garcia&#8217;s novel&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/6915301dbfb4cc5bedb42f2298c21d19.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-4638 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/6915301dbfb4cc5bedb42f2298c21d19-199x300.jpg" alt="6915301dbfb4cc5bedb42f2298c21d19" width="199" height="300" /></a>Hi All,</p>
<p>We&#8217;re back into science fiction and I have to say, Silvia Moreno-Garcia&#8217;s novel is a tough one to follow. It took me forever to find a book worth posting about, but I have to say &#8220;The 100&#8221; by Kass Morgan isn&#8217;t too shabby! Strangely enough, my podiatrist recommended it to me after confiding in me that he watched the CW show based on the novels. All the while puncturing a cyst I got from Salsa Dancing. Go figure, right?</p>
<p>Forewarning: this novel is the first in the series. While I dislike posting about serialized novels, sometimes it&#8217;s nice to see if books such as this can stand alone. While I&#8217;m not entirely sure &#8220;The 100&#8221; will leave the readers satisfied in the same way that a stand-alone novel would, they will definitely want to continue to read into this fascinating world.</p>
<p>At this point of time in the literary world, dystopian fiction is a hard sell. We&#8217;ve all read (and maybe even seen) <em>Divergence</em> and <em>Hunger Games</em> and the 100s (pun unintended) of other novels about a dystopic reality. While &#8220;The 100&#8221; isn&#8217;t necessarily dystopic, I would tentatively put it in the same category as the aforementioned books. In concept, this novel struck me as an inverse to <em>Dark Eden</em> by Chris Beckett (one of my favorite novels of all time. If you haven&#8217;t read it, you need to go out and do just that). Essentially, the premise of &#8220;The 100&#8221; revolves around the fact that the Earth has become radioactive due to thermonuclear war and due to its inhabitable state, humans created a space station in which they could survive away from the contaminated surface. Curious with regard to the effects of radiation, the head of the space station decides to send 100 of its convicts to Earth to see if the planet can be lived upon. As convicts in the space station are euthanized at age 18, we have a convenient cast of teenage characters thrust together to survive on Earth.</p>
<p>Like in <em>Hunger Games</em>, the space station is stratified by social-economic status with the wealthy Phoenicians (from Phoenix) working the most respected jobs and living in lavish areas while the Waldenites work the lowest jobs and live in poverty. Due to the scarcity of resources, law in the station is swift, merciless, and often corrupt.</p>
<p>The cast of characters Morgan provides is extensive with four main POV characters and additional key players. I&#8217;m no stranger to this sort of complex number of perspectives (I mean, c&#8217;mon, I&#8217;m a Game of Thrones fan). Still, I&#8217;m always a bit hesitant to trust authors using multiple perspectives. But Morgan does a great job differentiating their voices, fears, and desires. She provides us with the tone of two girls (Clarke and Glass) and two boys (Bellamy and Wells). All four are interconnected via friendship, romance, or even blood relation. Half the fun of the novel is figuring out how the four share the space of the novel. Plot-wise, &#8220;The 100&#8221; has a few twists which I enjoyed and Morgan did an excellent job of showing us Earth through the eyes of generations who had never touched its surface.</p>
<p>Although I don&#8217;t believe Morgan really gets into the themes that I normally discuss: feminist ideology, gender binaries, or diversity (in terms of race and sexual orientation), she does turn her analysis toward morality. The book, like most dystopias, illustrates a society in which the survival of a community weighs more than the concept of the individual. All four characters are scapegoats of a seemingly unjust and corrupt empire. They are essentially &#8220;sacrificed&#8221; (i.e. sent to an unstable environment) so that what is left of the human race has the potential to survive off of their space station (which we soon discover may not last much longer). While they have no choice in being sent to Earth, all four demonstrate their own versions of self-sacrifice for one another. Bellamy endangers himself constantly for his illegally born younger sister, Octavia. Clarke gives up her time and safety to care for members of the 100 who suffered injuries during their landing. Glass gives up her social status in order to be with someone she loves. Wells gives up his freedom on the space station to pursue Clarke. While you can say all four are motivated by some degree of selfishness and narcissism in their individual pursuits, they all demonstrate a degree of social conscience which is strangely aligned with the space station&#8217;s own actions.</p>
<p>Ultimately, while I don&#8217;t believe it was Morgan&#8217;s intention, she seems to be drawing a parallel between those operating the space station (and the cruelty associated with human experimentation, justice, and population control) with the four products of such an environment. Essentially, an oppressive and morally ambiguous environment does not spawn a population with duplicate values. In a way, the sacrifices asked of Clarke, Wells, Bellamy, and Glass by their &#8220;home&#8221; are the same they are willing to make for one another. The main difference, however, is that they have a choice previously subsidized by the space station&#8217;s government. Overall, the novel is what you make of it and how willing you are to dive into Morgan&#8217;s subtle discussion of cause vs. effect, nature vs. nurture. You might be surprised at what you find.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: &#8220;Signal to Noise&#8221; by Silvia Moreno-Garcia</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-signal-to-noise-by-silvia-moreno-garcia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Salena Casha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 14:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ladies of the Light Saber and Sword]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, I bring your attention to an inventive fantasy by Silvia Morena-Garcia titled Signal to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/SignalToNoise.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-4395 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/SignalToNoise-204x300.png" alt="SignalToNoise" width="204" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Today, I bring your attention to an inventive fantasy by Silvia Morena-Garcia titled <em>Signal to Noise. </em>As a music lover, this book entranced me from the start (not to mention that the prose skirted the line between minimalistic and emotionally resonant). It’s a deceptively short novel and I could tell Morena-Garcia definitely took her time putting this piece together. For me, there wasn’t one note, scene, or music selection out of key.</p>
<p>Similar to <em>Kindred, </em>this novel alternates between two time periods: 1988 and 2009. While this novel doesn’t contain time travel and the time periods depicted aren’t worlds apart like those written into Butler’s novel, Morena-Garcia’s work shifts between moments in the same way our memory can transition between and recall periods twenty years apart (part invention and fantasy in itself).</p>
<p>The novel follows Mercedes (Meche), a music enthusiast who struggles with popularity and growing pains in high school and eventually becomes a renowned programmer in Oslo. The catalyst of the novel resides in the recent death of Meche’s estranged father, an alcoholic whose obsession with music is one of the only legacies he leaves her. Though Meche wants nothing to do with him or her own past, she finds herself in Mexico City attending his funeral.</p>
<p>What’s fresh about Morena-Garcia’s approach is that <em>Signal to Noise</em> isn’t a straight fantasy or even, really, what many reviewers would call a contemporary fantasy. The story isn’t so much about magic as it is about growing up and the hardship and emotional intensity associated with those pivotal years. Like the magical metaphors that Lev Grossman provides in his novel, <em>The Magicians</em>, the magic that Meche and her two friends experiment with becomes an allegory for the choices that define our lives and personas at a young age. Perhaps, something that comes easily to us isn&#8217;t always the correct path to choose.</p>
<p>At a recent writer’s conference I attended, the buzz word thrown around most (other than diversity) was “strong female protagonist.” While I am one of the staunchest advocates of feminist ideology and believe a good percentage of science fiction and fantasy lacks strong female role models, I don’t believe, as a literary community, we’ve truly defined that moniker just yet or, even worse, we’ve confused the definition. In fact, the “strong female protagonist” in a lot of novels these days, especially in young adult literature, gets involved with a male foil or hero. I’m not knocking romance, but I do believe it’s hard to believe in a strong female protagonist when some male hero comes in and saves the day. Most female characters I’ve seen depicted are marked as overly emotional, boy-obsessed, and selfless. These aren’t terrible qualities, but I have to say that they seem a little stereotypically prescribed. And the fact of the matter is that I’m getting tired of seeing love triangles sprinkled into every female empowerment story. It’s not enough for a fictionalized woman to be able to fight or make snarky comments or be overly intelligent if, at the end, she just falls for a guy or gets rescued.</p>
<p>For me, a strong female protagonist is one who understands herself for all her strengths and flaws. Who doesn&#8217;t take any bullshit and can&#8217;t been shaken by flattery. She&#8217;s someone who is on a mission of self-discovery and she makes mistakes along the way.</p>
<p>Ultimately, she needs to be the hero of her own story.</p>
<p>In a way, Morena-Garcia provides us with one such characterization. Both the adult and teenage versions of Meche are quick-witted, number-obsessed, stubborn, and emotionally discerning (note that I didn’t use the word “cold”). She’s even got a little bit of evil in her as she begins to use the magic that she and her friends acquire to beat up bullies. She struggles with self-image and, believing herself to be unattractive and unpopular, becomes guarded and develops some serious anger issues. She’s everything my teenage self can relate to (and even, sometimes, my adult one). While there is a thread of romance between herself and her best friend Sebastien, the romance doesn’t revolve around their physical attraction but rather, their history and friendship. This is a story more about Meche’s journey back to a place she abandoned, to a family she no longer wanted anything to do with, and to the possibility of reconciling old wounds.</p>
<p>Look at that! 600 words and almost no mention of the fantasy components. Essentially, Meche learns to cast spells through vinyl records in her teenage years. Sebastian and their friend Daniela provide her with support for casting trickier spells. As the novel weaves on, Meche becomes power-drunk and, fueled by her anger at her father, Sebastian, and the world in general, she begins to take her magic too far. She’s a vigilante, dealing out punishment to those whose infractions are overlooked. And even if she scared me a few times throughout the novel, there’s no doubt that she’s a complete badass.</p>
<p>While the setting itself deserves an additional post, I’ll say what I can here. Both the past and present sections of the novel are set in Mexico City. Morena-Garcia doesn’t necessarily need to describe every bit of Meche&#8217;s surroundings. Instead, she creates atmosphere through the Spanish songs with which her protagonist is obsessed, the depictions of familial gatherings, and Meche’s jaunts through the city. This place is simultaneously ethereal and grounded, a place where magic could truly be possible.</p>
<p>I think, as we move forward, we as readers need to be more critical of the female protagonists we celebrate in our novels. Meche is worthy of such celebration for me mainly because she is uncomfortably realistic in both her guarded emotions and her simmering rage at the world around her. We need to ask: What are their motives? Do they inspire change themselves and allow themselves to evolve or do other characters take the lead for them? Because I want to live in a literary world where female characters don’t need romance to make them interesting or relatable. Here, Morena-Garcia forces us to see life isn’t about romance or finding “the one” but more about the choices and mistakes we make throughout our lives that affect others around us and define our existence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: &#8220;Kindred&#8221; (1979) by Octavia E. Butler</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-kindred-1979-by-octavia-e-butler/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Salena Casha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 15:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ladies of the Light Saber and Sword]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone! Spring has finally arrived and I&#8217;ve got some great science fiction for you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1339423248l/60931.jpg" alt="" width="270" height="400" /></p>
<p>Hi Everyone!</p>
<p>Spring has finally arrived and I&#8217;ve got some great science fiction for you in the form of Octavia E. Butler&#8217;s thought-provoking <em><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60931.Kindred?ac=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kindred</a>. </em>First of all, I had no idea the book was written 36 years ago until I began this post. Second of all, I normally steer clear of time-travel novels. Just personal preference really since I haven&#8217;t stumbled upon many compelling narratives. That being said, Butler completely shattered all my expectations of time-travel tropes and parallel universes.</p>
<p>Set in 1979 and 1819, the book follows Dana, an aspiring novelist, who begins experiencing abrupt time displacements over the course of a few weeks. Each time she suffers a strange dizziness, she is sent back in time to a slave plantation. It becomes apparent that her travel is driven by impending danger to one of her ancestors, the son of a plantation owner, named Rufus. In order to guarantee her own birth, Dana must save Rufus over and over again even though he plays into the patriarchal racist-driven hierarchy of the antebellum south.</p>
<p>One main thread within the novel comments upon the violence and shock-factor of televised re-enactments of slavery in the 1800s. As Dana experiences first-hand the horrors and pain inflicted upon slaves (and herself as she is treated like one when she returns to 1819), she argues that &#8220;most people around Rufus know more about real violence than the screenwriters of today will ever know&#8221; (48). Even though the novel was written in the 70s, way before the special effects of today, I think Butler makes a good point. In cinema, due to the inundation of violent images in our media, we&#8217;ve become immune to the reality that underlies them. What those in the 1800s experienced was terrifying violence that no movie can ever accurately depict, mainly because, as viewers, we do not feel the pain ourselves. We are merely made uncomfortable. History, Butler seems to argue, is the same because, even though we are aware of the hardships and inhumane treatment of others, we can never truly understand past experiences due to our distance from them.</p>
<p>The story is mainly about context. Even though Dana is far removed from 1819, in the 1979 of her real life she still experiences racist ideologies. Her family looks down on her husband, a white writer named Kevin, because they believe that she needs to marry a black man. Her grandfather goes even as far as saying that he would die before seeing his houses fall into the hands of a white man, no matter how liberal and well-adjusted Kevin is. In the same vein, Kevin&#8217;s sister essentially disowns him because he marries a black woman. The pair are alienated by their families in the same way that the past of 1819 tries to drive a schism between them based on race. They try to pretend that race doesn&#8217;t matter in the world in which they live, but are faced with the harsh reality that it does.</p>
<p>While Dana first goes to 1819 by herself, she later returns with Kevin. The pair must modify their behaviors in order to survive on the plantation even though Kevin dislikes the idea of pretending Dana is his slave. Dana states &#8220;I played the slave, minded my manners probably more than I had to because I wasn&#8217;t sure that I could get away with it&#8221; (91). While the first initial days are difficult for her to adjust, she observes later that &#8220;Time passed. Kevin and I became more a part of the household, familiar, accepted, accepting. That disturbed me too, when I thought about it. How easily we seemed to acclimatize&#8230;And I was perverse enough to be bothered by the ease&#8221; (97).</p>
<p>This sentiment becomes more and more disturbing as Dana and Kevin find themselves confined to 1819 for long stretches of time. She even goes as far as saying &#8220;I never realized how easily people could be trained to accept slavery&#8221; (101). Even as she experiences a form of Stockholm syndrome with the slave owners, she is able to keep some perspective and sarcasm. When she comments on Rufus&#8217; father, she says &#8220;His father wasn&#8217;t the monster he could have been with the power he held over his slaves. He wasn&#8217;t a monster at all. Just an ordinary man who sometimes did the monstrous things his society said were legal and proper&#8221; (134). However, Dana&#8217;s words do no excuse the plantation owners of their responsibility and culpability. I think she wants us to realize how easy it is for people to do unspeakable things to one another and understand the implications of such a sentiment.</p>
<p>While &#8220;Kindred&#8221; is just as much historical fiction as it is science fiction, I think Butler married the two to depict a sentiment that underlies the creation of science fiction as a genre. Science fiction is essentially alien to us in a way that 1819 is alien to us in today. It feels removed and unbelievable and I believe she juxtaposes the two to second-guess our own beliefs about history. Dana argues that &#8220;history happened whether it offends you or not&#8221; (141). The novel may be billed as scifi but the truth that grounds us in an otherwise alien time is profound and earth-shattering.</p>
<p>Read this book. NOW. Because it will serve to remind you how unreal reality is.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: &#8220;Ironskin&#8221;by Tina Connolly</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-ironskinby-tina-connolly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Salena Casha]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 16:36:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ladies of the Light Saber and Sword]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy February! We all know that love is in the air with Valentine&#8217;s Day approaching&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/9860837.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-3708 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/9860837-202x300.jpg" alt="9860837" width="202" height="300" /></a>Happy February!</p>
<p>We all know that love is in the air with Valentine&#8217;s Day approaching and who doesn&#8217;t want to cozy up with a dark fantasy romance modeled after <em>Jane Eyre</em> with all the right notes of creepy stalkers and maniacal fairies?</p>
<p>Anyone?</p>
<p>Well, if you are interested, Tina Connolly&#8217;s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9860837-ironskin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">&#8220;Ironskin&#8221;</a> gives the classic tale a delicious and twisted spin. There&#8217;s no crazy woman in the attic, but the story itself is very much about otherization and provides us with a strong female lead (at least by Victorian England standards).</p>
<p>Enter Jane Eliot. She&#8217;s a governess who was maimed during the Great War, a battle between woodland feys and humans. Touched by fey power that causes her to feel unnecessary rage, she must wear an iron mask to keep her curse from reaching and disturbing others. In need of self-sufficiency, Jane takes a job as caretaker to a motherless child in a &#8220;delicate situation&#8221;. The child named Dorie, born during the Great War, bears a similar fey curse to Jane but her malady extends beyond Ms. Eliot&#8217;s own experience: she demonstrates fey powers with no actual scar.</p>
<p>The house is run by Dorie&#8217;s father, a mysterious and sexualized version of Mr. Rochester (named Mr. Edward Rochart). He&#8217;s creepy to the point that I didn&#8217;t entirely understand Jane&#8217;s fascination with him and he is known throughout England as a superb sculptor of masks. Rich women from all over the countryside visit him to have their faces rendered by his hand. Once they leave his mansion, they demonstrate an otherworldly beauty that is attributed to Mr. Rochart&#8217;s powers of relaxation (and the rumored affairs he has with each).</p>
<p>The tale is equal parts fantasy and steampunk. Although humans &#8220;won&#8221; the Great War, there still remains a stigma toward the ironskin (those touched by fey curses) and an inability to completely cure those marred by the fey. The novel, while containing carriages and huge mansions and corsets, also has fey technology similar to lightbulbs called blue packs. These also enable the trains to run. Such technology is used because men have beaten back the threat of fey and as such, enjoy the spoils of war.</p>
<p>I think Connolly addresses a good number of interesting societal themes throughout the book. Her main character is concerned with beauty and the mutual relationship beauty seems to have with class. Essentially, if women can afford the arts of Mr. Rochart, their faces can be remade in a more other-worldly vein. This discussion runs parallel to the struggle Jane has with her slightly vapid sister who marries a man in order to be well-provided for. He, like Mr. Rochart, is also a bit of a creep. While Jane does demonstrate vanity, she isn&#8217;t entirely flawed in that respect as she is often shunned or feared by others because of her looks. She resigns herself to a spinster life in the beginning, but her own anger at the unfair situation is often at odds with her no-cares-given attitude.</p>
<p>That being said, the novel does provide an interesting commentary on the power of beauty and wealth. And how sometimes, beauty &#8211; whether natural or bought &#8211; perverts the nature of those who carry it if they aren&#8217;t careful. The novel also provides a commentary on self-control for its characters: Jane must learn to control her anger while Dorie must learn to control her mysterious powers. However, this self-control isn&#8217;t necessarily a positive attribute as it is mainly fostered by society&#8217;s need to &#8220;keep up appearances&#8221; (or in the British saying from WWII, keep calm and carry on). Connolly ultimately falls on the side that argues socially imposed vanity and concern regarding appearance can lead to humanity&#8217;s downfall.</p>
<p>Another interesting commentary that wasn&#8217;t fully developed was mankind&#8217;s laziness when it comes to progress. Due to the technology that humans gain from the Great War, men no longer create their own devices. Innovation is halted in the realm of scientific discoveries, providing a dangerous stalemate in the evolution of society. While Jane does invent a way to help Dorie control her curse, the focus of all are on the attainment of beauty rather than real societal progress (in both attitudes and in physical objects).</p>
<p>I was slightly disappointed with the lack of positive male characters in the novel. The ones portrayed are power-hungry, deceptive, and fall into the normal structure of Victorian England patriarchy. While this was probably the rule when it came to the time period Connolly wrote about, I still found it unsettling. Ultimately, both Mr. Rochart and Helen&#8217;s husband exhibit male societal power, impose the patriarchy on Helen and Jane, and ultimately forward humanity&#8217;s spiral towards extinction.  I was also disappointed that Jane lets society&#8217;s measure of beauty get to her and nearly destroy her as well.</p>
<p>Still, Jane does offer some remarkable bits of wisdom. One that I particularly enjoyed was on page 292 where, when accused that she has made a certain choice in order to be with Mr. Rochart, she responds that it is &#8220;The choice not to be a victim. Not to be on the run , and not to let you drive me from the few people left in this world whom I care about. Who care for me.&#8221; While this sentiment gave me the hope of redeeming Jane&#8217;s previous weaknesses, she still uses these strong-worded sentiments to choose Mr. Rochart. In doing so, she similarly lifts responsibility from Mr. Rochart of his actions by stating outside forces drove his shady deeds.</p>
<p>Ultimately, I found Jane a bit weak-willed as she plays into the stereotypical role she rails against and I&#8217;m not sure whether or not this was Connolly&#8217;s intention.</p>
<p>As far as fantastical elements go, there are a ton and they don&#8217;t necessarily prescribe to genre tropes which is really nice. The fey in the novel are pretty nasty buggers and I liked the notion of curses that they imposed on mankind to effect the personality of the victims. Granted, the twists aren&#8217;t really twists at all as I guessed them pretty far in advance. I&#8217;ll call them turns for lack of a better word. Still, Connolly&#8217;s work was nominated for a Nebula and I&#8217;m sure it will please others who are hard-core Jane Eyre fans (unlike myself).</p>
<p>Overall, 3.5 out of 5 stars.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
