<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Maria DePaul &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/maria-depaul/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:07:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Comediennes in Outer Space</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/comediennes-in-outer-space/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria DePaul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Though women make up slightly more than half of the population of this planet, we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Though women make up slightly more than half of the population of this planet, we remain woefully under-represented in all media. Frequently, female characters are limited to tokenism, window dressing, and the old clichés of cute kid, love interest, mother, and wise, nurturing grandmother. This is doubly true for women of color, who are shamelessly stereotyped everywhere, regardless of genre, even today. When reconsidering the topic of women in leadership roles in space movies and television – or women in any role in genre media &#8212; one place emerges where women consistently subversively defy and even redefine the norms: comedy.</p>
<p>In the 1950s, women were stifled in their ability to portray well-rounded characters, even when exposition gave them intelligent back stories. One of the most striking examples of this stereotyping comes from 1955’s <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0047577/"><em>This Island Earth</em></a>. Even though Faith Domergue was cast as Dr. Ruth Adams, who held credentials roughly equal to her costar Rex Reason’s character Dr. Cal Meacham, her role was limited to a plot device who asked questions, looked perplexed, and needed rescue from monsters. Yet her title and status alone were points of progress not seen in other media.</p>
<p><iframe title="THIS ISLAND EARTH" width="730" height="548" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DCT4xTywUEA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>A prior post noted one early film that was memorable for sneaking in campy rebellion under the guise of conformity. That film, 1958’s <em>Queen of Outer Space</em>, shook off the norms at times, even as it perpetuated some of the most tedious, long-held stereotypes about women desperate to “find a man.” While it showed a woman leading an authoritarian dictatorship, it also showed a character (played by Zsa Zsa Gabor) taking power away from the leader, whose oppression had become unbearable. Reversing the helpless woman narrative ever so briefly, the movie portrayed women ultimately saving the men they were supposedly so desperate to find. In the 1950s, only one of the Gabor sisters (a family of Hungarian immigrants whose celebrity is roughly analogous to the Kardashian family today) could pull something like that off &#8212; and only as a punch line.</p>
<p>Progress for women in genre media has been uneven and unsteady with many back steps, but a review of media from the dawn of the electronic age reveals that while the nature of women in science fiction movies, television, and video orbits around male-dominated clichés, women in comedic roles can be impulsive, rebellious, and frequently powerful. Yet for nearly seven decades, “the funny” has cracked open the door to wider possibilities for female characters. Here’s a sampler of movies in which female characters have bent or broken with norms.</p>
<ul>
<li>In 1987, spoof-master Mel Brooks took on the <em>Star Wars</em> saga in a send up of its mythos as well as its clichés in Spaceballs. The spoof featured Daphne Zuniga as Princess Vespa, who defies the dastardly Dark Helmet (played to comic perfection by Rick Moranis) and works with Bill Pullman as the roguish Lone Star and John Candy as Barf, his mog (half man/half dog) buddy. Joan Rivers (and briefly Lorene Yarnell) provided the voice of Dot Matrix, the plucky robot who accompanied the princess on her adventures. Together, they defeated Dark Helmet to go off for more adventures. Though a promised sequel has not yet materialized, the film has been immortalized of sorts by the Tesla Corp.’s use of the film’s <a href="https://www.theregister.co.uk/2015/07/17/tesla_model_s_ludicrous_speed/">starship speeds</a> for its acceleration levels.</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe title="Spaceballs ~ Princess Vespa Shoots Like Rambo" width="730" height="548" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMCDcKxMVGU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<ul>
<li>In 1999’s <em>Galaxy Quest</em>, Sigourney Weaver stepped away from her <em>Aliens</em> role of the serious Ripley. Instead, she played an actress portraying an officer on the bridge of a starship eerily reminiscent of the <em>Enterprise</em> from the original <em>Star Trek</em> series. Weaver’s character only had two tasks: first, to repeat everything the ship’s onboard computer says and second, to serve as the captain’s unobtainable love interest. The ultimate in meta, the movie was about a TV show that becomes “real” after the cast are kidnapped to fight a battle for aliens oppressed by an evil villain. In the process, Weaver reshaped her character as a strong leader who worked with her fellow cast members to help the aliens win their freedom. Completing the meta sequence, the team returned to Earth in a renewed TV show in which Weaver’s character was more fully developed as an active member of the team.</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe title="Galaxy Quest (1999) | (3/3) | It&#039;s All Real" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BN4x4apRrpY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<ul>
<li>In this century, 2005’s movie version of <em>The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy</em> portrayed women in multiple comedic roles. Zooey Deschanel portrayed Trillian (shortened from Tricia McMillan to make it “more spacey”) as a free spirit, ready to explore the galaxy with the right adventurer. Anna Chancellor portrayed Vice President Questular Rontok who tried to prevent the Vogons from killing Rogue President Zaphod Beeblebrox until she could try to talk him into coming to his senses. Though Rontok managed the former, she never quite achieved the latter. Viewers were free to draw their own parallels to the modern political process. Many fans with attuned ears recognized Helen Mirren as the voice of Deep Thought, the computer who discovered that “the answer” to the question of “Life, the Universe, and Everything” was 42.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Evolution of Female Politicians in Outer Space</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-evolution-of-female-politicians-in-outer-space/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria DePaul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 20:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As in all things political, the portrayal of women in politics has been problematic, uneven,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As in all things political, the portrayal of women in politics has been problematic, uneven, and riddled with outdated stereotypes. Even as strides forward were taken, old modes of thinking often pushed women in political roles right back into their prior limited options. Such was the result of a genre that was overwhelmingly dominated by males in every segment of production, from writing, through direction, editing, distribution, all the way up to studio leadership. As a result, very few women have ever portrayed political leaders in science fiction – as in any other genre of television or film. Often, there have been cringe-worthy results. Herewith comes a sampling of women as leaders:</p>
<p>In what would otherwise have been a minor footnote for genre video, <em>Project Moon Base</em> (1953) featured a female commander facing an enemy plot to sabotage a space station. Arguably, the movie was prescient in that it predicted reaching the moon by 1970 and ambitious in that it foresaw a woman president. However, the movie is ripe for parody because it also perpetuated some of the worst stereotypes of the period, with women too frightened, distracted by romance, or inept to lead.</p>
<p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6FONTnIPCw0</p>
<p><em>Queen of Outer Space</em> (1958) is a parody of itself. In this cheesy vehicle, Zsa Zsa Gabor played herself to campy perfection. An evil Venusian queen gets rid of all men, except for the scientists who serve some use to her. Meanwhile, Zsa Zsa and her friends find themselves desperate for male companionship, staging a revolt to save the Earth astronauts whose ship crashes on their planet. Audiences who managed to maintain their attention spans were too busy laughing along with Zsa Zsa to take anything seriously, including stereotypes the movie perpetuated because it was made with tongue firmly in cheek. With Zsa Zsa staging the coup, everyone was in on the joke.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Trailer | Queen Of Outer Space | Warner Archive" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/awWQo9gYayQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><em>Star Wars</em> stands in a class by itself, offering women leaders in a variety of time periods across the series of films. Princess Leia Organa, portrayed by Carrie Fisher, was a royal who ventured into politics. The character’s heroism, her willingness to stand up to tyranny, her ability to take decisive action in times of crisis, and her leadership ability assure that the character will be remembered among the best in speculative movies. Her mother, Princess Amidala, portrayed by Natalie Portman in <em>The Phantom Menace,</em> evidenced the potential to become an able leader. Unfortunately, her downfall came in the form of a fatal love for the man who would eventually succumb to the Dark Side and emerge as Darth Vader. In many ways, the character encapsulated the mixed results of the <em>Star Wars</em> prequels: reaching for the highest ideals, she was thwarted in her choices by sentimentality. Senator Mon Mothma, portrayed by several women over multiple movies, was a step forward as a politician undaunted by the threat of greater power, who stood up to the chancellor in the days before he achieved total control over the empire.</p>
<p><em>Battlestar Galactica</em> (2004) President Roslin: What can be said about the so called “Madam Air Lock?” She tried to steal an election and got caught. She suspended civil liberties. When her successor abandoned his post to an enemy, she seized power without holding an election. She allowed torture. She sanctioned stealing a baby and faking its death in the worst soap opera tradition. She blamed her actions on the need for security against alien insurgents. What wouldn’t she do? To what lengths wouldn’t she go to hold onto power? Which of the recent candidates for the presidency would Roslin most likely resemble, regardless of gender? Just like almost every significant female character in the show, she died before the series ended. Though Roslin constituted a step forward in gender politics for science fiction television dramas, the evolution of her character gave a metaphor of what went awry with a show that held itself out to be a feminist revision of its original concept. In the final analysis, Roslin’s strategy and tactics provided no role model for anyone, alienating much of the audience in the process.</p>
<p>President Lanford, as portrayed by Sela Ward, in <em>Independence Day: Resurgence,</em> provided a different kind of president entirely. Lanford led her people in the fight against an extraterrestrial invasion force by standing her ground, insisting all along that there would be “no peace,” before being assassinated during enemy interrogation.</p>
<p>Nova Prime, as portrayed by Glenn Close in <em>Guardians of the Galaxy</em>, did what most leaders do in times of battle. She led from the civilian side to protect the people, gave orders to the military and others engaged in battle, and then safeguarded the spoils of war, one of the infinity stones that would be key to future conflicts for the Avengers. There is potential for further development of the character.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Guardians of the Galaxy 100 percent a dick" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gdChJwDKFmI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is it a New Day for Women Scientists in Genre Movies and Television? Not Quite Yet …</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/is-it-a-new-day-for-women-scientists-in-genre-movies-and-television-not-quite-yet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria DePaul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the early days of cinema, male scientists in science fiction and fantasy had female&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the early days of cinema, male scientists in science fiction and fantasy had female counterparts, usually assisting, sometimes as partners, but generally in peril and requiring rescue once the action builds to a climax. Those roles have evolved over time, echoing changing roles for women in society. Still, gaps in the amount of screen time allotted for male and female characters remain entrenched, as do the roles they play in narratives.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Falling Down on the Job in the 1950s</span></p>
<p>Early women protagonists in science fiction and fantasy, no matter how much exposition lauded their accomplishments, were often confined to tropes. They were frequently required to trip and slow down their male counterparts as plot points, such as in 1956 the original <a href="https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/1010678_invasion_of_the_body_snatchers?"><em>Invasion of the Body Snatchers</em></a>.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Invasion of the Body Snatchers - Trailer" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/baoC7F7EWn4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>In many other instances, women were limited to other forms of peril requiring rescue as a plot device. They would succumb to irrationality as a result of alien influences, such as in Joan Taylor’s portrayal of Carol Marvin (wife to Dr. Russell Marvin) in <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0049169/"><em>Earth vs. the Flying Saucers</em></a>. They would require rescue from monster attacks, such as in Faith Domergue’s portrayal of Dr. Ruth Adams in the 1955 <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Film/ThisIslandEarth"><em>This Island Earth</em></a>.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, villainesses were more often allowed to be competent scientists and leaders. For example, <em>Devil Girl from Mars</em> features a female spaceship captain leading a mission to Earth, complete with ray gun, robot, and a shiny leather spacesuit. Patricia Laffan as Nyah, the titular Devil Girl, is more than balanced by “useless chick” Earth females, a fashion model and a barmaid, who stand around waiting for rescue. Such roles were so common and notoriously one dimensional that they were aptly defined in “The Gang Solves the Gas Crisis” episode of the TV show <em>It’s Always Sunny in Philadelphia</em> as the “useless chick.”</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Feminism Ushers in Expanded Rolls in Genre Movies and Television</span></p>
<p>When the <a href="https://www.progressivewomensleadership.com/a-brief-history-the-three-waves-of-feminism/">Second Wave of Feminism</a> arose in the 1970s, audiences began to see the gradual expansion of women’s roles. On television, shows like <em>The Bionic Woman, The Secrets of Isis</em>, and <em>Wonder Woman</em> showed women in professional roles stepping into superhero roles when ordinary citizens needed rescue. Still, those moments were far outnumbered both on television and in the movies by women whose weak token role continued to require rescue as a mere plot point on the way to a story’s climax.</p>
<p>Movies began to catch up in the 1980s and ‘90s, as women’s roles broadened substantially. In the horror genre, bold lead characters such as Sigourney Weaver’s Ripley in the <em>Alien</em> movies franchise were summoned not only to rescue those in danger but to lead return missions.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Alien: Ridley Scott Reveals Why He Cast Sigourney Weaver As Ellen Ripley | Entertainment Weekly" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M1ExNj56TvU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Black women had an expanded presence in genre television and film during the period as well. Launched with Nichelle Nichols’ groundbreaking role of Uhura on Gene Roddenberry’s original <em>Star Trek</em> in 1966, the role is now ably portrayed by Zoe Saldana in the reboot movie series launched in 2009. The trend continued into the 21st century as black women took on command roles in other movies and television series, such Angela Bassett’s portrayal of Dr. Kaela Evers in 2000’s <em>Supernova</em> and Gina Torres’ portrayal of Zoe Washburne on the television series <em>Firefly</em> and its companion movie <em>Serenity</em>.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Wakanda Forever: <em>Black Panther</em> Sets the Bar Higher</span></p>
<p>“Wakanda Forever” can be heard all over the U.S. lately as a result of the juggernaut that <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/markhughes/2018/04/02/theres-no-secret-to-why-black-panther-succeeded/#61f2bd0e6260"><em>Black Panther</em></a> has become. Yet another demonstration that the audience hungers for movies reframing the image of women and people of color, the movie remains among the top earners, inspiring repeat views in a year marked by empty seats and box office bombs.</p>
<p>Two of the most popular characters in <em>Black Panther</em> are women in charge. General Okoye is portrayed by Danai Gurira, a playwright who portrays Michonne on <em>The Walking Dead</em>. Scientist Shuri, T’Challah’s younger sister, who created Black Panther’s bullet proof suit, is portrayed by Letitia Wright, previously seen in many roles, among them the “Black Museum&#8221; episode of <em>Black Mirror</em>.</p>
<p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ql2y3Rr92Og</p>
<p>Boldly breaking glass ceilings of gender and ethnicity, the characters set a new high mark for other superhero movies (and movies in general) to reach. Both characters are seen in top form in <em>Avengers: Infinity War</em>.</p>
<p>All of which begs the question: has a new day dawned for female scientists in movies? Possibly, but old stereotypes neither die nor fade away without resistance. Are the days when female leads trip on their stilettos and wait for rescue over? Not completely; there are still many problems across genres.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Women Doctors Need Care in Comic Book Multiverse</span></p>
<p>Though the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU) is making strides on the big screen, gaps remain. For instance, women doctors seem to revert to more limited roles in the MCU. In the first season of <em>Jessica Jones</em>, the character of <a href="http://marvelcinematicuniverse.wikia.com/wiki/Wendy_Ross-Hogarth">Wendy Ross-Hogarth</a>, better known as Lawyer Jeri Hogarth’s soon-to-be-ex-wife, is defined in exposition is an activist for underserved populations. Robin Weigert, who was previously nominated for a Prime Time Emmy for her role in <em>Deadwood</em>, brought emotional depth to the role. Still, at crucial times in the story, the character is seen reeling from infidelity or passive-aggressively seeking vengeance against her partner by delaying court proceedings before her life is put in jeopardy first by both protagonist Jessica’s physical aggression and later by villain Kilgrave’s psychological control.</p>
<p>To be fair, Nurse Claire Temple is portrayed as a skilled healer by ALMA Award Winner Rosario Dawson across multiple series, starting with <em>Daredevil</em> and <em>Jessica Jones</em> before moving to <em>Iron Fist</em>, <em>Luke Cage</em>, and <em>The Defenders</em>.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="MCU Supercut - Claire Temple: The Night Nurse" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JI64ZIm49bY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Women doctors fare far worse in the DC Comics Universe. In the 2016 movie <em>Suicide Squad</em>, psychiatrist Harley Quinn as portrayed by Margot Robbie comes across as someone who lacks self-awareness. Though originally drawn as an abusive relationship in the comics, the movie’s editing seems to convey a romance. This rewrite is troubling because movies like <em>Suicide Squad</em> attract young audiences. Therefore, the effects of its mixed messages on boys and girls are unavoidable and potentially longer lasting. In a fantasy sequence, Quinn imagines herself and the Joker [played by Jared Leto] at a dinner table with two kids, after which she turns the dishwasher to the “normal” setting. Although meant to show Quinn as completely delusional, a very <em>un</em>subtle message about how traditional relationships are ideal seems to resurface. Both Robbie and Leto have reportedly committed to filming sequels. Depending on the writing and editing of subsequent movies, the issues will either be resolved or cemented.</p>
<p>There is not a lot of room for ambiguity going forward. The message is clear. Audiences are hungering for newer, more affirming images, as shown by mega box office smashes <em>Wonder Woman</em> and <em>Black Panther</em>. The older paradigms have been rewritten. With a little tweaking, the older tropes, such as the “useless chick” and the “bitter ex” will fade into cinematic history.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Early Pioneers of Women in Speculative Fiction Nominated For Retro Hugo Awards</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/early-pioneers-of-women-in-speculative-fiction-nominated-for-retro-hugo-awards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria DePaul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To recognize the breadth and depth of women’s speculative fiction, the first step is to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To recognize the breadth and depth of women’s speculative fiction, the first step is to rediscover the past. Thus, a movement is afoot to rediscover some of the early forays by women into the world of genre magazine publishing.</p>
<p>Recognizing the lasting influence of female pioneers into the science fiction magazine world, the Hugo Awards has nominated two of the creators of <em>Weird Tales</em> magazine for the 1943 Retro Hugo Awards: editor Dorothy McIlwraith and illustrator Margaret Brundage. For the complete list of nominees, go <a href="http://www.thehugoawards.org/2018/03/2018-1943-hugo-award-finalists-announced/#more-3163">here</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/alexander-andrews-464024-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10213 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/alexander-andrews-464024-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Named after Hugo Gernsback, founder of <em>Amazing Stories</em> magazine, the awards recognize excellence in the science fiction and fantasy genres. Voting for final awards opened in April, and winners will be announced at the World Science Fiction Convention (WSFC) in San Jose, Calif., on Thursday, Aug. 16, 2018. Visit <a href="http://www.thehugoawards.org/the-voting-system/">here</a> for more information on the voting process.</p>
<p><em>Weird Tales</em> magazine promoted the early work of several innovators in science fiction and fantasy, such as publishing H.P. Lovecraft’s “Call of Cthulu” in 1928 and Robert E. Howard’s “Conan the Barbarian” stories. Editor Farnsworth Wright originally hired Brundage for another publication, <em>Oriental Stories</em>, which was later renamed <em>The Magic Carpet</em>. Wright subsequently commissioned Brundage to produce covers for <em>Weird Tales</em> magazine, along with other illustrators. For more on the connection between the two publications, see <a href="http://tellersofweirdtales.blogspot.com/2013/08/weird-fiction-fantasy-fiction-magazines.html">this</a>.</p>
<p>Wright selected scenes from featured stories for cover illustrations. Mainly using pastels, Brundage created more than 60 covers for the magazine from 1932 until 1945. Her images pushed the boundaries of subject matter for the magazine and risked censorship due to their depictions of female nudity and bondage. The magazine published her work under her initial “M” until in 1934 when Wright revealed that the illustrator was a woman. Brundage’s work has developed a loyal fan base. For an in depth look at Brundage’s life and her illustrations, see Stephen D. Korshak and <a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/J._David_Spurlock">J. David Spurlock</a>, &#8220;The Alluring Art of Margaret Brundage: Queen of Pulp Pin-Up Art&#8221; (Vanguard / Shasta-Phoenix, 2013) <a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/International_Standard_Book_Number">ISBN</a> <a href="https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Special:BookSources/1-93433-151-1">1-93433-151-1</a>.</p>
<p>When Wright resigned as editor of <em>Weird Tales</em> in 1940, McIlwraith took the helm. Dorothy McIlwraith had previously edited <em>Short Stories</em> magazine from 1936 to 1938. The McIlwraith era continued to feature work by innovators such as Ray Bradbury. She had edited the publication until it closed in 1954. Since then, several attempts have briefly revived the publication, but its website activity ends with the aptly titled “Undead Issue” at <a href="http://www.weirdtales.com/">weirdtales.com</a>.</p>
<p>Another woman linked to that legendary magazine may not have earned a nomination, but she deserves recognition as an innovator in the field. She had an uncanny ability to recognize and promote talented writers in the science fiction and fantasy genres. Sonia Greene is known mainly for having discovered and briefly married H.P. Lovecraft, but in fact was an established writer and editor in her own right. Before her short story coauthored by Lovecraft appeared in <em>Weird Tales,</em> Greene produced fanzines and pulp publications of genre fiction as early as the 1910s and 20s. She worked to establish networks for their promotion through regional conventions, meeting the legendarily reclusive Lovecraft at a convention in Boston in 1921. She was president of the United Amateur Press Association. For a more extensive history of the group, see this <a href="http://www.thefossils.org/horvat/aj/organizations/uapa.htm">link</a>.</p>
<p>Greene wrote the short story “Four O’Clock” in 1922, which can be read free online at many sites, including this one from wikisource:  <a href="https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Four_O%27Clock">https://en.wikisource.org/wiki/Four_O%27Clock</a>. However, the story was not published until 27 years later as part of an anthology of her ex-husband’s work in <em>Something About Cats and Other Pieces</em>.</p>
<p>The book also includes a short story Greene wrote with Lovecraft, “The Invisible Monster,” which was originally published in the November 1923 issue of <em>Weird Tales</em>. Also known as “The Horror at Martin’s Beach,” the story can be read, along with a variety of works connected to all things Lovecraft, <a href="http://www.hplovecraft.com/writings/texts/fiction/hmb.aspx">here</a>.</p>
<p>No review of the pulp science fiction era would be complete without recognition of Gernsback’s juggernaut <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/les-anderson-164521-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10215 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/les-anderson-164521-unsplash-300x204.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="204" /></a>Experimenter Publishing, which featured <em>Amazing Stories</em> among its many publications. In addition to publishing reprints of classics by such legends as Edgar Allen Poe and Jules Verne, <em>Amazing Stories</em> featured early work from many notable genre authors of the twentieth century, including Isaac Asimov, Ray Bradbury, and Richard Masterson. Go <a href="https://amazingstoriesmag.com/">here</a> for more information about the publication’s history and future ambitions.</p>
<p>Cele Goldsmith Lalli, editor of <em>Amazing Stories</em> and <em>Fantastic</em> until 1965, promoted such female authors as Ursula Le Guin and Sonya Dorman. She received a special award for her work on<em> Amazing Stories</em> and <em>Fantastic</em> from the World Science Fiction Convention in 1962. Here&#8217;s a complete <a href="http://www.nesfa.org/data/LL/Hugos/hugos1962.html">list</a> of the 1962 awards.</p>
<p>From the early steps women took into the world of genre publishing in the twentieth century, the field has exploded in multiple directions. The print-based beginnings of science fiction and fantasy were viewed as a niche market. Thus, publishers frequently took a narrow, almost myopic, focus on the straight male point of view in its editing, marketing, and publishing. Women in editing positions were notable, not only because they were talented and willing to take risks on new authors, but because they were rare.</p>
<p>Now, thanks in great part to the growth of the internet and online publishing, the field has widened into a broad spectrum encompassing multiple perspectives. Readers, listeners, and viewers find science fiction and fantasy venues opening new paths for people who had previously been underrepresented. Online genre publishing not only supports print publications, but now also features voices from every nationality, ethnic and racial background, faith tradition, gender and sexual orientation, and ability level – an ever expanding universe.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hedy Lamarr: The Multi-Talented Star Who Put the Means of Communication into Our Hands</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hedy-lamarr-the-multi-talented-star-who-put-the-means-of-communication-into-our-hands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria DePaul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9891</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout her life, Hedy Lamarr played a variety of roles: movie star, inventor, patent holder,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Throughout her life, Hedy Lamarr played a variety of roles: movie star, inventor, patent holder, producer, wife, and mother. She was a rebel who challenged social norms, but after she fled Nazi Germany, she took pains to save her mother. Though her end may seem tragic, Lamarr’s bold pursuit of new ideas places her among the role models for anyone with dreams of advancing our technology. Lamarr&#8217;s scientific contribution is more than a mere footnote to her movie career. She changed our lives.</p>
<p>A new documentary, “Bombshell: The Hedy Lamarr Story,” is in theaters now. Here’s a clip of the trailer:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Bombshell: The Hedy Lamarr Story Trailer #1 (2017) | Movieclips Indie" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wa_AA_byQ58?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Lamarr is most known for her beauty and her movie roles. Lamarr was only 18 years old in 1933, when she starred in the Czechoslovakian film <em>Ekstase</em>. The film caused a scandal when it was first released. Lamarr appeared nude in some scenes, and in another she appeared to portray female orgasm. Here’s a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6e41ZtIfoek&amp;t=0s&amp;list=PL2FAE28714B06DBF9&amp;index=5">link.</a></p>
<p>After that movie and some stage roles, Lamarr married an Austrian arms merchant, who tightly controlled her life, according to Lamarr’s autobiography, <em>Ecstasy and Me</em>. Though both of Lamarr’s parents (and her father-in-law) were Jewish, her husband had ties to Hitler and Mussolini. After she fled the marriage and the growing movements of Nazism and fascism in Europe, Lamarr went on to star in some of the top American films of the 1930s and 1940s.</p>
<p>Still, she wanted to contribute to the war effort. During that time, Lamarr worked with Composer George Antheil to develop spread spectrum and frequency hopping technology, hoping that the technology would be used to avoid malfunctions in radio-controlled torpedoes. In this way, Lamarr and Antheil hoped that the technology would help shorten the war.</p>
<p>The technology was granted a secret patent in 1941, seen <a href="http://pdfpiw.uspto.gov/.piw?Docid=02292387&amp;homeurl=http%3A%2F%2Fpatft.uspto.gov%2Fnetacgi%2Fnph-Parser%3FSect1%3DPTO1%2526Sect2%3DHITOFF%2526d%3DPALL%2526p%3D1%2526u%3D%25252Fnetahtml%25252FPTO%25252Fsrchnum.htm%2526r%3D1%2526f%3DG%2526l%3D50%2526s1%3D2292387.PN.%2526OS%3DPN%2F2292387%2526R" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://pdfpiw.uspto.gov/.piw?Docid%3D02292387%26homeurl%3Dhttp%253A%252F%252Fpatft.uspto.gov%252Fnetacgi%252Fnph-Parser%253FSect1%253DPTO1%252526Sect2%253DHITOFF%252526d%253DPALL%252526p%253D1%252526u%253D%2525252Fnetahtml%2525252FPTO%2525252Fsrchnum.htm%252526r%253D1%252526f%253DG%252526l%253D50%252526s1%253D2292387.PN.%252526OS%253DPN%252F2292387%252526R&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521845953023000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGn_wZdDNP35PaT-zUy8DQWBo-Nkw">here</a>.</p>
<p>However, the U.S. military wanted her to focus on selling war bonds. The patent was ignored for decades. Upon its “rediscovery,” the technology led to development of global positioning systems (GPS), Wifi, and other applications that make consumer cell phone use ubiquitous.</p>
<p>Over the course of her life, Lamarr married six times and raised three children. Like many misunderstood geniuses, Lamarr faced reversals of fortune. In time, Lamarr’s star faded, but she continued to attract controversy.</p>
<p>Her later life was marred by arrests for shoplifting and theft, as well as numerous lawsuits. Her autobiography itself was the subject of dispute when it was first published in 1966. First, Lamarr sued the publisher, saying that many sections were fabricated by a ghost writer. Then, Lamarr was sued by a writer who claimed plagiarism. She lost both suits.</p>
<p>Regardless of her personal troubles, Lamarr continued to appear on talk shows and game shows in the 1950s and 1960s. IMDB lists nearly as many Lamarr appearances as “Self” (28) as Actress (35). Here’s a <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001443/bio?ref_=nm_ov_bio_sm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001443/bio?ref_%3Dnm_ov_bio_sm&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1521845953024000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHnaZ0YgIfVceQggsm9F0HgONAmEw">link</a>.</p>
<p>As an example, the new documentary points to a famous 1969 episode of “The Merv Griffin Show.” Lamarr appeared as a guest, along with actress Leslie Uggams, comedienne Moms Mabley, and filmmaker Woody Allen. Here is a clip:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Hedy Lamarr--1969 TV Interview" width="730" height="548" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/muYlAsUDibE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>By the 1970s, Lamarr’s reputation had declined to the point that her name had become a punch line in the Mel Brooks comedy, <em>Blazing Saddles</em>. Famously, Harvey Korman played a character named Hedley Lamarr. His most famous line is now the basis of a meme, “it’s not Hedy, it’s Hedley,” as seen here:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="It&#039;s Hedley! Blazing Saddles" width="730" height="548" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8vjEnkQdaHM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>When Lamarr sued in 1974 for infringement of her privacy, the claim was settled.</p>
<p>She finally died far from the limelight in 2000 at the age of 85. Still, her legacy lives on in every text message and GIF transmitted by cell phone.</p>
<p>Her life story is proof of what long term damage institutional sexism can cause. Her innovation languished for decades, only to be &#8220;rediscovered&#8221; by the same cultural structures that allow bro culture to persist and limit the advancement of women in tech now. Who couldn&#8217;t be frustrated – even angry &#8212; at the fact that Lamarr&#8217;s contribution is still being &#8220;rediscovered,&#8221; instead of being taught in history classes?</p>
<p>Only recently has Lamarr been given proper recognition for her accomplishments. In 2014, the National Inventors Hall of Fame inducted Lamarr for her <a href="http://www.invent.org/honor/inductees/inductee-detail/?IID=501">achievements</a>.</p>
<p>As users of the internet become interested in the history of its creation and development, Lamarr’s story has recaptured the attention of the cultural zeitgeist. Her life has become the subject of a one woman show by Heather Massie, who took the show to Baltimore, MD, last <a href="https://www.broadwayworld.com/baltimore/article/HEDY-THE-LIFE-INVENTIONS-OF-HEDY-LAMARR-to-Play-Charm-City-Fringe-20171108">November</a>. The story of her invention with Antheil has been portrayed in an off-broadway production.  Here’s one <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/06/09/arts/music/09ball.html">review</a>.</p>
<p>In time, her biography may come to be listed alongside other female scientific pioneers, like Vera Rubin, who revolutionized the studies of galactic motion and <a href="https://carnegiescience.edu/news/vera-rubin-who-confirmed-%E2%80%9Cdark-matter%E2%80%9D-dies">dark matter </a>and <a href="http://www.computerhistory.org/babbage/adalovelace">Ada Lovelace</a>, the visionary who advanced the development of computer algorithms.</p>
<p>How many students even know their names? Will the true history of women in science and technology simply fade into obscurity &#8212; or be lost completely? The only way to prevent such a fate is to learn our own history and teach it to others. The way to assure that women’s role in science history is recognized is to do it ourselves.</p>
<p>The popular culture is beginning to recognize women’s contributions to science and technology. However, these changes mainly take the form of incremental moves like the current documentary about Lamarr, or like <a href="https://www.minorplanetcenter.net/db_search/show_object?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;object_id=5726">naming an asteroid</a> after Vera Rubin.</p>
<p>After all that Lamarr endured, she at least deserves a posthumous nomination for inclusion into the “Me Too” Movement. Though I can&#8217;t offer apologies for what others put Lamarr through during her life, I can at least say this: &#8220;thank you.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Frankenstein and the Modern Zeitgeist</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/frankenstein-and-the-modern-zeitgeist/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria DePaul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Like many women writers, when I think of my early influences, I can’t help but&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/eery-1648250_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9643 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/eery-1648250_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Like many women writers, when I think of my early influences, I can’t help but reminisce on my first encounter with Mary Shelley’s seminal novel <em>Frankenstein, or the Modern Prometheus</em>. Shelley first published the book anonymously as this was a time when female authors faced vast discrimination and many successful women writers typically took a male nom de plume.</p>
<p>Since the epistolary novel was published on January 1, 1818, it has been the subject of extensive literary analytics. <em>LSQ</em>’s own Sara Amis ably chronicled the novel’s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/mothering-the-monster-mary-shelley/">creation</a>.</p>
<p>Any discussion of the women who pioneered the literary landscape of genre fiction must recognize this masterpiece. Shelley’s influence is too vast across the landscape to be ignored, so before I delve into the many women whose creativity broke barriers in the 20th century, which led to the explosion of new female voices now reshaping science fiction and fantasy, I just had to salute the influence of this epic tale. The many ways that her characters have penetrated the cultural landscape helped carved out the earliest path for so many of us to follow.</p>
<p>Thanks, Mary, for sharing with us your vision, thus expanding the road for generations of science fiction writers to follow. Inspired to reread the tale or try it for the first time? There are many free sources of her work on the web, but here’s a <a href="http://www.gutenberg.org/files/84/84-h/84-h.htm">link</a> to the mammoth Gutenberg site.</p>
<p>There are multiple days in which to celebrate the story, beginning of course with the author’s birthday. Here’s a <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-mary-shelley/">link</a> to Cheryl Wollner’s post in which she shared birthday wishes. Other days to celebrate the character include the moveable feast of Frankenstein <span data-term="goog_187392499">Friday</span>, the last Friday in October, and the set calendar date of <span data-term="goog_187392500">October 29</span>.</p>
<p>However, one of the best times to read the book is just after the New Year, when the holidays have past. The bleak landscape of winter with its snowy scenes and howling winds invokes memories of reading one of the book’s most iconic scenes. The crew of a ship is stuck in the ice while on a voyage to explore the North Pole. They see the large hulking shadow of a man before rescuing Dr. Victor Frankenstein, who is starving and nearly frozen to death in pursuit of that man, his monster.</p>
<p>Arguably one of the most influential female writers of her generation, Mary Shelley rewrote the cultural mythos with this one tale. Her monster stands as a cultural icon in a limelight as bright as Melville&#8217;s white whale. Dr. Victor Frankenstein&#8217;s ongoing struggle with his creation echoes in cultural influence with Ahab&#8217;s pursuit of his quarry, except for the argument that in Shelley&#8217;s novel, both creature and creator are driven to and by madness.</p>
<p>Shelley&#8217;s characters are now part of the political lexicon. The monster is frequently invoked in politics as a criticism of politicians who break free of handlers and the mad scientist meme is often referenced in relation to environmental disaster.</p>
<p>Frankenstein&#8217;s reach extends to every genre. Portrayals flow from the fine and performing arts to film, television, and every corner of electronic media. Not a year goes by without a cinematic reinterpretation. The work has been turned into both a <a href="https://www.sfgate.com/music/article/Berkeley-Symphony-previews-a-Frankenstein-7398039.php">symphony</a> and a heavy metal rock opera:</p>
<p>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5kZl74TMQyY</p>
<p>In dance, Liam Scarlett’s <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2016/may/08/frankenstein-royal-ballet-review-liam-scarlett">full length ballet</a> was staged at the Royal Opera House in London in 2016.</p>
<p>Comic send-ups of the characters have moved from movie cartoons to television shows. At the movies, Looney Tunes saluted the character along with others in 1938’s “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=reeyAELsSkY">Have You Got Any Castles</a>.” In 1946’s “<a href="https://www.bing.com/videos/search?q=hair+raising+hare&amp;view=detail&amp;mid=A780A8CDBA59BC420D55A780A8CDBA59BC420D55&amp;FORM=VIRE">Hair-Raising Hare</a>,” Bugs Bunny meets a character based on the monster. The original character was nameless, but it was later named Gossamer as the character came into its own.</p>
<p>On television, cartoon shows have embraced the monster. <em>The Simpsons</em> has referenced Shelley’s work in multiple episodes, such as this scene in which the monster plays basketball:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Frankenstein and the Harlem Globetrotters Meet the Mummy and the Washington Generals" width="730" height="548" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kRn9E5qNtOI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>In “<a href="http://rickandmorty.wikia.com/wiki/Total_Rickall">Total Rickall</a>,” an episode of <em>Rick and Morty</em>, an interstellar parasite attempts to control Rick’s mind by implanting a false “memory” of Rick serving in the Vietnam War with the Monster.</p>
<p>In print comics, Shelley’s legacy persists as well. <em>Archie Comics</em> featured a “Frankie” issue in February 1965. In November 2017, <em>Archie Comics</em> launched a digital feature, “<a href="http://archiecomics.com/franken9/">Franken 9.</a>”</p>
<p>Shelley’s characters have been so embraced by the zeitgeist that they have become endearing, inspiring, warm memories of childhood. For how many decades have kids dressed up as Dr. Frankenstein or (more likely) the monster for Halloween? What kid from Generation X onward doesn’t remember the <a href="https://blog.generalmills.com/2012/10/the-history-of-our-monsters/">Monster Breakfast cereals</a> launched by General Mills in 1971? In that series, Frankenberry is dedicated to the monster, while Boo Berry features a generic ghost, and of course Count Chocula salutes Dracula.</p>
<p>From the twentieth century onward, many of the modern reinterpretations of the work take strong influence from James Whale&#8217;s movies <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1qNeGSJaQ9Q"><em>Frankenstein</em></a>, as well as his sequel, <em>Bride of Frankenstein</em>. Here, the monster meets his “bride,” who rejects him at first sight:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="The Monster Meets His Bride - Bride of Frankenstein (10/10) Movie CLIP (1935) HD" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o1Izq-E3o7Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Whale’s movies included his own additions to the Frankenstein mythos. The movies used timely props such as the Tesla coil. Choreography of the legendary &#8220;Frankenstein walk&#8221; came from the Whale moves, as did the open sympathy for the monster as a substitute for the &#8220;other&#8221; in a time of cultural constriction. Shelley’s novel provided Whale with an apt metaphor for the persecution increasingly faced by many marginalized groups in the 1930s under the rising tide of fascism. All of these elements result from the novel&#8217;s power and depth, which allows it to be open to reinterpretation.</p>
<p>No salute could be complete without recognizing Gene Wilder’s <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0072431/"><em>Young Frankenstein</em></a>, which sends up the Whale movies. The movie later spawned its own musical tribute, seen here:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Official Trailer | Young Frankenstein Musical" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/84_6aqBXP04?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>While the film and television adaptations have introduced the book to many generations, one character, Igor the assistant, was not in Shelley’s original work. However, this character is inexorably linked to the Frankenstein genre as a spinoff creation. In Whale&#8217;s movies, Dr. Frankenstein had an assistant named Fritz. In 1939, Rowland Lee filmed <em>Son of Frankenstein</em> as a sequel to <em>Bride of Frankenstein</em>. That movie introduced Ygor, played by screen icon Bela Lugosi. The character so captured the imagination that he became a cultural icon himself, ably spoofed by comic genius Marty Feldman in <em>Young Frankenstein</em>. Most recently, Igor got his own feature length cartoon treatment, voiced by John Cusack, in 2008’s eponymous <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0465502/?ref_=ttpl_pl_tt">film.</a></p>
<p>Full disclosure: I discovered the book after watching the films and cartoon versions. I then used those reinterpretations to introduce the book to my own children. I wrote a bit of flash fiction based on my experiences reading and watching with my kids, which can be read <a href="http://www.akashicbooks.com/baby-frankenstein-by-maria-depaul/">here.</a></p>
<p>The book’s influence is so vast across time and format and so continuous into the present day that a definitive catalogue could encompass volumes. Ultimately, the best way to measure its impact is to return to source material and to share new interpretations with generations to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Single Moms in Space: Sci-Fi TV Recognizes New Parenting Concepts</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/single-moms-in-space-sci-fi-tv-recognizes-new-parenting-concepts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria DePaul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 11:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a medium given to formulaic plot lines, mainstream television can be slow to embrace&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/stefan-cosma-326337.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9450 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/stefan-cosma-326337-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>As a medium given to formulaic plot lines, mainstream television can be slow to embrace new narratives and cultural change, but the science fiction genre can take some strides, given its “futuristic” format. <em>Star Trek</em> justifiably comes to mind as the series legendary for the <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/tvs-first-interracial-kiss-star-896843">first interracial kiss</a> on the small screen and for its multicultural casting. Even so, the series took gradual steps to reflect many of the realities of modern parenting.</p>
<p>The roles widow and widower were used as windows to single parenting in S<em>tar Trek: The Next Generation</em>. That series’ version of the <em>Enterprise</em> is unique in the television cosmos as having two widowed parent characters. Doctor Beverly Crusher, played by Gates McFadden, joined the crew as a widow with a teenage son, Wesley, who in true television fashion was a boy genius ready and willing to help on the bridge. The child genius trope was problematic in itself to watch, as Wesley seemed to exhibit no sign of adolescent awkwardness, and internal conflicts were conveniently solved without hindering the overall narrative or even changing his mother’s overtime work schedule.</p>
<p>Security Officer Worf came more suddenly to single parenting. A former partner surprised him with a young son, Alexander, and then was killed by an adversary, repeating the overused “mom must die” trope. This time, however, Worf found himself overwhelmed with his new responsibilities and turned his son over to his adoptive parents. In a twist more reflective of reality, Worf’s adoptive mother, herself advanced in age, returned Alexander to Worf because she was not equipped to provide for her grandson’s needs. In contrast to the traditional interpretation of the trope, Worf’s experience was much more fraught because he and Alexander had to face loss and learn new ways of coping with issues of trust, grief, and adjustment to changed circumstances. Here’s one of many links to all things <a href="http://www.roddenberry.com/entertainment/#star-trek"><em>Trek</em></a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/tardis-1816598_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9452 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/tardis-1816598_1920-300x224.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="224" /></a>In the Dr. Who spinoff <em>The Sarah Jane Adventures</em>, the titular character, played by Elisabeth Sladen, became an adoptive single mother when aliens created a human teenage boy using human DNA. Though Sarah remained earthbound in the series, the character was visited weekly by aliens, including the Tenth and Eleventh Doctors in crossover appearances.</p>
<p>The relaunch of <em>Dr. Who</em> generally portrayed mothers of companions as antagonists to the doctor. Sarah Jane was once again unique among the companions, portrayed as a mother who assisted in operating the Tardis in one episode and whose child was saved by the doctor in another. To date, Amy and Rory have been the only companions who conceived a child, River Song, while traveling on the Tardis. However, because the child was stolen (a rare use by the show of a trope frequently used elsewhere) and River Song regenerated rapidly into adulthood in the series, Amy and Rory lacked classic parenting moments except for giving the bride away.</p>
<p>Though the Sarah Jane character currently marks the definitive image of mothering on the show, <em>Dr. Who</em> was also ahead of its time in its portrayal of grandparenting.  The First Doctor, portrayed by William Hartnell, traveled with his granddaughter Susan Foreman, portrayed by Carol Ann Ford. In “The Doctor’s Daughter,” the Tenth Doctor became a parent again for one episode.</p>
<p>Leading the way into a brave new parenting era, <em>Star Trek</em> parody/homage <em>The Orville</em> blithely jumps in where other series seem reluctant to tread. In one brave leap forward into modern parenting norms, the ship’s Doctor Claire Finn, played by Penny Johnson Jerald, became a single mother by choice when she used reproductive technology methods to conceive two boys with the intent of raising them on their own.</p>
<p><em>The O<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/ravi-roshan-383162.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9451 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/ravi-roshan-383162-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>rville</em> broke new ground again by portraying a couple from a male-only species who raise their child together on board ship. Upon discovering that their child is in fact a daughter, they were forced by court decree to change the child’s sex to male. The story line was a bold step forward, bringing gay parenting and gender identity issues before its audience, as well as leaving new issues open for the future of the series. The show has been renewed for a second season. For more information, here&#8217;s a <a href="https://www.fox.com/the-orville#season-1">link</a>.</p>
<p>The portrayal of parenting by space-faring science fiction series has evolved radically over the past six decades, and the genre continues to offer ways to expand the roles and options depicted. Over time, science fiction TV families have evolved to show a wider spectrum of careers, partners and custody roles, more accurately reflecting the world the audience inhabits. Fans can expect more of this variety in the future, offering a broader variety of story lines, conflicts and adventure in the process. Viva la difference!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Portrayal of Women and Parenting Roles in Sci-Fi TV</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-portrayal-of-women-and-parenting-roles-in-sci-fi-tv/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria DePaul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 11:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From the beginning, women have traveled alongside men in the exploration of our planet. So&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/hamish-clark-370542.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9446 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/hamish-clark-370542-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" /></a>From the beginning, women have traveled alongside men in the exploration of our planet. So too in space. Women have served in space since Soviet Cosmonaut <a href="https://starchild.gsfc.nasa.gov/docs/StarChild/whos_who_level2/tereshkova.html">Valentina Tereshkova</a> orbited the globe on June 16, 1963. At the same time, men and women sought to balance the demands of career and family. As roles changed, science fiction reflected those changes. Since the 1960s, the roles women and parents in televised science fiction have evolved, occasionally with mixed results. Here follows a sampler of some notable TV moms and dads in space.</p>
<p><em><strong>Welcome Aboard, Mrs. Sarek!</strong> </em>The arrival on <em>Star Trek</em> of Spock’s mother, <a href="http://www.startrek.com/database_article/grayson">Amanda Grayson</a>, played by Jane Wyatt in “Journey to Babel,” marked an event. The mother of a main character appeared in the seminal series, which was known for demographic and cultural venues. She returned for a cameo in <em>Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home</em>. The role of Amanda Grayson recurs in this century’s continuation of the TV series. Mia Kirshner now plays the role of Sarek’s wife on <em>Star Trek: Discovery</em>.</p>
<p><em><strong>That’s a great dinner, Mrs. Robinson.</strong></em> Basically, the first TV Mom in Space, Dr. Maureen Robinson on <em>Lost in Space</em> was a biochemist, played by June Lockhart. However, though she played a key role in the series, much of the character’s time still focused on traditional tasks such as meal planning, laundry, and supervision of the younger children. Regardless, the portrayal of Maureen Robinson as a professional in a lead role on the mission was a leap forward. To reminisce about all aspects of the show, go <a href="http://www.iann.net/lis/">here</a>.</p>
<p><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/john-baker-421759.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9447 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/john-baker-421759-300x198.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="198" /></a>And now a moment of parenting on our great quest for a new home&#8230;</strong> </em>Where the <em>Battlestar Galactica</em> series teetered between progressive and problematic portrayals of female characters, they frequently fell back on TV clichés when addressing parenting roles. Boxey on the original <em>Battlestar Galactica</em> fell under the “dying mother” cliché twice. The first time came when the boy was an orphan rescued by Serina, the journalist-turned-pilot-trainee played by Jane Seymour who married pilot Apollo. More problematic from a feminist perspective was the event in which Boxey was orphaned a second time. Apollo’s wife died during a mission, leaving Apollo a single stepfather. Thus, the show turned to a disturbing trope used in many entertainment genres: mothers die, leaving fathers open to new adventures as children magically raise themselves free from maternal influences.</p>
<p><em><strong>Redux, reuse, recycle.</strong></em> The portrayal of parenting on the “re-envisioned” <em>BSG</em> was shakier. When Starbuck faced the prospect of a possible half-Cylon daughter created through reproductive technology, many fans winced as the character faced the prospect of motherhood. Casey turned out to be a traditionally-conceived human child kidnapped from her mother. In typical space opera fashion, Casey’s mother reaching out to Starbuck to continue contact with Casey was met with ambivalence from the relationship-challenged fighter pilot. This trope so interested <em>BSG</em> writers that it was used again with two other crew members.</p>
<p>That’s not his half-Cylon baby, either. The not-my-baby trope resurfaced when Tyrol, upon discovering that he was a Cylon, found out that his son was not half-Cylon, but had been conceived by his wife in an extramarital affair with a pilot. This time, the guys cooperated in a shared custody arrangement. Where was the mom? She was dead.</p>
<p>Is that a trope addiction? Oh no! Our messiah hybrid baby was switched at birth! Much of the <em>BSG</em> redux hinged on the origins of a child conceived by a human pilot, Helo, and a cylon, Boomer/Athena. Their daughter emerged as the first Cylon-Human conception. Several ancient television soap opera writing tropes resurfaced in the process when the child was touted as a messiah, switched at birth, stolen by evil Cylons intent on having the baby save their people instead, proclaimed the “magic baby cure” for a virus affecting her mother and other Cylons, kidnapped (again?) by a Cylon clone/evil twin, etc., etc.</p>
<p>In the process of such meanderings, the series may have inadvertently set back portrayals of parenting in TV science fiction by a few decades. Luckily, the genre has a fluidity and a staying power strong enough that multiple images of parenting have surfaced in recent years.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: &#8220;Good Omens&#8221; by Terry Pratchett and Neil Gaiman</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-good-omens-by-terry-pratchett-and-neil-gaiman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria DePaul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 12:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Book Name: Good Omens Authors: Terry Pratchett and Neil Gaiman First Published: 1990 Now is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Book Name: <em><strong>Good Omens</strong></em></p>
<p>Authors: Terry Pratchett and Neil Gaiman</p>
<p>First Published: 1990</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/386282.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9025 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/386282-180x300.jpg" alt="" width="180" height="300" /></a>Now is a great time to reread <em>Good Omens</em> by Terry Pratchett, author of the <a href="https://www.terrypratchettbooks.com/discworld-reading-order/">Disc World</a> series of novels, and Neil Gaiman, author of the <a href="http://www.vertigocomics.com/characters/the-sandman">Sandman</a> graphic novels series and countless other works. Gaiman, whose novel <em>American Gods</em> provides the source material for the hit Amazon series, is serving as Show Runner for another Amazon series based on <em>Good Omens</em>.  The series is in production for an expected release in 2019.</p>
<p>If you’ve never read the book, you’re in for a treat. The sweeping satire of Apocalyptic prophecies re-situates the Battle of Armageddon in an English village. It centers on the lives of an angel and a demon, who are preparing for the war between good and evil.</p>
<p>The strongest points of the book stem from relationships. Seeming adversaries can form alliances, friendships&#8211;even romantic connections. The novel shines when setting up parallel dynamics. Meetings between representatives of the eternal conflict of good versus evil compare to spy versus spy. An “evil” nanny is countered by a “good” gardener. A Hell Hound tries to find his inner playful pup. A young couple finding new love contrasts with the chemistry between two neighbors at midlife.</p>
<p>The novel has fun upending tropes of religion and superstition in general, as well as the specifics of the Apocalypse. Some entities attempt to speed up the process, while others try to stop it from happening. Random humans appear eager to serve as acolytes to the Four Horsemen. The book parodies the standard issue glamorous accouterments of evil doers, such as elegantly appointed apartments and antique luxury cars. It also sends up divination, prophecy, witchcraft, the summoning demons, possession, and the techniques used by mediums to enhance seances.</p>
<p>The story is full of female characters at all stages of life. Agnes Nutter is the Cromwell-era prophetess burned as a witch. Nutter provides the nice (as in the Medieval definition of “precise”) and accurate prophecies driving the book’s plot.  Madame Tracy is a midlife “Jezebel,” who is also a part-time medium. Her neighbor is a local witch hunter who sends his assistant, Newton Pulsifer (a descendant of the man who burnt Nutter at the stake) to investigate whether Nutter’s descendant, “occultist” Anathema Device, is a witch. Device possesses the only extant copy of Nutter’s book of prophecies. Sister Mary Loquacious is a Satanic nun who supervises the substitution of the child of Satan for a human child, with many plot driving results. Red is the personification of War as a young professional arms dealer, who brings havoc wherever she goes before emerging as one of the Four Horsemen. Pepper is the only female member of the Them, a group of friends who play with the putative Antichrist. Many minor female characters are sprinkled throughout the book, such as attendees of Madame Tracy’s seances.</p>
<p><em>Good Omens</em> is an almost perfect novel. Though the novel gives its female characters nuances and depth infrequently <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Good-Omens-cover.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-9026 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Good-Omens-cover-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>portrayed by male authors of fantasy literature a quarter of a century ago, it sometimes slips back into traditional stereotypical limits. When Device has an intimate moment with Pulsifer, it’s described from his point of view. A long-winded séance attendee is unceremoniously told by her dead husband through Madame Tracy to “shut up.” When Pepper protests being given a girl’s bike as “sexist,” it’s done for laughs. Pepper’s mother, who is only referred to when the children discuss their parents, is portrayed as a series of tropes. Sexual harassment is trivialized when a televangelist casually gropes the bottom of a female assistant. To the authors’ credit, he gets a comeuppance of sorts when he mistakes angelic possession for a demonic one while speaking on camera.</p>
<p>Such harsh turns from an otherwise positive narrative can break suspended disbelief for a moment. It is important to remember, however, that the first edition of the book was published in 1990. Put into historical context, these distractions from a story line that gives significant development to female characters may be better understood, especially when followed by laugh out loud plot moments. Overall, the book’s representation of female characters as driving the plot, rather than as mere one-dimensional plot points, marked a step forward for the genre.</p>
<p>Later editions of the book include extra features, such as “Good Omens, The Facts,” which tells how the story was written. Gaiman was a journalist in 1985 when he interviewed Pratchett about the first Disc World novel. Gaiman approached Pratchett with part of a short story a few years later, beginning a back and forth writing and revision process that eventually produced the final version of <em>Good Omens</em>.</p>
<p>The common theme of facing adversity with hope that flows through both Pratchett’s and Gaiman’s writing continues into this collaboration. Even during the end times, life goes on. Children can find play opportunities in the grimmest of situations. No plan, no matter how diabolical, is beyond the possibility of change. Humor can be found in the most preposterous circumstances. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women Make History By Sequencing DNA In Outer Space and Underwater</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/women-make-history-by-sequencing-dna-in-outer-space-and-underwater/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maria DePaul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6881</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Women are making space history this July. NASA Astronaut Kathleen Rubins became the 60th woman&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_7332" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7332" style="width: 275px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/index-1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-7332 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/index-1.jpg" alt="Kathleen Rubins" width="275" height="183" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7332" class="wp-caption-text">Kathleen Rubins</figcaption></figure>
<p>Women are making space history this July. NASA Astronaut <a href="http://www.jsc.nasa.gov/Bios/htmlbios/rubins-k.pdf">Kathleen Rubins</a> became the 60<sup>th</sup> woman to fly in space. She is now leading a project to sequence DNA on the International Space Station.</p>
<p>Up until now, there has been no way to perform sequencing in space, NASA Scientist Sarah Castro-Wallace told a news conference at NASAs Johnson Space Flight Center in Houston, TX. Instead, samples must wait until crews aboard the ISS return to the ground to perform such testing. The ability to perform sequencing on the station would allow for in-flight microbe identification. Identifying sequences would help diagnose illnesses, assuring crew member health.</p>
<figure id="attachment_7333" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-7333" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Sequencer-580x406.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image wp-image-7333 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Sequencer-580x406-300x210.jpg" alt="sequencer-580x406" width="300" height="210" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-7333" class="wp-caption-text">minION DNA sequencer</figcaption></figure>
<p>The DNA sequencer is a hand-held device that can be connected to a laptop computer or a tablet with a USBconnection. It can perform experiments for up to six hours at a time and does not need a battery.</p>
<p>A team also performed a DNA sequencing under water on the ocean floor in the Aquarius research facility for NASAs Extreme Environment Mission Operations(NEEMO). <a href="https://www.ihmc.us/news20160622/">Aquanaut Dawn Kernagis</a> has <a href="https://twitter.com/dawn_kernagis/status/780420341281718272">tweeted photos of the sequencer</a>, which would be used as part of a program to monitor air, water and surfaces for microbial contamination on the station to ensure the safety of space crews. Such information would be crucial on long range missions.</p>
<p>Tests are being performed on blood samples to see if the effects of microgravity in space are similar to those of high pressure situations in underwater environments. This information could be especially helpful as extremophiles could potentially be found on Mars, Wallace explained.</p>
<p>Eventually, the sequencer may also help detect DNA-based life elsewhere in the solar system, Wallace added.</p>
<p>On the ISS, Astronaut Rubins, who became an astronaut in 2009, is uniquely qualified for this research. She has a PhD in Cancer Biology from Stanford University. She has studied viral infection and RNA transcription, including genome sequencing on Ebola and Lassa Fever viruses.</p>
<p>At the Aquarius facility, researchers work about 3.5 miles off the coast of Key Largo, FL. The facility has been in operation since 2001. Aquanauts can live on the facility for up to three weeks at a time, conducting space simulation missions with various crews. Women have been aquanauts in several NEEMO Missions, living and working on site at the facility to perform scientific experiments, including EVAs along the ocean floor. Women on the current mission, NEEMO 21, include Kernagis, scheduled to splash down July 26, and <a href="http://www.jsc.nasa.gov/Bios/htmlbios/mcarthur-km.pdf">Megan Behnken-McArthur</a>, who was joined the mission July 21.</p>
<p>Kernagis is part of the Naval Sea Systems Command and principal investigator for <a href="https://www.ihmc.us/">The Institute for Human and Machine Cognition</a>. She is a diver who has led underwater research and exploration projects since 1993. She was inducted into the Women Divers Hall of Fame this year before being selected to join NEEMO 21.</p>
<p>McArthur, an oceanographer who became an astronaut in 2000, has worked extensively in space before joining NEEMO 21. In space, she has served as a capsule communicator for both the ISS and the space shuttle. She made history in her role as mission specialist in the final mission to the Hubble Space Telescope when she became the last person to work with the telescope&#8217;s robotic arm, improving its capabilities and extending its useful life.</p>
<p>The NEEMO facility is located about 47 feet underwater. According to NASA, visitors can only stay about 80 minutes there before risking decompression illness. Aquanauts can stay for extended periods at the facility but must undergo 17 hours of decompression within Aquarius before leaving the facility and returning to the surface via scuba.</p>
<p>The ISS is a habitable artificial satellite in low Earth orbit that can be seen with the naked eye. The ISS is sunlit and can best be seen at night, including just after sunset or before sunrise. To see for yourself, go to <a href="http://www.jsc.nasa.gov/Bios/htmlbios/mcarthur-km.pdf">https://spotthestation.nasa.gov/sightings/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
