<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 034 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-034/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 03:30:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 034 Author Interview: Michelle Ann King and &#8220;You Pay Your Money and You Take Your Chance&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-034-author-interview-michelle-ann-king-and-you-pay-your-money-and-you-take-your-chance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 034]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 035 might be right around the corner but we had so much great stuff&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>Issue 035 might be right around the corner but we had so much great stuff in <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-034/">Issue 034</a> we&#8217;re back again with another author interview. Today we had the priveldge to chat with Michelle Ann King about her story &#8220;You Pay Your Money and You Take Your Chance.&#8221; Go read the story <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/you-pay-your-money-and-you-take-your-chance/">here</a>, then come back (don&#8217;t worry, we&#8217;ll wait) and read what Michelle has to say about her story, her writing process, and the source of her inspiration.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div>
<div><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/seth-macey-564693-unsplash.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11131 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/seth-macey-564693-unsplash-300x214.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="214" /></a>LSQ: In this story, you&#8217;ve captured the concept of time travel but with a twist that it&#8217;s not totally controlled. Where did this idea come from? Are you a fan of time travel stories? Do you have a favorite or at least one that sticks out in your mind?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p>Michelle: The idea came from a very wise piece of advice about gambling: &#8220;Don’t bet what you can’t afford to lose.&#8221; I think it’s typical of writers to take any idea to its worst-case extreme, so I ended up with a story about a woman gambling with something she’s very nearly run out of: time.</p>
<p>And yes, I do indeed love time travel stories! Robert Heinlein’s classic short &#8220;<a href="https://gist.github.com/defunkt/759182/ad44c6135d168ae54503a281bb7e1a24c6c2ea0c">All You Zombies</a>&#8221; is mind-bending in the best kind of way (you kind of need to draw a flowchart as you read, to follow the mechanics of it), and Audrey Niffenegger’s <a href="https://deadline.com/2018/07/the-time-travelers-wife-adaptation-steven-moffat-series-order-hbo-1202437332/"><i>The Time Traveller’s Wife</i></a>is a wonderful (but heartbreaking!) look at the emotional and psychological effects.</p>
<div><em><strong><span class="im">LSQ: Have you written other time-bending stories since the original publication of this piece in 2014?</span></strong></em></div>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<p>Michelle: I thought I must have, but my records say no. Clearly, I need to get on that! Although I’ve written about immortality, which is kind of at the other end of the spectrum to this story – what do you do when you have too much time, as opposed to not enough?</p>
</div>
<p><em><strong><span class="im">LSQ: The reader becomes sympathetic to Disa&#8217;s view, that of leaving it all to chance in the Time Pocket, yet the reader can understand her daughter Claudie&#8217;s standpoint as well. Did Disa&#8217;s situation lend itself easily to the plot? Which character, Disa or Claudie, was easier to write? Does one represent your own outlook more than the other or someone you know?</span></strong></em></p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Michelle: Disa’s situation highlights the inherent risk involved in this. If you use the Time Pocket you are literally gambling with your life –  and if Disa loses, she dies. The thought of taking that kind of chance makes me feel ill, but I can understand the choice to do it. I can also understand trying to influence the process – the rituals, the systems, the personally energized crystals – even if you know, as Claudie does, that it can’t really be done.</p>
<p>Claudie has a far more pragmatic attitude, and a lot of her anger at her mother is coming from fear, frustration, and grief, which is equally understandable. So I don’t think she’s entirely wrong, but there’s also a mercenary angle – the thought of that insurance payout -– to her thinking. I wanted to emphasize the financial aspect because I do believe that if something like the Time Pocket actually existed, this is exactly what would happen: it would be commercialized and monetized – turned into an industry – in a heartbeat.</p>
<p><em><strong><span class="im">LSQ: What was the most enjoyable part about writing this story? The most challenging? <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/luke-van-zyl-567816-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11132 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/luke-van-zyl-567816-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a><br />
</span></strong></em></p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<p>Michelle: The commercial setup was fun to do -– the First Class Lounge style of the place itself, and the story of Jaclyn Castleton and her rise to celebrity – but I needed to fit that rather light-hearted vibe within the darker, weightier core of a story that is, fantasy elements aside, about someone making an end-of-life decision. I hope I got the balance right.</p>
<p><em><strong><span class="im">LSQ: What have you been up to since 2014? Can you tell us about any of your current projects?</span></strong></em></p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<p>Michelle: I’ve been trying, on and off, to write a novel, but so far they’ve all crashed and burned at about 25,000 words. Some day I will break that barrier! But short stories are my main love, and I have just released my second collection, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Possibly-Nefarious-Purposes-Other-Stories-ebook/dp/B07D775DKM"><i>Possibly Nefarious Purposes and Other Stories</i></a>.</p>
<p><em><strong><span class="im">LSQ: Who are some authors you admire and why?</span></strong></em></p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<p>Michelle: Oh God, so many! Sara Gran has written a couple of glorious mysteries about Claire DeWitt, a marvelously strange, unorthodox PI, that I have re-read countless times. Ditto for Tana French’s <em>Dublin Murder Squad</em> series, which also tend to have an element of strangeness that lifts them above standard procedurals. Victoria Schwab writes marvelous fantasy novels (<i>Vicious</i> is one of my favorite books of all time and I am very excited about the sequel coming out this year) and for short stories, I think one of the best has to be Kelly Link. Oh, and Michelle Paver for ghost stories: <i>Dark Matter</i> terrified the absolute life out of me.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 034 Author Interview: Kim Rei and &#8220;Campfire Song&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-034-author-interview-kim-rei-and-campfire-song/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 034]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here we are again, lucky readers, with an author interview from our current issue, Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Here we are again, lucky readers, with an author interview from our current issue, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-034/">Issue 034</a>. Today we had the privilege to chat with Kim Rei about her short story &#8220;Campfire Song.&#8221; Go read the story <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/campfire-songs/">here</a>, then continue below for insight behind Kim&#8217;s words.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/almos-bechtold-645947-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11163 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/almos-bechtold-645947-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>LSQ: This story reveals little about Sura or the world she lives in, other than brief snippets gleaned from her surroundings. What made you decide to present her world this way?</strong></em></div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>Kim: I wanted to throw my readers right into the action. Years ago, I was given great advice about reading. Open a book to any page and read it. Do you care what happens next? If so, dive in! I tried to offer enough insight to catch attention, but keep it vague enough to hold attention. I don&#8217;t like works that spoon-feed me every detail. Let the imagination fill in a bit. &#8220;Campfire Songs&#8221; is a peek out of a train window. You can see some of the landscape, but there&#8217;s a whole world to still explore.</div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Dolls, especially talking dolls, are often used as an element of horror. Here, the doll is a guardian. What gave you the idea for Cathy’s role?</strong></em></div>
</div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>
<div>Kim: I love creepy dolls. I love tales of horror with creepy dolls. I also love the unexpected. When you find a doll in unusual circumstances, you expect it to say something off-kilter. You brace yourself for that moment when you are most certainly going to jump out of your skin. So what if that doesn&#8217;t happen? What if the anticipation shifts to something else? The doll isn&#8217;t the threat, but you know there has to be one. Where is it? What is it? When the scary becomes the safe place, what else is waiting?</div>
</div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Did you have any challenges writing this story? What were they?</strong></em></div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>Kim: This one came pretty smoothly. Not easy! They&#8217;re rarely easy. But the story spilled across the keyboard. My biggest challenge was my wife. She kept demanding more, in that encouraging way spouses have. I heard, &#8220;You can&#8217;t leave it here&#8221; and &#8220;Where&#8217;s the rest?&#8221; Each time she nudged, a little more of the story opened up for me.</div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: At the end, Sura’s future plans are uncertain. What made you choose this ending?<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/annie-spratt-486345-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11164 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/annie-spratt-486345-unsplash-193x300.jpg" alt="" width="193" height="300" /></a></strong></em></div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>Kim: This world has so much potential. I knew I wanted to do more, but I wanted to go beyond Sura. She&#8217;s young and there are events in motion around her that are bigger than she is. She&#8217;s not ready for them yet. But at the end, there&#8217;s a hint that she is becoming ready. She&#8217;s moved beyond her own tale and maybe there&#8217;s more about to happen for her.</div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
</div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>Kim: I am! Like most writers, my WiP file is both invigorating and intimidating. I&#8217;m a squirrel, tucking away ideas and half-formed plots for a long winter. (Except I live in Florida and we don&#8217;t really do winter here.)</div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>I&#8217;m continuing stories in this world, from other points of view (though we&#8217;ll likely see Sura again). The next &#8220;chapter&#8221; has been started. I&#8217;m not entirely sure where it&#8217;s going, but I can promise it will be unexpected! If it all goes the way I hope, one story will play off the next until the entire world is fleshed out.</div>
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>I&#8217;m also working on a fairly beefy trilogy of SFF novels. It has swords and space ships, seedy characters and betrayals. The two main characters are strong women, each with her own path to follow. How those paths collide will span galaxies&#8230; and maybe spin imaginations.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 034 Author Interview: Laine Perez and &#8220;Time and Space&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-034-author-interview-laine-perez-and-time-and-space/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 034]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10587</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dearest readers! It&#8217;s time again for another Issue 034 author interview and for this installment,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dearest readers! It&#8217;s time again for another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-034/">Issue 034</a> author interview and for this installment, we have the privilege of chatting with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/laine-perez/">Laine Perez</a> about her short story &#8220;Time and Space.&#8221; You know the rules: go read the story <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/time-and-space/">here</a>, then fall head over heels into the discussion below. Enjoy!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Mira is quick to dismiss Cy’s suggestion that she made a choice in choosing Cy. Why hasn’t Mira ever thought about trying to change what she sees in her visions? Why does she accept them so readily?</strong></em></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/jr-korpa-765678-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11082 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/jr-korpa-765678-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>Laine: To me, Mira’s reactions to her visions are directly related to the fact that she did not predict or see her mother’s death. If she had and had been able to prevent it, her reactions would likely be very different. As it is, though, not wanting to be blindsided again and fearing loss, she just mostly gives in to what she sees. This does hamper her quite a bit in her ability to form any kind of lasting relationship with anyone. I wanted to leave the possibility open at the end that her relationship with Cy might be different since Cy herself seems unwilling to abandon Mira, but whether or not their relationship will overcome Mira’s self-fulfilling prophecies is up to the way the reader interprets the final section.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Mira meets a lot of interesting girls over the course of the story, yet all eventually leave the facilities. What role or purpose did you intend for these facilities to serve?</strong></em></p>
<p>Laine: Initially, I wanted the facilities to be a place where those who didn’t fit into normal society could be hidden away—or as a place where they could attempt to fix those who didn’t fit. So, the spaces became a way to manage those who are different. This idea comes through mostly in the past sections of the story. As the story progressed, though, I started thinking about how spaces can be retooled and reimagined, serving an entirely different purpose than the one for which they were created. So, as Mira moves through the different facilities, I wanted to show how the facilities became a place capable of creating a community for all these women who were seen as too weird to be part of normal society. I wanted to explore the idea that places can be re-appropriated and reassigned meaning so that something created with a negative purpose can, in the end, serve a positive one.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: How do you envision the rest of the world in this story treating/viewing these girls with “oddities”?</strong></em></p>
<p>Laine: I envisioned the rest of the world as one that is uncomfortable with the girls and, especially, the lack of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/nicole-harrington-580158-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11083 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/nicole-harrington-580158-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>predictability and control over their abilities. So, most people have a strong desire to hide away those with oddities so that they don’t have to encounter them in everyday life. This possibly also results in a desire to “fix” the girls and help them control their oddities mentioned earlier. As time goes on in the story, I think probably people get a little more used to the girls which allows for more movement outside of the facilities.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: How did you develop the idea for these “oddities”?</strong></em></p>
<p>Laine: I was thinking quite a bit about insider and outsider status and about who gets to belong in society and who doesn’t, especially in relation to mental illness. I used the oddities to create women who are, to some degree, defined by a part of themselves that they can’t control. I wanted to explore how some of them built their lives around these qualities while others allowed themselves to be defined by their oddities.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Laine: I’m in the planning stage with a number of different stories right now, all about outsiders of different stripes. The one I’m working on currently is, at least in theme, modeled after <a href="https://public.wsu.edu/~campbelld/amlit/nenun.html">Mary Wilkins Freeman’s “A New England Nun.”</a> I’m interested in the idea of people who choose to be outside societal norms and make their own weird little ways in the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 034 Author Interview: C.L. Spillard and &#8220;Frost&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-034-author-interview-c-l-spillard-and-frost/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 10:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 034]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re here again, dear readers, with another Issue 034 author interview! Below is our chat&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re here again, dear readers, with another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-034/">Issue 034</a> author interview! Below is our chat with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/c-l-spillard/">C.L. Spillard</a> with her story &#8220;Frost,&#8221; which you can read <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/frost/">here</a> before continuing.</p>
<p><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/freestocks-org-505570-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11028 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/freestocks-org-505570-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>LSQ: There is a ton of story packed in just over 500 words. This could easily have been a much longer work. What made you decide to keep it brief?</strong> </em></p>
<p>Candida: I have to admit I really enjoy writing flash! I love the challenge of fitting as much action and imagery into as few words as possible, in much the same way that crossword enthusiasts love to fit the words into their puzzles. In fact I&#8217;m a bit of a fan of cryptic crosswords&#8230;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the hardest part about writing this story and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Candida: The hardest part in this particular story was making sure it was &#8220;relateable&#8221; for as many people as possible. Not everybody has thoughts of Chinese dissidents at the top of their minds right now. I wanted to bring out the continuum from old power structures—the man taking it for granted that the young woman wouldn&#8217;t refuse him— through the more recent past—exiles such as those during the Cultural Revolution—to the present day with its powerful industrial figures. Finally my lifelong interest in the country’s history meant I wanted to show the people&#8217;s courage and ingenuity winning out over injustice as it does in real life, even if sometimes only after much time and at a price.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There&#8217;s mention of a dubious &#8220;Laboratory.&#8221; Is this a place you&#8217;ve written about before or plan to revisit in future stories?</strong></em></p>
<p>Candida: The Laboratory could be any industrial research institute of the sort you may find in China, Russia, or even <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/yuanbin-du-87642-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11029 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/yuanbin-du-87642-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Germany. It&#8217;s not supposed to sound sinister: perhaps it&#8217;s just developing new cleaning products or dyestuffs. The Dissident came up against issues common to nearly all organisations, East and West: cost-cutting paired with the lack of ways to get vital information from the &#8216;floor&#8217; to the top. At the moment that particular place doesn&#8217;t figure in any other of my stories, but now there&#8217;s an idea&#8230;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on</strong></em><strong> othe</strong><strong>r</strong><em><strong> projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Candida: My fantasy novel <em>The Blackmail Engine</em>, set in a future Russia, is presently on the prowl for an agent:</p>
<p>&#8220;A fugitive dissident; a scheming Countess; a city where no night falls&#8230; night huntress Katya can trust no-one as she fights to save the city’s women, and herself, from their fundamentalist Commissar’s scheme. Snowden with a dash of <em>Crime and Punishment</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p>There are details on my website – <a href="http://www.cspillardwriter.co.uk/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.cspillardwriter.co.uk&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1527622019029000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHtcMA69QLgWS1OZuTVLiTACpDcRQ"> www.cspillardwriter.co.uk</a>., which also has a list of free-to-read short stories.</p>
<p>********************************************************</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Price-Time-C-L-Spillard/dp/0956046983/"><em>The Price of Time </em>(UK)</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Price-Time-C-L-Spillard-ebook/dp/B076BQQ995/"><em>The Price of Time </em>(US)</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 034 Author Interview: Sarah Pfleiderer and &#8220;Morph&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-034-author-interview-sarah-pfleiderer-and-morph/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 034]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buckle your seat belts, dear readers, as we head into another interview with an Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Buckle your seat belts, dear readers, as we head into another interview with an <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-034/">Issue 034</a> author. This time we had the privilege to chat with Sarah Pfleiderer about her short story &#8220;Morph.&#8221; You know how this works &#8212; go <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/morph/">read her story</a> now if you haven&#8217;t already and then feast your eyeballs on her thoughts below.</p>
<div><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/bryan-goff-395922-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10777 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/bryan-goff-395922-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>LSQ: It could be argued that Audra&#8217;s ambition to complete her studies jeopardized not only the Phytomorphs but also herself. What does this say about her character? Does this say something about the human race as a whole?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Sarah: I think curiosity is one of the most definable traits of the human race. We’ve gotten to where we are now because of the countless people pushing the realm of possibility and asking questions no one had ever thought to ask before. It’s fair to say Audra could represent that aspect of humanity; that ambitious drive for answers regardless of the possible consequences. As a person, Audra has allowed her work to consume her life, and the idea of having to give all that up because of a potential hiccup is inconceivable. But clearly her insistence to continue with the Phytomorphs brought about the end of her entire life’s work as well as the existence of the creatures she had grown to love.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: On the topic of Ziggy: do you have a clear idea of what the reader should conclude about him? If so, can you say, or do you prefer to leave it more ambiguous and let the reader decide for herself?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Sarah: I was originally inspired by Ray Bradbury’s “<a href="https://cms.springbranchisd.com/Portals/280/Users/195/79/48579/E1006_dark_they_were_and_golden_eyed-4.pdf?ver=2016-08-26-162836-133">Dark They Were, and Golden-Eyed</a>” where a settlement of humans slowly transforms into Martians. I wanted “Morph” to provide an inverse: aliens turning into humans and forgetting their original identity in the process. The human scientists unknowingly contaminate the Phytomorphs during their time together, and in the end, Ziggy became a human with no recollection of who he once was. I’ll let the reader decide what Audra ultimately chooses to do about Ziggy, whether she leaves him on the IGNSS or takes him back with her to Earth.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you a fan of other first contact stories? With such a story line, there&#8217;s some trepidation that the aliens will not be benevolent. What made you design the Phytomorphs as they are?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Sarah: There’s a lot of space for creativity in first contact stories and I’m always curious to see how other writers explore that idea. I wanted the Phytomorphs to be more connected to each other and their planet than humans are to make their transformation more impactful. I wanted to play with the idea of “what if, before we were infected with this ‘human virus,’ we used to be more in tune with our home and each other? What if the reason we’re so obsessed with finding &#8216;the meaning of life&#8217; is because we used to know, but became infected and forgot?” Depicting the Phytomorphs as a more peaceful species also brings attention to our own disconnect.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What do you think our first contact will be like? Is what you think different than what you <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/nasa-89125-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10778 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/nasa-89125-unsplash-300x285.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="285" /></a>hope?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Sarah: It would be nice to believe that humans’ first contact with an intelligent alien life form would be peaceable. But considering the violence with which we treat members of our own species, I suspect that might not be the case.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most enjoyable part about writing this story?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Sarah: I had the most fun writing the reveal at the end. I always enjoy writing the more disturbing scenes; I like finding that sweet spot of horrifying detail without it becoming overpowering. My original concept hinged on the grisly scene of a once docile and interconnected species becoming self-centered and violent. So it was satisfying to finally have all the build-up pay off and get the reader to the place I felt most excited about.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have any new writing projects in the works? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Sarah: I’ve been working on polishing a magical realism piece about ancient spirits living in the Great Lakes. I like experimenting with tropes used in fantasy and faerie stories, particularly the idea of contracts with immortal beings and the trickery used to ensnare unsuspecting humans.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 034 Author Interview: Jenny Wong and &#8220;The Volcano Keeper&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-034-author-interview-jenny-wong-and-the-volcano-keeper/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 034]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 034 author Jenny Wong&#8216;s story, &#8220;The Volcano Keeper,&#8221; is a quiet yet powerful story&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-034/">Issue 034</a> author <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/jenny-wong/">Jenny Wong</a>&#8216;s story, &#8220;The Volcano Keeper,&#8221; is a quiet yet powerful story rooted in nature. Go read her story <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-volcano-keeper/">here</a>, then come back for this enlightening interview.</p>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The setting is vivid, haunting, and desolate. What inspired you to write about a person, once a group of people, living in a volcano?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/clouds-dawn-dusk-923228.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10888 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/clouds-dawn-dusk-923228-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>Jenny: The idea that started it all never actually ended up in the story.  I was mulling over the theme of resurrection, trying to find a different take, when I began toying with the idea of a volcano coming back to life.  One of the first scenes that came to my mind was Ari gathering pine cones at the base of a volcano in winter.  I didn&#8217;t really see any other people with her, so I decided to leave her on her own and explore why that was the case.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Nature takes center stage here. Is there a message you wanted to convey by juxtaposing Mount Panajashi with the encroaching city of Hjarakhil?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jenny: I think, maybe, I wanted to touch on the fact that we don&#8217;t know (or no longer understand or even ignore) all of the impacts that our actions and cities have on the environment.  The story hints that Hjarakhil&#8217;s urban borders could overtake the Ujimi forest and, if the legends were true, might result in Mt. Panajashi&#8217;s awakening.  I didn&#8217;t want Mt. Panajashi to awake with vengeance, but to show that there was a natural balance between the pines and the volcano and that there may, in the future, have to be a re-balancing that might not work so well in Hjarakhil&#8217;s favor.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Not much is revealed about Ari’s character. What sets her apart from the others who left for Hjarakhil? Why are the volcano and forest so important to her?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jenny: As our world&#8217;s population grows, our cities expand into the surrounding areas and there&#8217;s a natural migration of people from rural areas to the cities.  Although, in this case, it&#8217;s taken to the extreme where Ari is the only one left.  Ari has an understanding in the history of her people and the belief that the growth and cultivation of the singing pines are what keeps the volcano from erupting.  I think she might also believe that she is making a difference by protecting the life around her from Mt. Panajashi&#8217;s awakening.  Too often, I find people are lured into a sense of &#8220;it&#8217;ll never happen&#8221;, or &#8220;it&#8217;ll never happen again&#8221; which fuels a disinterest in the world outside of our habitual bubbles.   I didn&#8217;t want Ari to have anything really different or unique about her other than her awareness of the world around <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/albay-clouds-daylight-910597.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10889 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/albay-clouds-daylight-910597-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>her, and I think it&#8217;s that awareness that causes her to act the way she does.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What is your favorite thing about this story and why?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jenny: My favorite part in the story is where Ari extracts the pine seeds by sending the cones down little holes in the volcano. There&#8217;s an existing biological phenomenon (I apologize to any biologists if this explanation is lacking) where some species of pine require heat and fire in order for the cones to open up and release the seeds.  I had a lot of fun imagining how the volcano could be used to mimic that fiery catalyst.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other projects currently? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jenny: There&#8217;s always little short term projects in the back of my mind, like the next poem, the next story, the next chapter in a novel, maybe.  More long term, I&#8217;m working on putting together a collection of poems from my travels which could be a book or a chapbook.  It really hasn&#8217;t decided what it wants to be yet.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 034 Author Interview: Carly Racklin and &#8220;Our Lady of the Wasteland&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-034-author-interview-carly-racklin-and-our-lady-of-the-wasteland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 034]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dearest readers! Let us continue our interviews with our fabulous collection of authors who have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dearest readers! Let us continue our interviews with our fabulous collection of authors who have short stories featured in our current <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-034/">Issue 034</a>! Up next: <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/carly-racklin/">Carly Racklin</a> with her story &#8220;Our Lady of the Wasteland.&#8221; Read it <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/our-lady-of-the-wasteland/">here</a>. Then continue on to her interview below.</p>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: It&#8217;s refreshing to see a bit of uplift in a dystopian story&#8211;we don&#8217;t see that very often. What made you put an angel in the wasteland?</strong></em></div>
<div>
<p>Carly: Thank you! I agree, and that&#8217;s the main reason why I wanted to write this story. Much of the dystopian or post-apocalyptic fiction I&#8217;ve come across has left me feeling more hopeless than when I began, and I don&#8217;t think any story should leave a reader feeling totally powerless like that. And I&#8217;m saying this as a person who loves sad stories, and who writes a lot of them. To me, there&#8217;s a difference between a sad story and a story that leaves readers in despair. Despair is counterproductive. I wanted to put an angel in the wasteland because it&#8217;s important to me that readers see how even in an ugly, cruel world, goodness can still flourish.</p>
</div>
<p><em><strong><span class="im"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/matthieu-joannon-457999-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10722 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/matthieu-joannon-457999-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>LSQ: The grit, dust, the red scarf: the world you built, using few words, is very visual. Did you build this world slowly in your head piece by piece or did it come as a fully formed mental image?</span></strong></em></p>
</div>
<div>Carly: I knew from very early on what I wanted the world of this story to look like. It needed to feel harsh but alive. Most of the visual details were in my head from the start, but it took a little while to get them all down in the right places. I was really inspired by the film <i>Mad Max: Fury Road</i> when conceptualizing this story. It&#8217;s a great example of a post-apocalyptic story that deals with so much beauty and ugliness all at once. It&#8217;s full of color and vibrancy, without sacrificing any of the brutality that would also come with the end of the world.</div>
<p><em><strong><span class="im">LSQ: Let&#8217;s talk a bit more about hope. How important do you think it is to have hope in stories, particularly sci-fi/dystopians? Do you think there needs to be more of it?</span></strong></em></p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Carly: I think it&#8217;s absolutely vital to have hope in a story that deals with such a harrowing subject like the end of the world. Every story needs some hope, even if it&#8217;s just a tiny seed that we never get to see grow. The planting of the seed is enough, in my opinion. Like I said, I love sad stories, but even the saddest stories I write still have glimmers of hope hidden in them somewhere, even if they&#8217;re never realized. I believe that to give into cynicism is the easy solution to a horrible situation, but it&#8217;s braver to cling to hope despite the world&#8217;s cruelty. I want to see more stories that present hope and compassion as things that can save the world.</p>
</div>
<p><em><strong><span class="im">LSQ: What was the hardest part about this story to write?</span></strong></em></p>
</div>
<div>
<p>Carly: For a while I had a difficult time getting an actual plot into this story. From the beginning I knew that I wanted the story to read as a kind of urban legend, a tale being told around a campfire. But in its early drafts, I clung too tightly to the idea of the angel as just a vague, larger-than-life figure. I had to get the reader in the dust storm with the narrator to really give the story the intimacy and impact it needed. It took a couple rewrites and heavy edits, but I think it did get there in the end, and managed to keep the voice I envisioned.</p>
</div>
<p><em><strong><span class="im">LSQ: The two characters, Uzi and the Lady, have very distinct voices. What was it like to build the story around the dialogue of these two characters?</span></strong></em></p>
</div>
<div>Carly: Uzi&#8217;s voice is the backbone of the story, and I had a really clear idea from the beginning of what that voice <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/edoardo-busti-581090-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10723 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/edoardo-busti-581090-unsplash-214x300.jpg" alt="" width="214" height="300" /></a>sounded like. There needed to be a curt feel to her narration, the somewhat inelegant rhythm of someone for which spoken communication has not really been a high priority. I personally pay a lot of attention to the sound of words when I write, so Uzi&#8217;s specific voice was very much a treat to craft, because of the specific lilt to her speech. In contrast, developing the angel&#8217;s voice threw me for a bit of a loop. I worried that she&#8217;d end up sounding corny, but I think the two voices balance each other out nicely in the final product. Seeing and hearing the angel through Uzi&#8217;s very human eyes softens the contrast just enough, I think.</div>
<p><span class="im"><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on another project at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about it?</strong> </em><br />
</span></p>
</div>
<div>Carly: I&#8217;m currently editing another short story, this time in the high fantasy genre. It deals with a wandering knight who&#8217;s been recently stripped of his honor and ostracized from society. He stumbles into a faerie&#8217;s domain, where he&#8217;s confronted about the cowardice driving him away from his home and family. The story grapples with forgiveness, and the pain of becoming someone you swore to never be. It also takes place in the same universe as a novella I&#8217;m working on as well, so I&#8217;m really enjoying tying the two stories together in little ways.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 034 Author Interview: Virginia Mohlere and &#8220;The Thing in the Walls. . . &#8220;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-034-author-interview-virginia-mohlere-and-the-thing-in-the-walls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 034]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re here today with a special interview with Issue 034 author Virginia M. Mohlere about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re here today with a special interview with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-034/">Issue 034</a> author <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/virginia-m-mohlere/">Virginia M. Mohlere</a> about her featured story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-thing-in-the-walls-wants-your-small-change/">The Thing in the Walls Wants Your Small Change</a>.&#8221; Come and join us as we talk dragons and curiosity.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: A tiny dragon and coins! What a fun story. Is this a modern take on the old theme that dragons sit on a pile of gold? Where did the idea for this story come from?</strong></em></p>
<div>Virginia: This story came straight from a cartoon drawn by one of my favorite tumblr artists, iguanamouth:<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/money-515058_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10577 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/money-515058_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="http://iguanamouth.tumblr.com/post/116689536962/can-you-draw-a-tiny-lizard-dragon-that-secretly" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://iguanamouth.tumblr.com/post/116689536962/can-you-draw-a-tiny-lizard-dragon-that-secretly&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1527937989348000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH46iBYMgIUfkqBxZxmorJVCDWS6w">http://iguanamouth.tumblr.com/<wbr />post/116689536962/can-you-<wbr />draw-a-tiny-lizard-dragon-<wbr />that-secretly</a></div>
<div></div>
<div>(Please note: I did get their permission to send this story out for publication.)</div>
<div></div>
<div>Isn&#8217;t that the cutest thing ever? I was completely delighted by the sheer glee of that little dragon in the cartoon. Iguanamouth&#8217;s dragons have enough personality for 16 dimensions. And having lived in several creaky, old, urban apartments, I know what it&#8217;s like to hear Mysterious Noises and to have equally mysterious, impossibly cool neighbors. Though you can bet that if I&#8217;d ever lived in an apartment with a mini-dragon, I would still be living there today, like any sensible person would.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most enjoyable part about this story to write?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Virginia: Definitely the parts where Caro was trying to make friends with the dragon. I thought of it much like trying to make friends with a feral cat, except with small change instead of cat treats.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: To have a dragon be an active protector &#8212; what made you choose to write this creature in such a way?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Virginia: Having the story seed being something so utterly delightful meant that my dragon could never be villainous. But the scene where the dragon came out to protect Caro caught me by surprise &#8211; I had planned that scene differently, but then the dragon turned into a mad kitten, and I laughed my way through writing that part. It was pretty difficult to revise, because I wanted to slow down to get in sufficient detail to get across how hilarious my mental picture of this scene is. I&#8217;m not sure I was wholly successful, but fingers crossed.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: One could easily see a character different than Caro (a character who is not curious, not open-minded) either be scared off from the house or take a more malevolent approach to the scratching at the walls. Is there something behind the notion that her open outlook and acceptance r</strong></em><em><strong>esulted in her protection? Is there a larger theme here?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Virginia: I think curiosity is a trait that most of my characters carry, in part because I myself don&#8217;t know how to be incurious. I&#8217;d SAY that maybe that suggests that I should write an incurious character to stretch my writing muscles, but UGH, how boring. (Might have to do it anyway.) But thanks to Nana&#8217;s spirit pennies and jars of herbs, Caro carries a little bit of the woo-woo around with her. It falls within the scope of her &#8220;normal.&#8221; She&#8217;s also stubborn: she got out, and into a place she loves; she finally has a place that&#8217;s *hers*, a daily life that&#8217;s actively good, so she chooses to greet the scritches and the strangeness with as much of an open mind as she can.</div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10578 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/dragon-1147635_1920-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></div>
<div>Your point that her acceptance is what makes space for her protection is spot on. That&#8217;s part of friendship, right? You make room for a new friend, and when you make that room sufficiently large and safe, they can fill it with the them-ness that gives back to you.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What&#8217;s your f</strong></em><em><strong>avorite dragon in literature and why?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Virginia: Thinking about my answer to this question made me want to write more and weirder dragons. As a little kid, I loved Smaug&#8217;s riddles and arrogance, and I always wanted to know what had caused him to lose that scale. I loved Eustace Scrubb as a dragon, and how it made him learn to be better. When I was older, the lady dragonriders of Pern meant a lot to me, and I desperately wanted a fire lizard of my own. Barbara Hambly&#8217;s Morkeleb the Black was so appealing that when spoiler spoiler at the end of <em>Dragonsbane</em> (can you spoil a book that old?), I threw the book across the room and refused to read any more Hambly for years, which was really only punishing myself.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you currently working on other writing projects? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
<div>Virginia: I&#8217;m currently working on a short (I hope) story about a witch with an overdeveloped sense of responsibility who&#8217;s deeply ticked off with her ex-boyfriend, and a novella about a young swordswoman who needs to dial back her revenge fantasies. I recently finished a novel, which of course means that I&#8217;m mostly lying under the coffee table shouting that it&#8217;s horrible instead of what I&#8217;m supposed to be doing, which is querying it.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 034 Release and Cover Artist Interview: Lâle Favre</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-034-release-and-cover-artist-interview-lale-favre/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 11:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 034]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s HERE!!!!! Issue 034 is now out, available online and in print &#8212; get your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_10462" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10462" style="width: 192px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/034cover-med.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-10462 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/034cover-med-192x300.jpg" alt="" width="192" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10462" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Fancy Meerkat Portrait&#8221; by Lâle Favre, LSQ Issue 034 cover</figcaption></figure>
<p>It&#8217;s HERE!!!!! <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-034/">Issue 034 is now out</a>, available online and in print &#8212; get your copy today and dive into eight fascinating speculative fiction short stories by female authors! <em>AND</em> while you&#8217;re at it, take a moment to lose yourself in the incredible cover: &#8220;Fancy Meerkat Portrait&#8221; by <a href="http://laleann.daportfolio.com/">Lâle Favre</a>. It is divine. We were lucky enough to chat with Lâle recently about her art. Read what she has to say below!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Please tell us about Issue 034&#8217;s cover art, &#8220;Fancy Meerkat Portrait.&#8221; Who is this character? Does she have a story? What inspired you to create this? What was the hardest part about creating this piece?</strong></em></p>
<p>Lâle: It was more of a personal exercise than an original character. It is based on a Sargent painting, a young woman&#8217;s portrait in a dress. I just turned the study into something more fun and changed the woman into a meerkat.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The bio on your website states you specialize in character design. What do you hope to capture in the characters you create? What are your favorite characters to create and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Lâle: I&#8217;ve always loved stories and I grew up surrounded by comics and fantasy books. Storytelling is still what I consider the most inspiring and important thing in art. I think the best characters are the ones designed in a way that gives enough information for you to have a good idea of who they are and what their personality is. We need to be able to guess what their background and their motivation is. For the past year, I&#8217;ve gone through a lot of different stages in my artistic growth, and I realized, recently, that storytelling was missing. The very same thing I loved to see in others&#8217; work was never in mine. My images seemed dull and weren&#8217;t engaging. So I started focusing more on adding that extra touch of story to my images. I think and prepare more before I start something new and make sure I know who the characters I&#8217;m depicting are and what is going on in the scene. As a friend advised me, most good stories in illustrations are the ones answering one of these two questions:</p>
<ol>
<li>What is just about to happen?</li>
<li>What has just happened?</li>
</ol>
<figure id="attachment_10512" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10512" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/JungleLadyWeb.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image wp-image-10512 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/JungleLadyWeb-300x209.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="209" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10512" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Panthers&#8217; Mistress&#8221; by Lâle Favre</figcaption></figure>
<p>This creates expectation, tension, or relief. I feel like it is something that is a little lost in the sea of digital art nowadays. We have many amazingly skilled artists in this community but I feel like most images I see, as beautiful as they may be, don&#8217;t tell much of a story. I sometimes compare it to blockbusters: there is a lot of action, explosions, light, and special effects . . . but there&#8217;s not much actually going on. My favorite characters to create are usually strong, evil, or fierce women. Warriors or half creatures. I love mermaids for that same reason and used to draw them so often. But I am now trying to push myself out of my comfort zone with each new piece, adding more males and different types of characters in my work.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Can you describe your creative process? How do you start, how long does a piece take from start to finish? How do you know when you&#8217;re finished? </strong></em></p>
<p>Lâle: I usually start with a few thumbnails and sketches. Then, I pick one I&#8217;m happy with and start refining it. I like to have a clear sketch before I start laying down flat colors and then paint over. Usually from dark to light. When it comes to the length, it depends completely on the kind of topic, level of details, etc., but anywhere from a day up to two weeks! I know I am finished with a piece when I&#8217;m able to look at it and imagine showing it to other people without cringing (too much).</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Can you tell us a bit about your background &#8212; experience, education, how you got started? </strong></em></p>
<p>Lâle: I was born in Switzerland and grew up surrounded with my crazy dad&#8217;s Disney figurine collection, which he started when I was about 7. New Disney and Pixar movies were sacred too and we&#8217;d always go and watch them as a family. I&#8217;m now 28 and my dad&#8217;s collection is approximately 12,000 strong ! And I think I&#8217;m infected with the same taste for pretty toys . . . I&#8217;ve always loved drawing and spent most of my time doing just that. But high school made me forget about that passion and I went full circle before going back into art. In Switzerland, illustration is little to not known at all. And, back when I was 20, I had no clue what to call the career I wanted to pursue. The closest career path to illustration there is graphic design. Which, I learned later on, had pretty much nothing to do with being an illustrator.</p>
<p>After high school, my plan was to become an art history and French teacher. Fortunately, I lived in Manhattan, NY, for half a year, and my love of art came back roaring. Next to my English classes, I got the opportunity to take photography and art classes, where I&#8217;d draw and paint a few times a week. That was the time I first started using Photoshop, got my first tablet and started listening to <a href="https://www.imaginismstudios.com/bobby-chiu">Bobby Chiu</a>&#8216;s livestreams (who now runs the famous <a href="https://www.schoolism.com/">Schoolism</a>). When I came back to Switzerland, I started working as a freelance photographer. I liked it but, later on, realized the only times I picked up my camera was when I would be making money with it. Whereas I would never spend a day without drawing.</p>
<figure id="attachment_10513" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10513" style="width: 212px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/CommanderBertha.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image wp-image-10513 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/CommanderBertha-212x300.jpg" alt="" width="212" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-10513" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Commander Bertha&#8221; by Lâle Favre</figcaption></figure>
<p>After that, I entered an art school (in Switzerland) and went there for about a year. I was 23 then. Unfortunately, it was a private school, very expensive and far away from home. I even spent 8 months living with nuns who rented cheap rooms, so I wouldn&#8217;t have to travel for five hours every day! The school was also quite lame, to be honest. The teaching was terrible and I felt intellectually and artistically frustrated, constrained. I didn&#8217;t feel like I was learning much and I was surrounded by teenagers who had no drive whatsoever. It wasn&#8217;t a place to grow.</p>
<p>So I left. And I started over. I tried to freelance and worked on the side as a hostess/waitress for fancy events while trying to get better at art. I was slow at it and had a hard time focusing properly on my own. The artistic community was also pretty much non-existent as well, so it was hard for me to live there and feel inspired. I had very few friends and people I could relate to. I didn&#8217;t feel like I belonged. And finally, in 2017, I moved to Berlin. Since then, I&#8217;ve been much more productive, happier, and I realize how important it is for me to be surrounded by like-minded people, artists who try and work hard and who I can be inspired by and rely on. The jump was scary and I postponed it for years. But it was the best decision I&#8217;ve ever made.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any ways in which you&#8217;ve changed as an artist over the years? </strong></em></p>
<p>Lâle: I probably answered this question a bit above. But yes, of course I&#8217;ve changed. Like every human, I&#8217;m never going to be a finished  product, but a forever ongoing process. It&#8217;s hard to describe how but I guess I was very dissipated in terms of my artistic and professional goals before. I didn&#8217;t know what to focus on or what I wanted to say or do with my work. I felt very stressed and pressured about it as well. And lately&#8211;this past year especially&#8211;I&#8217;ve been dedicating a lot of time thinking about and discussing my doubts and feelings in that regard, and the answers started coming up. I felt like I found one key after another, slowly unlocking many locks inside of me. I&#8217;ve slowly started to experience a freer side of my creativity. I am still searching and trying (and failing!), but I feel more at peace when it comes to what I draw or paint. There&#8217;s less pressure and I feel like I&#8217;m slowly narrowing down my path to what really matters to me, what I truly love to do, instead of what I think others expect of me. It&#8217;s still a struggle but my friends and my partner have helped me tremendously in reconnecting with that side of mine.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What would you like to do that you haven&#8217;t done yet artistically? Can you tell us about any upcoming projects you have, or your plans and aspirations for the future? </strong></em></p>
<p>Lâle: I&#8217;d like to attend an art convention as a speaker some day. I&#8217;ve spent an important amount of time on stage when I was younger and I feel comfortable in front of a crowd (but I can&#8217;t make phone calls to strangers, ironically!). Maybe teach as well. But for now I&#8217;m mainly focusing on improving and am still struggling to get client work to be honest. Gotta keep trying!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Among all your pieces, do you have a favorite? If so, which is it and why? If no, why not?</strong></em></p>
<p>Lâle: Lately I&#8217;ve been doing this short character design series and I&#8217;m having a lot of fun with it. They&#8217;re the only pieces I can look at without cringing too much. But otherwise, no <em>favorites</em>, no, simply because I always end up hating what I do! Sounds bad but don&#8217;t get me wrong, I love doing it!&#8230;Most of the time! Haha!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
