<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 13:31:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>We&#8217;ve got a fresh herd of stories for you to enjoy!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/weve-got-a-fresh-herd-of-stories-for-you-to-enjoy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=29643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Can you hear their thundering hooves? Have you caught a glimpse of a long, spiral&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Can you hear their thundering hooves? Have you caught a glimpse of a long, spiral horn? If you have, you may have figured out that our December issue has a very powerful theme: Horses!</p>
<p>Horses loom large in our collective histories. Symbols of power, of strength, companions on a long journey, heroes, magical creatures, etc. they’re woven through the fabric of our tales.</p>
<p>All this love of horses is pouring out here and now, the obvious inspiration for this year’s theme. There’s such a wild and varied selection of stories in this issue, tales full of magic and mayhem, court intrigues and cybernetic mounts. And of course, a few unicorns for good measure. It’s nothing less than you might expect from a stories centered on a creature with such presence in the tales we’ve told around a fire for millennia. We hope you enjoy the ride.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-056/">Read the issue now!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 055 is live and ready for you to enjoy!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-055-is-live-and-ready-for-you-to-enjoy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 12:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=29499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While we&#8217;re waiting here for autumn to arrive, there&#8217;s still a bit of time to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While we&#8217;re waiting here for autumn to arrive, there&#8217;s still a bit of time to settle into a comfortable chair in the sun for some reading. Might we suggest this latest fabulous issue of LSQ to keep you company?</p>
<p>Before you dig into the issue, however, we&#8217;d like to share and interview with the artist who created the beautiful, autumnal-tinted artwork that graces our cover.</p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;"><b><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium" src="https://harkale.art/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/diva_fun_colours_internet.jpg" width="1800" height="1260" />Please tell us about the cover image, “Warm Embrace&#8221;. Is there a story behind this image? What was your thought process while creating this image?</b></span></p>
<p>“Warm Embrace” is one of the few personal pieces I’ve been able to work on in the past few years, in between client work. While creating art for other people, giving life to their ideas is great in its own way and often allows me to explore new ground, painting for myself means I get to put a lot of the things I love into an image. Warmth and love, big yummy abstract brushstrokes, a quiet scene, kindness, colours that aren’t what they seem (the green dress is actually a greyish orange, colours are fun!) and dramatic lighting,… Like a warm cup of tea for the soul <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> I needed that at the moment.</p>
<p>And the cool thing about art is that it resonates with other people even if they don’t see the same things in it, so I was actually brewing a big pot of tea for the entire village. For instance I pictured these two women as a couple, but other people told me they read them as a mother and daughter, making them think about the love they feel for their own mothers or daughters, and that’s very valid too.</p>
<p><b>Take us briefly through your artistic process. How do you create such captivating images?</b></p>
<p>Usually, my paintings are commissions, painted for books, games,… that require a strict process where I explore different options in sketches, send a few of these sketches to the client, and after listening to their feedback refine one of these sketches into the painting itself. Most paintings on my website <a href="https://harkale.art/">harkale.art</a> fall into that category.<img decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium" src="https://harkale.art/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/painting_internet.jpg" width="1412" height="2000" /></p>
<p>But when I create a painting entirely for myself the process is much looser, I start with a vague idea or a source of inspiration (which can be anything, from a specific colour palette, a feeling, a pretty tree I saw while hiking, a character I want to make fanart of,…) and then I go from there. I paint and move things around and erase details, it’s a messy process and certainly isn’t time-efficient, but it feels great!</p>
<p><b>When did you realize you wanted to focus on fantasy in your art? Did you start out as a fantasy artist, or have you noticed changes over time? Please tell us a bit about your art journey!</b></p>
<p>I began my art journey by enthusiastically redecorating my bedroom walls (and floor), like most toddlers do when you leave them unattended with a box of crayons for even a few minutes. My two main critics back then weren’t happy about it. Growing up, bandes dessinées (European comic books, in particular Yoko Tsuno and Thorgal, respectively drawn by the badass Roger Leloup and Grzegorz Rosiński) were a huge source of inspiration for me. I was hoping to become a comic artist, but then life (and serious studies) got in the way.</p>
<p>It took me years to realise how much I loved painting, not just drawing. Playing with colours and lights and edges and my beloved brushstrokes. I was already a Very Respectable Adult when I rekindled my love for illustration, and since I’m such a big fantasy and sci-fi nerd my art naturally gravitated towards things that made me happy. And then people hired me to paint more fantasy art, which I’m never going to complain about.</p>
<p>My style evolved over time and it certainly will evolve further in the future, but I suspect I’ll always like fantasy!</p>
<p><b>Do you have a personal favorite of the projects you’ve worked on? Or one that was memorable due to its challenges? If so, can you tell us a bit about it?</b></p>
<p>Yes, “Grave to Cradle”. It was painted for a private client but I had a lot of freedom with that piece, and it ended up also being an homage to someone I was very close to, who passed away. The subject (skeleton contemplating flowers in their hand) isn’t that rare in fantasy art, but it’s the emotions I poured <b style="color: #333333;"><img decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium" src="https://harkale.art/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/skeleton_internet.jpg" width="2000" height="1500" /></b><span style="color: #333333;">into this piece that makes it so special to me. To me, this piece is about loss and hope, planting the seeds for beautiful things to grow even after you’ve died, no matter how far from perfection you think you are. And finding beauty outside even after the death of someone you were close to turned your world into a grey wasteland.</span></p>
<p>Of course other people see what resonates best with them in that painting, they’re welcome to. On a more light-hearted note, I’m proud of contrasting high-chroma blue with desaturated greens in the background, it’s so pretty!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Today&#8217;s the last day to submit applications!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/todays-the-last-day-to-submit-applications/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/todays-the-last-day-to-submit-applications/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 12:58:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=29381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Would you like to read for LSQ? We have openings for new editors. Proofreading skills&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Would you like to read for LSQ? We have openings for new editors. Proofreading skills and good instincts about stories are required, experience is not. Come help us choose the stories to share with our readers!</p>
<p>Our volunteer Editors read through the submitted stories, commenting on each one they read and voting for the ones they consider the best for that issue. Once stories are chosen, editors proofread the final choices before publication.<br />
While a simple job description, this is the core of what makes LSQ run, its individual issues and the stories within are the foundation upon which the whole of LSQ is built.</p>
<p>First time editors welcome. All positions are volunteer. We seek diverse applicants.</p>
<p>Find out more <a href="https://forms.gle/THh5NqkPN5pcDENG9" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">on our application</a>.</p>
<p>Applications close on <strong>TODAY</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/todays-the-last-day-to-submit-applications/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We&#8217;re looking for a few good editors&#8230;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/were-looking-for-a-few-good-editors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 14:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=29359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Would you like to read for LSQ? We have openings for new editors. Proofreading skills&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div data-slate-node="element"><span data-slate-node="text">Would you like to read for LSQ? We have openings for new editors. Proofreading skills and good instincts about stories are required, experience is not. Come help us choose the stories to share with our readers!</span></div>
<div data-slate-node="element">Our volunteer Editors read through the submitted stories, commenting on each one they read and voting for the ones they consider the best for that issue. Once stories are chosen, editors proofread the final choices before publication.<br />
While a simple job description, this is the core of what makes LSQ run, its individual issues and the stories within are the foundation upon which the whole of LSQ is built.</div>
<div data-slate-node="element">First time editors welcome. All positions are volunteer. We seek diverse applicants.</div>
<div data-slate-node="element" data-slate-fragment="JTVCJTdCJTIydHlwZSUyMiUzQSUyMnAlMjIlMkMlMjJjaGlsZHJlbiUyMiUzQSU1QiU3QiUyMnRleHQlMjIlM0ElMjJXb3VsZCUyMHlvdSUyMGxpa2UlMjB0byUyMHJlYWQlMjBmb3IlMjBMU1ElM0YlMjBXZSdyZSUyMGxvb2tpbmclMjBmb3IlMjBhJTIwZmV3JTIwdm9sdW50ZWVyJTIwZWRpdG9ycyElMjBQcm9vZnJlYWRpbmclMjBza2lsbHMlMjBhbmQlMjBnb29kJTIwaW5zdGluY3RzJTIwYWJvdXQlMjBzdG9yaWVzJTIwYXJlJTIwcmVxdWlyZWQlMkMlMjBleHBlcmllbmNlJTIwaXMlMjBub3QuJTIwQ29tZSUyMGhlbHAlMjB1cyUyMGNob29zZSUyMHRoZSUyMHN0b3JpZXMlMjB0byUyMHNoYXJlJTIwd2l0aCUyMG91ciUyMHJlYWRlcnMhJTIwJTIyJTdEJTVEJTdEJTJDJTdCJTIydHlwZSUyMiUzQSUyMnAlMjIlMkMlMjJjaGlsZHJlbiUyMiUzQSU1QiU3QiUyMnRleHQlMjIlM0ElMjIlMjIlN0QlMkMlN0IlMjJ0eXBlJTIyJTNBJTIyYSUyMiUyQyUyMnVybCUyMiUzQSUyMmh0dHBzJTNBJTJGJTJGZm9ybXMuZ2xlJTJGVEhoNU5xa1BONXBjREVORzklMjIlMkMlMjJjaGlsZHJlbiUyMiUzQSU1QiU3QiUyMnRleHQlMjIlM0ElMjJodHRwcyUzQSUyRiUyRmZvcm1zLmdsZSUyRlRIaDVOcWtQTjVwY0RFTkc5JTIyJTdEJTVEJTdEJTJDJTdCJTIydGV4dCUyMiUzQSUyMiUyMiU3RCU1RCU3RCU1RA==">Find out more <a href="https://forms.gle/THh5NqkPN5pcDENG9">on our application</a>.</div>
<div data-slate-node="element" data-slate-fragment="JTVCJTdCJTIydHlwZSUyMiUzQSUyMnAlMjIlMkMlMjJjaGlsZHJlbiUyMiUzQSU1QiU3QiUyMnRleHQlMjIlM0ElMjJXb3VsZCUyMHlvdSUyMGxpa2UlMjB0byUyMHJlYWQlMjBmb3IlMjBMU1ElM0YlMjBXZSdyZSUyMGxvb2tpbmclMjBmb3IlMjBhJTIwZmV3JTIwdm9sdW50ZWVyJTIwZWRpdG9ycyElMjBQcm9vZnJlYWRpbmclMjBza2lsbHMlMjBhbmQlMjBnb29kJTIwaW5zdGluY3RzJTIwYWJvdXQlMjBzdG9yaWVzJTIwYXJlJTIwcmVxdWlyZWQlMkMlMjBleHBlcmllbmNlJTIwaXMlMjBub3QuJTIwQ29tZSUyMGhlbHAlMjB1cyUyMGNob29zZSUyMHRoZSUyMHN0b3JpZXMlMjB0byUyMHNoYXJlJTIwd2l0aCUyMG91ciUyMHJlYWRlcnMhJTIwJTIyJTdEJTVEJTdEJTJDJTdCJTIydHlwZSUyMiUzQSUyMnAlMjIlMkMlMjJjaGlsZHJlbiUyMiUzQSU1QiU3QiUyMnRleHQlMjIlM0ElMjIlMjIlN0QlMkMlN0IlMjJ0eXBlJTIyJTNBJTIyYSUyMiUyQyUyMnVybCUyMiUzQSUyMmh0dHBzJTNBJTJGJTJGZm9ybXMuZ2xlJTJGVEhoNU5xa1BONXBjREVORzklMjIlMkMlMjJjaGlsZHJlbiUyMiUzQSU1QiU3QiUyMnRleHQlMjIlM0ElMjJodHRwcyUzQSUyRiUyRmZvcm1zLmdsZSUyRlRIaDVOcWtQTjVwY0RFTkc5JTIyJTdEJTVEJTdEJTJDJTdCJTIydGV4dCUyMiUzQSUyMiUyMiU3RCU1RCU3RCU1RA==">Applications close on <strong>June 30th</strong>.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Submissions are now open!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/submissions-are-now-open/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=29356</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do you hear the hoofbeats? Do you feel the soft muzzle? Do you see the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="public-DraftStyleDefault-block public-DraftStyleDefault-ltr" data-offset-key="6u5kl-0-0"><span data-offset-key="6u5kl-0-0">Do you hear the hoofbeats? Do you feel the soft muzzle? Do you see the beautiful mane? We’re talking about HORSES, of course.</span></div>
<div data-offset-key="6u5kl-0-0"></div>
<div class="public-DraftStyleDefault-block public-DraftStyleDefault-ltr" data-offset-key="6u5kl-0-0">For this year’s themed issue, we’re looking exclusively for stories featuring horses, filtered through the lens of Luna Station’s mission, of featuring female-fronted speculative stories. As always, we encourage you to dig deep, to go beyond the obvious. Set your horse-related stories somewhere unique in time or space, give it a unique twist, surprise and delight us!</div>
<div data-offset-key="6u5kl-0-0"></div>
<div class="public-DraftStyleDefault-block public-DraftStyleDefault-ltr" data-offset-key="6u5kl-0-0">As usual, all of our normal submission guidelines apply, just with a bit more hooves this time!</div>
<div data-offset-key="6u5kl-0-0"></div>
<div data-offset-key="6u5kl-0-0">Find out more on <a href="https://submissions.lunastationpress.com/">our new submissions site</a>.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 054 is now live!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-054-is-now-live/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 05:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=29316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 054 is not your usual issue of LSQ. As our Creative Director Tara Lindsey&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-054/">Issue 054</a> is not your usual issue of LSQ. As our Creative Director Tara Lindsey so succinctly described it, this is beach reading for strange people. I hope that description intrigued you as much as it amused me, because that&#8217;s a perfect description as possible for this issue.</p>
<p>We are once again lucky enough to have a beautiful piece of art gracing the cover of the issue. This time it’s the work of <a href="https://indicreates.com/">Indicreates</a>, who shares a bit below about the piece on our cover as well as some insights into her process.</p>
<p><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-29320" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-scales-and-wings-copy-300x215.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="215" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-scales-and-wings-copy-300x215.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-scales-and-wings-copy-1024x732.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-scales-and-wings-copy-768x549.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-scales-and-wings-copy-1536x1098.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-scales-and-wings-copy.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Please tell us about the cover image, “A Kind Face&#8221;. Is there a story behind this image? What was your thought process while creating this image?</em></p>
<p>I drew this illustration while going trough hard times, it was a symbol to myself to be kinder with myself. I printed it out so I’d remember it every time I look at it.</p>
<p>I’ve chosen green colors and flowers as both are calming to me.</p>
<p><em>Take us briefly through your artistic process. How do you create such captivating images?</em></p>
<p>I like to start with rough sketches, do research, listen to music that fits the art I’m going for and build my paintings from there.</p>
<p>At times I daydream and come up with ideas that way.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-29321" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-on-top-of-the-world-ptreon-1024x471.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="336" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-on-top-of-the-world-ptreon-1024x471.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-on-top-of-the-world-ptreon-300x138.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-on-top-of-the-world-ptreon-768x353.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-on-top-of-the-world-ptreon-1536x706.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/indi-creates-on-top-of-the-world-ptreon.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /></p>
<p><em>When did you realize you wanted to focus on fantasy in your art? Did you start out as a fantasy artist, or have you noticed changes over time? Please tell us a bit about your art journey!</em></p>
<p>I decided to focus on fantasy art in university, I realized I had most fun painting elves and fantasy worlds and that I have a deep love for worlds that feel different.</p>
<p>My love for fantasy started early, I already dreamed of other worlds as a kid and after many years of trying different things and building my skills I went back to my core in a way.</p>
<p>In my art I try to recreate the feeling of discovering new worlds.</p>
<p><em>Do you have a personal favorite of the projects you’ve worked on? Or one that was memorable due to its challenges? If so, can you tell us a bit about it?</em></p>
<p>My personal art that is based on my childhood fantasies mean a lot to me, sadly I don’t have too much time for these pieces but I try my best to paint a bit from that world whenever I can.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We&#8217;ve got a new way for you to submit your stories!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/weve-got-a-new-way-for-you-to-submit-your-stories/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 14:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=29241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello everyone! I&#8217;m here to get you up to speed on some behind the scenes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone!</p>
<p>I&#8217;m here to get you up to speed on some behind the scenes work that has been going on here at LSQ HQ (i.e. my house). We&#8217;ve decided not to continue our contract with Submittable at this time. The cost for an operation our size is simply far too high and we would rather make use of our generous <a href="https://www.patreon.com/lunastation">Patreon</a> supporter&#8217;s funds elsewhere (more on that to come in future announcements).</p>
<p>If we&#8217;re no longer using Submittable, then how will authors submit their stories? Well, I&#8217;ve built a new submissions manager, customized for LSQ. <a href="https://submissions.lunastationpress.com/">You can find it here</a>. It works quite simply. Fill out the form, paste your story into the box, and hit the submit button, after reading our submission guidelines, of course.</p>
<p>Other than where you&#8217;re submitting your stories, there&#8217;s really no other changes to our process. Our deadlines remain the same, our editors will still read all your submissions, and we&#8217;ll continue to publish the wonderful women-identified writers that come through our door.</p>
<p>If you have any questions, please feel free to use our contact form and I&#8217;ll get back to you ASAP.</p>
<p>Thank you all for your support!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 053 Release!!! Meet cover artist Olivia Hintz!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-053-release-meet-cover-artist-olivia-hintz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 12:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=29194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello dear readers and welcome to the fourteenth year of Luna Station Quarterly! Issue 053&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello dear readers and welcome to the fourteenth year of Luna Station Quarterly! <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-053/">Issue 053</a> is going to kick this year off right with 16 stories by 16 awesome authors. Some are familiar faces to you regular readers out there, along with a bunch of new voices for you all to enjoy.</p>
<p>We are once again lucky enough to have a beautiful piece of art gracing the cover of the issue. This time it&#8217;s the work of <a href="https://www.oliviahintz.com/">Olivia Hintz</a>, who shares a bit below about the piece on our cover as well as some insights into her process.</p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;"><b>Please tell us about the cover image, &#8220;The Prophet&#8221;. Is there a story behind this image? What was your thought process while creating this image?</b></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">The character depicted in The Prophet is a generic depiction of a prophet level priestess from a story I am writing. In my story the Temple studies travel between planes. The spatial distortion emanating from her head and the coins she wears are unique to these priestesses. Coins have historically been used as both a symbol of travel and in some mythologies as payment to cross certain mythological rivers etc. Since the Temple’s main theme is “travel”, the priestesses use coins as symbols of status rather than bartering. In short, the priestesses run a temple where certain gifted beings can travel between planes. The adornment of these coins represent levels of superiority/status. A lower level initiate would have only a few coins worn in their hair or as earrings. Prophets are recognized as high-mid level in the Temple’s system. Can you imagine how many coins the leaders have? It’s an ostentatious, ridiculous amount.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/59c05896cd39c3d49bffe7a4/1672692308110-D9GMBSI1H33BJ19N3S3H/image-asset.png" alt="The Prophet artwork by Olivia Hintz" width="1930" height="2474" />Most, if not all, of my work, derives from storytelling. When I visualize an illustration as part of a larger story, I can better decide what attributes, items, etc., the character should have and the emotional reaction I want to evoke.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">I am also a sucker for world-building. While I love painting faces most, some of my favorite illustrations are of plants, stone and other natural elements that bring a world to life. With The Prophet, I decided her surroundings should depict one of the planes I have built in my (hopefully) one-day-fully-realized graphic novel.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;"><b>Take us briefly through your artistic process. How do you create such captivating images?</b></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">I am still learning what I enjoy and what works for me. With The Prophet, I didn&#8217;t start with a sketch as I most definitely should have. Instead, I gathered some inspirational images and went straight to painting. Luckily, the structure did not change much. Sometimes this process works and sometimes the painting ends up in the &#8220;Hazard: Work In Progress&#8221; folder for eternity.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">The one thing I always do is gather references. It was such a taboo in art school. I&#8217;m glad artists are starting to push the notion that it&#8217;s necessary and welcomed. Using references is smart and efficient—no one should feel guilty looking up a 13th-century arbalest.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;"><b>When did you realize you wanted to focus on fantasy in your art? Did you start out as a fantasy artist, or have you noticed changes over time? Please tell us a bit about your art journey!</b></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">I have always been a fantasy nerd. Lord of the Rings, Magic the Gathering, Dungeons and Dragons, etc.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">Growing up, I never thought of fantasy art as a career. Fortunately, I had the opportunity to attend art school and supportive parents, who had no idea what an art career entails besides hustling paintings and eating from cans. They were great, though, and I&#8217;m super appreciative of my folks. I know a lot of artist friends whose parents refuse to support their creative path, so I count myself extremely lucky.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">My main goal was to be a graphic novelist, taking inspiration from the Japanese comic market and Rumiko Takahashi&#8217;s works like Ranma 1/2 and Inuyasha. Though, going to a school for fine art was probably not the best choice for a comic artist. I spent a few years after art school working various jobs to support myself, barely touching art again until I found Critical Role, a Dungeons and Dragons twitch stream. It was a gateway into the fantasy community, inspiring fan art and forcing me to learn digital painting. After investing in Smarterartschool and Swatches digital art courses, I’m at the point of freshly breaking into the industry.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;"><b>Do you have a personal favorite of the projects you&#8217;ve worked on? Or one that was memorable due to its challenges? If so, can you tell us a bit about it?</b></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">Every piece in my portfolio had its ups and downs. I don&#8217;t have a favorite, but several pieces changed how I draw and think about art.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">The first piece is called An Earthly Encounter: Harrowing Sentinel. It was a challenge issued by MTG artist Clint Cearley on his YouTube channel &#8220;Swatches.&#8221; Getting feedback from a professional at the time was incredible. My artwork jumped from a wavering understanding of digital painting to another level. I&#8217;ll forever be appreciative of the help I got from him.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium" style="color: #141414;" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/59c05896cd39c3d49bffe7a4/1639357725476-45T6N12X2TQAJHTKYJQK/20210115_093231.jpg" alt="An Earthly Encounter artwork by Olivia Hintz" width="2500" height="1837" /></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">The piece Lava River, with guidance from Donato Giancola, furthered my art into a deeper understanding of composition and reference gathering. I started taking more time to develop how a piece works and what I want it to look like when finished.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #141414;">The last piece I feel similarly about is a current work. Unfortunately, I cannot show it. But it will be out in a few months! It&#8217;s a multi-figure piece with horses and a castle depicting King Arthur and his knights on the way out of Camelot. It&#8217;s the most challenging illustration I&#8217;ve worked on yet. Greg Manchess and Scott Fischer gave me some invaluable advice with this piece, and I&#8217;m very excited to share it in the Arthurian Zine it&#8217;s a part of!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s alive!!!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/its-alive/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 14:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The print and kindle editions of our December issue are live at last! We&#8217;ve waded&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/1949077381">print</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0BNJFJ65D">kindle</a> editions of our December issue are live at last! We&#8217;ve waded through the hellfire of our POD publishing system and emerged victorious.</p>
<p>Our armor is a little singed, but it was WORTH IT!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LSQ Monthly News Flash: September 2022</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-monthly-news-flash-september-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 18:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome the the third quarter of Year 13! Here are all the things we’re up&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-14605" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/maxresdefault-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/maxresdefault-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/maxresdefault-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/maxresdefault-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/maxresdefault.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<div class="entry-content">
<p>Welcome the the third quarter of Year 13! Here are all the things we’re up to this month:</p>
<ul>
<li>We just released <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a>! Loaded up with 15 stories by emerging women authors, and sporting a truly gorgeous cover, this issue is sure to satisfy all your reading desires.</li>
<li>We’re looking for some new columns to add to our blog! If you, or someone you know, have a particular topic you’re passionate about and want to get the word out there, we’d love to add you to the blogging team! Check out <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSenqtyt_QlBVqK9yZKE49GjQtuq42WZ5H6PIRVkiVAVYynrQQ/viewform">the application</a> for more details.</li>
<li>Our next <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/submissions/">submission</a> window opens <strong>September 15</strong>. Start polishing those stories!</li>
<li>There’s even more LSQ fun to be had on our <a href="https://www.patreon.com/lunastation">Patreon</a>, from behind-the-scenes production to fun tidbits shared by our EIC. All pledges go right back into the quarterly and help us pay our authors!</li>
<li>If you just can’t get enough LSQ, be sure to check out our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-best-of-lsq-the-first-five-years/"><em>Best of LSQ: The First Five Years</em></a> anthology. It comes in print AND digital, and it’s packed with 50 of our best stories from Years 1-5.</li>
</ul>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
