<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 029 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-029/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:54:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cover Artist Interview: Priscilla Kim</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/cover-artist-interview-priscilla-kim/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 16:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 029]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today we&#8217;re featuring an interview with the artist who illustrated the lovely cover of Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8354 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/FFG_SabinesArmor_web-300x244.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="244" />Today we&#8217;re featuring an interview with the artist who illustrated the lovely cover of Issue 029, the very talented Priscilla Kim! </em></p>
<p><strong>Please tell us a bit about yourself and your work.</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m a genre illustrator who currently works primarily in RPGs and books. My style is largely centered around fantasy realism, and I tend to focus on portraits and heroines with a narrative element, although I&#8217;m also exploring some side paths here and there.</p>
<p><strong>What got you on the path to being an illustrator? Was there a defining moment that made you decide to make art your career?</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;d drawn pretty consistently all through high school, but elected not to go to school for art, due to uncertainties about my own capabilities and desires. I didn&#8217;t decide to actually go for it until maybe <span class="aBn" tabindex="0" data-term="goog_1660717529"><span class="aQJ">ten years later</span></span>, but it was more of a slowly-rising tide that eventually crested in taking a SmART School online mentorship with Dan Dos Santos, which finally tipped me over the edge into thinking I could do it full-time. (Admittedly, being laid off a few months later also helped.)</p>
<p><strong>The cover of Issue 029 has gotten great feedback. What was the inspiration for Fin&#8217;Amor?</strong></p>
<p>It was actually initially done as a sketch idea when Lightspeed Magazine commissioned me to do the cover for their <a href="http://www.destroysf.com/queers-destroy-fantasy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.destroysf.com/queers-destroy-fantasy/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1492456479528000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGEHEpz3BlibpFc7naRKI-2EyGT3Q">Queers Destroy Fantasy! special issue</a>. The editors decided to go with a different option, but I liked the idea enough to do it up later on my own. It was definitely inspired in part by <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:La_Belle_Dam_Sans_Merci.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:La_Belle_Dam_Sans_Merci.jpg&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1492456479528000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFmSNlxMR3BnFP5_PcgpecSoVNPpQ">Dicksee&#8217;s La Belle Dame sans Merci</a> and by <a href="http://steendraws.tumblr.com/post/76559358048/my-second-entry-for-month-of-love-this-weeks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://steendraws.tumblr.com/post/76559358048/my-second-entry-for-month-of-love-this-weeks&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1492456479528000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHUMFPgP53l2w_Nle5YTqAjYFbQkg">this lady and knight image</a> by Steen (although I didn&#8217;t realize until I just looked it up now that I happened to use the same hair colors, hah &#8211; that was more based on the Dicksee painting and the actual hair of my models).<img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8355 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/tumblr_np358lXeyH1uwk80ro1_1280-205x300.jpg" alt="" width="205" height="300" /></p>
<p><strong>What is your dream project? If there were no restrictions on time or money what would you create?</strong></p>
<p>I would paint lots of faces, mostly. But the current project I&#8217;m batting around is of a YA-oriented post-apocalyptic Arthurian take.</p>
<p><strong>Because LSQ is all about stories, I have to ask. What are some of your favorite tales?</strong></p>
<p>My current favorite series is Max Gladstone&#8217;s Craft Sequence books. Probably my first fiction loves that I remember were Tamora Pierce&#8217;s books (the Lioness Quartet really started my love of heroines, I think, along with a few others) and Mercedes Lackey&#8217;s Valdemar books. I&#8217;ve also had a long-standing fondness for fairy tales and mythology.</p>
<p><strong><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8356 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/expostmythos_web2-210x300.jpg" alt="" width="210" height="300" />Are you reading anything right now? And does what you&#8217;re reading/watching/listening to inspire any of your work?</strong></p>
<p>Currently alternating between Chuck Wendig&#8217;s <i>Blackbirds</i> and <i>La Morte d&#8217;Arthur</i>. It&#8217;s probably impossible to avoid picking up inspiration from the media I consume, but I&#8217;m not immediately aware of any direct inspirations between recent media consumption and my recent work. I do occasionally do fanart for media I particularly enjoy, like Dragon Age, Mass Effect or Life Is Strange.</p>
<p><strong>Do you think that women illustrators have had an even chance of success in the field in the past? And has that changed or is it changing now?</strong></p>
<p>Have women ever had an even chance of success in any field they didn&#8217;t dominate (sometimes even ones they did)? I think this is still the case, societal prejudice, unconscious bias and the long-standing tendency to favor people more like yourself being what it is. Finding any field that isn&#8217;t touched by these pervasive issues would be difficult. But I think it is slowly shifting, abetted by people talking about these issues and sites like <a href="http://fantasticalwomen.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://fantasticalwomen.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1492456479529000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEUVxkmPTFsvKaQKywGmRi_WpXxcg">fantasticalwomen.com</a> and <a href="http://womenwhodraw.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://womenwhodraw.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1492456479529000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHgO9kaDqQshr3mZGtTn8tF1xWOjA">womenwhodraw.com</a>.<br />
<strong>Where can people learn more about you and your work? Are you accepting commissions? </strong><br />
My website <a href="http://priscilla-kim.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://priscilla-kim.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1492456479529000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH-NE_OwLeazICG-iObEadz7DLw4g">priscilla-kim.com</a> is the main touchpoint for all the rest of my online presences, but I can also be found at Instagram (<a href="http://www.instagram.com/priscillakimart" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.instagram.com/priscillakimart&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1492456479529000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH4Vkm0MaRfu5_qCeoxCF8ofaDSyg">http://www.instagram.com/<wbr />priscillakimart</a>), Facebook (<a href="http://www.facebook.com/priscillustrations" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://www.facebook.com/priscillustrations&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1492456479529000&amp;usg=AFQjCNETdNaLzfMRJIany0JTbpp1vFNy1w">http://www.facebook.com/<wbr />priscillustrations</a>), and Twitter (<a href="http://twitter.com/autumnflame" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://twitter.com/autumnflame&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1492456479529000&amp;usg=AFQjCNENBp8cKx1IEdBiZO2TrYTse-Tw8g">http://twitter.com/<wbr />autumnflame</a>) primarily, in order of descending art-focus.</p>
<p>I am accepting commissions right now, particularly for book covers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Year eight is gonna be great!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/year-eight-is-gonna-be-great/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 17:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Issue 029]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8199</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello dear readers and welcome to the eighth year of Luna Station Quarterly! There are&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello dear readers and welcome to the eighth year of Luna Station Quarterly! There are is a great new batch of stories in <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-029/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this issue</a> (when isn&#8217;t there?) and a gorgeous cover by <a href="http://www.priscilla-kim.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Priscilla Kim</a>. You should see the print editions. So. Pretty.</p>
<p>Speaking of the print edition, we&#8217;ve also got a fancy new trade dress on the cover. That&#8217;s step one in an ongoing evolution in the way things look and feel around here and a much needed upgrade. I&#8217;m a little in love with it. Keep an eye out for more changes throughout the year!</p>
<p>Before I ramble about that any further, why don&#8217;t you go dig into the stories? I can recommend you start off with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/kristen-brand/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kristen Brand</a>&#8216;s &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/how-lady-nightmare-stole-captain-alphas-girlfriend/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">How Lady Nightmare Stole Captain Alph&#8217;s Girlfriend</a>&#8221; which is a really fun read and our featured story.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;d like to carry LSQ along with you, of course I highly recommend the aforementioned print edition or you can get yourself an ebook edition as well. All the details are on the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-029/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">issue page</a>. All proceeds from those sales go towards paying our authors and keeping things running.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;d like to help even more (and gain our undying love) you can support <a href="http://patreon.com/lunastation" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LSQ on Patreon</a>. We&#8217;ve got some neat rewards for you and we would love to have you on the crew.</p>
<p>Thanks as always for stopping by and if you like what you&#8217;ve read here, please spread the word!</p>
<p>P. S. &#8211; Sorry for the rhyming title. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
