<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Quaint and Curious Volumes &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/quaint-and-curious-volumes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 18:12:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>2022 Horror in Review</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/2022-horror-in-review/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 11:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28909</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Full disclosure: I did not get to everything. There is just so much horror out&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28943 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/daniel-jensen-NMk1Vggt2hg-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/daniel-jensen-NMk1Vggt2hg-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/daniel-jensen-NMk1Vggt2hg-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/daniel-jensen-NMk1Vggt2hg-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/daniel-jensen-NMk1Vggt2hg-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/daniel-jensen-NMk1Vggt2hg-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Full disclosure: I did not get to everything. There is just <em>so much </em>horror out there! But I’ll say that this was a great year for spooky stuff, with high-budget adaptions and original series plus remakes that hold up.</p>
<p>TV (well, streaming service) horror continues to lead as the most innovative format for telling scary stories, but we had some great podcasts and books as well. Films were a bit of a mixed bag – legacy sequels are starting to wear thin, particularly if they aren’t that well done. It’s like we’re back to “mediocre to bad installments that everyone goes to see anyway.” But we had some gems!</p>
<p>Let’s get into it, going by medium.</p>
<p><strong>Movies</strong></p>
<p><em>Scream </em>(2022) – a cool fun time. Better than some in the series but can’t top the first or second one. I talk about it more in-depth in another post here.</p>
<p>Halloween ended…and like, for a film, it was good. For the closing chapter of the <em>Halloween</em> franchise, it was less good, and when looked at as a whole, the 2018-2022 revival timeline is sloppy and incoherent, with a second film that doesn’t do much and storylines in <em>Halloween Ends</em> that should have been planted in <em>Halloween </em>(2018).</p>
<p>As a die-hard Grady Hendrix fan, I enjoyed <em>My Best Friend’s Exorcism</em>, but I don’t think it fully held up against the book. A few of the changes made sense, but some of them grated on me—particularly the sanitizing of “DBNQ (Dearly But Not Queerly)” into “LYLAS (Love You Like A Sister).” I get it—maybe wouldn’t be a popular saying in modern parlance, but to change it was inauthentic. A change I approved of, however, was not killing the dog. (Damn you, Grady!) But in the end (which was another lackluster part of the movie) who doesn’t love a faux-80s horror film?</p>
<p><strong>Books</strong></p>
<p><em>The Pallbearers’ Club </em>by Paul Tremblay – classic “was it supernatural or wasn’t it” New England Gothic Tremblay fare, beautiful and heart-breaking, and starring two punks I loved very much.</p>
<p>The fourth and final installment of <em>Tales From the Gas Station </em>came out in March and it was genuinely a perfect solution to my favorite weird and wonderful horror comedy. A story about mutant raccoons that never takes itself too seriously, this book somehow also teaches us a lot about grief and how to move forward afterwards. I’ll miss the gas station at the edge of town, but it couldn’t have had a better closer.</p>
<p>I’m pretty hard to scare, but <em>Just Like Home </em>by Sarah Gailey did exactly that. We’ve got Vera, returning to her childhood home because her mother is dying, and the shards of their relationship can still cut. Pretty standard fare? Oh, yeah, and her dad was a serial killer. I also don’t think you’ll see the end coming because it is coke-era King levels of metaphor-made-real and also it is SUPER gross.</p>
<p><em>Beneath the Stairs </em>by Jennifer Fawcett was a solid 2022 ghost story and <em>The Overnight Guest </em>by Heather Gudenkauf is a nice winter thriller to set the mood for snowed-in nights.</p>
<p><strong>TV</strong></p>
<p><em>The Midnight Club</em>: oh my god, I white-knuckled through this because I do NOT do sad. Beautiful, but a rough ride (terminally ill teenagers telling ghost stories is a hell of a premise. It’s based on the Christopher Pike novel.) It’s also not standalone, so don’t expect everything to tie up in episode 10.</p>
<p><em>Archive 81 </em>proved that more podcasts should be adapted into series because hot damn was it good.</p>
<p>See my review of <em>Devil in Ohio </em><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-devil-in-ohio/">here.</a> It’s nothing special, but it’s a nice mood-setter for October.</p>
<p><strong>Podcasts:</strong></p>
<p><em>Parkdale Haunt</em>’s final season had me FEELING things—and not just terror. The production of this one is FABULOUS, and I would kill for any of the characters, but particularly Judith.</p>
<p>We also got new seasons of <em>Haunted House Flippers </em>and <em>Unwell, </em>plus a fun little newbie called <em>Badlands Cola</em>. <em>Knifepoint Horror</em> doesn’t really do seasons, but we got some great new episodes—except what was the deal with the laundry one (“cleanse”)? And, to shamelessly self-promote: a piece of mine was on <em>Thirteen</em>, another anthology with self-contained episodes. (It’s called “Contortion”—look it up!)</p>
<p>I discovered a new microfiction podcast called <em><a href="https://hallwaytonowhere.carrd.co/">Hallway to Nowhere</a> </em>and if I do not get more episodes soon, I will scream. Thank you for coming to my TED Talk.</p>
<p>And we’re getting new Magnus Archives?????? Everything is amazing.</p>
<p>Check back next month for an overview of what to look forward to in 2023!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To End a Legacy Franchise</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/how-to-end-a-legacy-franchise/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 10:48:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here there be SPOILERS for damn near everything (but mostly Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28757 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/merch-husey-EEZgog4AS5M-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/merch-husey-EEZgog4AS5M-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/merch-husey-EEZgog4AS5M-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/merch-husey-EEZgog4AS5M-unsplash-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/merch-husey-EEZgog4AS5M-unsplash-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/merch-husey-EEZgog4AS5M-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />Here there be SPOILERS for damn near everything (but mostly <em>Nightmare on Elm Street, Halloween, Scream, </em>and <em>Friday the 13<sup>th</sup></em>)</p>
<p>I got the idea for this month’s blog after going to see <em>Halloween Ends. </em>Which…should be indicative of what I thought of that one. But that’s another post entirely.</p>
<p>I’ve talked before about how we’re in the era of high-budget sequels, requels, reboots, and remakes starring the horror pantheon. And if what goes up must come down, around 12 movies in, the question has to be asked: how do we get off the ride? Is it even possible?</p>
<p>How do you finally put a horror legend to bed when his whole thing is that he can’t die? From a practical perspective, it’s pretty difficult, given the canonical quasi-immortality of most baddies. The disaster that was <em>Jason Goes to Hell </em>shows how sometimes, it’s best to leave well enough alone when it comes to getting technical about just <em>how </em>these dudes live through bullets, machetes, and getting hit real hard with sticks. (Yes, I’m still salty about that mob scene in <em>Halloween Kills</em>. Come on guys. At least check his pulse or something. You’ve been living in Haddonfield for years.)</p>
<p>But ignoring all that and simply focusing on the story and what we owe to the original creators, to the fans, and to the characters themselves, the question still stands: is there ever a time to end a franchise, and if so, <em>how</em>?</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at a few attempts.</p>
<p><em>Halloween </em>has a lot of examples of which endings work and which don’t, because multiple timelines “end” different ways. The latest is perhaps the most final, but according to <a href="https://screenrant.com/halloween-h20-michael-myers-decapitated-survive-legal-reason/">Screenrant</a>, a clause prevents Myers from ever being officially killed—so we might get a retcon a la <em>H20</em>. Which feels pretty disingenuous—same as it did in <em>Resurrection</em>.</p>
<p>Just from a story perspective, we leave <em>Halloween Ends </em>with a pretty final conclusion. I mean, there’s not a lot of coming back from getting put through a trash compactor. However! We’ve had “it’s the wrong Michael!” before (although I think the fact that we saw his face was supposed to put the kibosh on that). Also, since Laurie still has the mask, someone else could take it up. Which is too <em>Scream </em>for comfort.</p>
<p><em>Friday the 13<sup>th</sup></em> gives a reasonably satisfying (if ridiculous) conclusion with <em>Jason X</em>, although the remake might make one question if a new timeline is going to start. Almost any sequel would take place <em>before Jason X</em> and possibly discount it canonically—or come up with a reason Jason got cryogenically thawed prematurely, then returned for the events of the 11<sup>th</sup> film. But we’ve got around 450 years to play around with there. And though we’ve been waiting for quite some time, we might have <a href="https://bloody-disgusting.com/movie/3729014/sean-cunningham-teases-13th-friday-the-13th-installment-for-next-year/">something to look forward to in 2023.</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28759 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/edilson-borges-GSrgTVqS0dk-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/edilson-borges-GSrgTVqS0dk-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/edilson-borges-GSrgTVqS0dk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/edilson-borges-GSrgTVqS0dk-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/edilson-borges-GSrgTVqS0dk-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/edilson-borges-GSrgTVqS0dk-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><em>Elm Street </em>got meta with the storyline—which works pretty well with a metaphysical monster like Freddy. He was allegedly finished off in <em>The Final Nightmare</em>, but then we had <em>Wes Craven’s New Nightmare </em>and the remake so… Currently, Craven’s estate <a href="https://bloody-disgusting.com/movie/3584709/the-u-s-rights-to-a-nightmare-on-elm-street-and-freddy-krueger-have-reverted-back-to-wes-cravens-estate/">owns the rights</a> to Freddy, so it’s possible he could return.</p>
<p><em>Elm Street </em>probably took cues from <em>Scream, </em>which is still going strong. <em>Scream </em>is the baby of the family, admittedly, and is uniquely qualified for infinite sequels given the recyclable nature of the villain. But, if Never Campbell or Courtney Cox ever bowed out, the future of the franchise would be pretty dark.</p>
<p>Ultimately, finishing off Myers or Krueger or Voorhees just isn’t a smart financial move, so it won’t happen. And we can debate until the cows come home whether that’s a bad thing or not. In a world with <em>Avengers </em>movies that multiply like rabbits, are we slowly draining the creativity out of our society one remake at a time? Or is there nothing new under the sun, so full steam ahead with new interpretations?</p>
<p>Doesn’t matter. Halloween didn’t end in 2022, that’s for damn sure. Even if Moustapa Akkad hadn’t granted Mikey legal immortality, someone would have bid high enough on the rights. Or just waited for our masked abstinence-only sex educator to enter the public domain. Same with Jason and Freddy and Leatherface.</p>
<p>So if we can’t end these stories—and we certainly can’t seem to—then how do we keep them new? Eventually, the original timeline runs out of steam, no matter who’s slashing their way forward. The end came for Freddy, and for Michael (and then again for Michael&#8230;and again…and <em>again</em>), and it’ll come for Ghostface, too.</p>
<p>We can remake, although the novelty wears off after one. Remaking sequels is just a bad idea, because no one is going to watch a high-budget 2022 <em>Dream Warriors</em>. You can reboot, like <em>Halloween</em>, which buys time, but that top winds down too. You can move formats, though I have yet to see a TV series spinoff actually work.</p>
<p>So what’s worth it, when it comes to prolonging a horror saga?</p>
<p>First of all, I think every big franchise deserves a remake of the first film. Just for fun—to see what we can do with new special effects. Purists will hate it, newcomers will enjoy it, and kids who wouldn’t be scared by the 80s classic will get some legitimate spooks from the new one.</p>
<p>If we leave the remake in its own little canon-bubble, what come next? I think the best thing to do after that is assess what you have to work with. <em>Friday </em>is falling apart, with different directors molding the rules of the universe until they accidentally created a black hole. New timeline time. Or, alternate universe.</p>
<p><em>Scream</em>, on the other hand, is fine for direct sequels. And “sequel” can be a loose term. The <em>Conjuring </em>universe does pretty well with loosely-connected threads in a big canon. This model can be adapted to suit classics, although it only makes sense to keep the title characters in the films (otherwise you <em>Season of the Witch</em>-level confusion. And that film would have worked, if it had been the second one. But that’s another blog post too.)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28761 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/hello-i-m-nik-S6ikL0QoeJw-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/hello-i-m-nik-S6ikL0QoeJw-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/hello-i-m-nik-S6ikL0QoeJw-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/hello-i-m-nik-S6ikL0QoeJw-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/hello-i-m-nik-S6ikL0QoeJw-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/hello-i-m-nik-S6ikL0QoeJw-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/hello-i-m-nik-S6ikL0QoeJw-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />For sequels, the secret is to stop thinking in a linear manner and realize that stories can go left, right, up, down, in on themselves, back in time, into another world, and more. Look how great it worked for <em>Into the Spiderverse. </em></p>
<p>Maybe I just have no taste. But I’ll be going to <em>Friday the 13<sup>th</sup> VX </em>when I’m 90, and I’ll probably blog about it, too. These stories <em>can </em>keep going almost infinitely—writers just have to get creative.</p>
<p>It is a truth universally acknowledged that it is not in the nature of a slasher to stay dead for long.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>October Special Edition: The Edgewater Chronicles by Paul Deady</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/october-special-edition-the-edgewater-chronicles-by-paul-deady/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 01:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was lucky enough to snag an ARC of The Edgewater Chronicles by Tom Deady&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was lucky enough to snag an ARC of <a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/the-edgewater-chronicles-tom-deady/1142207658"><em>The Edgewater Chronicles </em></a>by Tom Deady from Crossroad Press. I read it during my bout of Covid-19 (after two years, six months, three vaccinations, and gallons of hand sanitizer, it finally got me…). Covid sucks, but it gave me a good excuse to catch up on media I’d been neglecting.</p>
<p>So, what are we working with here? I’ll start with the spoiler-free basics and then (as I inevitably do) start picking the stories apart.</p>
<p><em>The Edgewater Chronicles </em>is composed of four novellas. Carrying on the proud tradition of Lovecraft, Tremblay, and many more, Deady’s work is classic New England Gothic. Our town is “Edgewater,” situated, as best I can tell, outside Boston, near the coast. Lynn (the City of Sin!) provides a landmark. The stories all stand alone, though the setting gives them a delightfully eerie throughline.</p>
<p>We enter Edgewater with fresh grief. While in town, we attend a class reunion and reminisce about those no longer with us…and why they’re not around. We explore an abandoned hotel with a patient malevolence. Even at home, the house we lovingly built turns out to hold more than we bargained for. And sometimes, those dearest to us don’t always tell the truth.</p>
<p>What worked for me: the themes of addiction, grief, loneliness, responsibility, and the feeling of missed chances. Dread built with breadcrumb trails. Anniversaries and the emotions they bring up. Complex characters who react messily and feel lots of emotions. Places that are themselves characters, and not very nice ones. Eerie atmosphere and lots of tactile details (I drank each of Tim’s cokes and heard the muffled sounds of 80s rock from the lobby. So too did I sip Dalia’s endless cups of tea and hear her fire crackle). Tantalizing threads left swinging.</p>
<p>What didn’t work for me: Dialog that sometimes got stiltedly formal. Repeated words a copyeditor should have varied up. Characters sometimes doing things that didn’t make sense for them and never getting a satisfactory explanation. The prevailing sense that maybe some of these novellas should have been a novel. Which, really, is more of a compliment than anything, because it meant they had good bones. Very good bones indeed. Unlike, say, certain other buildings in Edgewater…</p>
<p>Now for the spoilery, in-depth part!</p>
<p>I’ve ranked the stories from favorite to least favorite and gone into detail about each below. As usual, I’m annihilating my word count, so I’ve talked the most about the ones I like best!</p>
<p><em>Coleridge </em>was a great read because of the atmosphere. In the story, Dalia is grieving her partner Zadie. Zadie died, as we slowly find out, by leaping from the third floor of the house she and Dalia have been restoring. (There’s a wonderful, subtle note that Dalia tried to join her at one point.)</p>
<p>Then, one day, a man claiming to be Zadie’s father, appears in Dalia’s shop. Which makes zero sense because Zadie’s father is dead and this guy doesn’t look anything like her. He wants something from their home, something Zadie found, and he won’t leave until he gets it.</p>
<p>There’s a lot of “supernatural but with plausible deniability” shenanigans that I <em>love </em>here, and Zadie and Dalia are both great. I also love the house itself, with its huge fireplace and the the wind and rain outside. And holy crap, Dalia with a sledgehammer. <em>Excellent. </em></p>
<p>What didn’t work for me (and proceeds to not work again in the next story) is the villain obfuscating for the sake of obfuscating—or rather, for the sake of giving the reader time to get curious about what’s happening. The scene where Dalia pushes Slade closer and closer to the fire is the level of adrenaline I would expect from the moment Slade crosses the threshold, but we get a lot of on-again-off-again tension.</p>
<p>Taking a break from the villain monologue so Dalia can read the diary dials down the urgency of the situation. In the world where this story is a novel and has a little more space to breathe, Dalia has time to peruse it at her leisure and let the pieces add up, rather than scrambling for them.</p>
<p>Also, why <em>exactly </em>does Zadie have to die? Either I’m an idiot (a strong possibility with lots of evidence to support it) or it isn’t logically explained.</p>
<p>What’s more terrifying than a fortieth class reunion at the best of times? <em>Class Reunion </em>is both eerie and sad. Tim, in town because his mother is dying, attends a reunion for the first time. His painful past resurfaces when he greets old friends, but something odd is going on. Why <em>was </em>that newspaper clipping with the event in with his mother’s effects? She had dementia, after all, and could barely recognize him. Why did three classmates die before graduating. And what is it Tim can’t remember?</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong, I <em>love </em>the plot itself. But also like <em>why </em>did Kenneth go to all the trouble? Okay, him being mad because Tim doesn’t remember is a great basis for the twist, but we don’t really get enough motivation. Is he in love? Was Tim his only friend, or did he do anything particularly special? There’s not enough to kill three girls, bide his time for years, dress up in a nun habit, and manipulate his former friend into returning.</p>
<p>However, we <em>love </em>a main character than uses the recorder app on their phone to catch the confession monologue <em>and </em>tells someone where they’re going before the big confrontation. Ten points to Tim.</p>
<p><em>One Night at the Grand </em>blended a couple fun concepts: evil hotel and urban exploring. I wish I’d gotten to know the characters a little better; staying in the MC’s head the entire time reduced them to concepts-we get it, time and space were factors. Once again, the atmosphere was the selling point for this one!</p>
<p><em>The Devil Comes to Edgewater </em>played with my absolute favorite thing about exorcisms: <em>how do you know the demon is actually gone</em>?! I enjoyed the creep factor a lot, but I didn’t think I got enough characterization for the demon, and Pam is suuuuuuper flat. I do love the last line!</p>
<p>Ultimately, I enjoyed this collection! I think <em>Coleridge </em>(and maybe <em>The Devil Comes to Edgewater</em>) would have worked better as a novel, but the novella format is perfect for the others.</p>
<p>Thanks again to Crossroad Press, and keep an eye out for this one when it drops on October 25<sup>th</sup>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Devil in Ohio</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-devil-in-ohio/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 12:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I binge-watched this Netflix series on a whim because I thought it might be Rust&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28677 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jesse-gardner-JYU14tnbfOA-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jesse-gardner-JYU14tnbfOA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jesse-gardner-JYU14tnbfOA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jesse-gardner-JYU14tnbfOA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jesse-gardner-JYU14tnbfOA-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/jesse-gardner-JYU14tnbfOA-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I binge-watched this Netflix series on a whim because I thought it might be Rust Belt Gothic—which it wasn’t (more Midwest)—but I enjoyed it a lot! It’s pretty popular on Netflix, so I thought I’d give you guys my verdict in case you’re on the fence about watching it.</p>
<p>Full disclosure: <em>Devil in Ohio </em>isn’t amazing. But it’s not bad either, and it’s enjoyable enough to make it worth a watch.</p>
<p>So why is the devil in Ohio, one of the most nondescript American states? Well. <em>Devil in Ohio</em> is based on a book, which is loosely inspired by a true story. And it’s a mysterious autumnal adventure, perfect for your September/October viewing.</p>
<p>Basically, we’ve got a devil-worshipping cult! The opening scene is Madeleine Arthur tearing through cornfields in a white dress. Clearly, Stuff Is Going On, and we are going to get to the bottom of it.</p>
<p>Arthur’s character is Mae Dodd, and as her social worker, Suzanne Mathis gets to know said mysterious girl, we learn about Mae’s incredibly screwed up past in an isolated cult. Suzanne, who had a similarly unpleasant childhood, brings Mae to live with her—and weird stuff starts happening. Stuff like the house Suzanne’s husband is desperately trying to sell getting burned to the ground, and crosses flipping upside down when Mae is around.</p>
<p>The cult—Sliocht an Diabhal (Traces/Descendants/Breed of the Devil in Irish—and it’s not pronounced too horribly by our American cast. But maybe my standards are low after <em>Halloween II </em>tried to convince us that “Samhain” meant “Lord of the dead” and <em>American Horror Story </em>pronounced it “Sam Hane.” For the curious, the word is said “sow-in,” and it means “November.”)—wants their sacrifice princess back, though, and Suzanne’s family starts doubting that their new border is as innocent as she claims.</p>
<p>Okay, now let’s get into it.</p>
<p>First of all, I Strongly Disagree with all the twitter discourse (as usual). A lot of people are saying Jules, Helen, Dani, and Peter are terrible people with no empathy toward Mae. I’ve also heard “Mae did nothing wrong!”</p>
<p>The cool thing about these characters is that they’re <em>complex. </em>Mae isn’t the perfect sad, too-good-for-this-world, self-destructive trauma victim. She’s manipulative, because she had to be to survive. She uses what happened to her for attention because she’s smart enough to know she’ll either get admired or mocked—and the choice is a no-brainer. Her moral compass is busted <em>because she was raised by a devil-worshipping, human-sacrificing cult</em>! To say Mae did some messed up stuff isn’t doing her a disservice—it’s acknowledging her full characterization.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Mathis family aren’t horrible people with no empathy. The kids are just that: kids who had their own childhood/adolescent problems. And yes, compared with a pentagram carved into your back, a sexuality crisis and musical auditions don’t seem like a big deal. But these are suburban kids with good lives encountering normal challenges, and it’s not reasonable to expect them to mature overnight and push aside their lives for Mae, particularly when she does things that hurt or upset them. There’s a great tension between Jules and Mae—two misfits looking for companionship in each other and of course ending up at odds.</p>
<p>Suzanne, too, is a tropey psychologist with her own trauma. In her therapy session, she acknowledges it with a wry laugh—but this is a trope that works! We’re eager to see Suzanne’s story through flashbacks, and no one can blame her for getting in pretty deep with Mae. She’s not a horrible mother, either, twitter-fiends. Suzanne is compassionate and trying to make a continuously unravelling situation work.</p>
<p>All that to say: I enjoyed the characters. Here’s that else I liked:</p>
<p>The crow motif! The midwestern suburban horror vibe that was absolutely nailed. Not all of the soundtrack, some a lot of it, particularly “Soul Cake” over a particularly dramatic ending.</p>
<p>Now for what I didn’t like:</p>
<p>The dialog. The fact that these characters were credulous to the point of stupidity. The improbable stuff like Suzanne getting to take Mae home in the first place, corn rows being that far apart, and Amontown getting to just…exist under the radar like that. The overdone Ohio State University product placement. The dropped plotlines that could have been really interesting but fell by the wayside.</p>
<p>Okay but also! Speaking of plot stuff! Some of the things People on the Internet said were bad writing, were actually just things they didn’t understand.</p>
<p>For example, [SPOILER WARNING] the supernatural-or-not teasing can all be resolved in a mundane way: Mae could have flipped the cross when the camera cut away from her, and the crow hitting the window could have been a coincidence.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28679 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/kevin-mueller-iBER-hi4DyU-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/kevin-mueller-iBER-hi4DyU-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/kevin-mueller-iBER-hi4DyU-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/kevin-mueller-iBER-hi4DyU-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/kevin-mueller-iBER-hi4DyU-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/kevin-mueller-iBER-hi4DyU-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/kevin-mueller-iBER-hi4DyU-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1706w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<p>And the soup plotline wasn’t Mae trying to poison anyone! She was attempting to keep Jules from meeting her brother, but Peter ate the soup by mistake and slept it off, with no one being any the wiser. Not everything you don’t understand is poor writing, people!</p>
<p>All in all, <em>Devil in Ohio </em>is a solid pre-Halloween watch! Don’t expect high-concept, artful TV, but if you go in expecting a fun and spooky cult mystery, you’ll probably enjoy the miniseries.</p>
<p>It doesn’t really <em>need </em>a sequel…but I’d watch one.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: The Pallbearers&#8217; Club</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-pallbearers-club/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 11:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Boilerplate: my life is barely coordinated chaos so I still haven’t gotten a chance to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Boilerplate: my life is barely coordinated chaos so I still haven’t gotten a chance to finish 100 Years of Horror. Instead, I give you a review.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-28490 size-medium" title="left-image" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pall-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pall-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pall.jpg 262w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" />The Pallbearers’ Club hooked me with the title. It’s by the great <a href="https://www.paultremblay.net/">Paul Tremblay</a>, who I fell in love with after A Head Full of Ghosts. I think I mentioned it in January’s blog, where I discussed what I was looking forward to. And I’m happy to report that this one is worth it! Incredibly worth it, actually.</p>
<p>The premise here is that a nerd with scoliosis starts an afterschool club (because he needs to be “well-rounded” for college apps, a horror in and of itself). The club’s purpose? To volunteer to carry the caskets of those who die without anyone left in their lives.<br />
At this point, if you’re not hooked, you’re probably reading the wrong blog, because goddamn is that fun.</p>
<p>The book is framed charmingly (which is #ClassicTremblay). There’s the main narrative, written by someone who is not called Art Barbara, and the comments on it, “handwritten” by someone who shows up in the book and has some thoughts on her own portrayal—someone who is not named Mercy.</p>
<p>These two semi-reliable narrators, in conversation with each other, tell us something that might be a vampire story, but is also a tale about coming of age, grieving, and the wounds from our youth that never quite heal. The story isn’t gory per se, but it’s grounded in the body: particularly our fickle hearts and spines.</p>
<p>Art and Mercy are refreshingly real. The past few years’ pop culture diet of sugary 80s nostalgia has many of us yearning for childhoods we didn’t have—that no one had because they’re not real—but the characters in this book are ordinary, and I love them for it. Art’s parents are flawed but not horrific and he’s working-class and unassuming. He’s a dork but also a punk, and Mercy is mysterious but not in a manic-pixie-dream-girl way. Neither of them are tropes, even though they easily could have been. They’re friends without forced pining or romance, in the way I often find myself friends with men but never see in fiction. They love each other, certainly, but without the clutter of romance. Of course, there might be more to it—a spiritual and physical feeding off each other, for example. But more on that later.</p>
<p>I also love Art and Mercy because they are New England punks, and as usual, the story is dripping with detail. It’s a love letter to Massachusetts and to 80s and 90s punk rock. The sheer number of references could be called indulgent, and maybe they’d turn off someone who doesn’t love that stuff or who wasn’t, like me, born on the East Coast. (The town of my birth, Beverly, is actually mentioned a few times.) I find them wonderful set-dressing, similar to the gorgeous and intricate backdrops in Studio Ghibli movies. This is regional horror, with a strong tether to place.</p>
<p>The prose is both artful (see what I did there?) and funny. Art’s list of band names, from “Institutional Pasta” to “The Brent Underwoods,” described as “a pop-punk five-piece (which is too many pieces) that had no members named Brent or Underwood” is a delight, as is his habit of verbing nouns. Mercy, too, is dryly hilarious, both as she’s portrayed in the main story and in her own voice as she writes the frame. The book is scattered with asides, the type I always get scolded for, whether they live in parens or commas.</p>
<p>They story’s central “was it real?” conflict is one Tremblay likes to stick us with, but it’s not frustrating because of everything else the novel does. Mercy’s crossing out of “memoir” and editing it to “novel” pervades the book. Are there some parts where the device wears thin? Yeah—the floating dresser didn’t grab me. But the rest, holy crow.</p>
<p>I read a review on Goodreads where someone said this book was basically about a maybe-haunted jacket and that made it boring. And all I can say is that review proves it’s possible to miss the point of something spectacularly. Because the “haunting” in this book isn’t just about visions that could maybe be passed off as a bad trip. There’s so much more to it.</p>
<p>SPOILER WARNING: my reading is one of no supernatural powers. Mercy is not a vampire, nor did she make Art one. It’s not creatures of the night that kill us, it’s life itself. The real monsters, if I can be permitted the cliché, are the heart that betrays us, the bones that warp and curve, the self-loathing we can’t get over, the loneliness that we all feel and we all deny. I think that Art found comfort in those stories, like I did, and Mercy—notice the name that isn’t hers, though it’s the one we know her as while reading—indulges the interpretation.</p>
<p>I’ve heard stories called a lot of things but here’s a new one: Tremblay tells us that a book is a coffin. That we have, by reading to the end, joined the Pallbearers’ Club ourselves. This closing paragraph is one that will stick with me. I’ll use it to explain horror and why it’s so important to me like I do with “Most times, a ghost is a wish.” It’s beautiful, and I think you should read it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goodbye, Murder Attic!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/goodbye-murder-attic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 10:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Part two of horror through the decades is slightly delayed, because my life has been&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part two of horror through the decades is slightly delayed, because my life has been turned upside down lately. I started a new job (teaching English as a second language) and had to move from Limerick to Cork very quickly. Thus, I’ve had zero time to watch old horror movies, so instead, I’m going to tell you about the apartment I just moved out of.</p>
<p>Welcome to…the Murder Attic.</p>
<p>For privacy reasons, I won’t give the name, but the house I lived in from 2021 to 2022 was built in 1880 and was recognized by the Irish authorities as A Significant Property or whatever. There was a plaque.</p>
<p>Living in an old house wasn’t a new experience for me—I grew up in an American farmhouse built around the same time. I found the history pretty cool—a famous Irish author and playwright grew up in the place. I lived in the attic, which, according to the cartoonishly evil landlord, had once been the servants’ quarters.</p>
<p>It was located across the street from a (still-functioning) mental hospital and the city jail. Just a little ways down the road was an absolutely gigantic graveyard.</p>
<p>Here are some spooky looking black-and-white newspaper photos of the house (from articles about how terrible it was that the place was abandoned containing demands for Someone To Do Something). [Photos from <em>The Limerick Leader</em>]</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-28192 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Capture.png" alt="" width="300" height="184" /> <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28193 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/newspaper-pic-of-house-300x250.png" alt="" width="300" height="250" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/newspaper-pic-of-house-300x250.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/newspaper-pic-of-house.png 490w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The place was derelict for a lot of years and at one point, there was a fire that caused a fair bit of damage. Then, in 2015, said evil landlord purchased it on an 80,000 euro “whim.” He then filled it with more apartments than it was zoned for. Mine, when I checked the tenancy board, did not legally exist. Unsurprisingly, he demanded rent in cash. He said he preferred international tenants because it was easier to kill them and get away with it&#8230;.I mean &#8220;because Irish people &#8216;party too much.'&#8221;</p>
<p>When I got the place, it was filthy. Moldy water and spoiled milk in the fridge, a thick layer of dust…and a dead bird on the floor that was not in any way ominous.</p>
<p>My partner and I cleaned it, and I made it into a damn cozy place, if I say so myself. There was no oven provided, so I bought a large one. It did not fit into the kitchen, so it lived in my bedroom/living area.</p>
<p>Here are some more cool and fun things I discovered in the place:</p>
<p>A calendar someone had written on the wall in pencil, leading me to believe they may have been confined there against their will. I put a chair in front of it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28194 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20220626_135835-142x300.jpg" alt="" width="142" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20220626_135835-142x300.jpg 142w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20220626_135835-485x1024.jpg 485w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20220626_135835-768x1623.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20220626_135835-727x1536.jpg 727w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20220626_135835-969x2048.jpg 969w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20220626_135835-scaled.jpg 1211w" sizes="(max-width: 142px) 100vw, 142px" /></p>
<p>Back stairs to nowhere (well, to my downstairs neighbor’s apartment, but they were blocked up). They’d once been the servants’ stairs.</p>
<p>A pretty significant dark and cobwebby area under the eaves that I never entered.</p>
<p>An abandoned building out back that I’m pretty sure was once a stable but looks like something out of a bad ghost movie.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28195 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20210707_214657-142x300.jpg" alt="photo of a backyard with a derelict building in it that gives way to more city" width="142" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20210707_214657-142x300.jpg 142w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20210707_214657-485x1024.jpg 485w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20210707_214657-768x1623.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20210707_214657-727x1536.jpg 727w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20210707_214657-969x2048.jpg 969w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/20210707_214657-scaled.jpg 1211w" sizes="(max-width: 142px) 100vw, 142px" /></p>
<p>I want to emphasize that I did not have a single paranormal experience in this place (though to be fair, I’m not very sensitive to any other worlds that there may be). I slept great, with no more nightmares than normal. My cat loved the skylights and never seemed perturbed by anything I couldn’t see.</p>
<p>I watched plenty of horror movies, read scary stories, and never really got scared. I guess I habitually burn a fair amount of sage, which might have helped?</p>
<p>The landlord was predictably a jerk about giving me my deposit back (read the entire lease in front of me after he said I had violated it, trying to find something he could get me on. Spoiler: he did not.), but I never got locked away in the eaves and forced to scratch my own calendar on the wall. No one ever bothered me, nothing came up missing, and my neighbors were nice enough. It was the first time I’d gotten to live alone, and I loved it.</p>
<p>I will miss the murder attic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>100 Years of Horror (Part 1)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/100-years-of-horror-part-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 10:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27848</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For each decade, I present: the main baddie, a few thoughts, and a book and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28093 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thomas-willmott-2s-AelYnf3o-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thomas-willmott-2s-AelYnf3o-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thomas-willmott-2s-AelYnf3o-unsplash-769x1024.jpg 769w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thomas-willmott-2s-AelYnf3o-unsplash-768x1023.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thomas-willmott-2s-AelYnf3o-unsplash-1153x1536.jpg 1153w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thomas-willmott-2s-AelYnf3o-unsplash-1538x2048.jpg 1538w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thomas-willmott-2s-AelYnf3o-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1922w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />For each decade, I present: the main baddie, a few thoughts, and a book and film rec.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">2020s</p>
<p>We’re only in 2022, so it feels early to pick a monster to represent this tumultuous decade. Check back in 2030.<br />
The remake (or requel, thanks <em>Scream</em> 2022) train kept right on going with <em>Candyman</em> in 2021 and a reboot of Texas Chainsaw Massacre upcoming. We also got some new (and weird) stuff, with<em> Malevolent</em> and <em>Last Night in Soho</em>. The 2020s started strong, and I’m excited to see where they’ll go.<br />
<strong>What to read:</strong><br />
<em>My Heart is a Chainsaw</em> by Stephen Graham Jones<br />
<strong>What to watch:</strong><br />
<em>Gretel &amp; Hansel</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">2010s</p>
<p>This decade’s boogeyman was Slenderman. Technically, Slendy showed up on the Something Awful forums in 2009, but he was a solid part of the 2010s zeitgeist, with his game and (terrible) film occupying dropping during that decade.<br />
A season of high-budget remakes, the 2010s were a horror renaissance. Nostalgia alone wouldn’t have carried the decade, but there was plenty of new blood (and not the Friday the 13th kind). From <em>The VVitch</em> to <em>Hereditary</em>, horror movies that were genuinely good films abounded—often thanks to A24 studios. Horror on the small screen flourished as well, with <em>American Horror Story</em> establishing TV horror and streaming services like Netflix giving us gems like <em>The</em> <em>Haunting of Hill House</em> and <em>Marianne</em>. The big franchise of the decade was the thoroughly-enjoyable <em>Conjuring</em> universe, which is still going strong.<br />
<strong>What to read:</strong><br />
<em>The Twisted Ones</em> by T. Kingfisher<br />
<strong>What to watch:</strong><br />
<em>Midsommar</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">2000s</p>
<p>Jigsaw is the face of 2000s horror…but I can’t comment much on him because the <em>Saw</em> franchise is one I haven’t actually started. I’m hesitant, because even horror buffs have their “HELL NOPE” categories, and the films hit that niche for me. Still, the guy has a fabulous design and a respectable franchise.<br />
My lack of involvement in Jigsaw’s games doesn’t mean I don’t love the 2000s. (As a ’96 baby, how could I not?) Bad 2000s horror would be my guilty pleasure if I was the least bit guilty about it, but I’m absolutely 0% repentant for my love of films like <em>The Glass House</em>. We had a lot of overly dramatic and tropey horror, and several franchises that did well but weren’t extremely memorable. There are a lot of hidden gems in the 2000s, so don’t disregard this decade just because not that many blockbusters jump out.<br />
<strong>What to read:</strong><br />
<em>Heart-Shaped Box</em> by Joe Hill<br />
<strong>What to watch:</strong><br />
<em>The Others<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28094 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/jose-francisco-morales-ibYF02aYEbE-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/jose-francisco-morales-ibYF02aYEbE-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/jose-francisco-morales-ibYF02aYEbE-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/jose-francisco-morales-ibYF02aYEbE-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/jose-francisco-morales-ibYF02aYEbE-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/jose-francisco-morales-ibYF02aYEbE-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">1990s</p>
<p>Who could be the face of 1990s horror but Ghostface? Self-aware, twisty, still alive and well in 2022? Scream is the cream of the ‘90s crop.<br />
Low budget ‘90s horror often stood the test of time, with gems like the <em>IT</em> miniseries. Classics like <em>Misery</em> (the adaption of the Stephen King novel of the same name) and <em>Silence of the Lambs</em> are also mainstays of the decade. Plus <em>The Blair Witch Project</em> solidified found-footage horror as a genre, forever giving fans something to argue over. (For what it’s worth, I’m team “Found Footage Is Overrated.”)<br />
<strong>What to read:</strong><br />
<em>Welcome to Dead House</em> (<em>Goosebumps</em> 1) by R.L. Stine<br />
<strong>What to watch:</strong><br />
<em>Sleepy Hollow</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">1980s</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Jason Voorhees leapt through a window and onto the scene in 1980. Then, he terrorized us for the rest of the decade (and beyond, but he somewhat lost his touch along the way). Arguably, he shares the title with Freddy Krueger, who first appeared in our dreams in 1984.<br />
We were spoiled for choice back then—the 70s and 80s were the years of huge, sprawling horror franchises, and where quality was lacking, there was definitely heart. This was a big growth decade for the genre, and there are a lot of great picks.<br />
<strong>What to read:</strong><br />
<em>Ghost Story</em> by Peter Straub<br />
<strong>What to watch:</strong><br />
<em>A Nightmare on Elm Street</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">1970s</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Michael Myers is the face—or rather the Shatner mask—of the 1970s. Escaping from prison busses, stabbing and slashing, grabbing ankles, and saying nary a word, Michael has been around for fifty odd years and never lost his, er, charm.<br />
The ‘70s is where slashers really started to take shape (thanks, Mikey!), and as far as novels go, there is a <em>lot</em> of really good early-career King.<br />
<strong>What to read:</strong><br />
<em>The Shining</em> by Stephen King<br />
<strong>What to watch:</strong><br />
<em>The Exorcist</em></p>
<p>As always, these lists are non-inclusive and subjective as heck. Check back next month for the 1920-1969 installment, where I explore the boogeymen of the 20th century.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Escape the Field</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-escape-the-field/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 10:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I went into Escape the Field figuring it would be an off-brand In the Tall&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27726 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Escape_the_Field-203x300.jpg" alt="" width="203" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Escape_the_Field-203x300.jpg 203w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Escape_the_Field.jpg 260w" sizes="(max-width: 203px) 100vw, 203px" />I went into <em>Escape the Field </em>figuring it would be an off-brand <em>In the Tall Grass</em>, which is good enough that even a knock-off version seemed like a worthwhile way to spend an evening. This film (directed by Emerson Moore and written by Moore, Sean Wathern, and Joshua Dobkin) came out on May 6<sup>th</sup>, 2022, and if it’s not still in theaters when this comes out, you can rent it on Amazon.</p>
<p>Boilerplate SPOILER WARNING for the whole film.</p>
<p>We’ve got some fun tropes here: a woman called Sam (Jordan Claire Robbins) wakes up in a cornfield maze with no idea how she got there. She has been left a gun with one bullet. There’s a spider crawling on her face for the aesthetic.</p>
<p>It turns out there are other people trapped in the field, and they also have random items—matches, a knife, etc. For reference, our full cast is Sam, the sympathetic lead, Tyler (Theo Rossi) the nice guy you root for, Ryan (Shane West), the toughie, Denise (Elena Juatco), the sexy one who doesn’t do much, Ethan (Julian Feder), the cute/sympathetic kid, and Cameron (Tahirah Sharif), who is just…entirely unpleasant.</p>
<p>So far, so <em>Maze Runner</em>. There’s some group tension, characters coming and going, and general shenanigans before <em>Escape the Field</em> turns into an escape room movie as the The Gang realizes they have to solve puzzles. They do this a little too easily, because most of the challenges involve fitting their given items into other things.</p>
<p>However, a scary something-or-other that runs around stabbing people keeps interrupting Family Fun in the Corn Maze. I’m going to call him the maze-beast. His favorite hobby is stabbing.</p>
<p>Also inhabiting the maze are weird scarecrow-creatures, some of who shoot darts with mystery substances in them. These guys are some of the freakiest visuals of the whole thing.</p>
<p>Per usual, the cast drops like flies as they progress through puzzle-based tasks. Finally, Sam and Tyler reach a machine they’re able to shut off…to no result! Because they’re mice in a maze! Who could have seen this coming?</p>
<p>And then, the maze-beast kills Tyler. Sam isn’t pleased about this, so she sets him on fire, in a decent display of badassery.</p>
<p>The film ends with some guys in gas masks coming out and hauling Sam away, while a voiceover speaks jargon about procedures and moving on to “Stage Two,” insinuating it’s some sort of experiment (and also that if the studio will fund it, there’s going to be a sequel).</p>
<p>Denise teased the whole “government experiment” idea earlier, with some backup from Cameron, who is a coder. Denise worked for the Pentagon! And allegedly dealt with data that could only have come from experiments like this! She mentions it randomly, it never comes up again, and then maze-beast gets her!</p>
<p>This would have been such a cool storyline. I feel robbed.</p>
<p>We also get an end credits scene. Which didn’t seem to come up for me when I rented it on Amazon, but according to <a href="https://fictionhorizon.com/escape-the-field-ending-explained/05e63b7aa4e97/Documents/LSQ%20Blogging/Types%20of%20fear.docx">Fiction Horizon</a>, it’s a shot of Ryan becoming the new maze-beast, in the classic cycle-repeating horror trope.</p>
<p><em>Escape the Field </em>isn’t a good movie, but there was potential, and the atmosphere is enjoyably creepy, melding a Midwest gothic vibe with an evil institute feel.</p>
<p>To fix the rest of it, I’d cut down the cast (axing Denise and Ethan is a no-brainer, and realistically, Ryan and Tyler could be combined). If the guy who comes out of the corn counting and saying there’s no way out is going to exist, he needs a little more purpose and explanation. Given the ending, it seems unlikely a random survivor would be left in the maze (with the exception of the doped-up maze-beast), so what’s the deal with “Business Man,” as he’s referred to in the credits?</p>
<p>(He’s Emerson Moore doing a cameo, btw.)</p>
<p>I’d also pick a thread to follow. Is this a movie about a sadistic puzzle, with a focus on solving riddles, or is it a movie about government experiments with a mystery element? If you’re going to drop the breadcrumbs about Pentagon experiments and pretty much confirm them in the end, give us a little more to go on, and let the characters engage with the concept a little more.</p>
<p>Keep the tension and the scary robo-scarecrows, tidy up the cast, pick a plotline and stick to it, and you have yourself a winner, instead of the mediocre film we ended up with.</p>
<p>Final rating: 2.5/5 stars—watchable but no real shame if you skip it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scares of All Shapes and Sizes: Categorizing Fear</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/scares-of-all-shapes-and-sizes-categorizing-fear/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/scares-of-all-shapes-and-sizes-categorizing-fear/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 10:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27345#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=27345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stephen King classifies scares in three categories: Terror, Horror, and Gross-Out. “The 3 types of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stephen King classifies scares in three categories: Terror, Horror, and Gross-Out.</p>
<p>“The 3 types of terror: The Gross-out: the sight of a severed head tumbling down a flight of stairs, it&#8217;s when the lights go out and something green and slimy splatters against your arm. The Horror: the unnatural, spiders the size of bears, the dead waking up and walking around, it&#8217;s when the lights go out and something with claws grabs you by the arm. And the last and worse one: Terror, when you come home and notice everything you own had been taken away and replaced by an exact substitute. It&#8217;s when the lights go out and you feel something behind you, you hear it, you feel its breath against your ear, but when you turn around, there&#8217;s nothing there&#8230;”</p>
<p>Far be it from me to argue with the master of horror. However, I want to subdivide these three categories a little further.</p>
<p>The reason I started thinking about this was because I watched <em>Apartment 1 Br</em>, and even though it’s a good movie, I really didn’t enjoy it. I ended up watching <em>Howl’s Moving Castle </em>to calm down.</p>
<p>But Eve, you like being scared! That’s your whole thing! *insert montage of me riding rollercoasters alone because my friends have reached their limit, watching horror movies in the dark, and generally spooking myself silly*</p>
<p>Thinking about this seemingly contradictory idea: that I can love being scared sometimes and not others, led me to the idea that “fear” is a catch-all term that can be defined even further. So…</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Types of Terror </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Cosmic Horror</p>
<p>“The universe and the laws thereof are absolutely not what I thought they were.” This is the heart of cosmic horror, and of course I’ve got to nod to Lovecraft for solidifying this genre.</p>
<p>There’s a great line from Stephen King’s <em>IT </em>that explains it pretty well, I think. It’s from Stanley Uris’ POV, and it explains why he’s completely unable to cope with the monster that is It.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27485 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1706w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />“It&#8217;s offense you maybe can&#8217;t live with because it opens up a crack inside your thinking, and if you look down into it you see there are evil things down there, and they have little yellow eyes that don&#8217;t blink, and there&#8217;s a stink down there in that dark and after a while you think maybe there&#8217;s a whole other universe where a square moon rises in the sky, and the stars laugh in cold voices, and some of the triangles have four sides, and some have five, and some have five raised to the fifth power of sides. In this universe there might grow roses which sing. Everything leads to everything, he would have told them if he could. Go to your church and listen to your stories about Jesus walking on the water, but if I saw a guy doing that I&#8217;d scream and scream and scream. Because it wouldn&#8217;t look like a miracle to me. It would look like an offense.”</p>
<p>What’s interesting is that this feeling of tininess in a world you don’t understand manifests much differently in other genres. In sci-fi, it can be a moment of awe and hope, while in religious tradition it can be sacred, proof of forces larger than us.</p>
<p>Paul Tremblay posits (and pushes back against) the idea that horror is a fundamentally conservative genre. New, unknown things that break the rules of the world as we know it are scary and bad. Cosmic horror, anyway, reinforces his theory.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Too Close For Comfort</p>
<p>This one is anything that doesn’t exactly rearrange your concept of reality, but it hits a little too close to home. Babysitters getting mauled while they order pizza and ghosts hover just on the edge of your vision, for example, are scary because “Hey, maybe that could happen, after all, you know that story about my friend’s cousin’s mom who…”</p>
<p>This kind of fear has us checking over our shoulders and doubting the people we see every day.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Types of Horror</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Profanity</p>
<p>I almost wanted to categorize this one as “perversion,” but there’s connotations there I don’t <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-27486 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />mean. This kind of horror is what happens when something usually perceived as innocent is twisted into something frightening: possessed children’s toys, evil carnivals, cannibal clowns.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Spooky Stuff</p>
<p>This one is simple: things that creep us out on a cultural or species level like dead bodies that zombify, ghosts, curses, haunted objects or houses. This kind of fear explores things we find disturbing on the best of days (but also sometimes find fascinating).</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Types of Gross-Out</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Phobia</p>
<p>Sometimes, whether there’s a reason for it or not, specific things can put a person into a deep state of fear, even if they aren’t in any danger. Phobias range from “Hey, don’t ever ask so-and-so to hold your pet tarantula” to medical diagnoses that can be debilitating.</p>
<p>An ophidiophobe would rather fight a bear than go into the reptile house and a claustrophobe might find a tanning bed intolerable. Some movies play on these fears and allow viewers a form of DIY exposure therapy that rarely works. And they create their own audiences, because some children form phobias just from seeing something scary on screen.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Adrenaline Rushes</p>
<p>Jump scares! VR horror experiences! Sitting next to me in a theater during a jump-scare-heavy movie because I always grab my companion!</p>
<p>I think this one is so much fun. It’s reasonably easy to do: set a tense atmosphere (a POV short where a character creeps down an empty hallway with plenty of places for the big bad to hide, for example, or a scene where the viewers can spot the danger but the character can’t), draw it out for as long as your sadistic little heart thinks is necessary, and then BAM! Hit ‘em with a shock to the senses like sudden movement or loud noise.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Body Horror</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27487 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-198x300.jpg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-676x1024.jpg 676w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-768x1163.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-1014x1536.jpg 1014w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-1353x2048.jpg 1353w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1691w" sizes="(max-width: 198px) 100vw, 198px" />This one is very evolutionary in nature—where Lovecraft terrorizes our frontal cortexes, squeamish body horror goes straight for the hindbrain. Messy kills, buckets of blood, snapping bones—either you love this stuff or you hate it. We’ve got the effects team to thank for the images that stick in your mind and the sympathy pain you experience.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Trauma-Triggers</p>
<p>This one is probably the least fun. Watching <em>The Shining </em>if you grew up with an abusive alcoholic or <em>Hush </em>if you’ve lived through a home invasion can, for a lot of people, bring on the mental and physical symptoms of being back in the situation. 0/10, do not recommend.</p>
<p>On my way out, I’ll leave a helpful link: <a href="https://www.doesthedogdie.com/">https://www.doesthedogdie.com/</a>. This is a really good resource for vetting movies for really specific stuff. It won’t get inside your brain and tell you what’s really going to bother you, but a quick search will bring up most common phobias. Some of the entries paint with a pretty broad brush, ie considering Grizabella’s ascension to the Heaviside Layer in <em>CATS </em>a “cat death.”</p>
<p>Which yes, is still on topic, because <em>CATS </em>(2019) is a horror movie and no one can tell me different.</p>
<p>Anyway, drop your “absolutely nope” movies in the comments, and I’ll see you all next month!</p>
<p><!-- Stephen King classifies scares in three categories: Terror, Horror, and Gross-Out. “The 3 types of terror: The Gross-out: the sight of a severed head tumbling down a flight of stairs, it's when the lights go out and something green and slimy splatters against your arm. The Horror: the unnatural, spiders the size of bears, the dead waking up and walking around, it's when the lights go out and something with claws grabs you by the arm. And the last and worse one: Terror, when you come home and notice everything you own had been taken away and replaced by an exact substitute. It's when the lights go out and you feel something behind you, you hear it, you feel its breath against your ear, but when you turn around, there's nothing there...” Far be it from me to argue with the master of horror. However, I want to subdivide these three categories a little further. The reason I started thinking about this was because I watched Apartment 1 Br, and even though it’s a good movie, I really didn’t enjoy it. I ended up watching Howl’s Moving Castle to calm down. But Eve, you like being scared! That’s your whole thing! *insert montage of me riding rollercoasters alone because my friends have reached their limit, watching horror movies in the dark, and generally spooking myself silly* Thinking about this seemingly contradictory idea: that I can love being scared sometimes and not others, led me to the idea that “fear” is a catch-all term that can be defined even further. So… Types of Terror Cosmic Horror “The universe and the laws thereof are absolutely not what I thought they were.” This is the heart of cosmic horror, and of course I’ve got to nod to Lovecraft for solidifying this genre. There’s a great line from Stephen King’s IT that explains it pretty well, I think. It’s from Stanley Uris’ POV, and it explains why he’s completely unable to cope with the monster that is It. “It's offense you maybe can't live with because it opens up a crack inside your thinking, and if you look down into it you see there are evil things down there, and they have little yellow eyes that don't blink, and there's a stink down there in that dark and after a while you think maybe there's a whole other universe where a square moon rises in the sky, and the stars laugh in cold voices, and some of the triangles have four sides, and some have five, and some have five raised to the fifth power of sides. In this universe there might grow roses which sing. Everything leads to everything, he would have told them if he could. Go to your church and listen to your stories about Jesus walking on the water, but if I saw a guy doing that I'd scream and scream and scream. Because it wouldn't look like a miracle to me. It would look like an offense.” What’s interesting is that this feeling of tininess in a world you don’t understand manifests much differently in other genres. In scifi, it can be a moment of awe and hope, while in religious tradition it can be sacred, proof of forces larger than us. Paul Tremblay posits (and pushes back against) the idea that horror is a fundamentally conservative genre. New, unknown things that break the rules of the world as we know it are scary and bad. Cosmic horror, anyway, reinforces his theory. Too Close For Comfort This one is anything that doesn’t exactly rearrange your concept of reality, but it hits a little too close to home. Babysitters getting mauled while they order pizza and ghosts hover just on the edge of your vision, for example, are scary because “hey, maybe that could happen, after all, you know that story about my friend’s cousin’s mom who…” This kind of fear has us checking over our shoulders and doubting the people we see every day. Types of Horror Profanity I almost wanted to categorize this one as “perversion,” but there’s connotations there I don’t mean. This kind of horror is what happens when something usually perceived as innocent is twisted into something frightening: possessed children’s toys, evil carnivals, cannibal clowns. Spooky Stuff This one is simple: things that creep us out on a cultural or species level like dead bodies that zombify, ghosts, curses, haunted objects or houses. This kind of fear explores things we find disturbing on the best of days (but also sometimes find fascinating). Types of Gross-Out Phobia Sometimes, whether there’s a reason for it or not, specific things can put a person into a deep state of fear, even if they aren’t in any danger. Phobias range from “hey, don’t ever ask so-and-so to hold your pet tarantula” to medical diagnoses that can be debilitating. An ophidiophobe would rather fight a bear than go into the reptile house and a claustrophobe might find a tanning bed intolerable. Some movies play on these fears and allow viewers a form of DIY exposure therapy that rarely works. And they create their own audiences, because some children form phobias just from seeing something scary on screen. Adrenaline Rushes Jump scares! VR horror experiences! Sitting next to me in a theater during a jump-scare-heavy movie because I always grab my companion! I think this one is so much fun. It’s reasonably easy to do: set a tense atmosphere (a POV short where a character creeps down an empty hallway with plenty of places for the big bad to hide, for example, or a scene where the viewers can spot the danger but the character can’t), draw it out for as long as your sadistic little heart thinks is necessary, and then BAM! Hit ‘em with a shock to the senses like sudden movement or loud noise. Body Horror This one is very evolutionary in nature – where Lovecraft terrorizes our frontal cortexes, squeamish body horror goes straight for the hindbrain. Messy kills, buckets of blood, snapping bones—either you love this stuff or you hate it. We’ve got the effects team to thank for the images that stick in your mind and the sympathy pain you experience. Trauma-Triggers This one is probably the least fun. Watching The Shining if you grew up with an abusive alcoholic or Hush if you’ve lived through a home invasion can, for a lot of people, bring on the mental and physical symptoms of being back in the situation. 0/10, do not recommend. On my way out, I’ll leave a helpful link: https://www.doesthedogdie.com/. This is a really good resource for vetting movies for really specific stuff. It won’t get inside your brain and tell you what’s really going to bother you, but a quick search will bring up most common phobias. Some of the entries paint with a pretty broad brush, ie considering Grizabella’s ascension to the Heaviside Layer in CATS a “cat death.” Which yes, is still on topic, because CATS (2019) is a horror movie and no one can tell me different. Anyway, drop your “absolutely nope” movies in the comments, and I’ll see you all next month! wp:paragraph /--></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/scares-of-all-shapes-and-sizes-categorizing-fear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eve Watches All the Escape Room Horror Movies So You Don&#8217;t Have To</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/eve-watches-all-the-escape-room-horror-movies-so-you-dont-have-to/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/eve-watches-all-the-escape-room-horror-movies-so-you-dont-have-to/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 11:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You know how a lot of my posts that have to do with ranking and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You know how a lot of my posts that have to do with ranking and discussing horror movies have, like, a lot of thought behind the watch order and reverence for whatever franchise it is?</p>
<p>This time, I offer none of those things! Instead, I simply watched all the movies I could find about escape rooms and ranked them. Obviously, most of them were terrible, but I will take any excuse to watch a godawful horror movie, so here we are.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27319 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/kdwk-leung-3oqHaTT_j8o-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/kdwk-leung-3oqHaTT_j8o-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/kdwk-leung-3oqHaTT_j8o-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/kdwk-leung-3oqHaTT_j8o-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/kdwk-leung-3oqHaTT_j8o-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/kdwk-leung-3oqHaTT_j8o-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>I was pretty strict about interpretation: it couldn’t just be a “characters are stuck in a deadly place” film; it had to be “characters went to something marketed as an escape room and found themselves in a horror film.”</p>
<p>Films in this sub-genre are incredibly formulaic, so here is the basic anatomy of the cast, in case you want to make one of these bad boys yourself.</p>
<p>Strangers are plopped together (which has never actually happened to me when I’ve done an escape room) tends to work better than groups who know each other, but either is a decent starting point. This group contains…</p>
<ul>
<li>The guy who’s way too into it: This person is sometimes a jerk and sometimes charmingly optimistic.</li>
<li>The one who doesn’t want to be there: The lesson here? STOP FORCING YOUR PARTNERS TO DO STUFF THEY DON’T LIKE! It’s not a healthy dynamic and it might end in one or both of you being chopped up into little pieces.</li>
<li>The smart final girl: What it says on the tin.</li>
<li>Sundry redshirts to get slashed up: Also what it says on the tin,</li>
</ul>
<p>Then, The Gang Realizes This Is For Real (usually because a redshirt dies), and hijinks ensue.</p>
<p>Basically, this subgenre is just an extension of the “bad guy forces victims to play sadistic games” genre. And that stuff goes way back, to H.H. Holmes, the serial killer who operated during the Chicago World’s Fair. The mythology surrounding Holmes is that he had a deadly, funhouse hotel where he trapped people. IRL, he was a serial killer, but not that interesting of one. But people ran with the idea, because there’s nothing people like more than Messed Up Stuff In the News.</p>
<p>Then, of course, we have the SAW franchise. Pretty much any “sadistic game” type film is Jigsaw’s twisted offspring in one way or another. The Collection and other b-movies follow in the same noble track.</p>
<p>And all this leads, unsurprisingly, to escape rooms. With the boom in popularity in the 2010s, making them into horror was a recipe for success.</p>
<p>Escape room films are fun because they keep you tense. As someone who likes puzzles—and actual escape rooms—following along with the characters and trying to solve the puzzles alongside them is most of the fun.</p>
<p>All this makes for a solid niche, so it’s no surprise there are quite a few escape room horror flicks.</p>
<p>Onward to the ranking! Per usual: spoilers for all the films below.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27320 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Escape_Room_2019_poster-202x300.png" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Escape_Room_2019_poster-202x300.png 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Escape_Room_2019_poster.png 245w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" />1. Escape Room (2019) dir. Adam Robital<br />
This one’s got the basic premise, with a cool twist: the strangers who are stuck in the game together are all lone survivors. And the ending—it’s actually metal as hell. In this one, the gamemaster’s motivation is to create life-or-death games to entertain the world’s richest. “The Most Dangerous Game” and The Hunger Games put together, it has the twist you’d expect at the end, but is still satisfying.</p>
<p>2. No Escape Room (2018) Dir. Alex Merkin<br />
Does it have more plot holes than a slice of Swiss cheese? Yeah, but it leans into the surreal element and is genuinely a good time, when the characters are constantly. yelling. each. others’. names. I did not count how many times the dad yells “Karen!” but it’s enough to make you think he’s fending off a horde of manager-hunters. The characters also do a fair bit of standing agog while Things Happen, which, though probably realistic, doesn’t make for good cinema.</p>
<p>All that being said, this one is atmospheric and trippy in some fun ways! Time goes all bendy, the ending makes no sense but is wickedly delicious, and there’s a weird lady-in-the-lake scene that either has some deep significance I can’t figure out or is just there to mess with us. I was skeptical of supernatural elements working in this sub-genre, but Merkin makes it happen.</p>
<p>3. Escape Room: Tournament of Champions (2021) dir. Adam Robital<br />
The first one was good so they made another one, and it was decent but not as good. In fairness, that’s the story of sequels everywhere (with the exception of Shrek 2). We’ve got a Catching Fire scenario where winners of previous games get roped back in. There’s interesting backstory for Minos, the corporation that does the escape rooms and some pretty rad puzzles (the one on the subway car was my favorite). This one’s generally a good time, if not very inspired. Tournament sequel-baits, and I’d watch a third!</p>
<p>4. Escape Room (2017) dir. Will Wernick<br />
Has all the ingredients of a good film but isn’t that great. It’s a decent slasher, and “The Teddy Bear Picnic” is a creepy soundtrack, but overall, it’s not too impressive.</p>
<p>5. Escape Room (2017) dir. Peter Dukes<br />
This one just misses the mark. The beginning is…basically Jumanji? Anyway there’s this demon infested box, which is the most cursed object in the world. It is called “the skullbox.” A guy buys it for his escape room.</p>
<p>Well, technically he steals it after the Cryptic Antique Dealer goes to talk to someone on the phone about gremlins. (Yes, the ones from Gremlins.) She has told him that the prominently displayed box in her store is not for sale, and then leaves him alone with it. I guess technically he leaves some money on the counter, but she doesn’t seem to bothered either way. What’s a demon-box here or there?</p>
<p>As expected, integration of the demon box into the escape room goes poorly, and the actor dude ends up possessed and murdering everyone while they solve the clues. Then, of course, he possesses someone else and the credits roll.</p>
<p>Final verdict: Watch Escape Room (2019) and skip the rest—with the possible exception of No Escape Room for a rainy day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/eve-watches-all-the-escape-room-horror-movies-so-you-dont-have-to/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
