<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>KC on YA &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/kc-on-ya/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:06:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Book Review: The Firefly Code (Megan Frazer Blakemore)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-the-firefly-code-megan-frazer-blakemore/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 10:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[KC on YA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8209</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This middle grade sci-fi story was recommended to me by a friend interning at Bloomsbury&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-8210" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/firefly-code.jpg" alt="" width="183" height="276" />This middle grade sci-fi story was recommended to me by a friend interning at Bloomsbury around the time it was published. Knowing my bent for science fiction, he sent the recommendation my way. It took me a while to get to it, partly because I was reading a stack of young adult books at the time and didn’t want to switch gears to middle grade (yes, I get caught in an “age group” rut sometimes) and partly because it didn’t actually look that much like a sci-fi book. To me, the cover looks more like a fantasy or contemporary story, so I was thrilled to learn, when I started reading, that it’s pure sci-fi and it deals with the questions I love thinking about, like the nature of humanity. What makes us truly human? How much genetic engineering can we do to ourselves before we turn into something else? Where’s the line between “natural” and “manufactured” when it comes to life on this planet?</p>
<p>What’s particularly amazing about this book is that author <a href="http://www.meganfrazer.com/">Megan Frazer Blakemore</a> manages to prod at these huge questions in a manner that’s not only accessible to younger readers, but that’s downright engaging. I seriously couldn’t put the book down, and neither could my kids when they read it.</p>
<p>The book got me to wondering why we don’t see more sci-fi books for this age group that probe the nature of humanity in this way (science getting out of control is a very accessible conceit for middle grade readers). I’ve seen quite a few spaceship stories on the middle grade shelves in recent years, but nothing more down-to-earth, so to speak.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26073153-the-firefly-code?from_search=true"><em>The Firefly Code</em></a> has engaging characters facing an unusual world with some really challenging moral dilemmas. The characters are well-drawn, and each of the group of friends that shares the spotlight with protagonist Mori contributes an important perspective to the story, as well as providing lots of friendly (and sometimes frenemy-like) banter and competition.</p>
<p>The ending is a little ambiguous, but not in a way that I think would cause unrest or unease to younger readers. I’m guessing it’s intended to make them think about scientific ethics in a complex world and what we want our future to look like, and I suspect most of today’s younger readers are ready and yearning for the challenge.</p>
<p>Blakemore has combined a fun, engaging narrative with just the right undercurrent of unease, concern and mystery. I’d highly recommend this for readers of any age.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Brother&#8217;s Ruin (Emma Newman)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-brothers-ruin-emma-newman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 16:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[KC on YA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I know a lot of writers manage to move back and forth between hard sci-fi&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-8342" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/brothers-ruin.jpg" alt="" width="177" height="284" />I know a lot of writers manage to move back and forth between hard sci-fi and fantasy without any trouble, and Emma Newman is definitely one of them. My hat is off to authors who understand the nuances of the different genres and manage to create engaging characters and develop engaging worlds whatever the genre or likely market. In <em>Brother’s Ruin</em>, Newman has obviously slipped a first toe into the water of what promises to be a much longer and richer fantasy series. This book is, in many ways, a prologue for a longer work. The volume is less than 200 pages, reading almost like a novella, but it introduces the key players and positions them on the chessboard in anticipation of more adventures to come.</p>
<p>Charlotte (Charlie) is our young protagonist in an alternate Victorian society in which magic exists and the houses of magic are juxtaposed with the nobility in government. For some, being identified as latent in magic promises rewards of financial recompense for their families and positions of power in the magical academies. For others, like Charlie, the thought of exposing herself as a holder of magic would ruin her life. She would have to leave her family, wouldn’t be able to marry, and would effectively lose her freedom. In fact, the book explores the meaning of freedom in various contexts. How free can a young woman (of secretly independent means) hope to become in any walk of this society?</p>
<p>There is much second-guessing of right and wrong, good and evil, strength and weakness, all set against a richly detailed backdrop of a society that is very Victorian, but where the underpinnings of the society are threatened by the presence of magic. In some ways, this work reminded me a little of Victoria Schwab’s recently completed <em>Shades of Light</em> trilogy. For those who like fantasy, alternate history, and a straight up good story, I’d highly recommend <em>Brother’s Ruin</em>. While it’s not technically a YA book (at least I don’t think it’s intended to be), it would definitely be suitable for younger and older readers alike.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tempus Fugit &#8230; (or does it?)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/tempus-fugit-or-does-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 16:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[KC on YA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lately I’ve been reading a lot of draft manuscripts, including a couple of my own,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8206 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/tempus-fugit.jpg" alt="" width="282" height="179" />Lately I’ve been reading a lot of draft manuscripts, including a couple of my own, and for some reason I started thinking about the use of “time” in story structure. It may be a function of what was on my desk this week, or something deeper and more profound, but as writers we don’t seem to often talk about the specifics of time movement in our work. We hear lots of general guidelines like “avoid opening with a flashback” or “avoid too much backstory; it can interrupt pacing.” We even hear things like “the pacing lags in your piece.” But generally these comments are vague shorthand for a feeling someone has about the manuscript in terms of the emotion – or lack thereof – on the page. Probably the most specific thing I’ve heard consistently about time in the editing/critiquing context is that when you write an action scene it’s good to use short, sharp sentences to convey a faster pace.</p>
<p>What about time writ large?</p>
<p>What more can we do with time in our writing to create the emotional depth we’re seeking in our work?</p>
<p>I found myself recently suggesting to a writer that she compress the time period over which her short story took place on the basis that there was no apparent need for the story to take 12 months when it could just as easily take two or three. That was simply a gut feeling on my part. My thought was that compressing the time period would raise the tension in the piece (the genre was psychological mystery so tension on the page was particularly important).</p>
<p>When I’ve taught flash fiction (stories typically between 500 and 1,000 words) I’ve suggested avoiding any kinds of unnecessary time jumps (backstory, flash forwards etc) and simply keeping the reader in the present moment of the story. I’ve seen flash forwards (forward time jumps) done effectively in flash in some circumstances, but backstory hardly ever seems to work in such a compressed story form.</p>
<p>I find myself thinking about time much more in short pieces than in novels and novellas. And epic novels are another story altogether. I just finished reading the third and final book of <a href="http://enterthepassage.com/">Justin Cronin’s <em>The Passage</em> trilogy </a>and he ends up spanning centuries (more accurately, millennia) and jumping backward and forward in time, inserting lengthy backstory etc all over the place. In that context, it works for the most part.</p>
<p>So is it true that we need to be more careful about the passage of time in shorter works than in longer pieces? I don&#8217;t know for sure but it seems plausible (although there&#8217;s no excuse for a longer piece that drags and loses the reader because of a lack of pacing.)</p>
<p>What&#8217;s the best approach to handling time in the writing context?</p>
<p>I’d love to hear what other writers think about this.</p>
<p>I suppose it’ll all become clear to me in a matter of time …</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Humble Kitchen-Timer: An Underappreciated Writer&#8217;s Friend</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-humble-kitchen-timer-an-underappreciated-writers-friend/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[KC on YA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Writers often complain about how it’s impossible to organize our writing time because we&#8217;re always distracted&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-8011 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/OWL-TIMER-169x300.jpg" alt="" width="169" height="300" />Writers often complain about how it’s impossible to organize our writing time because we&#8217;re always distracted by other things. Very often those other things revolve around computer screens, smartphones, iPads etc. We know we *can* turn off the computer (or at least the Internet connection), but we don’t *want* to. We can even download software that temporarily disables our Internet connectivity for a time so we can focus on writing.</p>
<p>I usually don’t worry too much about any of that stuff when I write. I seem to have two binary modes of writing: I’m either at the computer with the Internet on, or not at the computer at all. Often I’m at the computer when I’m revising, but sitting in a library or coffee shop with a notepad when I’m writing a first draft.</p>
<p>Be that as it may, how many of you have also heard the advice to turn everything off, use a kitchen timer (i.e. not a smartphone timer or iPod timer) and find 10, 20, 30 minutes in a day to sit quietly and write?</p>
<p>Well, last week I finally bought myself a GOOD OLD-FASHIONED KITCHEN TIMER exactly for this purpose (see picture!) Actually, I bought two because the first one didn’t work and Amazon was kind enough to send a replacement.</p>
<p>Did I think I would use the thing?</p>
<p>Not really – just seemed like a cute idea at the time.</p>
<p>BUT then I did use it for writing by myself and with friends. Having a good old-fashioned mechanical, and happy-looking owl watch over (and time) my writing, somehow seemed to create a different feeling for me. Sitting with my owl is somehow a happier and more grass-rootsy experience than sitting with technology.</p>
<p>But that’s not all!</p>
<p>A friend recently suggested that these timers are good for other things we might face in the writing life: for example, REJECTION.</p>
<p>We all face it and it’s horrible. Processing a rejection (particularly if accompanied by suggestions about everything you’re doing wrong with your work) is hard work in itself. The suggestions and comments are usually constructive, or at least intended to be constructive, but there’s no way your ego won’t be a tiny bit bruised at least the first time you read or listen to them.</p>
<p>So my friend suggested using the timer to process the negative emotion attached to rejection. Set the timer and give yourself 10, 20, 30 minutes (an hour, two – whatever it takes) just to let yourself process those nasty bad feelings, and then, when the bell rings, move on.</p>
<p>This is my new mantra. Those negative feelings aren’t bad or wrong. They do need to be processed, but you can’t give them free rein. A timer can help you out with that, and if you have a nice friendly-looking timer like my little owl, so much the better.</p>
<p>Maybe I’m getting jaded by our technological, always switched-on, digital world, a world in which feelings have to be processed in six seconds or less so we can move on to the next important thing, and in which instant gratification is more important than laying the foundations for long term creation. (Ugh, I seem to be up on a soapbox now.) But don’t shortchange the humble kitchen timer as a writer’s friend. Keep one in your glove box or your carry bag so you always have it with you should the urge take you to jot down some thoughts or to process a negative emotion. I’m partial to owls for some reason, but find one that you like and consider adopting him, her or it as a little writing buddy. The idea may not be as silly as it sounds!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Bad Beginning &#8230;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-bad-beginning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 17:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[KC on YA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[… can spell the end of your book, or at least set you back a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>… can spell the end of your book, or at least set you back a few paces.</p>
<p>It seems unfair that so much emphasis is placed on the first 10-20 pages of a novel. What about all those amazing plot developments in chapter five? That huge reveal in chapter seven that the antagonist is really the protagonist’s long lost [fill in the blank]? And that tear-jerker of an ending!!</p>
<p>But think about it. Are you going to keep reading a book that doesn’t hold your interest in chapter one? Or even page one, paragraph one, or line one?</p>
<p>The beginning of your book has a lot of important work to do:</p>
<ul>
<li>It should introduce us to the main character(s).</li>
<li>It should give us at least a hint of what that character wants and what’s standing in her way.</li>
<li>It should give us some sense of the setting – where and when the story takes place and why we should care about the people in it.</li>
<li>It should NOT contain information that the reader doesn’t need to know until later in the story.</li>
<li>Most importantly, it is the foundation stone for the rest of the book. In terms of story structure, the backbone is seeded in those first pages.</li>
</ul>
<p><a class="left-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/index-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-8049 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/index-2-300x159.jpg" width="300" height="159" /></a>How do we write that first line, first paragraph, first page, or first chapter with all the weight of the world (or at least the weight of the plot) on its (and our) shoulders?</p>
<p>The most important thing to keep in mind is that your first draft will not be your final draft, so take that weight off your shoulders right now and simply get something down on the page. It doesn’t matter if it’s terrible. It doesn’t even matter if it ends up not being the right place to start the story. In my work as a developmental editor, and in my own writing, I sometimes realize that where the story starts (as currently written) is not its true beginning. I’ll often advise other writers – or myself, as the case may be – to dump the existing first chapters and take any important information from them to sprinkle later into the story when the reader really needs to know it.</p>
<p>You may not know exactly what the reader needs to know at what point in the story until well after you’ve written the first draft, but that’s fine. That’s what revision is for.</p>
<p>A very smart author, and one of my favorite M.F.A. advisors, once told me that a novel’s beginning “should shake hands with the ending.” This is a reminder of how important the beginning is as the foundation stone of the story. What are you going to seed in the first chapter that will pay off in dividends later? Remember that in the classic hero’s journey (or heroine’s journey), it’s often said that when the hero returns home after her adventure, she must be changed in some significant way. The protagonist at the end of the book is different from the protagonist who first sets out on the journey. She’s been challenged and changed by the story&#8217;s events. Keeping the relationship between the beginning and the ending in mind when you write is a great way to keep a handle on character development.</p>
<p>One of my favorite writing exercises is to picture the final scene of the story and work backwards from there, either drafting or outlining. This will ensure a consistent storyline where the beginning does indeed shake hands with the ending. Most of us outline from the beginning to the end, but doing it the other way around is sometimes helpful.</p>
<p>Of course, now I’m getting into overall story structure when I’m supposed to be talking about beginnings!</p>
<p>What should be in a good beginning?</p>
<blockquote><p>There are exceptions to ALL the rules, like with the dialogue example above, but it’s easier to justify an exception if you understand the rules.</p></blockquote>
<p>Well, that’s pretty obvious. I’m sure we’ve all heard something like the following in whatever writing classes we’ve taken or craft books we’ve read:</p>
<p>The first chapter should include a main character in a challenging setting with the promise of an adventure to come. It should introduce the stakes for the character, and the kinds of obstacles likely to be in her way. We also want to see a “hook” or “inciting incident.” As another of my M.F.A. advisors put it, “What makes this day different from any other day in the protagonist’s life?” In other words, what has changed that makes the character need to take action and embark on the story?</p>
<p>The problem is that you can do ALL of this and still have a bad beginning if you fall into any of the following traps:</p>
<p><strong><u>The dreaded info-dump</u>.</strong> This can happen when we’ve introduced all the key elements of the story described above, but have also added a ton of weighty and unnecessary exposition – information about the characters, setting, political scene etc that the reader doesn’t need to know until later, if at all.</p>
<p><strong><u>Purple prose.</u> </strong>Again, you can hit all the important points described above for a good beginning, but immediately alienate your reader with a florid, dense, or even dull writing style. Adjectives and adverbs usually aren’t your friends here. Neither are overly descriptive speech tags in dialogue. “Said” and “asked” are always your best bets.</p>
<p><strong><u>Disorienting the reader</u>.</strong> This is a tricky one. On the one hand we don’t want to give everything away in the first chapter. We want to avoid info-dumps and we want to give the reader some work to do in figuring things out. On the other hand, if you pull all your punches, relying on big reveals later, you may end up with a confused and annoyed reader who puts your book down. You may want your reader to be disoriented in a good way, in a way that makes them want to know more. However, you don’t want them to be frustrated and annoyed with you. In the YA dystopian genre, <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2767052-the-hunger-games"><em>The Hunger Games </em></a>by Suzanne Collins and <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10429045-shatter-me?from_search=true"><em>Shatter Me</em></a> by Tahereh Mafi are good examples of books that disorient the reader in a good way. The reader has a lot of questions at the end of those first chapters, but also has a sense of who the protagonist is, what she’s like, what she wants etc.</p>
<p><a class="left-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/24178.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-8048 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/24178-200x300.jpg" width="200" height="300" /></a>A specific example of disorienting the reader too much is starting the book with a line of dialogue. Many authors, editors and agents suggest avoiding starting this way because the reader has no idea who’s saying the words, where they are, or why we should care. Of course, many great books and stories DO start with lines of dialogue. The most cited in children’s literature is probably <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24178.Charlotte_s_Web?from_search=true"><em>Charlotte’s Web</em></a> by E.B. White. It’s hard to think of a better opening line than: “ ‘Where’s Papa going with that axe?’ said Fern to her mother as they were setting the table for breakfast.”</p>
<p>Note that: (a) this is a GREAT line of dialogue; (b) it does introduce the characters – a mother and a father and a young daughter are all included between the dialogue and the dialogue tag; (c) the fact that Fern and her mother are setting the table for breakfast tells you a little something about the setting. In other words, along with being an exception to the rule, this sentence also does a lot to orient the reader in the story. So if you ARE considering starting with a line of dialogue, make sure you give the reader something to go on about who’s speaking and where they are.</p>
<p>Some other tips about what NOT to start with (and these are all from agents and editors I’ve spoken to) include.</p>
<ul>
<li>Don’t start with the character getting up in the morning, putting on her slippers and brushing her teeth. It’s overdone and boring!</li>
<li>Don’t start with a dream the character had the night before she got up in the morning, put on her slippers etc. Also overdone.</li>
<li>Don’t start with a weather report. Why would we care if it’s a “dark and stormy night” if we don’t know who the protagonist is and what her problem is (unless maybe her problem IS the weather …)</li>
<li>Avoid prologues for the sake of flowery prose, but if you need a prologue in terms of information the reader has to know before the story starts, go for it! (Just be careful you’re sure you’re doing it for a good story reason and not to show off your writing style.)</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course there are exceptions to ALL the rules, like with the dialogue example above, but it’s easier to justify an exception if you understand the rules.</p>
<p>Beginnings are hard. There’s no question about it. And you won’t get it right the first time. You should think about what needs to be in your first chapter, and why, and proceed from there. Your thoughts will change as you draft more of the story and you may decide to draft or outline from back to front or completely out of order. That’s okay. You’ll go back to your opening lines and chapters again and again until they sparkle and they’re ready for prime time. Don’t sweat the early drafts!</p>
<p>(cross posted from <a href="http://savvyauthors.com/blog/avoiding-bad-beginning-jacqui-lipton/">Savvy Authors Blog</a>, February 1, 2017)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: &#8220;The Hero is You&#8221; (Kendra Levin)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-the-hero-is-you-kendra-levin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 17:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[KC on YA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Usually I review young adult and middle grade speculative fiction books here, but if I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7815 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/hero-is-you.jpg" width="183" height="275" />Usually I review young adult and middle grade speculative fiction books here, but if I find a craft or craft-related book that I think is really worthwhile, I’ll add it to the mix. That was definitely the case with Kendra Levin’s <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hero-You-Sharpen-Conquer-Demons/dp/1573246883"><em>The Hero is You</em> </a> (2016). It’s not a traditional craft book, but rather a book about a writer’s process based on Levin’s many years of experience as a life coach for authors and artistic professionals. She takes the unusual approaching of re-crafting the classic hero’s journey from literature as a structure to guide a writer’s process in a fascinating and effective way. The book can be read straight through or in chunks that are relevant to particular parts of an individual’s journey. It’s definitely a book many writers will dip back into, in whole or in part, over the years. She also includes a ton of really wonderful exercises geared toward writers who are better trying to understand their process and what gets in their way. So while you’re learning about who you are and how your process works, you’re also <em>writing</em> if you undertake the exercises. Levin is so well read and experienced that she draws from literature, psychology, her own coaching practice and observations from her own life and career to illustrate the points she makes in each chapter. The entire book is around 200 pages so you could easily read it in one sitting without doing the exercises, but even reading without attempting all the exercises, I found that I wanted to take my time with it and really pause to mull over the issues she raised in each chapter and section. The book is extremely hard to describe, and no description would probably do justice to the unusual but highly effective approach Levin takes here. I wholeheartedly suggest dipping into a copy and experiencing the fascinating approach to a writer’s process firsthand.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Precipice: Write On or Fall Back?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-precipice-write-on-or-fall-back/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[KC on YA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve often received two seemingly contradictory pieces of advice as a writer when I face&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve often received two seemingly contradictory pieces of advice as a writer when I face a problematic section of a manuscript and feel like I can’t go on. So I thought, what better way to try and tease them apart than to blog about it?<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7809 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/GoatPrecipice-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></p>
<p>Think about those days when you absolutely can’t write another word. You know you’re supposed to. It’s part of your writing schedule. You’re on track to finish this draft if you just get your butt into that chair and do it. You even  know what’s supposed to happen in the next scene, so it’s not really writer’s block, but something is stopping you from putting pen to paper, or fingers to the keyboard.</p>
<p>Smarter and more experienced writers than I have suggested two strategies to deal with this situation:</p>
<p>1/ Push through the pain and write on. The fact that you are resisting moving forward means there’s something worth digging into there.</p>
<p>2/ Give yourself a break. Maybe your writer’s well is exhausted and you need to take your mind off it and refresh your writing brain.</p>
<p>Both are good pieces of advice and both can work well in the appropriate situation, even though they seem contradictory. I suspect each works in certain situations, but not others, and I have trouble knowing when to move forward versus when to give myself a break. If I&#8217;m prevaricating over something I’m scared of writing, I probably need to take the first approach (move forward) but if I&#8217;m confused about what happens next, I probably need a break. The risk is that if I confuse the two situations and give myself a break when what I&#8217;m facing is fear rather than confusion about what happens next in the story, I might continue to give myself break after break and never finish.</p>
<p>How does a writer know which situation is which?</p>
<p>Sometimes if I force myself to sit and write for 20 minutes however washed out I feel, it becomes obvious pretty quickly whether my brain needs a rest or whether I was only scared. If the 20 minutes turns seamlessly into two hours without me noticing the time flying by, I was likely in the first (fear) scenario, but if I literally can’t write another word after five minutes, chances are that I was in the second (exhaustion) scenario.</p>
<p>What do I do if I can&#8217;t even get as far as sitting down to write for 20 minutes?</p>
<p>Maybe I need to ask myself the question: Do I know what happens next in my story?</p>
<p>If I do and I’m simply resisting writing it, chances are I’m facing fear rather than exhaustion and I need to make myself sit down and do it.</p>
<p>If I have no idea what the characters are going to do next, chances are I need to refill my creative well before I write anything.</p>
<p>Has anyone else ever faced this “fight or flight” conundrum with a particular scene, chapter or story? Any other good tips for how to deal with the problem?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Matching Obstacles to Character Desires</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/matching-obstacles-to-character-desires/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 17:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[KC on YA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It won’t be news to many writers that one of the best ways of creating&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7741 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/obstacles.jpg" width="276" height="182" />It won’t be news to many writers that one of the best ways of creating narrative tension on the page is to give a character a powerful desire and then throw obstacles in her way. The character’s ability to overcome obstacles and move forward is what creates the tension that will make the reader keep reading.</p>
<p>What we don’t talk about so often is how to select the most effective obstacles to test our character’s fortitude, and ability to overcome whatever is standing in her way. By this, I’m not asking how we choose whether the most effective obstacle is, say, a person versus a raging river (although that’s an important choice too.) Rather, I’m talking about the gravity of the obstacle, and the degree of difficulty inherent in overcoming it.</p>
<p>The reason I’ve been thinking about this lately is that in critiquing my own work, and the work of friends, I’ve realized that sometimes an obstacle isn’t really an obstacle. It’s more of a little hiccup in the road. At other times, what looks like an obstacle is actually an insurmountable wall for the character, and the character’s inability to conquer it can make that character seem passive or hopeless.</p>
<p>Of course we don’t mind if our characters have hopeless moments before they regroup and succeed, or before deciding to head home and give up on the journey having learned something about their limits. However, what we don’t want is for the character to stand in front of the wall shaking her head and seeming confused and without direction.</p>
<p>While desires and obstacles are a basic part of most hero’s (and heroine’s) journeys, we don’t always talk about crafting obstacles of an <em>appropriate magnitude</em> to maximize tension.</p>
<p>If a desire is too weak and an obstacle too strong, the character is likely to give up, and that will create a very unsatisfying reading experience.</p>
<p>By the same token, if the desire is strong, but the obstacle is minimal and easy to overcome, the reading experience will be equally unsatisfying.</p>
<p>By “strong” and “weak,” I mean in terms of their significance to the character. A desire for a pink party dress can be a very strong desire if there is a powerful narrative reason why the dress is important to the character, and she’ll go to great lengths and defy serious odds to achieve it.</p>
<p>If my character has to fight her way through an inhospitable jungle to get to safety, I might throw obstacles in her way like mountains that are difficult to climb, rivers that are difficult to cross, armed bandits chasing her etc. But I have to make it possible for her to confront and conquer, or at the very least to somehow circumnavigate, the obstacles. If I make the mountains too high, the river impassable (with no alternate routes available) and the bandits too formidable, it won’t be much of a story, especially if the setup leaves my characters dispirited and befuddled, potentially along with my readers.</p>
<p>It might be worthwhile at some point in your writing to create a list of obstacles and the stakes attached to them for the character to ensure that the degree of difficulty and the stakes are escalating (if that’s the effect you want) or at least the obstacles are sufficiently challenging, without being impossible for the character to confront in some meaningful way.</p>
<p>Even if your ultimate message is that a specific obstacle is too steep and your character has to learn when to give up, you’ll still want to match the magnitude of the obstacle with what you want the character to learn from it in terms of her narrative stakes. Whether or not your character ultimately succeeds and experiences a happy ending, versus fails and ends up losing, the desire-to-obstacle ratio should ideally support your character’s narrative arc and maintain sufficient tension on the page to engage the reader.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Or is It? (THE SINGING BONES by Shaun Tan)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-or-is-it-the-singing-bones-by-shaun-tan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[KC on YA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Intrigued by recent advertisements, I wandered over to the library to check out a copy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7660 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/singing-bones.jpg" alt="singing-bones" width="196" height="257" />Intrigued by recent advertisements, I wandered over to the library to check out a copy of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Singing-Bones-Shaun-Tan/dp/0545946123"><em>The Singing Bones</em></a> by <a href="http://www.shauntan.net/">Shaun Tan</a>. All I knew was that it had something to do with fairy-tales and boasted a foreword by Neil Gaiman.</p>
<p>I’m also highly embarrassed to admit I haven’t read (if that’s the correct word in relation to the work of someone who writes graphic novels and wordless picture books) any of Tan’s work before.</p>
<p><em>The Singing Bones</em> made me question my definition of a “book” and what we mean by &#8220;reading&#8221; a book. It’s really a collection of beautiful plates of sculptures Tan created to illustrate characters/scenes from classic Grimm Brothers fairy-tales along with snippets from the tales themselves.</p>
<p>Thus, it’s not so much a “reading” experience, but more like a total immersion into Tan’s mind, an insight into the images the tales conjure up for him.</p>
<p>This probably isn’t surprising for an author/illustrator/artist who spans so many different aspects of the creative enterprise and whose output has been eclectic (an understatement).</p>
<p>Because <em>The Singing Bones</em> isn’t really a book, I guess this isn’t really a “book review,” but I can say delving into the pages of this volume was a breathtaking experience. Some of those images will be with me for a long time. The book itself would be a marvelous holiday gift because it feels more like a collector’s item than a simple children’s book. In fact, it doesn&#8217;t feel like a children&#8217;s book at all – although it’s marketed through children’s book channels, and children would be sure to love it too. It’s really, I think, an artifact that is ageless and timeless in its appeal and the reader comes away with such a fresh new perspective on what we mean by storytelling that I highly recommend diving into if you can get your hands on a copy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Mindy McGinnis (&#8220;The Female of the Species&#8221;)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-mindy-mcginnis-the-female-of-the-species/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 17:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KC on YA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7648</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m delighted to be sharing a recent interview with YA writer extraordinaire, Mindy McGinnis, about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7649 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/spcies.jpg" alt="species" width="182" height="276" />I’m delighted to be sharing a recent interview with YA writer extraordinaire, <a href="http://mindymcginnis.com/">Mindy McGinnis</a>, about her new novel,<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Female-Species-Mindy-McGinnis/dp/0062320890/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1480429375&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=female+of+the+species"> THE FEMALE OF THE SPECIES</a>. She’s one of the most eclectic YA writers out there, moving between genres so fast it could make your head spin – and mastering all of them (and she also loves cats!) When I asked her about her new novel, here’s what she had to say …</p>
<p><strong>KC</strong><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Female-Species-Mindy-McGinnis/dp/0062320890/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1480428371&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=the+female+of+the+species">: THE FEMALE OF THE SPECIES</a> is a very different book for you, although your novels to date have been somewhat eclectic in terms of genre (dystopian, historical fiction/horror, and now teen vigilante justice). In your author notes you say that you&#8217;d actually written a draft of this book 15 years ago and decided to dust it off now. What was the original inspiration for the book, what prompted you to dust it off now, and what were the main things that changed between the original version and the final published version?</p>
<p><strong>MM</strong>: I was in college when I ran into the inspiration for SPECIES. I never had cable television growing up, so my freshman year in a dorm I was suddenly mainlining all kinds of things, but especially true crime. I watched a mini-doc about a girl who had been raped and murdered in a small town, but there wasn&#8217;t enough evidence to convict. Even so, everyone knew who did it. I was watching this becoming more incensed, and realized, that if I were capable of it, I could easily find this town, find that mine, and take care of things myself. Then I thought it was probably time to turn off the TV.</p>
<p><strong>KC</strong>: If I&#8217;m remembering correctly, this is the first book you&#8217;ve written from multiple/alternating points of view. Did you find writing the alternating characters&#8217; viewpoints challenging or freeing, or a little of both?</p>
<p><strong>MM</strong>: It was my first time for alternating POV&#8217;s, although I was also drafting a fantasy (GIVEN TO THE SEA) at the same time, which has four alternating POV&#8217;s, two male and two female. Even so, SPECIES came first, and more importantly than being my first POV dive, it was my first time writing a male MC, first person. So that was something I wanted to make sure I got right. I had various male readers and critique partners, so that I would know I was in the head of a teen boy, both for the good and the bad.</p>
<p><strong>KC</strong>: This is also your first contemporary YA &#8211; your previous books have been set respectively in the future and the past. How did you find the worldbuilding aspects of creating a contemporary township for this book versus a dystopia (in your<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Not-Drop-Drink-Mindy-McGinnis/dp/0062198505">NOT A DROP TO DRINK</a></span> duology) and a historically accurate past (in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Madness-So-Discreet-Mindy-McGinnis/dp/0062320874/ref=pd_sbs_14_t_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;psc=1&amp;refRID=G03CYRFQ0JF330SCVQBP">A MADNESS SO DISCREET</a>)?</p>
<p><strong>MM</strong>: Ha &#8211; this one was a breeze in that respect! I&#8217;ve worked in a high school for 15 years, so I know the voice, I know the small town environment, and I know the narrators. Once when I was writing MADNESS I had to stop and do 15 minutes of research just to figure out what policemen were called in 1890 Boston. Here &#8230; so much easier!</p>
<p><strong>KC</strong>:  One thing that has stayed with me very viscerally since reading the book is your depiction of the scene where the cop speaks at the high school assembly about drug and alcohol abuse and does so in a very different way to what the students (and probably readers) were expecting. What was the inspiration for Officer Nolan&#8217;s character and how did you come up with his approach to educating teens about alcohol and drugs?</p>
<p><strong>MM</strong>: We had a task force come into the school to educate the staff about different drugs, their uses / effects and paraphernalia. The guy was amazing, because he made everything personal. But he also talked to us like adults (which we were), and I couldn&#8217;t help but think, Geez, I wish he could come in and talk to the kids like that. Whenever there&#8217;s an assembly that is about safety &#8211; drugs, alcohol, sex, whatever &#8211; it&#8217;s typically condescending and very antiseptic. They kids are bored and it has no impact. So I wrote what I thought would actually <em>work</em>.</p>
<p><strong>KC</strong>:  Do you have a plan for your next book that you can share with us?</p>
<p><strong>MM</strong>: I do! My first fantasy, titled GIVEN TO THE SEA will be releasing from Penguin/Putnam on April 11, 2017. It is the first in a duology. I also have another contemporary coming from Harper in the Fall of 2017, titled THIS DARKNESS MINE.</p>
<p><em>Thanks for sharing your time and thoughts with us, Mindy! Write on!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
