<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Girl of Words &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/girl-of-words/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 21:56:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Review: The Midnight Bargain (C.L. Polk)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-midnight-bargain-c-l-polk/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katarina Betterton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 11:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girl of Words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=23217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, all!  I’m thrilled to bring my next review to you today for The Midnight&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hello, all! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m thrilled to bring my next review to you today for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Midnight Bargain</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by C. L. Polk.</span></p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium aligncenter" src="https://bookjockeyalex.files.wordpress.com/2020/10/midnightbargain-feat.png" width="1200" height="727" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">4.5/5 stars</span></p>
</blockquote>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Book Blurb</span></h1>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Midnight-Bargain-C-L-Polk/dp/1645660079"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sourced from Amazon</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beatrice Clayborn is a sorceress who practices magic in secret, terrified of the day she will be locked into a marital collar that will cut off her powers to protect her unborn children. She dreams of becoming a full-fledged Magus and pursuing magic as her calling as men do, but her family has staked everything to equip her for Bargaining Season, when young men and women of </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">means descend upon the city to negotiate the best marriages. The Clayborns are in severe debt and only she can save them, by securing an advantageous match before their creditors come calling. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a stroke of luck, Beatrice finds a grimoire that contains the key to becoming a Magus, but before she can purchase it, a rival sorceress swindles the book right out of her hands. Beatrice summons a spirit to help her get it back, but her new ally exacts a price: Beatrice’s first kiss . . . with her adversary’s brother, the handsome, compassionate, and fabulously wealthy Ianthe Lavan. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The more Beatrice is entangled with the Lavan siblings, the harder her decision becomes: If she casts the spell to become a Magus, she will devastate her family and lose the only man to ever see her for who she is; but if she marries—even for love—she will sacrifice her magic, her identity, and her dreams. But how can she choose just one, knowing she will forever regret the path not taken?</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall Thoughts</span></h1>
<p><img decoding="async" class=" alignright" src="https://i.cbc.ca/1.5827741.1609886214!/fileImage/httpImage/image.png_gen/derivatives/16x9_940/the-midnight-bargain-by-c-l-polk.png" width="362" height="204" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honestly, it took awhile for me to get into the book but once I did, I couldn’t stop reading.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I thought this was a really well-done novel. It did a great job of presenting gender inequality in a new and exciting way; I definitely felt connected to (and rooted for) the main character/narrator; and as a standalone, it had an HEA that was both satisfying and open to interpretation to let the reader decide what was next for the characters.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the acknowledgements, Polk describes an early pitch as “Pokemon, but make it Jane Austen,” and that’s almost exactly what it felt like (but switch out Pokemon for Black Clover and it’s there). I originally picked up the book because I was interested to read something that had grimoires in it and wasn’t disappointed. This is a great book for anyone who enjoys Regency Era-inspired settings, strong female characters, and a touch of magic/fantasy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Super petty, nitpicky thought: I think the book deserved a stronger title! I don’t know what it would be, but its current title references the first bargain that Beatrice makes when honestly, I don’t feel that sets everything in motion as much as the situation of the impending bargaining season vs. Beatrice’s desperate need to keep magic did.</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Characters</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beatrice was a great main character. Though her seemingly-unwinnable situation was the main conflict of the book, she had great agency. Just because she couldn’t get what she wanted doesn’t mean she didn’t try. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ysbeta was an awesome secondary character and I kind of wished she was the love interest instead of her brother. The author might not have tried it, but I definitely felt some chemistry between Beatrice and Ysbeta! She was a badass all around, and I looked forward to any scene with her in it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ianthe was a fine secondary character/love interest. I didn’t like him as a character by himself as much as I liked Beatrice/Ianthe together as a couple, but he wasn’t a bad character by any means. I loved his “knight in shining armor” disposition for the most part, he just seemed a little </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">too</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> perfect to be believable in some situations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The antagonists were really great. I’m a reader who enjoys stories where villains are constrained by society as much as the heroes and have to find surreptitious ways to mess with the protagonists’ plans. Danton Maisonette was my favorite over Mrs. Lavan (less of an antagonist and more of a stereotypical potential mother-in-law?).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My least favorite character in the book was Beatrice’s mom. I think a little more could have been done with her storyline.</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">World-Building</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23218 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/mcsnra2vrqq-300x199.jpg" alt="pink flowers" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/mcsnra2vrqq-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/mcsnra2vrqq-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/mcsnra2vrqq-768x509.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/mcsnra2vrqq-1536x1017.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/mcsnra2vrqq-2048x1356.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Polk really impressed me with the ease of her world-building. We’re jumping into a completely new historically-based fantasy world filled with magic, and I never felt like I got an info dump. In some places that was problematic for me (I didn’t always remember which towns/cities were which) but there was always enough context to figure it out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The spirits and grimoires were also done well. As I said earlier, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Black Clover</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> meets Jane Austen is one of the most accurate depictions I can make. As we spend more time with Beatrice and Nadi (a lesser spirit of fortune), it becomes clear to readers just how important—and dangerous—using magic and spirits can be, especially for anyone who can’t see the magic aura around another’s head. The magic-filled setting kept me on the edge of my seat for the second half of the book as I realized anyone that Beatrice interacted with was just a breath away from the ability to put a curse or hex on her.</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Plot</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The main conflict, for Beatrice to decide to marry the man she loves or keep her magic, keeps readers guessing until the last 20 or so pages. Throughout the book, we’re told that there’s literally no solution that will give the MC exactly what she wants, and that stress follows through the entire plot. In each scene, especially with Ianthe, there’s a sort of dark cloud hanging over what could be a perfect moment because Beatrice (and readers) know the only way this relationship flourishes is if Beatrice gives up the most important thing to her.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There weren’t many subplots (honestly, there wasn’t room!) but the one between Danielle Maisonette and Ianthe was kind of pointless to me. It gave Danton a more desperate edge to his “evilness” but Danielle never got closure/etc, at least that we saw, and it felt like the subplot was only created to give Danton more depth instead of Danielle, too.</span></p>
<p><b><em>SPOILERS BELOW!</em> </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One question I still have is regarding the warding collars: I thought I read earlier in the book that once a mage puts the collar on, they can no longer call a greater spirit? Beatrice has it placed on her twice but is still able to have Nadi (a lesser spirit) in her that then “evolves” into a greater spirit? Was that the way around that rule—binding with a lesser spirit that then evolves to a greater one?</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pacing</span></h1>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23222 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/i2kwra-nzzc-300x200.jpg" alt="architectural photography of brown and beige concrete house" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/i2kwra-nzzc-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/i2kwra-nzzc-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/i2kwra-nzzc-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/i2kwra-nzzc-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/i2kwra-nzzc-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ramp up to the meat of the story was long and not </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">terribly</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> exciting. If you can hold on for 200 pages, then the story really picks up. Most of the first portion of the book takes extra care in helping you learn about Beatrice, her relationship with magic, her family background and life, and to understand the social standing of the other characters. These 200 pages also make the stakes of Beatrice’s pending decision painstakingly clear to readers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The back half of the book’s pacing is incredible. The action is well written and romance scenes get enough time to blossom. I truthfully couldn’t put the book down after getting about halfway through—I needed to know what was going to happen next.</span></p>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Relationships</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As I stated before, I ship Beatrice and Ysbeta more than the actual pairing of Beatrice and Ianthe. But the Beatrice/Ianthe coupling was still charming and I definitely rooted for them to get an HEA.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beatrice and her sister Harriet had a nice sister relationship—reminiscent of Lizzie Bennett and a less impetuous, more clever Lydia. Beatrice’s relationship with her parents was a little wonky. I wished we had a bit more characterization of her father so his cruel coldness in the second half of the book was explained. I already said above that I wish Beatrice’s mother was more fleshed out. She seemed like she’d be a really interesting character. </span></p>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Thoughts</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This was a really great novel and I wish more people were talking about it. Beatrice was a strong female character who knew what she wanted and was willing to sacrifice everything she held close to do what she knew was right.</span></p>
<p><b>I definitely recommend </b><b><i>The Midnight Bargain</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Crown of Coral and Pearl (Mara Rutherford)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-crown-of-coral-and-pearl-mara-rutherford/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katarina Betterton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 11:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girl of Words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22986</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, all!  I’m thrilled to bring my third review to you today, this time for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hello, all! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m thrilled to bring my third review to you today, this time for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crown of Coral and Pearls</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by Mara Rutherford.</span></p>
<h1 style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">3/5 stars</span></h1>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Book Blurb</span></h2>
<p><a href="https://books.google.com/books/about/Crown_of_Coral_and_Pearl.html?id=fhuLDwAAQBAJ&amp;source=kp_book_description"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sourced from Google Books.</span></i></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium" src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/911Ly9q4dKL.jpg" width="1706" height="2560" />For generations, the princes of Ilara have married the most beautiful maidens from the ocean village of Varenia. But though every girl longs to be chosen as the next princess, the cost of becoming royalty is higher than any of them could ever imagine…</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nor once dreamed of seeing the wondrous wealth and beauty of Ilara, the kingdom that’s ruled her village for as long as anyone can remember. But when a childhood accident left her with a permanent scar, it became clear that her identical twin sister, Zadie, would likely be chosen to marry the Crown Prince &#8211; while Nor remained behind, unable to ever set foot on land.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then Zadie is gravely injured, and Nor is sent to Ilara in her place. To Nor’s dismay, her future husband, Prince Ceren, is as forbidding and cold as his home &#8211; a castle carved into a mountain and devoid of sunlight. And as she grows closer to Ceren’s brother, the charming Prince Talin, Nor uncovers startling truths about a failing royal bloodline, a murdered queen&#8230;and a plot to destroy the home she was once so eager to leave.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In order to save her people, Nor must learn to negotiate the treacherous protocols of a court where lies reign and obsession rules. But discovering her own formidable strength may be the one move that costs her everything: the crown, Varenia and Zadie.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall Thoughts</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve realized after the last few reviews I’m making the age-old mistake of judging a book by its cover (or more accurately, back blurb). I really thought I was going to fall in love with this book and its world, but I didn’t.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From my perspective, one of the book’s biggest downfalls was its awkward straddle of standalone/duology. I know it was sold as a standalone and had duology/series potential (as I write this I believe its sequel, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kingdom of Sea and Stone</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, is out) but to be honest, it didn’t feel like it needed a sequel to me.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, I wasn’t thrilled. There were a lot of issues that kept me from liking the book, which I’ll go into below.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Characters</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m a huge fan of first-person narration and tend to gravitate toward books that are written this way. Unfortunately, I think first-person narration is a slippery slope for writers to walk. If the character/voice isn’t relatable, it almost always ruins the book. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crown of Coral and Pearl</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, our narrator Nor wasn’t </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">unlikeable</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, per se, but I also didn’t feel like I could relate to her or that I wanted to root for her. She was probably my favorite character, but that’s not saying much, as I didn’t like anyone else in the cast either. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A quick note about character names: I loved the thought behind “Nor” and “Zadie” but I literally rolled my eyes at the princes’ names &#8211; just a masculine version of their mothers’ names. It’s small and petty but added another reason I wasn’t into the book.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think the hang-ups I have with these characters are their motivations. Everything read as half-baked; no one seemed to have an actual plan and just kind of did whatever they wanted. That’s fine, but there should have been someone to cull all those broken pieces of plot together instead of an out-of-the-blue sudden solution like there was.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The worst-written characters in the book were Prince Ceren (a weird Prince Joffrey knock-off with weak hints of Cardan) and Lady Melina (whose seemingly only purpose in the book was her last-spoken line, that easily could have been said by someone else).</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">World-Building</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22988 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tbef3aiybcs-225x300.jpg" alt="body of water during daytime" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tbef3aiybcs-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tbef3aiybcs-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tbef3aiybcs-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tbef3aiybcs-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/tbef3aiybcs-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />I actually loved the world of Varenia in the first portion of the book. When we move to Ilara the setting becomes less immersive, but it was still pretty vivid. Rutherford’s descriptions were a little lengthy for me, but as someone who tends to enjoy more info-dumping than the next person, it didn’t bother me that much.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The mythology was another story. It felt very jumbled… the only god I knew for sure was Thalos, who I believe is the god of the sea? I’m not a voracious fantasy reader, but even for me the mythology/religion didn’t seem super planned out and very basic &#8211; not unique at all.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Plot</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oof. The next three sections are going to get a bit scathing, so I apologize.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This book had little to no plot. Maybe it’s my fault that I read it after </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Folk of Air </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">series and I shouldn’t compare the titles… but c’mon. You can’t put “Nor must learn to negotiate the treacherous protocols of a court where lies reign and obsession rules” on the back cover and then </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">not deliver those things</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, right?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nor, who’s called Zadie most of the book (remember, they switcheroo’d?) isn’t shrewd, or clever, or intelligent. Any lucky break she gets is at the hand of someone else. Her actions read like a reckless, pouty child who’s mad about her lot in life and jumps into a reactive, rash plan instead of strategizing what will work best. I mention the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Folk of the Air </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">series because it’s a great example of what I think Rutherford was trying to accomplish. Jude from that series </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> clever. She has agency. She thinks through things. Nor, on the other hand, doesn’t seem to have agency and instead lets the wandering plot pull her every which way.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, why did the entire village need to know Nor was switching places with Zadie? Why couldn’t they have duped the entire village in addition to the Ilara kingdom? It seemed like a random, unnecessary stick to place in the metaphorical wheels of the plot. Maybe it was to give the sequel some drama with the Phaedra character, who is only named like 3/4th of the way through the book and apparently an unstoppable force? Don’t even get me started on her.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pacing</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don’t want to say I almost DNF’d this book (because I didn’t), but it was a pretty rough start. Again, I’m someone who doesn’t mind a good bit of world-building before the “big” inciting incident, but when that incident is the sisters’ switch and it takes dang near 150 pages for that to happen, I feel jipped as a reader. I kept flipping pages thinking </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">when is this damn story going to start?</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and honestly, never felt like it really did.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nothing very exciting happened throughout the book. Maybe the story was elongated in hopes of a sequel? Maybe I just didn’t get it? </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Relationships</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/leuxyh1kftg-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22990 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/leuxyh1kftg-300x200.jpg" alt="brown jellyfish in black background" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/leuxyh1kftg-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/leuxyh1kftg-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/leuxyh1kftg-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/leuxyh1kftg-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/leuxyh1kftg-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Let’s talk about the relationships between the MC and the other characters:</span></p>
<p><b>Nor and Zadie: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">By far the best relationship in the book, I just wish it was weaved throughout. When Nor leaves Varenia, it feels like that’s the last time she ever thinks of Zadie in a positive light. Throughout her time at New Castle, Nor only seems to compare herself to Zadie (while also acting in the exact opposite way she knows her sister would act) instead of talk about how much she misses her. When she does, however, those scenes are really good.</span></p>
<p><b>Nor and Sami: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">This was a really weird dynamic. It seemed like Nor was interested in him in the first few chapters, then we learn that Sami has always liked Zadie, then Zadie’s all coy until it’s too late, then all of a sudden Zadie’s willing to die for this dude and Nor’s a little jealous. The “brother-sister” dynamic was pounded into our heads with Nor and Sami but it really felt to float in the middle for me. That dynamic wasn’t 100% believable.</span></p>
<p><b>Nor and her father/mother: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I loved Nor’s relationship with her dad, and her mom turned into a piece of work out of the blue… so much so that she seemed almost as cruel as Prince Ceren? I wasn’t a fan of her mother’s characterization so most of my problems with their relationship stem from that.</span></p>
<p><b>Nor and Prince Ceren: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">I thought Prince Ceren was one of the worst-written characters in the book, which made his relationship with Nor beyond chaotic. There were hints of what the point of his characterization was throughout the book (a boy who felt he wasn’t worthy of love and pushed people away to test their loyalty) but it wasn’t executed well. Reading his relationship with Nor ended in whiplash with every scene.</span></p>
<p><b>Nor and Prince Talin: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Completely unbelievable romance. I was not rooting for them to get together. Also, do not tell me after seeing Nor for like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">one dinner</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a week before they met he could immediately tell the difference. </span></p>
<p><b>Nor and Ebb: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">This was a cute friendship, though semi-insignificant. </span></p>
<p><b>Nor and Lady Melina: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">As I believe Lady Melina was unnecessary to the plot, I believe this taboo friendship wasn’t needed either.</span></p>
<p><b>Nor and Lady Hyacinth: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honestly I have no idea why Lady Hyacinth was even in this book. She made no impression on the plot whatsoever.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Thoughts</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Look, as a writer who hopes to be published one day, I hate giving poor reviews. I do think constructive criticism is helpful, though, and will give this author another chance on another book series. As for this book though, I won’t mask my disappointment. I wanted </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">more</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from this story because it had really great bones. It just didn’t live up to my expectations, which was a bummer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I haven’t decided if I’m going to buy the sequel yet, because I honestly don’t really care what happens to any of the characters. The end was tied together nice enough for me to be satisfied with the ending.</span></p>
<p><strong>Did you read <em>Crown of Coral and Pearl</em> and love it? Hate it? Tell me in the comments!</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Folk of the Air Series (Holly Black)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-folk-of-the-air-series-holly-black/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-folk-of-the-air-series-holly-black/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katarina Betterton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 12:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girl of Words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22874</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, all!  I’m thrilled to bring my second review to you after devouring the Folk&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hello, all! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m thrilled to bring my second review to you after devouring the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Folk of the Air</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> series by Holly Black! The books (in order) are </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Cruel Prince, The Wicked King</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Queen of Nothing</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h1 style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">5/5 stars</span></h1>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Book Blurb</span></h2>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sourced from </span></i><a href="https://www.amazon.com/The-Folk-of-the-Air/dp/B07SL9FC7C"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amazon</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, based on the first book’s plot.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium alignright" src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/71MXGABh1kL.jpg" width="1105" height="1200" />Of course I want to be like them. They&#8217;re beautiful as blades forged in some divine fire. They will live forever.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And Cardan is even more beautiful than the rest. I hate him more than all the others. I hate him so much that sometimes when I look at him, I can hardly breathe.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jude was seven years old when her parents were murdered and she and her two sisters were stolen away to live in the treacherous High Court of Faerie. Ten years later, Jude wants nothing more than to belong there, despite her mortality. But many of the fey despise humans. Especially Prince Cardan, the youngest and wickedest son of the High King.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To win a place at the Court, she must defy him&#8211;and face the consequences.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In doing so, she becomes embroiled in palace intrigues and deceptions, discovering her own capacity for bloodshed. But as civil war threatens to drown the Courts of Faerie in violence, Jude will need to risk her life in a dangerous alliance to save her sisters, and Faerie itself.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #020202; font-family: 'Source Sans Pro', sans-serif; font-size: 28px;">Overall Thoughts</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium alignright" src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/I/61fKd8CT5hL.jpg" width="333" height="500" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> absolutely loved this series. I’m not a particularly fast reader, but I finished </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Cruel Prince</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> within a day and then (after a week of waiting for my local indie to have the other two) I finished both </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Wicked King</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Queen of Nothing</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the same day. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Folk of the Air</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> series is an easy read that pulls a variety of more complex plots and themes into a lush fantasy world.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Characters</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m a sucker for first</span>-person narration and these books are no exception. I think I enjoyed this series even more because I that Jude was such a relatable protagonist. She’s written so well (and with a mature voice) that I often forgot she was only 17. Prince Cardan is an incredible antagonist, and I love the growth his character sees throughout the series.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The whole cast of characters were interesting, well-fleshed-out, and realistic (with the exception of Jude’s twin sister Taryn in the last book).</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">World-Building</span></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium alignright" src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/91VxO6ObJZL.jpg" width="1710" height="2560" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honestly, I went into </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Cruel Prince</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> thinking I’d hate it because I’m not a huge “fae” fan, but the world of Faerie didn’t deter me at all. I loved almost all the settings and found descriptions to be just enough that I had a clear picture of where I was but could make my own images in my mind instead of relying on the book for every little detail.</span></p>
<p>A really well-done part I wasn’t expecting was the mortal world. Holly Black did an incredible job of describing the human world through a human who’s lived with Fae for most of her life. It gave really great mental pictures to imagine this badass protagonist who wears armor and delicate dresses and eats weird fruit/meat combinations to also shop at Target, drink coffee, and eat gummy worms.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I do think the second book’s underwater setting (“Undersea” in the book) was a bit of a letdown after a book and a half of it being talked up, but in the same vein, I get why. As Jude’s our narrator and only allowed very limited access to much of the Undersea, there wasn’t a natural way for us to learn more through her eyes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Faerie’s rules for its inhabitants (particularly that Fae can’t lie) gave the entire series a really unique tone. While the mortal characters could straight-up lie, the rest of the cast found intricate ways to weave their words so they couldn’t lie outright but also didn’t have to fess up the whole truth if they didn’t want to. The bargains they made throughout the series are a perfect example of this.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Plot</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The overarching plot(s) of the series were well-carried throughout the trilogy. While the second book felt a little like a lull to me (and set up a lot that we got “pay off” in the third book), there wasn’t a subplot mentioned that we didn’t get resolution to. It was intricate, engaging, and not easily guessable, which made each book a furious page-turner.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pacing</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The only book in the series I felt had some pacing issues was </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Wicked King</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (book two). There were a few scenes I read very quickly/skimmed because they didn’t seem to contribute to the overall plot or weren’t as engaging as the rest of the book.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Relationships</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In my mind, Jude and Cardan are going in the hall of “Best Enemies-to-Lovers” right next to Elizabeth and Mr. Darcy.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright" src="https://i.pinimg.com/originals/56/79/6c/56796c3fcbc43695b2e3bf1a2e54bbc2.png" width="256" height="355" /></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Their chemistry was off the charts and I felt like screaming </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">KISS ALREADY! </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">more than once amid all three books. The beauty of their relationship lives in the time it takes them to learn themselves, as well as each other, before they can confront their feelings toward each other.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The family relationships in this book are so important. Jude’s relationships with her sisters, as well as her murderous foster father, step-mother, and brother are all explored at different times and different depths, giving us really unique insights to the dynamics of their family. As someone who has step-siblings on both my mother’s and father’s sides, I really loved reading the dynamics of this non-nuclear family.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Random note: I don’t understand how I keep picking up books with identical twin sisters, but that’s where we are I guess? First </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-kingdom-of-the-wicked-kerri-maniscalco/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kingdom of the Wicked</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, now this, and my next, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crown of Coral and Pearl</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> all have twins!</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Thoughts</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buy all three books at the same time&#8211;you’ll thank me. My favorite book was </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Queen of Nothing</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, followed closely by </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Cruel Prince</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and lastly </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Wicked King</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. My favorite parts of the series were the romance and the main character’s journey to reach her goals. I found some minor parts of the series not to my liking (Jude’s twin sister’s unrealistic arc in the third book and the Undersea in the second) but those things didn’t taint my view of the trilogy as a whole.</span></p>
<p><b>I absolutely loved this series and recommend it to anyone who enjoys romance, fantasy, political intrigue, and complex family dynamics!</b></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-folk-of-the-air-series-holly-black/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SFF Opening Lines: Girl, Serpent, Thorn; Romanov; Wilder Girls</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/sff-opening-lines-girl-serpent-thorn-romanov-wilder-girls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katarina Betterton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 11:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girl of Words]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to SFF Opening Lines! As a reminder, this series focuses on the all-important&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Welcome back to SFF Opening Lines! As a reminder, this series focuses on the all-important first line of a novel; the sentence that shapes the tone and very essence of the novel that follows those words. While a first line doesn’t have to shock you to your core, it should intrigue you enough to want to keep reading.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This mini-review will include the first line and—depending on if I’ve read the book or not—either my opinion on how this first line sums up the novel or my first impression and predictions of what the vibe of the story will be. This week, I’m looking at </span><b><i>Girl, Serpent, Thorn, Romanov,</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><b><i> Wilder Girls.</i></b> <span style="font-weight: 400;">I haven’t read any of these, so I’m excited to give my first impressions!</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22616 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-300x176.jpg" alt="books on bookshelf" width="300" height="176" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-300x176.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-1024x600.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-768x450.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-1536x901.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-2048x1201.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Girl, Serpent, Thorn (Melissa Bashardoust)</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Stories always begin the same way: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">There was and there was not</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
<p><b>First Impressions/Predictions</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Okay, so I’ve read the first ~20 pages of this book, but I’m still going to do first impressions/predictions on this line.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This sentence intrigued me because, in my mind, there are a million ways stories begin that don’t include “there was and there was not.” I want to read on to discover if this adage is commonplace in the world we’re diving into, or if it’s a bold claim the story will work to support. To be fair, this is the prologue’s first line, but the prologue </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> where the story begins, which is why I chose this sentence instead of Chapter 1’s first line. I have no idea where the story goes from this line, though.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium aligncenter" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/interviews/1593126714p8/1516.jpg" width="700" height="368" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Romanov (</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nadine Brandes</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">)</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I watched my diaries burn.”</span></p>
<p><b>First Impressions/Predictions</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oof. I really like this one &#8211; it’s probably my favorite this week. As a huge fan of the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anastasia</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> movie and musical (I’m also querying my own </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anastasia </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">retelling), this first line caught my attention straight away. Why are her diaries burning? Why is she watching them burn? From where is she watching? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think this one does a great job of giving us some insight to the character, the world, foreshadowing motivations, and inviting readers to continue on within five words. This is a really great opening line.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium aligncenter" src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/S/aplus-media/vc/003448a4-6cac-476e-9c0c-03c213887d27.__CR59,0,335,335_PT0_SX300_V1___.jpg" width="300" height="300" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wilder Girls (Rory Power)</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Something. Way out in the white-dark.”</span></p>
<p><b>First Impressions/Predictions</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because the first line was one word, I gave this book two sentences. While it doesn’t give us an indication of who’s speaking, it does a great job of world-building and stake- or conflict-setting up from the get-go. I’m immediately invested in figuring out who or what is in the “white-dark,” what the “white-dark” is, and if that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">thing</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is dangerous to our narrator or main character. This was a very close second.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-medium" src="https://jjoshhcom.files.wordpress.com/2020/01/wilder-girls-cover-reveal-1.jpg" width="2391" height="1800" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next Time on Opening Lines…</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My next post will include </span><b><i>Spellbreaker, Aurora Rising, </i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><b><i>Mother Knows Best</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Have other SFF books’ first lines you’d like me to comment on? Drop them below and I’ll add them to my list!</span></p>
<p><b>As always, thank you for reading. Have a wonderful day!</b></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Three SFF Opening Lines And Why They&#8217;re Intruiging</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/another-three-sff-opening-lines-and-why-theyre-intruiging/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katarina Betterton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 11:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girl of Words]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22756</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to SFF Opening Lines! As a reminder, this series focuses on the all-important&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Welcome back to SFF Opening Lines! As a reminder, this series focuses on the all-important first line of a novel; the sentence that shapes the tone and very essence of the novel that follows those words. While a first line doesn’t have to shock you to your core, it should intrigue you enough to want to keep reading.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This mini-review will include the first line and—depending on if I’ve read the book or not—either my opinion on how this first line sums up the novel or my first impression and predictions of what the vibe of the story will be. This week, I’m looking at </span><b><i>Circe, House of Salt and Sorrows,</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><b><i> The Invisible Life of Addie Larue.</i></b></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Circe (Madeline Miller)</span></h2>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When I was born, the name for what I was did not exist.”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><b>How does it sum up the book?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think this first line does a great job. Circe spends so much of her immortal life trying to decide which world she belonged to after centuries of her family’s unwarranted wrath toward her existence. Toward the end of the book, she finally finds her answer—a satisfying one for both her and readers.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22759 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dscfb6f1xwu-220x300.jpg" alt="woman in yellow and brown floral dress holding black and brown book" width="220" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dscfb6f1xwu-220x300.jpg 220w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dscfb6f1xwu-751x1024.jpg 751w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dscfb6f1xwu-768x1047.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dscfb6f1xwu-1126x1536.jpg 1126w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dscfb6f1xwu-1502x2048.jpg 1502w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/dscfb6f1xwu-scaled.jpg 1877w" sizes="(max-width: 220px) 100vw, 220px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">House of Salt and Sorrows (Erin Craig)</span></h2>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Candlelight reflected off the silver anchor etched onto my sister’s necklace.”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><b>How does it sum up the book?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To be honest, I wasn’t a huge fan of HOSAS, but I won’t waste your time going into why here. If you’re interested, feel free to take a look at </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2667865778?book_show_action=false&amp;from_review_page=1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">my Goodreads review</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think this line is a fair amalgamation of the book. It has some good worldbuilding but tells us nothing of our speaker, their motivations, foreshadows any conflict, or gives us a reason to read on. The latter point is an accurate reflection of my experience reading HOSAS &#8211; I almost DNF’d a few times. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What this first line doesn’t give away is that the necklace is around the throat of the main character’s dead sister and we’re at her funeral. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">That</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> would have been striking to read in a first line, especially because the main character’s sister had a mysterious, untimely death.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22758 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lldqpnerfxo-300x200.jpg" alt="aerial view photography of sea" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lldqpnerfxo-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lldqpnerfxo-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lldqpnerfxo-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lldqpnerfxo-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lldqpnerfxo-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Invisible Life of Addie Larue (V. E. Schwab)</span></h2>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“A girl is running for her life.”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><b>First Impressions/Predictions</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All I know about this book is that a young woman makes a Faustian bargain to live forever but no one remembers her… until someone does. I’ve actually never read V. E. Schwab before either (I know, I know. My TBR pile looks at me with that same expression of disdain too). Even so, this is my favorite opening line from this week’s picks, hands down. I mean, that simple sentence—only 6 words—practically begs you to keep reading, and how could you not? I’m really looking forward to reading this one.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22757 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/uhjiu8fjnsq-300x195.jpg" alt="photography of starry sky" width="300" height="195" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/uhjiu8fjnsq-300x195.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/uhjiu8fjnsq-1024x666.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/uhjiu8fjnsq-768x499.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/uhjiu8fjnsq-1536x998.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/uhjiu8fjnsq-2048x1331.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next Time on Opening Lines…</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My next post will include </span><b><i>Girl, Serpent, Thorn, Romanov, </i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><b><i>Wilder Girls</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Have other SFF books’ first lines you’d like me to comment on? Drop them below and I’ll add them to my list!</span></p>
<p><b>As always, thank you for reading. Have a wonderful day!</b></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three More SFF Opening Lines and *IF* They&#8217;re Intruiging</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/three-more-sff-opening-lines-and-if-theyre-intruiging/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/three-more-sff-opening-lines-and-if-theyre-intruiging/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katarina Betterton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 12:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girl of Words]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to SFF Opening Lines! As a reminder, this series focuses on the all-important&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Welcome back to SFF Opening Lines! As a reminder, this series focuses on the all-important first line of a novel; the sentence that shapes the tone and very essence of the novel that follows those words. While a first line doesn’t have to shock you to your core, it should intrigue you enough to want to keep reading.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-22679 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/hpktywj4fuo-300x200.jpg" alt="woman reading a book while sitting on black leather 3-seat couch" width="344" height="229" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/hpktywj4fuo-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/hpktywj4fuo-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/hpktywj4fuo-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/hpktywj4fuo-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/hpktywj4fuo-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 344px) 100vw, 344px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This mini-review will include the first line and—depending on if I’ve read the book or not—either my opinion on how this first line sums up the novel or my first impression and predictions of what the vibe of the story will be. This week, I’m looking at </span><b><i>Nevernight, Radiant,</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><b><i> Kingdom of the Wicked.</i></b></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nevernight (Jay Kristoff)</span></h2>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“People often shit themselves when they die.”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><b>How does it sum up the book?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perfectly. In my limited reading experience, I don’t think I’ve ever read a line that better encapsulates a series’ voice than this one. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How striking is this line? We’re talking about death and shit, for goodness sake. Not to mention the semi-surprising statement because, well, how often do you think about what happens to a person after they die? If you’ve read <em>Nevernight</em> (or its sequels <em>Godsgrave</em> and <em>Darkdawn</em>), you know Mia Corvere is a deadly force no one should ever cross. And, if for some reason they do, they probably won’t be alive to apologize.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A+ opening line. Draws you in immediately and keeps that pace the entire book.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-22681" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tr6jlx1a6i0-300x225.jpg" alt="man in blue t-shirt sitting on bed reading book" width="332" height="249" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tr6jlx1a6i0-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tr6jlx1a6i0-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tr6jlx1a6i0-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tr6jlx1a6i0-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/tr6jlx1a6i0-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 332px) 100vw, 332px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Radiant (Karina Sumner-Smith)</span></h2>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Curled in a concrete alcove that had once been a doorway, Xhea watched the City man make his awkward way through the market tents, dragging a ghost behind him.”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><b>First Impressions/Predictions</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is a pretty interesting first line, but only for the last five words. “Dragging a ghost behind him” is the hook of this story, and the reason I read on. What sort of alternate world is this where people drag ghosts around? Can everyone see the ghosts? How are ghosts controlled on their tether, if at all?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In my opinion, there’s a bit too much worldbuilding in the first line. It could be cut down to “Xhea watched the City man make his way through the market tents, dragging a ghost behind him” and it’d have the same effect.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-22685" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/otfkligsdpc-300x168.jpg" alt="dark cloud above city buildings" width="359" height="201" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/otfkligsdpc-300x168.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/otfkligsdpc-1024x575.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/otfkligsdpc-768x431.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/otfkligsdpc-1536x863.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/otfkligsdpc-2048x1150.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 359px) 100vw, 359px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kingdom of the Wicked (Kerri Maniscalco)</span></h2>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Outside, wind rattled the wooden chimes in warning.”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><b>How does it sum up the book?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’ve read my </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-kingdom-of-the-wicked-kerri-maniscalco/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">KINGDOM review</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, you’ll know that I wasn’t a massive fan of the book. I’ll say, then, I think this opening line is reflective of the rest of the book. To me, the entire novel felt like a ramp up to the sequel, which I’m assuming is the “real” story. This first line doesn’t tell us much but a bit of a scene set up. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My two cents: this line isn’t </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">that</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> intriguing. There’s no reason for me to figure out what the warning is for—which is the only part of the sentence that’s interesting—and I could care less about wood chimes or wind.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22682 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/f10vpk8aedi-300x200.jpg" alt="green plants besides wooden chimes" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/f10vpk8aedi-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/f10vpk8aedi-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/f10vpk8aedi-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/f10vpk8aedi-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/f10vpk8aedi-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next Time on Opening Lines…</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My next post will include </span><b><i>Circe, House of Salt and Sorrows, </i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><b><i>The Invisible Life of Addie Larue</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Have other books’ first lines you’d like me to comment on? Drop them below and I’ll add them to my list!</span></p>
<p><b>As always, thank you for reading. Have a wonderful day!</b></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/three-more-sff-opening-lines-and-if-theyre-intruiging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three SFF Opening Lines and Why They&#8217;re Intriguing</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/three-sff-opening-lines-and-why-theyre-intriguing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katarina Betterton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 13:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girl of Words]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m excited to share with you this new series for 2021! It focuses on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m excited to share with you this new series for 2021! It focuses on the all-important first line of a novel; the sentence that shapes the tone and very essence of the novel that follows those words. While a first line doesn’t have to shock you to your core, it should intrigue you enough to want to keep reading.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This mini-review will include the first line and—depending on if I’ve read the book or not—either my opinion on how this first line sums up the novel or my first impression and predictions of what the vibe of the story will be. First up, we have </span><b><i>Illuminae, The Hobbit,</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><b><i> The Hunger Games.</i></b></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22616 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-300x176.jpg" alt="books on bookshelf" width="300" height="176" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-300x176.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-1024x600.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-768x450.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-1536x901.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ylswjsy7stw-2048x1201.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Illuminae (Amy Kaufman and Jay Kristoff)</span></h2>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“So here’s the file that almost killed me, Director.”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><b>How does it sum up the book?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’d say pretty well. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Illuminae </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is unique in that it’s told in dossier format through IMs, medical reports, emails, and more. As such, we get a bit more information even before we read the first line, as the first page is an email from “Ghost ID” to “Executive Director Frobisher.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This first sentence gives us a peek at the conflict (what did the narrator have to go through to get these files?) and at least two characters (the Director and the Narrator), in addition to the stakes (if it almost killed the narrator to get this file, it must be important). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I read the book over a year ago but remember it well and can confidently assert this line encapsulates the book’s ensuing chaos and rollercoaster of emotions well. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22618 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/e0ahdsenmdg-300x205.jpg" alt="blue and purple galaxy digital wallpaper" width="300" height="205" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/e0ahdsenmdg-300x205.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/e0ahdsenmdg-1024x699.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/e0ahdsenmdg-768x524.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/e0ahdsenmdg-1536x1049.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/e0ahdsenmdg-2048x1398.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Hobbit (J. R. R. Tolkien)</span></h2>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“In a hole in the ground there lived a hobbit.”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><b>First Impressions/Predictions</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though I’ve read the Lord of the Rings trilogy and seen all the Hobbit and LOTR movies multiple times, I’ve never read </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Hobbit</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While deceptively simple, this first line gives the reader pause for two reasons: what is a hobbit and why do they live in the ground?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At this point in modern society—even if you haven’t read any of Tolkien’s work—you probably know what a hobbit is. You may not know why they live in holes in the ground, though, or that those holes aren’t </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">real</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> holes. They’re decorated to be cozy and comfortable; the very peak of hospitality. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think this line does a good job of describing Bilbo’s current life. On the surface, it’s simple and content to exist as it is. When you dig deeper, though, you find a complex world full of things you never imagined.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-22619" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ofrxuceyv40-300x199.jpg" alt="brown and black wooden house with garden" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ofrxuceyv40-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ofrxuceyv40-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ofrxuceyv40-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ofrxuceyv40-1536x1021.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ofrxuceyv40-2048x1362.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Hunger Games (Suzanne Collins)</span></h2>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“When I wake up, the other side of the bed is cold.”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><b>How does it sum up the book?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I wanted to say “terribly,” but the more I think about it, the more it makes sense. The entire series is centered on Katniss protecting her sister. Sure, Collins throws in a revolution or two and a plot to overthrow a corrupt government, but Katniss’s first and main priority throughout her character arc is ensuring Prim’s safety. This first line tells us Katniss shares a bed with someone (who we assume she’s close to) and she’s concerned about their whereabouts. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think, at the very least, this line makes us want to read on to discover more about both the narrator and the person with whom she shares a bed.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-22620" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/l1y-aocu_yc-300x200.jpg" alt="brown wooden bed frame with red bed sheet" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/l1y-aocu_yc-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/l1y-aocu_yc-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/l1y-aocu_yc-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/l1y-aocu_yc-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/l1y-aocu_yc-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next Time on Opening Lines…</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My next post will include </span><b><i>Nevernight, Radiant, </i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><b><i>Kingdom of the Wicked</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Have other books’ first lines you’d like me to comment on? Drop them below and I’ll add them to my list!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em><strong>As always, thank you for reading. Have a wonderful day!</strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>16 Motivating Reasons To Get You Out Of Your Writing Slump</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/16-motivating-reasons-to-get-you-out-of-your-writing-slump/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 16:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girl of Words]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[All writers hit a wall sometimes. We’re only human, after all. In fact, I’m in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All writers hit a wall sometimes. We’re only human, after all. In fact, I’m in the middle of a reading and writing slump right now, which is why I chose this topic to write about. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes passion isn’t enough to motivate you to write. Sometimes, the creative well runs dry, life gets in the way, or you hit the worst Writer’s Block ever encountered in the universe. It happens! The key is figuring out how not to let your writing slump overtake you, though. In this post, I outline 16 different motivating reasons to keep you writing and pick you up from the slump you’re in!</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22266 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/randy-tarampi-U2eUlPEKIgU-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/randy-tarampi-U2eUlPEKIgU-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/randy-tarampi-U2eUlPEKIgU-unsplash-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/randy-tarampi-U2eUlPEKIgU-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/randy-tarampi-U2eUlPEKIgU-unsplash-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/randy-tarampi-U2eUlPEKIgU-unsplash-2048x1363.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>No one tells a story quite like you</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Sure, there are a finite number of ways the basics of a story go, but no other writer has your voice or your imagination. <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/genres/retellings" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">How many retellings have sold wildly well?</a> I’ll answer for you—tons. Tons of retellings have sold well.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>For your characters</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Often our characters seem more like close personal friends than fictitious figments of our imagination. You wouldn’t leave your real friends high and dry, would you? Don’t abandon the characters you’ve created, or start calling yourself Victor Frankenstein (because, you know, he </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">did</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> abandon his creation and it… didn’t go well).</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>At least one person will benefit from the words you write</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Maybe that person is you. Maybe it’s your partner. Maybe it’s a stranger who will never tell you how your words affected them. The point is, at least one person will benefit from your writing—there just may not be instant gratification.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Because it’s fun</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Admit it, writing is fun. It’s also hard, frustrating, and every other emotion you can think of, but you’re a writer because you enjoy it. I mean, what other profession creates worlds and people in their head and gets to call it work? Writing doesn’t always have to be stressful; try out some silly writing prompts to loosen your fingers and ease back into it.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Don’t let your aesthetic boards go to waste</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. We stand behind a great <a href="https://www.pinterest.com/search/pins/?q=aesthetic&amp;rs=typed&amp;term_meta[]=aesthetic%7Ctyped" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">aesthetic board</a>, always! Personally, I love perusing other authors’ aesthetic boards to get the vibe of their current project. But no writing = no more aesthetic boards, and that’s a world too cruel and empty to fathom.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Stories are meant to be shared</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. So what if your project is at the first draft stage? Give it to a critique partner for a positivity pass and do the same for them. As writers, we learn from each other.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>To create something</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Just like baking, or painting, or playing an instrument, writing is the process of creating something from nothing. And as a creative, it is in your nature to, well, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">create</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. What you create is up to you; it doesn’t have to be a flashy best-seller or award-winning piece. You can just create it because it makes you happy.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>You don’t know what great idea you’ll have next</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. As I said at the opening of this post, there are times when you’re creative well is dry as a bone. That’s okay. But in the absence of ideas, remember this is a small season in your writing journey and actively fill your well with more creative ideas to help you get back on track. Listen to music, read, take a walk, talk to other creatives, and you’ll be ready to go in no time.<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22267 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/drew-beamer-Vc1pJfvoQvY-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/drew-beamer-Vc1pJfvoQvY-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/drew-beamer-Vc1pJfvoQvY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/drew-beamer-Vc1pJfvoQvY-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/drew-beamer-Vc1pJfvoQvY-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/drew-beamer-Vc1pJfvoQvY-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>For yourself</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You owe it to yourself to see this sentence, paragraph, chapter, or project through. You deserve to finish, to look back, and proudly say “Look what I did” because you’re awesome. If not for your future readers, for family or friends, or for strangers who may need your words, do it for you.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>To process your feelings</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Writing can be a visceral journey, which is why some books and characters are so relatable. Infusing your problems into your work can help you weigh out different options, foresee solutions and consequences, and connect with others who’ve experienced something similar. It’s part of the beauty that brings us all together in books.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Because it’s your passion</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Nothing worthwhile comes without hard work, am I right? And what’s more worthwhile than your passion? Working through the sticky, not-so-fun parts now </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">will</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> pay off in the future.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>To get better, and better, and better</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It is a truth universally acknowledged that a writer in possession of a brain will write crap at some (or many) points in their career. Seriously. I don’t think there is a writer on this planet whose every written word is pure gold. Writing is a process—a long, arduous, full-of-twists-and-turns process. The more you write, the more you learn, and the better you become. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Imposter Syndrome will </b><b>not</b><b> keep you down</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Admittedly, this is the problem that slips me into writing slumps the most. As much as I love bookstagram, I follow a lot of great authors who I constantly compare myself to. And instead of accepting and celebrating my own accomplishments, I discredit them by convincing myself I didn’t deserve them or they aren’t genuine. </span><span style="text-decoration: underline;">This is not right.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Imposter Syndrome may not be going away any time soon, but identify those thoughts and then combat them with things you know you’re proud of, or just push through the lies and continue creating.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>To celebrate the small victories. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">You wrote 100 words after weeks of nothing? You finally thought of a title for your new project or discovered a character’s name? Amazing! </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>You’d be furious with yourself if you gave up.</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Picture yourself six months from now. Are you still calling yourself a writer? Are you still writing? Yes? Then make the future you a reality by jumping back in the saddle. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><b>Your voice matters</b><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Despite what Imposter Syndrome tells you, despite the rejections that keep coming, despite the empty creative well in you—your voice is unique, and valuable, and worthy. Don’t silence yourself before anyone has a chance to hear you sing. You never know, you might become their new favorite song.</span></li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-22268" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mika-baumeister-Y_LgXwQEx2c-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mika-baumeister-Y_LgXwQEx2c-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mika-baumeister-Y_LgXwQEx2c-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mika-baumeister-Y_LgXwQEx2c-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mika-baumeister-Y_LgXwQEx2c-unsplash-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/mika-baumeister-Y_LgXwQEx2c-unsplash-2048x1368.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I hope these reasons helped you feel a bit more confidence in your writing! If you’d ever like to talk about getting out of a writing slump or need a positivity pass on your work, send me a message on Instagram! I’d love to connect.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thanks for reading!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Kingdom of the Wicked (Kerri Maniscalco)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-kingdom-of-the-wicked-kerri-maniscalco/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-kingdom-of-the-wicked-kerri-maniscalco/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katarina Betterton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 12:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girl of Words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi, all! I&#8217;m excited to bring you my first (of many!) reviews. This is a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi, all!</p>
<p>I&#8217;m excited to bring you my first (of many!) reviews. This is a review of <em>Kingdom of the Wicked</em> by Kerri Maniscalco.</p>
<h1 style="text-align: center;">3.5 / 5 stars</h1>
<figure style="width: 508px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1578938260l/52735921._SX0_SY0_.jpg" alt="Kingdom of the Wicked by Kerri Maniscalco" width="508" height="763" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Sourced from Goodreads</figcaption></figure>
<p><b>Book Blurb</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Two sisters.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One brutal murder.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A quest for vengeance that will unleash Hell itself…</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And an intoxicating romance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Emilia and her twin sister Vittoria are </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">streghe</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – witches who live secretly among humans, avoiding notice and persecution. One night, Vittoria misses dinner service at the family’s renowned Sicilian restaurant. Emilia soon finds the body of her beloved twin…desecrated beyond belief. Devastated, Emilia sets out to find her sister’s killer and to seek vengeance at any cost – even if it means using dark magic that’s been long forbidden.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then Emilia meets Wrath, one of the Wicked – princes of Hell she has been warned against in tales since she was a child. Wrath claims to be on Emilia’s side, tasked by his master with solving the series of women’s murders on the island. But when it comes to the Wicked, nothing is as it seems…</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall thoughts</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve read Kerri Maniscalco’s other highly-acclaimed series, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stalking Jack the Ripper</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and loved it so I went into this with high hopes. Unfortunately, it didn’t meet my expectations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, it was good, not great. I’m bummed because I really wanted to fall in love with this new series (and tried!) but at the end of the day, there were a number of problems too distracting for me to fully love this book. </span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1479669732031-affb2ce2d265?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1000&amp;q=80" alt="body of water" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Characters</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Honestly, my favorite character was Wrath, not the main character Emilia. Emilia was a bit unrelatable to me. She’s characterized as smart and timid when other characters talk about her (or she reflects about herself), but portrayed as reckless and all over the place by her actions. Obviously the grief of losing her twin brings about that shift, but even before Vittoria’s murder the “shy and smart” characterization didn’t really come through.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I really liked Wrath. I thought Maniscalco did a good job personifying the sins we met, though they could have stood to be even more evil.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Besides Emilia and the sins (Princes of Hell), the only other character who seems fleshed out is Nonna, Emilia and Vittoria’s grandmother. I think she was supposed to be portrayed as cool and powerful, but that’s not how I read her. She kept life-or-death secrets from the girls, then when one of them </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">died</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, she was surprised—as if the information she had kept to herself wouldn’t have saved Vittoria. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The rest of Emilia’s family was completely one-dimensional and only there in certain scenes to prove Emilia wasn’t an orphan. Her friends were the same.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">World Building</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As someone with an Italian heritage, I was excited to read a story based in Italy. I think Maniscalco did a great job with the scents of the city, but most of the other descriptions were left up to the reader’s interpretation. The only places I felt I had a solid view in my mind were the cavern by the sea and Wrath’s ruined palace. That’s more of a knock on my imagination, though.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I actually had a problem with the time period too. I didn’t realize it was set in the 19th century until halfway through—everything in the world seemed semi-modern. Even after I realized it (by reading a blurb online), I’d argue it’s still not clear when this story is set.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As far as the magic system goes, I wasn’t fully immersed. I kept trying to remember what witches had which type of magic and the rules that confined them. Demon magic seemed infinitely more thought out, but the rules of it seemed to weaken the potency of it, leading me to believe witches are stronger than demons (which is fine, but demonstrate it in the book). </span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1503416997304-7f8bf166c121?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;w=1000&amp;q=80" alt="total lunar eclipse" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Plot</span></h2>
<p><b>Mild Spoilers Below.</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ugh, this is where the book’s low rating really comes from. To be 100% honest, it felt like a 300-page set up for the “real” book that will be the sequel. There were too many easter eggs or foreshadowing scenes that were never brought up again.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another thing: Everything was so </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">convenient</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and somehow at the same time, all over the place. I called the villain within the first chapter or two and, unlike Maniscalco’s other books, I didn’t have fun during the rest of the book to see if I was right. We didn’t get a resolution to the quest for Vittoria’s murder either which is fine, but I’d have liked at least a bit of progress toward it. The book ended with us knowing pretty much the same thing we did at the start of it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The biggest holes were Emilia getting away with </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">a lot</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, especially with the Princes of Hell. I’m not sure if that was because she was “marked” by Wrath, but if it was it wasn’t mentioned, which deteriorated the strength of the Princes in my eyes. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In my opinion, the way the book was framed led to my disappointment. It promises an intoxicating romance (no) and persuades the reader to believe Wrath and Emilia will work together begrudgingly to solve what happened (also no). I’ll talk about the romance later, but Emilia investigates mostly on her own. If I had liked her more than Wrath, I probably would have preferred that.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pacing</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though I felt like nothing really “happened” in the book, the pacing is one of the things pulling my rating of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kingdom of the Wicked</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> up. </span><b>This book is such an easy read.</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I read it across two days, an hour the first day and finished it the next night. If you’re looking for a semi-spooky YA to gobble up, I highly recommend this one.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Relationships</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wrath and Emilia’s relationship had okay chemistry, but I didn’t buy into their enemies-to-lovers schtick that much. As much as I loved Wrath, his kindness/gooey softness in their relationship was a little uncharacteristic and wasn’t explained. Then the “twist” at the end kind of made me hate their relationship — it wasn’t really a twist, Emilia overreacted because </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">it wasn’t surprising at all</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and now that they’re behind square one for book 2, I’m not really rooting for them to get together.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Emilia and her family had a pretty close bond, I guess? I don’t have a sister so maybe that relationship would resonate more with readers who have siblings/are close with their siblings. Her parents had almost no effect on the story and her grandmother (who I already groused about) was only available to Emilia to give enough information to tease but not reveal anything we actually wanted to know.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I would have loved to see more scenes with Claudia and Antonio. </span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1504036583833-1b9340d6722f?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1000&amp;q=80" alt="brown twigs near black container" /></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Thoughts</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did I hate the book? No, not at all. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Will I recommend it to friends or read it again? No, not at all.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ll probably buy the next in the series because I like Wrath enough to see where his story goes, but after the lackluster “mysteries” from two of the four books in her first series and now </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kingdom</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, I won’t go in expecting much. Maybe I’ll enjoy it more that way.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><b>Have you also read </b><b><i>Kingdom of the Wicked</i></b><b>? What did you think? Tell me in the comments below!</b></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-kingdom-of-the-wicked-kerri-maniscalco/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Things We Can Learn From Reading Science Fiction and Fantasy</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/5-things-we-can-learn-from-reading-science-fiction-and-fantasy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katarina Betterton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 11:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girl of Words]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=21998</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Come one, come all, fans of science fiction and fantasy (SFF)! Whether SFF is all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Come one, come all, fans of science fiction and fantasy (SFF)! Whether SFF is all you read or you’re merely dipping your toe in the genre, I believe there are universal lessons to be found in SFF literature that everyone should learn.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Human Imagination Knows No Bounds</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m someone who likes escapist reads—I want my books to ferry me to far-off places or times. Sometimes that means a post-apocalyptic or dystopian future, sometimes it’s a spaceship circling a black hole, or maybe it’s a fantastical kingdom not of this world at all.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the top reasons I enjoy reading SFF so much is the imaginative settings. The best books in these genres are the ones with such immersive, well-fleshed-out world building that you forget <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21999 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jeff-finley-bK8Wlaq7NaA-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jeff-finley-bK8Wlaq7NaA-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jeff-finley-bK8Wlaq7NaA-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jeff-finley-bK8Wlaq7NaA-unsplash-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jeff-finley-bK8Wlaq7NaA-unsplash-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jeff-finley-bK8Wlaq7NaA-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />the place you’re reading about doesn’t actually exist. Middle Earth, Westeros, The Republic of Gilead, OASIS… every amazing place you read in a SFF book was created by a human with a dream. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SFF books show us just how creative humans are and that there is no lack of imagination in this world.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Be Brave When All Hope Seems Lost</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Especially in these dark and frighteningly uncertain times, looking to main characters of SFF novels can give us the courage to press on and fight for what’s right. Faced with seemingly insurmountable odds, these characters react in dozens of different ways—giving us emotions to which we can relate. Then they remember the reason they’re fighting, pick themselves up from despair, and march on, which is exactly the message we need now.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Magic is Real</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maybe not in the traditional sense; maybe the magic of Fae or witches isn’t in our world, but the magic system isn’t what’s enchanting. What’s enchanting are the words woven in these stories and the feelings they evoke. Books are magic in their power to bring people together. Books are magic by stringing letters, words, and sentences together to make our hearts ache or swell. Books are magic because in them, we find ourselves; we find hope; we find inspiration; we find family within the inky pages. Make no mistake—a world with books is a world full of magic.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22000 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/thought-catalog-LrHek0iJTAE-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/thought-catalog-LrHek0iJTAE-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/thought-catalog-LrHek0iJTAE-unsplash-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/thought-catalog-LrHek0iJTAE-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/thought-catalog-LrHek0iJTAE-unsplash-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/thought-catalog-LrHek0iJTAE-unsplash-2048x1364.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Progress Isn’t (Always) What We Envision</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dystopian (and more broadly, speculative) fiction is a notorious harbinger for this lesson. The best of these books deal with the fallout of what happens after the “change” has been achieved. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One example is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mockingjay</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the third book of Suzanne Collins’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Hunger Games</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> trilogy. Though it’s rated as the least-liked of the series (<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/73758-the-hunger-games" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">according to Goodreads reviews</a>), I think the ideas and darkness of its messages are the best of the trilogy. Katniss has grown from a slight, starving teen only focused on saving her sister to a fierce, capable young woman fighting for the very lives of all those in her broken country of Panem. The losses and sacrifices she endures at every turn later bring about a better world, devoid of teens fighting to the death and starving citizens.</span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">You Are Not Alone</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maybe this isn’t specific to SFF literature, but the beauty of books is the fact you are never alone. Not in the world, not in your feelings—never. The #bookstagram community is a wide and diverse place with book lovers abound. Personally, I’ve built several enduring friendships by connecting over a book I loved with a stranger.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">SFF Literature Is A Reflection of Reality</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though SFF stories don’t take place in our world, their conflicts and characters are rooted in reality—in the human experience. That’s the basis of all books; without reality, we wouldn’t have fantastical places to escape to. </span></p>
<blockquote><p>“Fantasy is hardly an escape from reality. It’s a way of understanding it.” &#8211; Lloyd Alexander</p></blockquote>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22003 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/olga-tutunaru-plbb7pkEjkQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/olga-tutunaru-plbb7pkEjkQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/olga-tutunaru-plbb7pkEjkQ-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/olga-tutunaru-plbb7pkEjkQ-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/olga-tutunaru-plbb7pkEjkQ-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/olga-tutunaru-plbb7pkEjkQ-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What else have you learned from reading sci-fi and fantasy novels? Drop your favorites below!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
