<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cheryl Wollner &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/cheryl-wollner/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:05:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Signing Off as Blog Managing Editor</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/signing-off-as-blog-managing-editor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 16:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am stepping down as blog managing editor for LSQ. It has been a pleasure&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am stepping down as blog managing editor for <em>LSQ. </em>It has been a pleasure to work with our array of talented bloggers and editors. To all our bloggers, thank you for supporting an inclusive future for publishing. <em>LSQ </em>is <em>the</em> place for feminist genre fiction and our bloggers, published authors, editors and, of course, readers make that possible.</p>
<p>Though I am resigning as the blog managing editor, I will still contribute to <em>LSQ </em>as a monthly columnist. We need to promote female writers of speculative fiction and female writers of diverse backgrounds however we can. While I am no longer in a position to devote the time to <em>LSQ </em>to remain a part of the editorial team, I stand behind what editor Jennifer Lyn Parsons says to open <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-029/">Issue 29</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>With the world as it is, we need stories more than ever. Stories that lift us up, that take us to new places, that hurt us and build us back up again. We need strong fresh voices, unafraid to go deep, to bring these stories into the light. And we need you, to be curious, to feel everything, to get past the trappings of superheroes and fairy tales and androids and timey wimey stuff to the beating heart of our shared humanity, which these stories exhibit in droves.</p>
<p>Welcome to year eight of Luna Station. We’ve been expecting you.</p></blockquote>
<p>I will always believe in the power of stories! I hope you do too. Right now, <em>LSQ </em>is entirely volunteer. In the future, we hope to be able to pay our writers, bloggers and editorial staff for their work and dedication to a feminist future. If you like what we do, consider donating to our <a href="https://www.patreon.com/lunastation">Patreon </a>or buying <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-029/">issue 29</a> (or a back issue of the journal).</p>
<p>Keep an eye out for more information on the search for a new blog managing editor. Whoever <em>LSQ</em> chooses for the role will join a team of positive and creative individuals making the world a better place one word at a time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speculative Literature Foundation Grants</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speculative-literature-foundation-grants/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 16:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8311</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Speculative Literature Foundation wants to fund your writing project. Defining speculative literature as fantasy,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://speculativeliterature.org/">The Speculative Literature Foundation</a> wants to fund your writing project. Defining speculative literature as fantasy, science fiction and horror, the Speculative Literature Foundation offers  grants for writers working within these genres (though anything fabulist will be considered). Each grant has no application fee, and is designed to be as accessible as possible to writers of all backgrounds and income levels.</p>
<p>Below is more information pulled from blurbs on the Speculative Literature Foundation&#8217;s website.</p>
<p><a href="http://speculativeliterature.org/grants/slf-diverse-writers-and-diverse-worlds-grants/"><strong>Diverse Writers</strong></a><strong> Grant ($500) </strong>(apply between May 1st &#8211; July 31st )</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The Diverse Writers grant is awarded annually to assist new and emerging writers from underrepresented and underprivileged groups, such as writers of color, women, queer writers, disabled writers, working-class writers, etc.—those whose marginalized identities may present additional obstacles in the writing / publishing process&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="http://speculativeliterature.org/grants/slf-diverse-writers-and-diverse-worlds-grants/">Diverse Worlds Grant</a> ($500) </strong>(apply between May 1st &#8211; July 31st )</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The Diverse Worlds grant is awarded annually to assist work that best presents a diverse world, regardless of the writer’s background.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="http://speculativeliterature.org/grants/the-slf-working-class-impoverished-writers-750-grant/">Working Class Writers Grant</a> ($750) </strong>(December 1 &#8211; February 28)</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;This grant is awarded annually to assist working class, blue-collar, poor, and homeless writers who have been historically underrepresented in speculative fiction, due to financial barriers. We are currently offering one $750 working class grant annually, to be used as the writer determines will best assist his or her work. This year, we will accept applications December 1 through February 28.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="http://speculativeliterature.org/grants/the-gulliver-travel-grant/">Gulliver Travel Research Grant </a>*not for academic research ($800) </strong>(July 1st &#8211; September 30th)</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;This grant is awarded annually to assist writers of speculative literature (in fiction, poetry,drama, or creative nonfiction) in their research. This year, we will accept applications July 1 through September 30. They are not currently available for academic research, though we hope to offer such funds in the future. We are currently offering one $800 travel grant annually, to be used to cover airfare, lodging, and/or other travel expenses. Learn more <a href="http://speculativeliterature.org/site/grants/the-gulliver-travel-grant/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="http://speculativeliterature.org/grants/slf-older-writers-grant/">Older Writers Grant </a>(2 $500 grants awarded annually) </strong>(apply January 1st- March 31st)</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;This grant is awarded annually to a writer who is fifty years of age or older at the time of the grant application, and is intended to assist such writers who are just starting to work at a professional level. The SLF offers two $500 grants annually, to be used as each writer determines will best assist his or her work. We will be accepting applications for the grant starting in January.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>For more information on deadlines and past winners of these grants, check out the <a href="http://speculativeliterature.org/grants/">grants page</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Call for Submissions: Zoetic Press Seeking Dystopian Lit by POC</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/call-for-submissions-zoetic-press-seeking-dystopian-lit-by-poc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 16:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“In order to rise from its own ashes, a Phoenix first must burn.” —Octavia Butler,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>“In order to rise from its own ashes, a Phoenix first must burn.”</i><br />
—Octavia Butler, <em>Parable of the Sower</em></p>
<p><a href="https://zoetic-press.myshopify.com/">Zoetic Press </a>is seeking dystopian stories written by people of color for their upcoming anthology, <em>A Phoenix Must First Must Burn. </em><strong>Please only submit work if you identify as a person of color.</strong></p>
<p>As Zoetic Press explains:</p>
<blockquote><p>The past few years have brought the injustices suffered by people of color into sharp relief. Not just because people of color are being victimized and killed, but because when people of color rightly bring attention to the realities of their situation, they are shouted down by white people, and their experiences erased.</p>
<p>This puts people of color in a better position than anyone to write about dystopian futures, and we want to hear about those futures. Take the events of the present to their logical conclusion. Introduce a new catastrophe that makes things worse, if possible. Tell us about the superpowers we will have to develop to survive. Tell us the story of our future with yourself as the lead character.</p></blockquote>
<p>Submit fiction up to 5,000 words, or up to five pieces of flash fiction (up to 1,000 words each piece). For more details, check out <a href="https://nonbinaryreview.submittable.com/submit/74647/a-phoenix-first-must-burn">their Submittable page</a>. <strong>Deadline to submit is 9/1/2017.<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Not a person of color? You can still help out by<a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1505437588/a-phoenix-first-must-burn"> contributing to their kickstarter campaign</a>. Please share this information widely.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Princess Elena of Avalor</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-princess-elena-of-avalor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I first heard about the Disney Channel show Princess Elena of Avalor last summer when&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I first heard about the Disney Channel show <em>Princess Elena of Avalor </em>last summer when speaking with a Chicana high school student about how she notices the lack of Latin@ and Chican@ representation in animation and live action programming.</p>
<p><em>Elena of Avalor </em>begins to break that barrier, featuring Disney&#8217;s first Latina Princess.</p>
<p>Last week, I finally had the chance to watch the first episode. I tend to surround myself in grimdark stories and well deserved character angst. My favorite cartoon <em>Young Justice, </em>with its dark and complicated story arc, is arguably meant for an older audience. I didn&#8217;t expect much of <em>Elena of Avalor </em>because I tend to find children&#8217;s programming cutesy, as if children are incapable of handling anything except fluff. But <em>Elena of Avalor </em>was fun!</p>
<p><iframe title="Theme Song &#x1f3b6;  | Elena of Avalor | @disneyjunior" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BUi9vMqXxDo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>The series is definitely meant for elementary school and early middle school audiences, but I still found myself grinning throughout, as if the show were meant for me. With catchy songs (it is a Disney show, after all), talking animals and a healthy dose of magic, the show knows how to create engaging fantasy.</p>
<p>A few additional highlights:</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/index.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8302 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/index.jpg" alt="" width="221" height="228" /></a>Elena is Disney&#8217;s first Latina Princess and is voiced by a Latina actor!</strong> Aimee Carrero (<em>Young and Hungry, Blindspot, The Americans</em>) lends her voice to Elena. From her Dominican and Puerto Rican background, she couldn&#8217;t be more thrilled to be bringing Latina children a role model. As she said in an <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Entertainment/10-things-disneys-newest-princess-elena-avalor/story?id=40716449">interview with ABC:</a> “It means the world to me because people have been waiting a very long time for this, myself included&#8230;I really hope that my future daughters or granddaughters will look back and say, ‘Hey, she was sort of trailblazing that at that time.'&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>The plot subverts standard fantasy fare. </strong>In the opening episode, we learn that for the past 41 years, Elena has been trapped inside a magic amulet. Just before the start of the series, a wizard frees her and she successfully takes back her kingdom from an evil sorceress. <em>Then </em>the show begins. It&#8217;s an odd choice to have what would ordinarily be the plot of a series, told as background. But the subversion sparks an interest that this show will be different than other fantasy fare.</p>
<p><strong>Elena and her sister have a strong relationship. </strong>I&#8217;m a sucker for sister stories, especially stories which treat each sister as a full person, not the accessory or annoying baggage to the protagonist. Elena and  her younger sister Isabel love and trust each other. More than that, from the first episode Isabel already has a distinguishing character trait: she&#8217;s an artist. I&#8217;m excited to see how her interest in sketching and art plays into the rest of the series.</p>
<p>Whether you&#8217;re a cartoon buff, looking for a bit of lighthearted fun, or seeking media with diverse women of color (aren&#8217;t we all?), I would definitely recommend giving <em>Elena of Avalor </em>a go. The first episode is available <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eXEvnce5Mvw">free on youtube</a>.</p>
<h3></h3>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday Elizabeth Hand &#038; Mary Gentle!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-elizabeth-hand-mary-gentle/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 16:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today we celebrate two female genre writers: Elizabeth Hand (1957- ) and Mary Gentle (1956-&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today we celebrate two female genre writers: <a href="http://elizabethhand.com/">Elizabeth Hand </a>(1957- ) and <a href="https://www.fantasticfiction.com/g/mary-gentle/">Mary Gentle</a> (1956- ). Those these authors share the same birthday and nearly the same birth year, they are known for vastly different material.</p>
<p>Hand&#8217;s most well-known (and on-going!) series, beginning with <em><a href="http://elizabethhand.com/books/generation-loss/">Generation Lost</a>, </em>is noir detective novel, following Cass Neary. Hand described her anti-heroine as &#8220;this total screwup-alcoholic-speed freak&#8221; and that Cass continues to be trouble. Check out a video about the most recent book in the series <em>Hard Light </em> (2016).</p>
<p><iframe title="HARD LIGHT by Elizabeth Hand/Book Trailer" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/160785147?dnt=1&amp;app_id=122963" width="730" height="411" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture"></iframe></p>
<p>Today we celebrate Hand for being unafraid to delve into darkness of action and psychological darkness. Especially for creating complicated, screwed up female characters for readers to love. As Hand explained in an interview with the <em><a href="http://www.pressherald.com/2016/04/17/author-qa-elizabeth-hand-on-the-freaking-mess-of-her-anti-heroine-the-steadiness-of-her-own-writing-life/">Portland Press Herald</a>, </em>after the publication of <em>Hard Light, </em>&#8220;if I make somebody cry at the end, then I know that my work here is done. Or if I know that I’ve succeeded in really disturbing somebody.&#8221;</p>
<p><a class="entry-author" title="Posts by Liz Bourke" href="http://www.tor.com/author/liz-bourke/" rel="author">Liz Bourke</a>, writing about Mary Gentle&#8217;s novel <em>The Black Opera, </em>similarly <a href="http://www.tor.com/2012/05/23/sleeps-with-monsters-go-thou-and-read-mary-gentle/">describes Gentle&#8217;s work </a>as &#8220;uncomfortable  or at least disconcerting  is the way she plays with expectation, genre, and continuity.&#8221; For instance, her alternate history novel <em>Ash: A Secret History </em>(the omnibus was released in 2013), is unflinching in its depiction of medieval violence, especially through the female captain Ash. Looking for flawed female characters and grimdark before grimdark was a coined term? Pick up Mary Gentle.</p>
<p>Thank you Hand and Gentle for giving us flawed women to admire, love and shy away from, with all their imperfections laid bare. Happy birthday to two women, unafraid to venture into darkness to bring light to women&#8217;s stories.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday, Patricia Wrede!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-patricia-wrede-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 16:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8280</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy birthday, Patricia Wrede (March 27, 1953&#8211;)! Best known for her fantasy YA and children&#8217;s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy birthday, <a href="http://www.pcwrede.com/">Patricia Wrede</a> (March 27, 1953&#8211;)! Best known for her fantasy YA and children&#8217;s books, Wrede says she doesn&#8217;t write for children; she writes for herself. Wrede is an advocate for writing what you love. She writes fantasy. She writes about dragons. Why change what you love? As she explains: &#8220;I loved getting my M. B. A., and I really enjoyed being an accountant and financial analyst before I quit my day job twenty-five years ago to write full time. I just liked writing more…plus, I knew even then that as a full-time writer, I&#8217;d get plenty of chances to do business-type stuff, while as an accountant, I probably wouldn&#8217;t get a lot of opportunities to write about dragons.&#8221;</p>
<p>Her initial writing goal was to publish a short story, but that short story became a novel and that novel sold. By her fifth novel she could support herself as a full-time writer. Today, we celebrate a female fantasy writer whose best <a href="http://www.pcwrede.com/about-patricia/faq/">advice to emerging writers </a>is pretty simple: &#8220;write every day, whether you feel like it or not&#8221;.</p>
<p>But most of all, always choose dragons.</p>
<p>A full list of her novels can be found below.</p>
<p><b>Books<br />
<span style="font-size: small;">Lyra Series * These books can be read in any order, but this is the order Wrede recommends<br />
</span></b><span style="font-size: small;"><em>Caught in Crystal</em> (1987)<br />
<em>The Raven Ring</em> (1994)<br />
<em>Shadow Magic </em>(1982)<br />
<em>Daughter of Witches</em> (1983)<br />
<em>The Harp of Imach Thyssel </em>(1985) *updated in 1995 to create greater continuity<br />
</span><b><span style="font-size: small;"><br />
</span></b><strong><span style="font-size: small;">The Enchanted Forest Series</span></strong><br />
<em>Dealing with Dragons </em>(1990)<br />
<em>Searching for Dragons</em> (1991)<br />
<em>Calling on Dragons</em> (1993)<br />
<em>Talking to Dragons</em> (1985)<br />
<span style="font-size: small;"><br />
<strong>Kate &amp; Cecelia Series</strong> (with Caroline Stevermer)<br />
<em>Sorcery and Cecelia</em> (1988)<br />
<em>The Grand Tour</em> (2004)<br />
<em>The Mislaid Magician </em>(2006)</span></p>
<p><strong>Mairelon the Magician Series</strong><br />
<em>Mairelon the Magician</em> (1991)<br />
<em>The Magician&#8217;s Ward</em> (1997)</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><em>A Matter of Magic</em> (2010 &#8211; omnibus edition)<br />
</span><span style="font-size: small;"><br />
<strong>Frontier Magic</strong><br />
<em>Thirteenth Child</em> (2009)<br />
<em>Across the Great Barrier</em> (2011)<br />
<em>The Far West</em> (2012)</span></p>
<p><strong>Other Novels<br />
</strong><em>The Seven Towers</em> (1984)<br />
<em>Snow White and Rose Red</em> (1989)<br />
<em>The Book of Enchantments</em> (1996)</p>
<p><strong>Middle-School Novelizations</strong><br />
<em>Star Wars, Episode I &#8211; The Phantom Menace</em> (1999)<br />
<em>Star Wars, Episode II &#8211; Attack of the Clones </em>(2002)<br />
<em>Star Wars, Episode III &#8211; Revenge of the Sith</em> (2005)</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"> </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get Your Youtube Education: Fandom Videos All Around</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/get-your-youtube-education-fandom-videos-all-around/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 16:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A person&#8217;s youtube history say a lot about them. I organize my youtube life into&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A person&#8217;s youtube history say a lot about them. I organize my youtube life into personalized playlists based on different fandoms. I don&#8217;t officially consider myself a part of any fandom until I have amassed a collection of at least 10 AMVS (anime music videos), videos dedicated to that fandom, or songs that remind me of a fandom.</p>
<p>I have a <em>Doctor Who</em> playlist, an <em>X-Men</em> (animated) playlist, a <em>Teen Titans</em> (mixed with a bit of <em>Young Justice</em>/DC animated movies) playlist, a <em>Dragon Ball Z</em> playlist, a <em>Doctrine of Labyrinths</em> playlist, and&#8211;most recently&#8211;a <em>RWBY</em> playlist. Fandom is how I find my music.</p>
<p>AMVs (though really, for me, the broader spectrum of fandom music videos both animated and live action) have often provided me new insight into characters or relationships I had barely given a second thought.</p>
<p>When I was in high school, I read the first few trades of the comic <a href="http://marvel.com/comics/series/744/astonishing_x-men_2004_-_2013"><em>Astonishing X-Men </em></a>(2004-2013), by Joss Whedon. I was a newbie to comics and the realm of superheroes, just beginning to dip my feet into this oceanic world. I watched the cartoon <a href="http://marvel.wikia.com/wiki/Wolverine_and_the_X-Men_(Animated_Series)"><em>Wolverine and the X-Men</em></a> religiously each week as I grew more and more invested in these characters. When I began seeking out youtube videos on the X-Men, I stumbled upon an Emma Frost video that pulled images from <em>Astonishing X-Men. </em>At the time, I knew next to nothing about Emma Frost and while her character in <em>Astonishing X-Men </em>interested me, I didn&#8217;t focus my attention on her as I should have.</p>
<p>Then I found this video:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Emma Frost" width="730" height="548" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ym1btlabIYQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>I fell in love with Emma Frost. Not through the comic, but through this video which paired the comic book images with &#8220;Breath&#8221; by <em>Breaking Benjamin. </em>I saw Emma&#8217;s struggle in ways the images alone could not produce for me. Only through creating this video as a new piece of art, did I begin to love her character.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/favorite-female-characters-rwby/">I&#8217;ve written a few times about <em>RWBY</em></a>, the animated series out of Rooster Teeth Productions. When I started seeking out <em>RWBY</em> videos, I sought the wonderful queer ship of Blake/Yang (affectionately called Bumblebee). But I didn&#8217;t find a video that revealed new insight into their characters.</p>
<p>Then, just a few weeks ago, I stumbled upon this gem:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="girls like girls // rwby mep" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oAe9jcvFBCc?start=63&#038;feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>A whole video dedicated to queer female relationships. Watching <em>RWBY</em> I knew about the major ships: Blake/Yang (please!!!) and Ruby/Weiss, but I had never thought to consider that any number of the female characters in the series could be wonderfully queer. Why restrict ourselves to just the canon or queer-baited pairings?</p>
<p>Youtube videos are an art just as much as comic books and as much as writing. Because these videos elicit emotions and create novelty within fandoms. When I fall in love with a fan video, I&#8217;m remembering why I fell in love with the series or the character to begin with. I&#8217;m interacting with another person&#8217;s art and interpretation. I&#8217;m learning something new.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Favorite Female Characters: Pippi Longstocking</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/favorite-female-characters-pippi-longstocking/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Favorite Female Characters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8272</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I dressed up as Pippi Longstocking for Purim as a junior in high school,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/index-5.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8273 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/index-5.jpg" alt="" width="136" height="236" /></a>When I dressed up as Pippi Longstocking for Purim as a junior in high school, I knew I had discovered something special. And it wasn&#8217;t just in the thrill of wearing mismatched knee-high socks.</p>
<p>Pippi Longstocking, created by Swedish author Astrid Lindgren, provided a new definition of female strength. A sea-captain&#8217;s daughter, Pippi and her father get caught in a storm and her father goes overboard. Pippi waits for her father&#8217;s return at her home: Villa Villekulla (pronounced Villa Villa Coola). She lives with her monkey and her horse, but without adults.</p>
<p>I grew up fascinated by the animated movie (1997) where this red haired child knew no social constraints, lived life shouting with joy, had the strength to <em>pick up her horse </em>(literally. She has unexplained super strength.) and all the while remained at heart a vulnerable child. As a junior in high school, my heroes were the muscled men of Dragon Ball Z. I desired the gritty, physical strength of beating an opponent. But rekindling my childhood love of Pippi reminded me that strength does not lie in conquering others. When I stumbled upon my childhood favorite film, I rediscovered that women could be both physically and mentally strong without having to prove it through physical violence.</p>
<p>Pippi lives each day as an adventure she doesn&#8217;t plan to miss. In the opening to the film, she sings, &#8220;I am the sea and nobody owns me.&#8221; Before I would even begin to call myself a feminist, I was writing this phrase again and again as a mantra into my journal: <em>nobody owns me. </em>What could be more feminist than claiming ownership over your actions and desires? What better lesson can we teach young girls?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a7m4vPcfeOE">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a7m4vPcfeOE</a></p>
<p>Pippi is magic. She has no love interest. She is not a child version of a manic-pixie-dream-girl. Her joy and her exuberance is for her. But what further strikes me is that the film knows Pippi cannot be joyous one-hundred percent of the time. Particularly in the quiet moments at night, waiting for her father&#8217;s return, I love her all the more. She has hope that her father survived. She has hope that all loneliness can be conquered. At her core, Pippi holds strength and vulnerability.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creating Characters: A D&#038;D Example</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/creating-characters-a-dd-example/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 16:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was the college kid who spent her weekends around a table in the Student&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was the college kid who spent her weekends around a table in the Student Center, rolling dice, playing Dungeons and Dragons (D&amp;D). Playing D&amp;D became more than a weekly hangout with friends and more than a stress reliever. This game taught&#8211;and continues to teach&#8211;me about creating characters.</p>
<p>When I sit down to start a new story, creating characters remains intimidating. Yet, it&#8217;s no secret that knowing your characters creates plot. At the very least, knowing your character makes the process of plotting much easier. You don&#8217;t have to <em>come up with </em>what happens next; your characters decide for you! Or, at least that&#8217;s how it works in an ideal world.</p>
<p>Most writers don&#8217;t live in that ideal world. Character and plot continue to vex us.</p>
<p>But when I get stuck, I think about my characters from various campaigns I&#8217;ve played in Dungeons and Dragons and how they&#8217;ve developed and continue to develop. Because D&amp;D is a multi-player interactive game, where you sit around a table with friends, roll dice and talk &#8220;in character&#8221;, there&#8217;s no time to ponder for hours on end  what your character will do or say next to move the plot forward. You are in the moment. Your character has to act or else the game comes to an agonizing halt. If you&#8217;re a writer like me, who likes to have all of your background information on your character and world before you feel confident to move forward with your piece, consider this D&amp;D approach.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/index-3.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8266 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/index-3.jpg" alt="" width="421" height="120" /></a>Have a basic outline of your character. </strong>I usually know how old my character is, their gender, a few basic notes about their childhood/adult life (poor? rich? lived with their parents? grew up an orphan? etc), and above all, <em>what they want. </em>No, you still cannot escape the extensive reach of character desires, even in this crash theory on character creation.</p>
<p><strong>Put on your character&#8217;s voice. </strong>What does your character sound like? Talk like they would for a few hours, even if you&#8217;re talking to yourself interview style. This will not only help with dialogue, but will be great for crafting first person narration. I will unashamedly talk in character on my commute to work. It&#8217;s especially amusing to get to know your character&#8217;s music taste&#8211;and even better when you disagree with their song choices and radio stations. Have fun and experiment with their voice.</p>
<p><strong>Let your character fail and come up with the reasoning as you go along. </strong>In D&amp;D, you can have a critical fail. You roll a nat 1 (a natural 1 on a 20 sided dice) and your character fails miserably at whatever they are attempting to do. Thought you could kill that orc with your axe? Nope, you wiff and stab yourself in the foot. And while you as a player know you rolled a nat 1, your character only knows that they have an axe in their foot. Now&#8217;s your chance to get creative with why they failed so miserably. Maybe she looked over, saw one of her companions in trouble and got distracted. If that&#8217;s the case, this could open up a whole new avenue in their relationship. Take each action as it comes.</p>
<p><strong>Listen to your character. </strong>It sounds corny and we&#8217;re venturing into &#8220;my characters just write themselves&#8221; dreamland, but sometimes this can be an effective tool. I had a monk character who refused to go downstairs in an inn the party stayed at. I didn&#8217;t know at the time why he refused to join the rest of the group, but I knew that if I, as a player, made him move, I would be doing a disservice to his personality and the autonomy I hoped he would eventually achieve. Because I listened to him, I realized later that night that he is terrified of soldiers and the inn was hosting a battalion. His fear became a major piece of his character and created further plot developments as the story progressed.</p>
<p>As writers, we create characters. Sometimes an interactive approach is just what we need.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday, Lois Lowry!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/happy-birthday-lois-lowry/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Cheryl Wollner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 16:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy birthday, Lois Lowry (1937-)! Often credited as writing the first YA dystopian novel (The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy birthday, <a href="http://www.loislowry.com/">Lois Lowry </a>(1937-)!</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/500898753-quote-Lois-Lowry-i-write-books-because-i-have-always-199089.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8261 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/500898753-quote-Lois-Lowry-i-write-books-because-i-have-always-199089-293x300.png" alt="" width="293" height="300" /></a>Often credited as writing the first YA dystopian novel (<em>The Giver, </em>1993), Lois Lowry has gifted the literary world with each series and stand-alone novel she writes. Lowry does not categorize <em>The Giver </em>and its sequels as science fiction, but rather views her work as telling stories.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s refreshing to remember that at the heart of what writers do is tell a story and bring people into a world they&#8217;ve created.</p>
<p>Lowry brought us into the dystopian world of <em>The Giver, </em>a world she describes as &#8220;seductive&#8221;&#8211;where all peoples&#8217; wants are met but with a price. She transported readers to Denmark during WWII in <em>Number the Stars. </em>I remember reading <em>Number the Stars</em> while in Hebrew School. It wasn&#8217;t an assignment, just a book I read on my own. And while my Holocaust education in Hebrew School was intensive (and honestly traumatic), reading <em>Number the Stars </em>was the first time the Holocaust felt both immediate and terrifying, but also universal. This wasn&#8217;t just a Jewish story. By reading Lowry&#8217;s work, I understood what fiction could do that history alone could not: create new meaning that could connect people.</p>
<p>In honor of Lowry&#8217;s birthday, read one of her other works. Read <em>The Giver</em>? Try <em>Gathering Blue, </em>and the rest of <em>The Quartet </em>series in that universe. Liked <em>Number the Stars? </em>Pick up <em><a href="http://www.loislowry.com/index.php?option=com_djcatalog2&amp;view=item&amp;id=29:the-silent-boy&amp;cid=6:standalone-books&amp;Itemid=185">The Silent Boy</a>, </em>another historical fiction text.</p>
<p>Remember that today, and everyday, is a great day to tell a story. And even better to write that story down.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
