<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Reviews &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/reviews/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 23:21:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Review: The Pallbearers&#8217; Club</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-pallbearers-club/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 11:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Boilerplate: my life is barely coordinated chaos so I still haven’t gotten a chance to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Boilerplate: my life is barely coordinated chaos so I still haven’t gotten a chance to finish 100 Years of Horror. Instead, I give you a review.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-28490 size-medium" title="left-image" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pall-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pall-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/pall.jpg 262w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" />The Pallbearers’ Club hooked me with the title. It’s by the great <a href="https://www.paultremblay.net/">Paul Tremblay</a>, who I fell in love with after A Head Full of Ghosts. I think I mentioned it in January’s blog, where I discussed what I was looking forward to. And I’m happy to report that this one is worth it! Incredibly worth it, actually.</p>
<p>The premise here is that a nerd with scoliosis starts an afterschool club (because he needs to be “well-rounded” for college apps, a horror in and of itself). The club’s purpose? To volunteer to carry the caskets of those who die without anyone left in their lives.<br />
At this point, if you’re not hooked, you’re probably reading the wrong blog, because goddamn is that fun.</p>
<p>The book is framed charmingly (which is #ClassicTremblay). There’s the main narrative, written by someone who is not called Art Barbara, and the comments on it, “handwritten” by someone who shows up in the book and has some thoughts on her own portrayal—someone who is not named Mercy.</p>
<p>These two semi-reliable narrators, in conversation with each other, tell us something that might be a vampire story, but is also a tale about coming of age, grieving, and the wounds from our youth that never quite heal. The story isn’t gory per se, but it’s grounded in the body: particularly our fickle hearts and spines.</p>
<p>Art and Mercy are refreshingly real. The past few years’ pop culture diet of sugary 80s nostalgia has many of us yearning for childhoods we didn’t have—that no one had because they’re not real—but the characters in this book are ordinary, and I love them for it. Art’s parents are flawed but not horrific and he’s working-class and unassuming. He’s a dork but also a punk, and Mercy is mysterious but not in a manic-pixie-dream-girl way. Neither of them are tropes, even though they easily could have been. They’re friends without forced pining or romance, in the way I often find myself friends with men but never see in fiction. They love each other, certainly, but without the clutter of romance. Of course, there might be more to it—a spiritual and physical feeding off each other, for example. But more on that later.</p>
<p>I also love Art and Mercy because they are New England punks, and as usual, the story is dripping with detail. It’s a love letter to Massachusetts and to 80s and 90s punk rock. The sheer number of references could be called indulgent, and maybe they’d turn off someone who doesn’t love that stuff or who wasn’t, like me, born on the East Coast. (The town of my birth, Beverly, is actually mentioned a few times.) I find them wonderful set-dressing, similar to the gorgeous and intricate backdrops in Studio Ghibli movies. This is regional horror, with a strong tether to place.</p>
<p>The prose is both artful (see what I did there?) and funny. Art’s list of band names, from “Institutional Pasta” to “The Brent Underwoods,” described as “a pop-punk five-piece (which is too many pieces) that had no members named Brent or Underwood” is a delight, as is his habit of verbing nouns. Mercy, too, is dryly hilarious, both as she’s portrayed in the main story and in her own voice as she writes the frame. The book is scattered with asides, the type I always get scolded for, whether they live in parens or commas.</p>
<p>They story’s central “was it real?” conflict is one Tremblay likes to stick us with, but it’s not frustrating because of everything else the novel does. Mercy’s crossing out of “memoir” and editing it to “novel” pervades the book. Are there some parts where the device wears thin? Yeah—the floating dresser didn’t grab me. But the rest, holy crow.</p>
<p>I read a review on Goodreads where someone said this book was basically about a maybe-haunted jacket and that made it boring. And all I can say is that review proves it’s possible to miss the point of something spectacularly. Because the “haunting” in this book isn’t just about visions that could maybe be passed off as a bad trip. There’s so much more to it.</p>
<p>SPOILER WARNING: my reading is one of no supernatural powers. Mercy is not a vampire, nor did she make Art one. It’s not creatures of the night that kill us, it’s life itself. The real monsters, if I can be permitted the cliché, are the heart that betrays us, the bones that warp and curve, the self-loathing we can’t get over, the loneliness that we all feel and we all deny. I think that Art found comfort in those stories, like I did, and Mercy—notice the name that isn’t hers, though it’s the one we know her as while reading—indulges the interpretation.</p>
<p>I’ve heard stories called a lot of things but here’s a new one: Tremblay tells us that a book is a coffin. That we have, by reading to the end, joined the Pallbearers’ Club ourselves. This closing paragraph is one that will stick with me. I’ll use it to explain horror and why it’s so important to me like I do with “Most times, a ghost is a wish.” It’s beautiful, and I think you should read it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: The Impossible Resurrection of Grief, by Octavia Cade</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-impossible-resurrection-of-grief-by-octavia-cade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanna Z. Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 10:27:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Noteworthy Novellas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Octavia Cade is not the first author to tackle the looming specter of climate change,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"><a href="https://ojcade.com/">Octavia Cade</a><a href="https://ojcade.com/"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27841 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/grief-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/grief-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/grief.jpg 267w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></a> is not the first author to tackle the looming specter of climate change, but <a href="https://www.stelliform.press/index.php/octavia-cade-impossible-resurrection-of-grief/"><i>The Impossible Resurrection of Grief</i></a> still manages to find a unique niche in that landscape. In a world of sometimes strident diatribes, Cade crafts a eulogy. This isn’t a fire and brimstone preacher demanding that you repent. It’s a friend taking your hands in their own, looking you straight in the eye and saying, “yes, I see it, too.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"><i>The Impossible Resurrection of Grief</i> takes place in the near future, in a time when species and ecosystems that are now critically threatened have finally succumbed. In the wake of this loss, people have begun suffering from the Grief – an all-consuming fixation on what the world has lost, which always ends in suicide. When our narrator, Ruby, loses her best friend to the Grief, she is drawn into a web of secrets and manipulations that pulls her from Australia to Tasmania and New Zealand.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">I found the first chapter a little confusing, as it is not told in chronological order, but </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">the novella</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> quickly settles </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">in</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">to a straightforward narrative. The suspense comes from the mystery that Ruby must unravel, and from her own ruminations. This is a very internal book, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">and a lot of the forward momentum comes from Ruby’s growing understanding of the Grief, of herself, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">and of humanity as a whole. What does it say about us, that we can watch so many species die, yet do nothing?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Cade describes Ruby’s questions and her suffering </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">beautifully</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">, not to mention the </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">detailed observations of the </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">world around her. I think that is part of why the book works – the themes are dark, but the writing is so gorgeous that it provides something of a protective balm. It makes the pain bearable.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">The ending feels inevitable, but also</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> somewhat incomplete. Cade carries the reader through an emotional journey</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">but I finished the book still unclear on </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">exactly </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">what the people behind the mysteries wanted from Ruby. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Or perhaps I’m just not smart enough to see it. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Thematically, the ending is perfect, and I can see why a book about such a weighty topic could not wrap everything up in a bow.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">This is not </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">comfortable</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> reading. But </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">I never felt like it was wallowing in sorrow, so much as revealing </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">the </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">thoughts and feelings that I normally </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">turn away from</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">. T</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">here is a catharsis to reading a narrative that speaks aloud the deepest fears and knowings of a bruised heart. I found this novella to be more bracing than </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">depress</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">ing, but of course that is a</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">n</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> individual line.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">I doubt that any story could convince somebody to care about climate change, and I don’t think that was Cade’s intention. However, if you would like a book to help you sit with the sadness you already feel, I believe that <i>The Impossible Resurrection of Grief</i> will serve you well.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: The Anthropocene Reviewed</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-anthropocene-reviewed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy May, everyone! Spring weather is finally upon us here in New York City, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy May, everyone! Spring weather is finally upon us here in New York City, and it&#8217;s putting pep in my step as I bring you today&#8217;s book review: <em>The Anthropocene Reviewed </em>by John Green. Unlike his usual YA fiction, this is a collection of short, personal essays penned on a variety of topics. It can get a little bleak at times &#8212; this might have been a little too dark and quippy to be on my winter bookshelf &#8212; but reading it as the days grow longer and the sun glows brighter has allowed me to stay positive and have hope for the future.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-27583 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/download.jpg" alt="" width="183" height="276" /></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><em>Anthropocene (noun): the current geological age, viewed as the period during which human activity has been the dominant influence on climate and the environment.</em></h4>
<p>Let&#8217;s back up a bit. What even <em>is </em>an &#8220;anthropocene&#8221; anyway? As explained in this book, the anthropocene is the current state of the planet, where humans are essentially the most powerful race and have the most impact on our world. In a way, we&#8217;re basically zooming out from terms like ethnocentrism, to something more globally &#8220;human-centric.&#8221; From accelerating climate change with fossil fuels, to littering our waters with discarded plastic, humans have more influence than any other living creature on Earth. John Green takes a bunch of topics that seemingly have no correlation to each other, but all relate back to the subject at hand: the anthropocene.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><em>“I know the world will survive us &#8211; and in some ways it will be more alive.”</em></h4>
<p>This book actually started as a <a href="https://www.johngreenbooks.com/podcast">podcast</a> he did with his brother, Hank, a few years ago. For written publication, he compiled transcripts from those podcast episodes and expanded upon the ideas presented in them, along with adding essays on brand new topics. A lot of his editorial work takes place during the height of The Pandemic <em>(Does this get capitalized? It&#8217;s a new-enough situation. Has anyone decided yet? Who&#8217;s in charge here?).</em></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;">&#8220;<em>It is May of 2020, and I do not have a brain well suited for this.”</em></h4>
<p>Reading &#8220;post-Pandemic&#8221; literature (though we aren&#8217;t quite out of the woods yet) produced an odd sensation in me. Seeing it written and mentioned like it was just another historical era, like The Great Depression or The Cold War&#8211;as though it is something that has passed us&#8211;was almost refreshing in a way. Like the worst was finally over, and we were factly on the way to recovery. No if&#8217;s, and&#8217;s, or take-backs.</p>
<p>The introduction then talks about John Green&#8217;s history of how he got into writing: by starting as a book reviewer on a blog <em>(just like me!). </em>He brings up that nowadays, almost everything is given a review out of 5 stars, but back then there was no such thing. It wasn&#8217;t really until Amazon that <em>everything </em>was given a numerical review&#8211;even though most things aren&#8217;t so simply quantified.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><em>“The five-star scale doesn’t really exist for humans; it exists for data aggregation systems, which is why it did not become standard until the internet era. Making conclusions about a book’s quality from a 175-word review is hard work for artificial intelligences, whereas star ratings are ideal for them.”</em></h4>
<p>He then proceeds to review the topic of every one of his essays on a five-star scale, from the Polio vaccine to Super Mario Kart, which is ironically hilarious. He even rates his own book on the copyright page, which I totally missed until my fellow book clubber pointed it out to me. He&#8217;s casually witty like that.</p>
<p>To put it frankly, I both love and hate John Green&#8217;s writing style. I hate his Charles-Dickens-but-more-interesting way of overcomplicating things that could have been simple if he just phrased them like a normal person. At the same time, however, I love his poetic words and how he makes the most frivolous sentences seem magical. As someone who has read a few of his YA novels, it was fascinating to see here that his nonfiction voice is exactly the same as his writing style for fiction. I&#8217;d know his words anywhere.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;">“life is never simple paths- only dizzying labyrinths folding in on themselves”</h4>
<p>As a PSA, I don&#8217;t suggest reading this novel as a start-to-finish &#8220;pick up and read&#8221; project. I found it the most successful as a &#8220;bathroom reader&#8221; or coffee table book. It was the most enticing to jump around; just crack it open and pick a topic that sounded interesting.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><em>“I suppose I missed writing, but in a way you miss someone you used to love.”</em></h4>
<p>As a PSA: if you&#8217;re a fan of his podcast and wanted to read the book, I feel compelled to tell you that you might sometimes read things that were word-for-word taken from the transcription. It isn&#8217;t always that way&#8211;he expanded on some essays and wrote some completely new ones&#8211;but  it deserves pointing out. It&#8217;s not similar enough that you can follow along as if it&#8217;s an audiobook (one of those also exists for the written publication) but being that the podcast is free, I recommend giving it a listen before you buy it. It&#8217;s also available on Spotify, Apple Music, and all the other usual listening places if you&#8217;re interested. The individual episodes are a really good length for a 20-ish minute drive. Or, you can do like I did and just borrow the e-book from the library.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><em>“Gatsby is a critique of the American Dream. The only people who end up rich or successful in the novel are the ones who start out that way. Almost everyone else ends up dead or destitute. And it’s a critique of the kind of vapid capitalism that can’t find anything more interesting to do with money than try to make more of it. The book lays bare the carelessness of the entitled rich—the kind of people who buy puppies but won’t take care of dogs, or who purchase vast libraries of books but never read any of them.”</em></h4>
<p>Overall, I really enjoyed this quirky little book. I could wax poetic for hours, go on and on &#8230;.<br />
<em>OR, </em>I could be like John Green and quantify my review like a robot.</p>
<p>I give <em>The Anthropocene Reviewed </em>four stars. ✰✰✰✰</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: &#8216;The Memory Librarian&#8217; (2022)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-memory-librarian-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With six stories ranging from micro-fiction to novella in length, The Memory Librarian (2022) extends&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_27440" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-27440" style="width: 197px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-27440 size-medium" src="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/memory_librarian_harper_collins-197x300.webp" alt="Cover of 'The Memory Librarian' book (2022). Features an edited image of Janelle Monae in 'Dirty Computer' (2018)." width="197" height="300" srcset="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/memory_librarian_harper_collins-197x300.webp 197w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/memory_librarian_harper_collins.webp 425w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-27440" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Source: Harper Collins</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With six stories ranging from micro-fiction to novella in length, <em>The </em></span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Memory Librarian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (2022) extends </span><a href="http://www.transchordian.com/2013/10/metropolis-janelle-monaes-hidden-sci-fi-epic/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the dystopian world</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that thespian-musician Janelle Monae has been constructing for at least 15 years. Working with five acclaimed speculative fiction writers (Alaya Dawn Johnson, Eve Ewing, Danny Lore, Yohanca Delgado, and Sheree Renée Thomas), Monae weaves her own discography and the science-fiction classics that inspired it into a debut collection that insists upon black-queer politics and black-queer futurisms. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Librarian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">’s recurring theme is the importance of communal memory to political resistance, which is metaphorized through rebel characters who “remix” </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nevermind </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">: a gaseous chemical that erases deviants’ memories in order to maintain the social order of New Dawn. New Dawn is a fascist metropolis, but it nonetheless contains pockets of resistance that thrive and survive in its neglected districts.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Librarian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">’s stories — namely “The Memory Librarian” (co-written with Johnson) and “Nevermind” (co-written with Lore) — representations of transness that were </span><a href="http://blackyouthproject.com/janelle-monaes-pynk-subtly-acknowledges-the-existence-of-trans-bodies-but-we-deserve-more-than-that/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">only alluded to</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Monae’s otherwise outspoken </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dirty Computer</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (2018) find rooting in principal, trans characters with complicated lives — lives that are touched by both pleasure and hardship. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The title story (“The Memory Librarian,” co-written with Johnson) was by far my favorite piece in the collection, both for its sensitive sketch of a rebellious, black trans woman (Alethia a.k.a. Lethe), and for its vivid depiction of New Dawn. This story seems to be the heart of the collection, dramatizing its revolutionary investments (see: protagonist Seshet’s gradual defection from New Dawn’s government), and fleshing out an exciting magic system (see: disc jockeys’ abilities to “remix” Nevermind into an intoxicant). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve been of two minds, however, about “Nevermind” (co-written with Lore). Not because of the quality of its writing or its story arc, which were fine (I enjoyed its considerations of non-punitive justice, and of the disappointments we face as we try to ‘find our people’). My issue with the story is that I suffer from a continued ambivalence towards </span><a href="https://youtu.be/PaYvlVR_BEc"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pynk</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which I see</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">as an essentialist feminist concept. Even with an explicitly nonbinary character (Neer) starring alongside Jane 57821 (one of Monae’s dirty-computer personae), and even with a sharp critique of transphobic feminists, by choosing to set this story in Pynk Hotel (a women’s commune depicted in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dirty Computer</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">’s </span><a href="https://vimeo.com/268498567"><span style="font-weight: 400;">emotion picture</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">), the writers confine the narrative to oversimplified conceptions of femininity and womanhood. This story suggests that anyone who identifies with womanhood is welcome at </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pynk</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but it doesn’t sufficiently (re)consider what womanhood is, or how </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">pynk </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">could be an alternative to normative gender categories. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The four stories that cushion the title story and “Nevermind” — “Breaking Dawn” (solely authored by Monae), “Timebox” (Ewing), “Save Changes” (Delgado), “Time Altar(ed)” (Thomas) — have promising moments, but they ultimately feel less grounded in the sleek aesthetics of New Dawn. They&#8217;re emotionally resonant, but lack the tightness and focus that could have turned a decent collection into an excellent one.  </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">**I received an Advance Reader Copy through NetGalley in exchange for a review.</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: The Moth Girl</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-moth-girl/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 10:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27385</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’ve all seen the stories where the protagonist starts to feel strange aches in their&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We’ve all seen the stories where the protagonist starts to feel strange aches in their body, have sudden disorienting perceptions of the world, or begin floating, usually right before a cathartic <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27394 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/58395029-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/58395029-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/58395029.jpg 265w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" />realization of their new self as a superhero, but <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/623424/the-moth-girl-by-heather-kamins/"><em>The Moth Girl</em></a> by <a href="https://heatherkamins.com/">Heather Kamins</a> is a story where those symptoms mean something entirely different. Protagonists with chronic illness are a rarity in sci-fi and fantasy and I hope to read more novels like this that bring those characters to the forefront in the genre.</p>
<p>Anna’s starting her sophomore year on a high note with new outfits to try out at parties and burgeoning friendships with the fastest squad on the cross-country team. She’s finally running at the front of the pack when the stunning swiftness in her feet turns to a growing pain that leaves her unconscious, and hovering, in the middle of practice. She’s diagnosed with a manifestological disorder that bars her from doing almost everything she’d enjoyed before and leaves her with the question of who she really is and how she defines herself.</p>
<p>This book was something I hadn’t realized I was searching for, and I’m glad that it’s out there now on the shelves. The illness has several fantastical effects, from floating to growing scales, but the looming fear and dread of what each small indulgence might mean and having to remind others of new needs and limitations is a very grounded depiction of the experience of chronic illness. As is the uncertainty that comes with the promise of a “normal life span” and yet the <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-27396 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/evie-s-ykP_G8afgCE-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/evie-s-ykP_G8afgCE-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/evie-s-ykP_G8afgCE-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/evie-s-ykP_G8afgCE-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/evie-s-ykP_G8afgCE-unsplash-1228x1536.jpg 1228w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/evie-s-ykP_G8afgCE-unsplash-1638x2048.jpg 1638w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/evie-s-ykP_G8afgCE-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2047w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />potentially debilitating and deadly consequences of living everyday life. It’s not every experience of diagnosis, but the tangle of emotions in Anna and the reactions from her family and friends are something that can apply to many. The part that really struck home for me was the awkward and sometimes harmful perspectives Anna’s friends had towards her diagnosis. For some, communication on both sides was enough to mend the fractured bridges, but for others it was simply best to let them go when they were dragging her back.</p>
<p><span id="m_-8947184348929310520gmail-docs-internal-guid-411d936f-7fff-17ed-7b35-35b030cf177f">I’d recommend this book to those who like magical realism, the movie <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patema_Inverted"><em>Patema Inverted</em></a>, or who need a story about chronic illness where the fantastical doesn’t magically fix it.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Everything, Everything</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-everything-everything/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 11:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2022&#8217;s Book Club is in full swing, and our January pick has been keeping me&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="noteHighlightTextContainer__highlightContainer">
<div class="noteHighlightTextContainer__highlightText" style="text-align: left;">2022&#8217;s Book Club is in full swing, and our January pick has been keeping me warm during these cold winter months. Like <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-house-of-hollow/">last time</a>, I begged fellow LSQ blogger and YA enthusiast <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/alexa-kelly/">Alexa</a> for another recommendation. For this month, we were focusing on books written by Black authors, and my friend did not disappoint&#8211;though that comes to no surprise; she never does.</div>
</div>
<p>Before I start waxing poetic about my experience with this book, let me give you the gist of what it&#8217;s all about.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone " src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/918UijrZ4pL.jpg" width="229" height="344" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>“What did you wish for?” she asks as soon as I open my eyes. Really there’s only one thing to wish for—a magical cure that will allow me to run free outside like a wild animal. But I never make that wish because it’s impossible. It’s like wishing that mermaids and dragons and unicorns were real. Instead I wish for something more likely than a cure. Something less likely to make us both sad. “World peace,” I say.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.nicolayoon.com/everything-everything-book-details"><em>Everything, Everything</em></a> by <a href="https://www.nicolayoon.com/">Nicola Yoon</a> is a book about life; living, and what it takes to get there. Madeline Whittaker is just your average 18-year-old girl&#8211;oh, except for the fact that she has a rare disease that makes her allergic to everything and she&#8217;ll die if she leaves the house. She&#8217;s accepted this, and she&#8217;s pretty content with her days of online learning and nightly games of Phonetic Scrabble (or Fonetik Skrabbl) with her mom.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Until one day, she&#8217;s not. A boy about her age and his family move across the street, and suddenly her tiny, residential life isn&#8217;t enough anymore. Suddenly, she wants everything, everything the world has to offer.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p>As someone with a short attention span, I can&#8217;t help but <em>rave </em>about the length of this book. It&#8217;s about a 3 1/2 hour read, barely above 300 pages. This book is told through Madeline&#8217;s perspective, and her little doodles and journal entries really make the pages fly by.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>He’s tall, lean, and wearing all black: black T-shirt, black jeans, black sneakers, and a black knit cap that covers his hair completely. He’s white with a pale honey tan and his face is starkly angular.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>One thing Yoon really excels at is contrast. She features it in her descriptions often, and also uses it as symbols. To some, it might seem a little on the nose to have rebel Ollie dressed in all black and innocent unworldly Madeline in pure white, but having their wardrobe be opposite to their skin tones is a nice touch.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>I’ve never lied to my mom. I’ve never had a reason and I don’t think I know how to. </em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I adore Yoon&#8217;s use of premonition. Her finely-tuned ability to make the twists featured later in the novel sound reasonable and realistic in the world she&#8217;s set before us, but still surprising in a way that doesn&#8217;t make the reader feel talked down to.</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Madeline: I’m not a princess.<br />
</em><em>Madeline: And I don’t need rescuing.<br />
Olly: that’s ok. i’m no prince</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>It&#8217;s not easy for modern day authors to ignore the technology we have access to in our present day world. Making a relationship bloom on the page using features like instant messaging can be tricky, but the way Yoon intersperses it throughout the novel gives the reader aptly-timed breaks in between delightful chunks of prose.</p>
<p>This was such a quick, enjoyable read! Watching the &#8220;first love&#8221; between Ollie and Madeline blossom is really endearing; it made me feel 18 again! I&#8217;d recommend this book to anyone who wants a warm, one-sitting Sunday morning read, or just wants to read some cute YA. If you like  <a href="https://beckyalbertalli.com/simon-vs-the-homo-sapiens-agenda"><em>Simon vs. the Homo Sapiens Agenda</em></a>, or books in the same vein, you should check this out. Bonus: the actor who plays Simon in the movie also plays Olly in the film for this that came out a few years ago! I haven&#8217;t gotten a chance to see it yet, but now I think I might need to!</p>
<blockquote>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><em><strong>“Life is a gift. Don&#8217;t forget to live it.&#8221;</strong></em></h4>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: ‘Where the Rain Cannot Reach’ by Adesina Brown</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-where-the-rain-cannot-reach-by-adesina-brown/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liza Wemakor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 11:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Enclaves: A Black Femme Dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26756</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Published by Atmosphere Press in December 2021. 318 pages. My personal notes for Where The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-26766 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_ABrown_frontcover-194x300.jpg" alt="Front cover of Adesina Brown's novel, 'Where The Rain Cannot Reach.' The image shows a dagger piercing a large, red sun. A smaller yellow sun is shown behind the dagger's hilt. The background is black." width="294" height="455" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_ABrown_frontcover-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_ABrown_frontcover-663x1024.jpg 663w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_ABrown_frontcover-768x1186.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_ABrown_frontcover.jpg 971w" sizes="(max-width: 294px) 100vw, 294px" /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-26767" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_Map.jpg" alt="Map of Gosso, a fictional continent. This is the setting of Adesina Brown's novel, 'Where The Rain Cannot Reach.'" width="295" height="456" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_Map.jpg 312w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/WTRCR_Map-194x300.jpg 194w" sizes="(max-width: 295px) 100vw, 295px" /></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Published by </span></i><a href="https://atmospherepress.com/books/where-the-rain-cannot-reach-by-adesina-brown/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Atmosphere Press</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400"> in December 2021. 318 pages.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">My personal notes for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Where The Rain Cannot Reach </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">(</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">WTRCR</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">) abound with direct quotes that either shifted or affirmed my understanding of freedom (which I’ll return to later). </span><a href="https://www.adesinabrown.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400">Adesina Brown</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">’s debut novel is remarkably wise and gentle, though it doesn’t exempt its characters from the inevitable hardships of resisting centuries-long oppression. This novel is rife with ruminations on love, relationships, identity and political struggles that are integral to its worldbuilding. Readers of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">WTRCR </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">will encounter a world that is reminiscent of Tolkien’s Middle-Earth, yet proves </span><a href="https://theconversation.com/was-tolkien-really-racist-108227"><span style="font-weight: 400">far more effective</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> at depicting </span><a href="https://nkjemisin.com/2013/02/from-the-mailbag-the-unbearable-baggage-of-orcing/"><span style="font-weight: 400">race</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400"> and gender in ways that diverge from real-world racism, patriarchy, and imperialism. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">WTRCR</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> is constructed around an epic, heroic journey. Tair, the protagonist, is introduced to us as a young, brown-skinned, displaced Human on the brink of adulthood. Her elders consist of a Dwarf (Shianna), an Elf (Silaa), and a Fel, or Faery-Elf hybrid (Alyn). These elders have raised Tair in the Elf-land of Mirte — alternately training her for and protecting her from the challenging future that lies ahead. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As an infant, Tair was abandoned in the Darkwoods that separate Human lands (Sossoa) from non-Human lands (Nossoa), on the continent of Gosso. As the prophesied “lost” Human child, Tair is destined to trigger the end of Sossoa’s fascistic regime, which perpetuates mass-murder and torture against all non-Human life (derogatorily referred to as </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">raiso</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">). Until the end of the novel, it isn’t clear </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">how </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">Tair will end this regime, but there’s no small chance that it will involve a great amount of self-sacrifice. Brown is deliberate about making readers wait to learn what Tair is truly capable of, and the drawn-out conclusion makes Tair’s journey all the more revelatory. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Tair’s perpetual alienation (as a multilingual Human raised by non-Humans) opens up </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">WTRCR </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">to many reconsiderations of Tair’s world specifically, and of life generally. In an attempt to avoid spoilers without withholding the author’s tender words, I’ll share bits of the </span><span style="font-weight: 400">wisdom </span><span style="font-weight: 400">I mentioned at the beginning of this review. Below are some chronological excerpts that strike me as wise and </span><span style="font-weight: 400">a</span><span style="font-weight: 400">ffective:</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“&#8230;she had been told that she was not unique in her responsibilities, her path, her life, but that she was precious all the same.” (p. 14)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“Shianna herself was rather averse to complacency [&#8230;] </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">It is in the refusal to defend others that one loses their ability to defend themself</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">, she had said on occasion.” (p. 19)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“There had to be something else lingering within her and other Humans that they had not yet been able to discover. Something that had perhaps laid dormant for generations.” (p. 118)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“In Sossoa, there were beings who looked like her, yet she was still unsure of whether or not simply looking like someone made anywhere feel like home.” (p. 205)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“‘Liberation may one day mean the ability to move freely between lands, to determine for oneself where they belong and what they will do with their lives once they get there,’ Rose continued on.” (p. 223)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: left"><span style="font-weight: 400">“Both of them knew that something had changed in Tair. Something was different. Different, not wrong. Not wrong but changing. She could not place what it was, but she at least had a secret now— something she could not, and would not, allow Rain to see.” (p. 293)</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Having discussed what I enjoyed in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">WTRCR</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">, I’ll close this review with what left me wanting more. In the middle third of the novel (starting around Chapter 5, when Tair is troubled to learn more about what’s expected of her, or what her heroism entails), the story loses some of its emotional force — zipping through major events in Tair’s journey without allowing readers ample time and space to digest them. In this middle section, Tair’s reactions to her changing circumstances often felt like obligatory details as opposed to integral ones — quickly fading into the background to make way for another plot point. The final third of the novel ultimately won me over again, but there are missed opportunities, in the telling of this story, to elaborate upon Sossoa’s cruelty in relation to other realms and establish Tair’s personality beyond her pacifism, stubbornness, and youthful naivete. <em>WTRCR</em> is meant to be the first book in a multi-book series; I hope the subsequent volumes pick up on those missed opportunities.</span></p>
<p><em>*I was provided with an e-book in exchange for an honest review</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: A Psalm for the Wild-Built</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-a-psalm-for-the-wild-built/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanna Z. Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 11:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Noteworthy Novellas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Once upon a time, a monk living on a solarpunk moon left the city on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26557 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/psalm-188x300.jpg" alt="" width="188" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/psalm-188x300.jpg 188w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/psalm.jpg 297w" sizes="(max-width: 188px) 100vw, 188px" />Once upon a time, a monk </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">living on a solarpunk moon</span> <span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">left</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> the city on a quest to hear crickets. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Sibling Dex leaves their post as a gardener and takes up the life of a tea monk, traveling through the small towns bringing comfort to all they meet. </span><a href="https://publishing.tor.com/apsalmforthewildbuilt-dbtmp1203370/9781250236210/"><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"><i>A Psalm for the Wild-Built</i></span></a><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">, by <a href="https://www.otherscribbles.com/">Becky Chambers</a>, is a touching exploration of purpose, relationships, humanity, and the keening ache for something out of reach.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Dex is an amazingly relatable protagonist. I realize that is </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">a</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> cliche, but in this case, it’s absolutely true. Their yearning for something more, their moments of intense embar</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">r</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">assment, the way they freeze up when they don’t know what to do – I saw myself in them. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">I, too, have been dissatisfied despite living a life that </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">looks</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> good from the outside. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Many people have experienced that sort of existential angst</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Sibling Dex’s</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> problems are </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">my</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> problems, set in a fantastical world.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">And what a world it is! Sibling Dex lives on a moon, Panga. It’s been two hundred years since the Age of Factories, when the robots woke up and left humanity behind. Since then, humans have built a new, more sustainable society: a solarpunk near-utopia where the environment is respected, nobody goes hungry, and solar, wind, and water provide all the power they need.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">The early part of the book focuses on Sibling Dex and their situation, but </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">the story</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> really comes alive when they are met by an unexpected visitor – a robot called Mosscap. Their conversations are at turns humorous and philosophical, a series of fumbling but well-intentioned attempts t</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">o</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> bridge the gap between their experiences. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Dex has a lot of preconceived notions about robots, which leads to some hilarious misunderstandings. Mosscap’s gentle corrections are always firm, without ever suggesting that Dex was speaking with bad intent. Dex, in turn, accepts Mosscap’s corrections with grace. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">This is the kind of healthy interaction I love to see modeled.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">A</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">s you may have gathered, the stakes </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">in this book </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">are not high. There is no life or death conflict, no great evil to defeat or destiny to achieve. Personally, I cherished this philosophical, conversational journey into meaning, but if you are in the market for something more </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">fast-paced</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">, then I recommend that you look elsewhere.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">The ending is as sweet and tender as the rest of the book, which won’t be a surprise to anyone familiar with the author’s other work. Your heart is always in good hands with Becky Chambers. There are no easy answers (I don’t think I would be recommending this book if there were!), but there is a lot of hope, not to mention plenty of plot threads for the upcoming sequel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Nearly two years into a pandemic, with the holiday season </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">in full swing</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">, many of us need something grounding, something comforting that will tell us that we’re okay, that the world can be safe and good. This little book could be that something.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: House of Hollow</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-house-of-hollow/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-house-of-hollow/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Samantha Penn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 11:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“I am the thing in the dark.” Like most lost souls in 2020, I joined&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-26416 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/d0csy5qs0ze-225x300.jpg" alt="black bare tree inside a forest covered with fog" width="314" height="357" /></p>
<h4 style="text-align: center;"><em>“I <strong>am</strong> the thing in the dark.”</em></h4>
<p>Like most lost souls in 2020, I joined a quarantine-era book club to fill the time. Unlike many of those 2020 book clubs, I&#8217;m proud to say our group is surprisingly still going strong! When it was my turn to pick the club book last month, I wanted it to capture the spooky vibes that October has to offer. Naturally, I turned to LSQ blogger and witchy friend <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/alexa-kelly/">Alexa</a> for a rec. She has never steered me wrong before, and she certainly didn&#8217;t with this pick!</p>
<p>Let me start by offering a word of advice: be careful what you wish for. For all of you &#8220;cottagecore&#8221; folks out there wanting to become moss or something, read <em><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54613751-house-of-hollow">House of Hollow</a> </em>by Krystal Sutherland. You&#8217;ll either 1) love it or 2) change your mind about the whole &#8220;becoming moss&#8221; thing.</p>
<p>Let me give you a little taste of what the book is about.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26430 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hollow-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hollow-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hollow-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hollow-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hollow-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hollow-1366x2048.jpg 1366w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hollow.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />House of Hollow follows 17-year-old Iris Hollow, the youngest of the three Hollow sisters, on her quest for normalcy in her everyday life. Don&#8217;t get the wrong idea: she&#8217;s normal for all intents and purposes&#8211;almost to a fault. She never skips class, always does her homework, always does what her mom asks of her. Despite all this, something has always felt off, but maybe that&#8217;s just because her two older sisters, Grey and Vivi, are eccentric enough for the three of them.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Maybe it&#8217;s because they mysteriously went missing one New Years Eve, as children on a crowded Edinburgh street barely a foot away from their parents. Or maybe because it&#8217;s they returned exactly one month later, without their clothes and with absolutely no memory of what happened. The only clue they had was the crescent-moon shaped scars at the base of their throats.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Iris would stay wrapped in mystery forever if it meant she could hold on to her remaining strands of normalcy, but life has other plans for her.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p>This book really has something for everybody: urban fantasy, mystery, family drama, spookiness, <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">dead people</span>. (Well, maybe that last one&#8217;s not true&#8230; or is it?) It&#8217;s British gothic meets voodoo magic meets realism. It&#8217;s <em>Stranger Things</em> meets <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43521657-the-ten-thousand-doors-of-january">The Ten Thousand Doors of January</a> meets <em>The Craft</em>. I can&#8217;t even begin to express how vivid and vibrant Sutherland&#8217;s descriptions are. Reading this book allowed me to feel the moss between my toes, the sharp vines twisting around my limbs, and the awful smell the decaying human flesh rotting in the ceiling&#8211;and I loved every minute of it. Her ability to make your skin crawl or your heart beat fast with words alone is truly mesmerizing. The whole experience feels like a cloudy dream and a horrible nightmare, reveling in the beauty of her words while dreading to turn the page and learn their meaning.</p>
<p>The three sisters are the embodiment of &#8220;look but don&#8217;t touch,&#8221; though you don&#8217;t know why (at first). People are drawn to them because they&#8217;re beautiful, but there&#8217;s a sense of danger lurking behind their pretty smiles. They are equal parts compelling and strange, frightening and ethereal. That enigmatic quality is what draws the reader to them as well. In theory, they shouldn&#8217;t be anything other than normal, but there&#8217;s something there that goes beyond a simple <em>je ne sais quoi. </em>They have a secret, hidden so deep that not even Iris is aware of what it is, but you&#8217;ll keep turning the pages until you find out what it is. The mystery will eat at you, crawling and scratching at your mind until you&#8217;re just waiting for the next time you can open the book back up and find out what happens next.</p>
<p>If you want to keep the Halloween vibes going, I highly recommend this book. It can be a little on the horror/gruesome side at times, so be warned, but I can&#8217;t stress enough how thoroughly I enjoyed my time reading <em>House of Hollow</em>. If this author were to make another book in this series, I&#8217;d pick it up in a heartbeat.</p>
<p>What are you reading? Come find me on <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/55341903-samantha">GoodReads</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-house-of-hollow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: The Godma&#8217;s Daughters</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-godmas-daughters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 11:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reading this book was like being on a rollercoaster: dipping in and out of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26302 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Godmas-Daughters-200x300.jpeg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Godmas-Daughters-200x300.jpeg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Godmas-Daughters-684x1024.jpeg 684w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Godmas-Daughters-768x1150.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Godmas-Daughters-1026x1536.jpeg 1026w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Godmas-Daughters-1368x2048.jpeg 1368w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Godmas-Daughters.jpeg 1710w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Reading this book was like being on a rollercoaster: dipping in and out of the past, present, and future; letting you catch glimpses of the drop coming ahead; ending right back where it started. It was a dizzyingly fast read despite being a rather long one!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://whitemonkeychronicles.com/the-godmas-daughters"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Godma’s Daughters</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by <a href="https://whitemonkeychronicles.com/">Isabella Ides</a> is the story of Mocheela A’chimal and her life, both in the border town of Trescabras and the life she lives in her grandmother’s story. When her cousin, Lilliana, comes to live with them and their two’s company becomes a crowd of three, it is not just the beginning of their lives together as they grow up but their history together as CocoMocheela and LilyHá, their spirit sisters whose stories unfold alongside their own. Never has ‘parallels’ been a more appropriate word for what happens in this story. There’s burro mayors and Maya jade and cenotes as the centerpieces of this novel and the antics, more like adventures, of Lilliana and Mocheela are caught up in the unveiling of their grandmother, Máhkina’s, grand epic. You’ll learn some things about Maya culture and beliefs, and even pronunciation, and the worlds a border woman crosses on her journey. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What I enjoyed the most about this book was Lilliana; her entrance is unapologetic in disturbing the tranquil balance of Mocheela’s life, but she elbows her way into Mocheela’s good graces with that very same brash and honest edge. She’s an artist with an eye for design and she’s determined to make a name for herself, a drive that feels grounded despite the usually lofty ambitions that come with that goal. She’s not afraid to stand up and bite back nor of flying too close to the sun; I sympathized with Mocheela in both admiring and being afraid for her at the same time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s a very feminist-themed book; Mákhina tells legends about the Godma, Ixmukháne, and the core of many of Mocheela’s interactions and lessons from her grandmother are on the idea of a secret history that has been buried and forgotten on the important role of women in Maya society and religion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’d recommend </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Godma’s Daughters</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to anyone who likes monkeys, coming-of-age stories, and the power of the guaya pit.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
