<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>VeeMakeTheWay &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/veemaketheway/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 11:00:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Virginia Woolf&#8217;s &#8216;A Room of One&#8217;s Own&#8217; Through a Millennial&#8217;s Eyes</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/virginia-woolfs-a-room-of-ones-own-through-a-millennials-eyes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VeeMakeTheWay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[VeeMakeTheWay]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25931#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=25931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you already know who Virginia Woolf is and you have read her spectacular works&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you already know who Virginia Woolf is and you have read her spectacular works like <a class="md-crosslink" href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/Mrs-Dalloway-novel-by-Woolf"><em>Mrs. Dalloway</em></a> (1925) and <a class="md-crosslink" href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/To-the-Lighthouse"><em>To the Lighthouse</em></a> (1927), you would be familiar with her independent, empowering thoughts that were way ahead of her time. Her thoughts about literary history, women&#8217;s writing, and the politics of power created ripples throughout history across the world. </p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26150 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ARoomOfOnesOwn-183x300.jpeg" alt="" width="183" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ARoomOfOnesOwn-183x300.jpeg 183w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ARoomOfOnesOwn.jpeg 250w" sizes="(max-width: 183px) 100vw, 183px" />But what you should really read is the work  <em><span id="ref124723"></span><a class="md-crosslink" href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/A-Room-of-Ones-Own">A Room of One’s Own</a></em> (1929), which is a wake-up call for women to stop being absent from history. It is thought-provoking for us as millennial women who don&#8217;t have to go through the same constraints that women of her time had to go through. She advocates that women are absent not because of their lack of intelligence or talent but because of their financial status.</p>
<p>Our society at the moment is at its most progressive of periods, as women can access education and obtain employment anywhere at a higher position based on their experience and skills. So it is quite evident that unequal opportunities for women negatively affected all of society back then. But the fight for acknowledgment and compensation without being compared to the abilities of a male counterpart is still sometimes what a woman faces. On Women&#8217;s Day, in a progressive society like ours, we still need to address and fight against unequal pay at our workplaces.</p>
<p>Woolf talked about women in creative industries vastly, with an example of a hypothetical sister of Shakespeare in particular. She might have equal talent as her brother, but she was required to fulfill the mundane domestic duties and eventually, meets her fate in demise. But she doesn&#8217;t fail to celebrate those women who overcame these traditions and embraced their creative gifts like Jane Austen, Aphra Behn, etc.</p>
<p>The solution for a woman in those days, according to Woolf, to break free of such traditions was to earn something of her own and have a room of her own. Only a woman can write and represent the struggles of a woman, which lacked immensely in the literary works of those days. A man&#8217;s representation of a woman would always reaffirm the gender roles assigned to her by the male ego.</p>
<p>But in modern times, when a woman is earning her own money and is leading a life of her own independently of a man, is she still able to creatively express herself? Is a woman given her privacy to express her true self to the world? I would say, we are getting there but we still have a long way to go. But can following Virginia Woolf&#8217;s advice as a modern woman help you get you there faster?</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26151 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sam-goodgame-L7OCryC-s08-unsplash-300x185.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="185" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sam-goodgame-L7OCryC-s08-unsplash-300x185.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sam-goodgame-L7OCryC-s08-unsplash-1024x630.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sam-goodgame-L7OCryC-s08-unsplash-768x473.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sam-goodgame-L7OCryC-s08-unsplash-1536x946.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/sam-goodgame-L7OCryC-s08-unsplash.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Well, having your own room with a lock on it is not such an odd concept anymore. Most women even live alone, but is that taking them to where they want to be? I reckon it is; I watch many creative women on platforms like YouTube, Instagram, etc., trying to create their own brands and eventually starting up their own businesses. Creative expression in any form should be encouraged, and all women should strive to have something to themselves that will aid in this expression. Because we won that fight after centuries-long struggles, using this freedom is not only for our own good, but can result in positive influences for generations to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pursuing Careers in Publishing as a Woman of Color</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pursuing-careers-in-publishing-as-a-woman-of-color/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[VeeMakeTheWay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[VeeMakeTheWay]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It didn&#8217;t take me long to realize that my career and passion always laid in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25846 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/0frj2scuy4k-300x200.jpg" alt="bokeh photography of open book" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/0frj2scuy4k-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/0frj2scuy4k-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/0frj2scuy4k-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/0frj2scuy4k-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/0frj2scuy4k-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />It didn&#8217;t take me long to realize that my career and passion always laid in books. But the question was, what do I do? Or how? Well, I haven&#8217;t really gotten there yet, at least not where I want to be, but I have been through what all passionate publishing-hopeful people go through. I have been hopeful in the times when I thought &#8220;there is no better person out there for the job than myself.&#8221; I have always been terrified that I will never get there. I will never do the job that I love.</p>
<p>And to make it worse, I am still in a country where book careers are rather unreachable or most uncommon. You get up there on a job search portal and see absolutely nothing that you are looking for; instead, you just find something to help you get by, and all I am left with is hopes and dreams that I am not sure if I will ever accomplish. But I am not one of those who will just dream and never take any action. It wasn&#8217;t long ago that I began preparing to take a publishing course in the UK. I know it is the biggest risk anyone could ever take, especially for someone in a third-world country. My only option to fund my studies is the unbearable weight of student loans. And it is even harder to get there when the industry falls under the creative category, because most banks or organizations in these countries fund creative people for chasing their dreams.</p>
<p>The publishing industry is one of the most competitive industries in the world. There are few jobs available and the people pursuing them are far greater in number. But love for books and reading some of the marvelous but miraculous ones gave me hope (could be false hope). I immersed myself in the London-based publishing world, signed up for all types of virtual events, and spoke to some amazing people who are already there where I want to go. That&#8217;s how I came across someone who is known to be a career expert in publishing.</p>
<p>I thought it would help me but it didn&#8217;t. In fact, I regretted speaking with her, but I wouldn&#8217;t say she was wrong with what she said. The interaction went like, &#8220;You are an immigrant, it is unlikely that you will get any work.&#8221; I didn&#8217;t flinch or back down even as she kept repeating it. Even though I knew the immigration rules and alternative ideas that I was planning to work through, she just refused to give me any help or encourage me. And on what grounds? Because I was an immigrant, a woman of color, and the chances of me trying to navigate through such a competitive industry were out of the question in her eyes.</p>
<p>She might be right, but the book world, an industry which should be more open-minded and looking for the right talent, is more biased towards people of color (even if they don&#8217;t really require sponsorship from the employer). It was just disheartening that for a half-hour slot, she gave me about five minutes of her time to tell me that I should just give up and not look into a publishing career at all (unless I have the right to work in the UK).</p>
<p>Should I give up? Am I that far away from my dream? I would like to believe that I&#8217;m not. I know the path is harder than any other career choice; it might take longer for me to get there and I would have to work twice as hard as others, but I could pave the way for others who are in my position to make their dreams come true more easily. If I give up, I will just be another person who wished to be part of a world which has least of the representation for people like us, but if I strive, I know I can help many others. Many big publishers are already incorporating changes such as <a href="https://www.the-scheme.co.uk/">https://www.the-scheme.co.uk/</a> under Penguin Random House UK, which helps underrepresented publishing career aspirants to get first-hand experience working at their office.</p>
<p>It is a long road, but it&#8217;s worth going forward, and the result that awaits will be reforming the publishing industry worldwide for the better.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
