<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Year 10 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/year-10/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:28:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Year 10 Blogger Interview: Meet D.M. Domosea</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/year-10-blogger-interview-meet-d-m-domosea/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/year-10-blogger-interview-meet-d-m-domosea/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Year 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We might be edging toward the end of the year with a bit of fall&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We might be edging toward the end of the year with a bit of fall in the air, but being the party animals we are, we&#8217;re continuing to celebrate our tenth year of publication. We&#8217;re delighted to feature an interview with one of our monthly bloggers, D.M. Domosea, today. Read below for a behind-the-scenes peek at her writing process and creativity.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: T<span class="im">ell us about how you got involved with LSQ&#8217;s blog⁠—how long have you<br />
been a blogger, how did you first learn about LSQ? What made you want to<br />
join the blog?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>DM: I’ve been blogging at my own website with consistent infrequency since June 2015 on a variety of subjects, but I don’t know that I’d call myself a “blogger.” Maybe more a chronicler of random nonsense and the ennui of everyday life. Wait, I guess that IS blogging! I’ve also been active since 2014 with my local writing group, the Frederick Writers’ Salon, which is<br />
where I met <em>LSQ</em>’s indefatigable managing blog editor, Anna O’Brien. She announced through our Meetup site in late 2017 that <em>Luna Station</em> was looking for regular blog contributors. My work and life schedule precluded me from taking immediate advantage of the opportunity, but I was fortunate enough the following summer to nab a work-from-home position. That switch gave me back nearly three hours a day previously spent on a horrendous commute. Every writer will tell you that three extra hours is a GIFT. It allowed me to ramp up my writing goals, which included contributing in a regular fashion to an established platform. I honestly couldn’t have found a better fit for my interests and writing personality than <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em>. It thrills the old-school <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anne_McCaffrey">Anne McCaffrey</a> geek in me!</p>
<p><em><strong><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16159 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/alex-read-uFAuASBMOVw-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/alex-read-uFAuASBMOVw-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/alex-read-uFAuASBMOVw-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/alex-read-uFAuASBMOVw-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />LSQ: </strong><span class="im"><strong>Tell us about your monthly column, &#8220;The S Word.&#8221; What topics and themes</strong><br />
<strong>do you explore? How do you curate fresh subject matter? Does any of what you</strong><br />
<strong>cover relate to your own writing?</strong> </span></em></p>
<p>DM: I just wrapped up a year-long thought experiment series called “A World Without Sex,” which imagines what our modern world might look like without human sexual reproduction. The idea evolved from the combination of a blog post I wrote in July 2017 on my site about the continued use of prostitutes in speculative fiction and a non-fiction book idea I’ve been toying with for some time that examines the history of sex and its effect on all facets of modern society. I realized after writing that blog post that it may be difficult for writers to create worlds that aren’t intrinsically patriarchal, because it’s all we’ve ever known. But I think that if we were to conceptually rip away an aspect (sex and sexuality!) that has historically served as both tool and weapon to disproportionately advantage and empower men (especially white cishet men), it could leave space enough to reimagine true-to-the-bone egalitarian and matriarchal worlds. Each month, I focused on a single broad subject—from religion to relationships—so I had no shortage of fresh topics to cover. The “A World Without Sex” series hasn’t directly related to any of my past or current writing projects, but I have an adult rom-com on my shortlist of prospective novels to write that deals with modern gendered perceptions of sex and sexuality. I’m still fine-tuning the details on my next series for “The S Word,” but it will explore the ways women-identifying artists express their geek-love for speculative fiction through their art, be it music, painting, or even performing arts. I hope to feature interviews with various artists, as well as articles that explore unique ways to convey a fondness for science fiction and fantasy.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">What&#8217;s the most challenging aspect about writing your column and why?<br />
What&#8217;s the most enjoyable?  </span></strong></em></p>
<p>DM: From day one, I was keenly aware of the limitations of my own perceptions and experiences when writing the “A World Without Sex” series. I addressed that in my introduction column and invited readers from all backgrounds to share their thoughts on the topic, because I’m always looking to learn more not just about the world I live in but about worlds I don’t live in. I can confidently speak to how a lack of sex in human history might have affected the environment of a small-town, middle-class, mostly hetero, formerly Baptist white girl from the United States, but I can only theorize in the most general way about sexual roles in other communities. My hope is that the column might inspire other female-identifying writers to reimagine their own communities in a sexually-neutered context and apply that to their work. As to the second question, I’ve immensely enjoyed everything I learned in my research for this series, even when it’s information that has angered or outraged me (and there’s been plenty of that!) Funny enough, I also stressed in my introduction column that I wasn’t going to spend a lot of time on research because of the potential time suck. I’d intended to take a strict “as I see it” approach, but as it turns out, the Virgo in me just couldn’t do that. That’s not to say I did extensive, heavy-lifting research on all my topics, but I definitely fell down a rabbit hole on certain subjects (LOL).</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Can you name some authors you draw inspiration from and tell us why? </span></strong></em></p>
<p>DM: Much of my formative fiction experience was shaped by Anne McCaffrey. I haven’t read her work in years, though I was lucky enough to come across her <i>Dragonriders of Pern</i> collection at the thrift store several months ago, so it’s waiting on my bookshelf. I’m curious to see if adult D.M. feels the same way about her writing as teenage D.M. I’ve spent the past four or five years reading heavily in young adult sci-fi and fantasy, because I’d been working on my own epic YA fantasy, and it’s crucial to be well-versed in the categories and genres you write.  There’s a tactile lushness and compelling aspect to Laini Taylor’s prose in her <i>Daughter of Smoke and Bone</i> series that I’d love to capture in my own projects. Sabaa Tahir is another current favorite. She knows how to draw in (i.e. torture) readers with beautiful descriptions and heart-wrenching tension. She’s created one of my all-time favorite characters in Helene Aquilla. I’ve also been following Diana Gabaldon’s <i>Outlander</i> saga for close to twenty years now. I’ve been less impressed with her latest novels in the series, but I’ve often been sucked into reading binges with her books. She’s writes in such a finely detailed way that her work has become my model of “immersive writing.”</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Can you tell us a bit about your own writing? Are you working on any<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16160 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/green-chameleon-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/green-chameleon-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/green-chameleon-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/green-chameleon-s9CC2SKySJM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><br />
other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about<br />
them?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>DM: Ooh—humble-brag time! I have projects out the wazoo right now. It’s a self-inflicted pain in the ass, I know, but it’s the good kind of hurt. I’m currently in the query trenches with a middle grade superhero novel, so that’s always fun (not!) I wrapped up and submitted a romance-horror tale to a Scary Stories anthology at the end of August, and I’ve just started work on another short story (think <i>Cats and Dogs</i> meets <i>Freaky Friday</i>) for a pet-focused beach reads anthology produced by Cat and Mouse Press.  They’ve included two of my short stories in their most recent anthologies, so I feel like I’m on a roll with them.  My writing group is now working on our third anthology, so in addition to contributing my own story (a juicy lesbian Prohibition-era noir), I’ve volunteered to serve as publication manager and lead story wrangler. And of course, I’m never truly happy unless I’ve got a full-length novel in the works. I’m weighing three different projects (including the aforementioned rom-com), trying to determine which holds the most promise and personal interest, all while marinating on deep revisions for the young adult epic fantasy saga that I just can’t let die. <i>The Fourborn Chronicles</i> is the project that brought me back into writing and—almost literally—saved my life during some dark days four years ago. I queried book one unsuccessfully for a year or two before I realized/accepted it had significant pacing and plot issues. But I believe in the story and love the four main characters like they are my own daughters, so I’m committed to doing the work. I know, I know…I have absolutely NO consistency when it comes to genres, format, or target audience. I like to think of myself as a writer-of-all-trades.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/year-10-blogger-interview-meet-d-m-domosea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Year 10 LSQ Blogger Interview: Meet Tisdale Flannery</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/year-10-lsq-blogger-interview-meet-tisdale-flannery/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/year-10-lsq-blogger-interview-meet-tisdale-flannery/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 10:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Year 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Can you believe it&#8217;s almost the third quarter of Year 10? Where does the time&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Can you believe it&#8217;s almost the third quarter of Year 10? Where does the time go? Thankfully we&#8217;ve still got lots to celebrate. We&#8217;re shining the spotlight today on blogger Tisdale Flannery, author of the &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/tea-with-strangers/">Tea with Strangers</a>&#8221; column.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about how you got involved with LSQ&#8217;s blog &#8212; how long have you been a blogger, how did you first learn about LSQ? What made you want to join the blog?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Tisdale: A brilliant writer invited members of our critique group to participate! At first, I was honestly intimidated. I&#8217;ve never blogged before, and I don&#8217;t consider myself an expert on much of <img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16081 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/tarot-991041_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/tarot-991041_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/tarot-991041_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/tarot-991041_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/tarot-991041_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />anything outside of my imagination. But Anna reassured us that yes, we were capable of doing this, and so, with trepidation, I began casting about for ideas. Initially I wanted to write about women in fiction in underrepresented nations. I quickly realized I was out of my depth; I knew so little about that. I did, however, know a great deal about Tarot, having read cards for decades now. So realizing that should be my topic was like being in a dark room when someone flips on the bright light:  of course that&#8217;s what I can share with the world. I have enjoyed writing every one of these posts.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about your monthly column, &#8220;Tea with Strangers.&#8221; Can you tell us how you became interested in Tarot? Each post of yours relates the concept of a card to a theme about the practice of writing. Can you tell us how you made the connection between Tarot and writing? Do you find that considering these interconnected themes helps you with your own writing? </strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Tisdale: One of my roommates in college was an artist. She was also a bit prickly; she slept only when no one was home and covered her headboard and footboard in concertina wire. Once she bought a deck of Tarot cards for a project. When she was out of the room, I figured she wouldn&#8217;t mind if I took a look at them. She did mind. In fact, she told me, I now needed to buy them from her, because my energy had already been transferred to the cards when I touched them with my bare hands. I considered questioning her on this, but her latest expression of rage on canvas changed my mind. (Exaggerating, just a little, and in actuality, we&#8217;re still friends, but that doesn&#8217;t mean it would have been wise to cross her.) That was the beginning of a long and fruitful relationship with cartomancy.</div>
<div></div>
<div>As for the connection, that was natural, because writing really is always on my mind. I frequently go to my cards with issues or questions I have about my writing projects. I find that the cards reveal both things I knew, but wasn&#8217;t admitting to myself, and things I&#8217;d never considered. So, in that way, Tarot has always been helping me with my writing.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: How closely do you identify with the interviewer in your column? Is there cross-over between her questions and writing worries and your own? Alternatively, the people the interviewer seeks provide extremely sage advice. Hopefully you identify with the interviewees as well?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Tisdale: My poor interviewer is more serious and more stressed out about life than I generally am, though what she learns in each interview, I am in the process of learning, myself; many lessons have to be learned over and over again, with different shades of meaning cast by the changing light of experience. I see myself as a bit more like the doppelganger. I don&#8217;t take too much of anything seriously these days; I&#8217;m along for the ride, artistically. I don&#8217;t at all identify with the interviewees, I&#8217;m afraid. I would say that, to me, they&#8217;re more like the voice of the muse that speaks through us when we&#8217;re able to shut up for a moment. I think that&#8217;s why I really love this fictional format. It allows me to go into my storytelling mode and write these characters without my conscious guidance at all. I don&#8217;t think I could write a non-fiction blog!</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Can you name some authors you draw inspiration from and tell us why?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Tisdale: Right now, my favorite books are the Crystal Cave trilogy by Mary Stewart. I&#8217;ve been listening to them on Audible (highly recommended!), rewinding, and trying to internalize her beautiful language. She&#8217;s on the List of Writers I Wish To Emulate, which also includes John Steinbeck (for the simple profound observations about human nature), Isak Dinesen (for the sheer power of her storytelling voice), Peter S. Beagle (for the lyrical, musical nature of his prose), Susanna Clarke (for the reality of the world she&#8217;s built, and the richness of place she creates), Kim Stanley Robinson (for the truth and depth of his research), Richard Adams (for the unfettered freedom of his imagination), and others: Angelica Gorodischer, Gabriel Garcia Marquez, Alice Hoffman, Barbara Kingsolver. I think, though, that one of the writers that shaped <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16082 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/key-3087900_1920-300x168.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="168" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/key-3087900_1920-300x168.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/key-3087900_1920-768x430.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/key-3087900_1920-1024x573.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/key-3087900_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />me the most was John Irving. My sisters and I grew up in a very restrictive environment, but we somehow kept a secret library of his books, banned by our religious community, and boy, did they open our eyes. I think, from that, I learned the most important lessons of all: Open locked closets and pull everything out. Go face to face with your deepest fears. Speak the truths that threaten the status quo, that make the people in charge uncomfortable.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Can you tell us a bit about your own fiction writing? What are the writing projects you are working on at the moment?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Tisdale: I have two novels and a handful of short stories written at this point in my life, in various stages of unsatisfactory revision, but right now, I&#8217;m in the process of gestating a new novel. This time, I intend to let it develop only naturally, not forcing the story in order to meet any self-imposed deadline. I research, and moodle, and dream, and draw, and jot ideas down, and go places by myself, and stare at moving water, and make playlists of songs that have the right feel; basically, I&#8217;m using the pretext of writing this novel as an excuse to do all the things I love to do. But so, in order not to let the pipes get rusty, I&#8217;m writing a short story here and there as I go, whenever I feel the impulse. I&#8217;m probably wasting a great deal of time, but it&#8217;s fun.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/year-10-lsq-blogger-interview-meet-tisdale-flannery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Year 10 blogger interview: Meet Suz Thackston</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/year-10-blogger-interview-meet-suz-thackston/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 11:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Year 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15888</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wow, the end of summer is sneaking up on us while we&#8217;ve been busy celebrating&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15889 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/markus-spiske-hl3W0M7aYPM-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/markus-spiske-hl3W0M7aYPM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/markus-spiske-hl3W0M7aYPM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/markus-spiske-hl3W0M7aYPM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Wow, the end of summer is sneaking up on us while we&#8217;ve been busy celebrating our tenth year of publication! Let&#8217;s continue the party by introducing you all to one of our regular bloggers, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/suz-thackston/">Suz Thackston</a>. Suz is the author of the column &#8220;Waifs, Wolves, &amp; Warriors &#8212; Women in Greek Mythology&#8221; and her love of ancient myths and speculative fiction shine through in her work.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about how you got involved with LSQ&#8217;s blog &#8212; how long have you been a blogger, how did you first learn about LSQ? What made you want to join the blog?</strong></em></p>
<p>Suz: I’ve been blogging in some capacity for, geez, almost two decades now. My old LiveJournal is still hanging around out there in the aethyr. Every few years I go back and re-read it. It’s fascinating to see what’s changed and what’s remained the same. I’ve had my WordPress for 7 or 8 years now, with long, long neglected stretches in there. I think there’s a Blogspot or something like that of mine out there too. I really should keep better track. I first heard about <em>LSQ</em> from you (Anna) and was very intrigued to hear about the premise of a women-centered SF and fantasy site. Also delighted to be invited to participate. There’s SO much great writing going on there!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about your bi-monthly column, &#8220;Waifs, Wolves, &amp; Warriors.&#8221; What is it about Greek mythology that you love? Do you have a favorite Greek character or myth? Do you find that knowing about Greek myths and ancient history helps you in your own writing?</strong></em></p>
<p>Suz: &#8220;Waifs, Wolves and Warriors&#8221; arose from a lifelong love of myth of all sorts. I think I first fell in love with Greek myth in particular back in my Latin classes when I was 11 (although of course they used the wrong names). I circled back around to Hellenic tales in particular 12 or 15 years ago. I’d made my way to modern paganism via American Neo-Wicca which morphed into reconstructionism when I realized that the dualistic paradigm didn’t quite fit for me, but the gods of ancient Greece do. Falling in love with the gods brought me back naturally to the myths I’d loved as a child, re-reading them with fresh eyes as I search for clues to help understand my gods better.</p>
<p>My favorite is the Descent of Persephone from the Homeric Hymn to Demeter. But all the Greek myths inspire me. Homer in particular lights my fire&#8211;the ability to see all sides of issues, the honesty in presenting the foibles and failings of the ‘heroes’, the glimmerings even in a society steeped in misogyny of the brilliance and power of women.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there aspects about Greek mythology, and in particular female Greek characters, that people frequently get wrong? </strong></em></p>
<p>Suz: <span class="m_6976529150388770958DefaultFontHxMailStyle">I think the aspect that I bump up against most is a very common trope in the modern world, the assumption that the myths are meant to be read literally, and that all ancient Greeks understood them to be literal. Like today’s Christians, I’m sure there <em>were</em> folks who understood the tales to be literal truth, but I doubt it applied universally, and that’s not relevant anyway. I’m firmly in the camp of ‘stories are far deeper and more important than literal truth.’ Zeus isn’t a horndog rapist any more than the Christian god is a bloodthirsty child murderer. I don’t pretend to have the bottom-level final unpacking of any myth, not even one in which I’m as thoroughly steeped as the Demeter mythos. They’re like endless onions, you never stop pulling back the layers. It’s also okay to stop at the first layer &#8211; not everyone is interested in all of them. But one should understand that the literal interpretation is the least important or exciting. <u></u><u></u></span></p>
<p class="m_6976529150388770958MsoListParagraph"><span class="m_6976529150388770958DefaultFontHxMailStyle">As for female characters, my beloved Persephone is the one I see most discussed and bitterly <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15890 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/micheile-henderson-VWpOwhCzPuE-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/micheile-henderson-VWpOwhCzPuE-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/micheile-henderson-VWpOwhCzPuE-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/micheile-henderson-VWpOwhCzPuE-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />argued over. Is she a raped and murdered child? A rebellious teen with an overbearing mother? An archetype of the natural progression from innocent childhood through sexual awakening to powerful womanhood? A victim? A symbol? A call to action? A representative of a necessary status quo?<u></u><u></u></span></p>
<p class="m_6976529150388770958MsoListParagraph"><span class="m_6976529150388770958DefaultFontHxMailStyle">The answer to all of these is ‘yes.’</span></p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Can you name some authors you draw inspiration from and tell us why? </strong></em></p>
<p>Suz: <span class="m_6976529150388770958DefaultFontHxMailStyle">Oh, my, so many authors! I love the old Greek playwrights, Aeskhyus and Sophokles and Euripides and Aristophanes. And the old authors, Homer and Sappho and Thucydides and ‘the father of lies’ Herodotus (as if storytelling is lying!!). I also love modern takes on them. Margaret Atwood’s <em>Penelopiad</em> is sheer divinely-inspired genius. <em>Weight</em> by Jeanette Winterson thrilled me. Mary Renault’s amazing series are a little heavy for me for &#8220;fun&#8221; reading but if I approach them as research, they transform. She’s so devoted to historical accuracy that she makes it sing. I could write responses to this question for hours.</span></p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Can you tell us a bit about your own fiction writing? What are the writing projects you are working on at the moment? </strong></em></p>
<p>Suz: <span class="m_6976529150388770958DefaultFontHxMailStyle">I’m in the last stages of shopping out my VERY Greek myth-inspired first novella, <em>Dark Horses</em>, which is, not surprisingly, based on a variant of the Demeter myth. I’ve got a few short stories in various stages of angst and excitement &#8211; one is destined, if I finish it in time, for an anthology on <em>The Odyssey.</em> I’m in the beginning stages of a book about death for 7 to 10 year olds and a series of dark-ish faery tales aimed at the grandkids I don’t have yet.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Year 10 Blogger Interview: Meet Erin Wagner</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/year-10-blogger-interview-meet-erin-wagner/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Year 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yep, we&#8217;re still celebrating our tenth year of publication here at LSQ, which means we&#8217;ve&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-15664 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/kevin-laminto-634740-unsplash-684x1024.jpg" alt="" width="684" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/kevin-laminto-634740-unsplash-684x1024.jpg 684w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/kevin-laminto-634740-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/kevin-laminto-634740-unsplash-768x1150.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 684px) 100vw, 684px" />Yep, we&#8217;re still celebrating our tenth year of publication here at <em>LSQ</em>, which means we&#8217;ve got a big ol&#8217; spotlight we want to shine on our amazing staff. Today, we&#8217;re thrilled to introduce to you one of our bloggers, Erin Wagner.</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about how you got involved with LSQ&#8217;s blog &#8212; how long have you been a blogger, how did you first learn about LSQ? What made you want to join the blog?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<div>
<div>Erin: <em>LSQ</em> is actually my first go-round at any sort of official, organized blogging. I started blogging here in September of last year. Before that, I reviewed a story here and there on the blog portion of my website (<a href="http://erinkwagner.com/">erinkwagner.com</a>), but it was far from regular. I was excited to join <em>LSQ</em> because I wanted to be part of a bigger community of writers&#8211;especially writers affiliated with such a great goal, like those at <em>LSQ</em> with its dedication to representing women in the world of speculative fiction.</div>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about your monthly column, &#8220;A Woman Was Here.&#8221; What topics and themes do you explore? How do you curate fresh subject matter? Does any of what you cover relate to your own writing?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>Erin: &#8220;A Woman Was Here&#8221; is a column dedicated to examining the woman as speculative artist (writer, painter, musician, poet, etc.) present in a variety of spaces we don&#8217;t always consider diverse. These can be spaces in the past or present. Specifically, I&#8217;ve tried to bring my experience with medieval and early modern literary analysis to the column, since these eras are often only remembered for their male authors. In general, the goal is to spotlight a woman (or group of women) who has produced great speculative art. So I determine what woman I want to write about each month by drawing from my own academic research or hobbies, as well as from news that crosses my path. Since I am myself a woman creating speculative fiction, I&#8217;m invested in promoting this representation of my peers, contemporary or not.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Have you come across anything surprising in your writing for this column? Or, perhaps learned something unexpected about a particular individual or period of time or something that&#8217;s caused you to pause and re-evaluate a theme or assumption?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Erin: First of all, producing regular, monthly content takes effort&#8211;not because women aren&#8217;t <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-15665 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/laura-dewilde-1680610-unsplash.jpg" alt="" width="4440" height="2952" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/laura-dewilde-1680610-unsplash.jpg 4440w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/laura-dewilde-1680610-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/laura-dewilde-1680610-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/laura-dewilde-1680610-unsplash-1024x681.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4440px) 100vw, 4440px" />everywhere, but simply because production takes time and dedication. So I&#8217;ve learned to really value all of my colleagues at <em>LSQ</em> and elsewhere who routinely write columns and blogs. And the work of the editors who have to organize and fine-tune all of these entries! I&#8217;ve also found out how necessary it is to examine the intersectionality of any topic I cover. Many women I write about were still privileged compared to many of their contemporaries, and I find it important to discuss that even as I want to highlight their accomplishments.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Can you name some authors you draw inspiration from and tell us why?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Erin: Too many to count! Ursula Le Guin and Octavia Butler, for starters. I feel like they&#8217;re the godmothers of modern speculative fiction. Le Guin&#8217;s carrier-bag theory of fiction helped dig out a space for slow, introspective stories. I also love the ever-present fantasy authors&#8211;C. S. Lewis (whose <em>Till We Have Faces</em> is woefully under-read compared to the <em>Chronicles of Narnia</em>) and Tolkien&#8211;though I acknowledge the need to recognize the problems inherent in their representations of race and gender.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Can you tell us a bit about your own writing? Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Erin: My novella, <a href="http://www.aqueductpress.com/authors/ErinKWagner.php"><em>The Green and Growing</em></a>, was released from Aqueduct Press (a press dedicated to feminist science-fiction) earlier this year, so I&#8217;ve been promoting that piece. I&#8217;m also trying to draft a novel this summer. In addition to these projects, I&#8217;m constantly submitting short stories. You can see published and forthcoming stories on my website. Most of my work dwells on humans trying to comprehend or relate to things or beings they qualify as non-human.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LSQ Year 10 Special &#8212; blogger interview: meet Beth McCabe</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-year-10-special-blogger-interview-meet-beth-mccabe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 10:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Year 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re almost halfway through Year 10, but we still have plenty of staff and bloggers&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re almost halfway through Year 10, but we still have plenty of staff and bloggers to chat with. Today we talk with twofer Beth McCabe, one of our bloggers and authors!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about how you got involved with LSQ&#8217;s blog &#8212; how long have you been a blogger, how did you first learn about LSQ? What made you want to join the blog?</strong></em></p>
<p>Beth: I did a blog on my own a few years ago, but it wasn’t a regular thing. LSQ was totally on my radar for story submission, and <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-mercenary/">“The Mercenary”</a> was accepted in 2017. That led to the wonderful editing staff of LSQ including me in the invitation for authors to join the blog staff. I took a closer look at the blog and didn’t hesitate.</p>
<p>I am still impressed every week by the quality of posts. Hard to find a more thoughtful, well- educated (in all senses of the word), well-read, fearless crew. Also, it’s super helpful to blog as part of a community rather than trying to do it on one’s own. And the monthly deadline is great. I like knowing that however busy I am, I need to string 700 or 800 words together in a quasi-<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15440 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/steve-halama-485154-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/steve-halama-485154-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/steve-halama-485154-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/steve-halama-485154-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />readable fashion every month.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about your monthly column, &#8220;Breakfast Anytime.&#8221; What topics and themes do you explore? How do you curate fresh subject matter? Does any of what you cover relate to your own writing?</strong></em></p>
<p>Beth: It’s all been sort of a surprise to me. My first post was about time travel, hence the name of the column, but I don’t think I ever wrote on that topic again. (I still like the name, though.) I thought I would talk a lot about challenges in my own writing, which I find helpful in others’ posts. But I rarely mention that either.</p>
<p>I’ve had an enormous amount of fun talking about space exploration in fiction, early women spec writers, and bookstore cats. Who knew? I write what I’m passionate about, and that seems to do the trick for coming up with fresh ideas. Every now and then my daughter Mikah <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-womans-roll/">collaborates with me</a> on a post, which is delightful. Talk about nerd mom-daughter bonding activities.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What do you see as &#8220;hot topics&#8221; that writers and readers of speculative fiction are encountering right now? Have these sorts of issues changed over the past 5 or 10 years?</strong> </em></p>
<p>Beth: That’s a really good question. I would like to see more women writing hard sci-fi, which loosely defined is fiction based on current science fact. I feel like we are very comfortable in our hut in the woods with our herbs and cats. I’d like us to get out and claim more of the universe. And not just space travel – biology, neuroscience, environmental science. It’s a stretch if you don’t have a science background, which I don’t. But I don’t think any of us are afraid of some hard work and research.</p>
<p>Gender is obviously a hot topic these days, and spec fiction lends itself well to exploring it. On the feminist side, I love reading LSQ’s younger bloggers and authors. No crumbs for these women. They demand a seat at the table! It’s a joy to older feminists like me to see.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What are some of the most interesting topics for you that you&#8217;ve enjoyed writing about for the blog? What are some themes you&#8217;d like to delve into in the future?</strong></em></p>
<p>Beth: I mentioned some of my favorites above. To be honest, I’m not sure what I’m going to delve <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15441 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/chuttersnap-146799-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/chuttersnap-146799-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/chuttersnap-146799-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/chuttersnap-146799-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />into in the future. When I finish my current series something will bite me on the ass and off I’ll go.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Can you tell us a bit about your own writing? Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Beth: Like most writers, I’m sort of solitary and prickly about talking about this. We’re a superstitious lot. The answer is yes, always, although I tend to take over-long hiatuses sometimes while my next round of characters beat on the inside of my skull to be let out. I’m revising three stories for submission right now, and feeling a bit at odds because I don’t know what my next new story will be about. There’s no one beating on the inside of my head, and I’m lonely.</p>
<p>One thing I’m happy about is that after a string of rejections in the literary market (and a few hard-won placements) I returned to my spec roots. I realized that adding a spec element, whether it is a light touch of magic realism or hardcore space opera, only enhances the emotional content and arc of a story. I have had more success in this market, not to mention a lot more fun.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Lastly, have you pickled any unusual vegetables lately?</strong></em></p>
<p>Beth: See, this is what I love about the awesome LSQ staff! Up close and personal. The answer is no, I’ve been sticking with cucumbers. Boring, right?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Special Year 10 Interview — meet blogger Christina &#8220;DZA&#8221; Marie</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/special-year-10-interview-meet-blogger-christina-dza-marie/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 10:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Year 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12680</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Year 10 is in full swing, and we&#8217;re celebrating by showcasing our staff, the people&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Year 10 is in full swing, and we&#8217;re celebrating by showcasing our staff, the people whom without, LSQ could not exist. Today, we&#8217;re chatting with one of our bloggers, Christina &#8220;DZA&#8221; Marie.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about how you got involved with LSQ&#8217;s blog—how long have you been a blogger, how did you first learn about LSQ? What made you want to join the blog?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Christina</strong>: I got involved with LSQ when I was first looking to get some stories published in college (about four years ago now). Fun fact: the first short story I ever published was with you guys! It was a little drabble I wrote for class and I actually forget the title of it. I specifically sent it to LSQ because I love the idea of an organization that&#8217;s uplifting voices that have been silenced for so long in a genre that I love. So when I heard you were looking for bloggers, I jumped at the chance!</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><em>LSQ:</em> <em>Tell us about your monthly column, &#8220;The Bitch Shelf&#8221; and really, its sister blog &#8220;Dragons, Zombies &amp; Aliens.&#8221; What topics and themes do you explore? How do you curate fresh subject matter? </em></strong></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Christina</strong>: &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-bitch-shelf/">The Bitch Shelf</a>&#8221; was inspired by one of my other favorite websites <a href="https://www.bitchmedia.org/">BitchMedia</a>, a feminist media organization that covers&#8230;everything. Politics, music, education, entertainment,<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15232 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/miguel-bruna-503098-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/miguel-bruna-503098-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/miguel-bruna-503098-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/miguel-bruna-503098-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /> the environment, you name it. It&#8217;s one of those truly intersectional feminist groups. Not just women&#8217;s issues, but LGBTQ+ issues, race issues, disability, class lines, etc. They&#8217;re the kind of bloggers that I try to model myself after (except I&#8217;m too polite and Minnesotan to be <em>exactly </em>like them).</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="http://www.dzamarie.com/blog"><em>Dragons, Zombies &amp; Aliens</em></a> was the start of my writing career. Admittedly it was a way for me to get my name on the internet, but for the most part I needed an outlet for all the excitement and love I have of books and fantasy, as well as a way to promote the works of other great writers who may not be very well-known.</div>
<div></div>
<div>As for what I write about, this is a little excerpt from my home page:</div>
<div>&#8220;All of my writing is done through a feminist/social justice lens. No damsels in distress. No stereotyped people of color acting as comic relief. No unnecessary romantic subplot that does nothing for the story except reduce the woman lead into a sex object. My goal is to change the landscape of speculative fiction writing and media entirely.&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div>Basically I want to promote good writing in the speculative fiction genres (that is: fantasy, sci-fi, horror, paranormal, supernatural, superhero, etc.) that does not conform to the old, hurtful stereotypes we&#8217;ve all been subjected to. One of the best ways I do this is by keeping an eye out for authors and creators outside of the American mainstream, like Nnedi Okorafor or Tiana Warner.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: You have several different writing projects to your name now and it seems many more up your sleeve. Can you tell us about what you&#8217;ve finished so far and what&#8217;s to come? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Christina</strong>: 2018 was nuts, and 2019 is proving to be even more so. I&#8217;m working with two small publishing companies. One is <a href="https://www.endlessinkbooks.com/">Endless Ink Publishing</a>, their main project being the <em>Earth&#8217;s Final Chapter </em>illustrated novella series. It&#8217;s a post-apocalyptic Earth story that&#8217;s written and illustrated by people all around the world. Last year they published book eight, <a href="https://www.endlessinkbooks.com/products/earths-final-chapter-vol-1-book-8-homestead-hunts-paperback-english"><em>Homestead Hunts</em></a>, which was my first contribution to the series. Basically it&#8217;s Canadian cannibals, rebellious teens, their murderous parents, and politics. This year I&#8217;ll be working on the follow-up, tentatively titled <em>Homestead Heroes</em>.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The other publishing company I work with is <a href="https://www.sicsemperserpent.com/">Sic Semper Serpent</a>, which is based in Minneapolis, a fifteen-minute drive from where I live. I already have an ongoing short story series with them: <em>Twisted Tales</em>. I take classic fairy tales and give them a feminist rewrite. We just finished a <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15231 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/courtney-baucom-606505-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/courtney-baucom-606505-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/courtney-baucom-606505-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/courtney-baucom-606505-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />two-part story of Hansel and Gretel, wherein Gretel herself is a witch in a world that hates her kind. This year, I just got contracted for another series with SSS, titled <em>Diary of the Green Snake</em>. It&#8217;s a historical fantasy: a Western with a magic system based off of Chinese mythology. We&#8217;re all <em>really </em>excited about that one, and when it&#8217;s done it will have anywhere from ten to thirty stories.</div>
<div></div>
<div>There are other projects stacked up—<em>Sovadron</em>, the <a href="http://www.nycmidnight.com/">NYC Midnight</a> short story and flash fiction contests, and an epic fantasy novella that I will be publishing to my patrons on Patreon first before bringing it to Amazon. But <em>Homestead Heroes </em>and <i>Green Snake</i> are the two most immediate projects that I&#8217;m working on.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Your creative work crosses some different media, e.g. graphic novels, novellas, short stories, etc. Can you tell us a bit about what&#8217;s different when writing for a graphic novel versus a novel without art? What is it like to collaborate with an artist in order to capture what&#8217;s in your mind&#8217;s eye?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Christina</strong>: It&#8217;s interesting writing a graphic novel because you don&#8217;t have to spend any words or time describing how an object, person, or place looks. Often you don&#8217;t even have to describe how a character feels. It&#8217;s just there on the page for you to see. In a way it&#8217;s very freeing, and it allows me to concentrate on what the characters are <em>doing</em> and <em>saying</em>. At the same time, the medium demands a higher speed than a traditional novel format. The eye has to glide across the page. It&#8217;s not natural to peel through a comic with the thought and care you would give to a novel. The whole point of the comic is to deliver the maximum amount of information in the shortest amount of time. I&#8217;ve enjoyed creating <em>Sovadron—</em>that&#8217;s my graphic novel series set in a fantasy world inspired by post-colonial America—in large part because of this unique challenge.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Another challenge with creating a graphic novel: I can&#8217;t draw. Well, I <em>can</em>, but not very well. Certainly not to a professional&#8217;s standards. Luckily, my working with Endless Ink Publishing gave me some network connections. The artist who illustrated <em>Homestead Hunts</em>, John Hawkins, is also illustrating <em>Sovadron</em>. And he is unfairly skilled.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What do you see as &#8220;hot topics&#8221; that writers and readers of speculative fiction are encountering right now?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Christina</strong>: One of the biggest—and most exciting—revelations occurring among readers, writers, and creators right now is that we do not have to conform to the same rigid societal rules that our predecessors have in stories. The idea that &#8220;people aren&#8217;t interested in female superheroes&#8221; or that &#8220;a gay romantic subplot just won&#8217;t have the same appeal as a straight one&#8221; has been disproved again and again and again. We&#8217;re seeing stories created and dominated by marginalized communities—<em>Wonder Woman </em>and <em>Black Panther—</em>making <em>billions</em> in the box office. We&#8217;re seeing allies like Rick Riordan take a crack at LGBTQ and Muslim characters, and rocking it. (Seriously, if you haven&#8217;t read the <em>Percy Jackson </em>series and its parallel trilogy <em>Magnus Chase</em>, get on that.)</div>
<div>The fact is, the vast majority of stories—at least the ones that have been given the most resources and exposure—have been centered around straight, cisgender, able-bodied, white men. And while there&#8217;s nothing inherently wrong with that—see, Harry Potter, Tony Stark, Percy Jackson, etc.—the fact is this is only a very small demographic in society, never mind the world! The narrative centers around this one type of person because, for most of Western history, it has been this one type of person who has controlled the narrative. But now the rest of us, who have been pushed to the sidelines, are pushing back with enough force to enter the playing field. That&#8217;s exhilarating!</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LSQ Year 10 Special Blogger Interview: Jacqui Lipton</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-year-10-special-blogger-interview-jacqui-lipton/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Year 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12609</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In celebration of our tenth year of publication, we&#8217;re showcasing the amazing work and behind-the-scenes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15076 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/joao-silas-72563-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/joao-silas-72563-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/joao-silas-72563-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/joao-silas-72563-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />In celebration of our tenth year of publication, we&#8217;re showcasing the amazing work and behind-the-scenes stuff of our staff. Today, we present to you one of our regular bloggers, Jacqui Lipton.</p>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about how you got involved with LSQ&#8217;s blog &#8212; how long have you been a blogger, how did you first learn about LSQ? What made you want to join the blog?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jacqui: I actually published a short piece of flash fiction in <em>LSQ</em> so many years ago I can&#8217;t even remember when exactly it was. Jennifer [Parsons, ed-in-chief] later contacted folks who had published with <em>LSQ</em> previously and told us about the blog, inviting pitches for columns. I started out with a column on YA writing because I was studying kid-lit in my MFA program at the time. I later moved to the &#8220;On the Books&#8221; column (legal issues for authors) because I found I was doing so much consulting work in the area because of my law professor background and my interest in the publishing industry. Prior to blogging with <em>LSQ</em>, I was involved in several law professor group blogs and also my own blog at: <a id="m_-2724072788838315262LPNoLP153967" href="http://jdlipton.com/blog.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://jdlipton.com/blog.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725289000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE0-GqepMVCh-Whqu5iRb9USqP9Xg">http://jdlipton.com/blog.html</a></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about your monthly column, &#8220;On the Books.&#8221; How does this relate to your background? How do you curate fresh topics?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jacqui: &#8220;On the Books&#8221; is an outgrowth of my consulting work as I mentioned above. I also write several other columns on legal issues for authors (one for the SCBWI Bulletin and one for Savvy Authors). I have an unusual background in both intellectual property/commercial law and writing/publishing, which gives me the ability to look at legal issues for authors from both a legal/business and craft perspective. I also feel that there&#8217;s not enough accurate legal information available for authors and artists. There&#8217;s a lot of misinformation online and often, hiring a lawyer to answer a question is too costly for authors (although my blog posts are obviously no substitute for legal advice when necessary!). I have a book coming out in early 2020 on legal issues for authors with University of California Press where I&#8217;m putting together a lot of the basic issues authors confront in a&#8211;hopefully&#8211;user-friendly manner. I was worried initially that there wouldn&#8217;t be enough fresh topics to write about, but now I feel there are way too many topics to cover in the time I have. There&#8217;s so much going on in publishing: digital publishing, copyright and fair use issues, concerns about plagiarism and author attribution, questions about defamation and privacy. The list goes on and on. I do watch the trade magazines and blogs to see what&#8217;s of the most concern to folks, as well as keeping a lot of the questions I&#8217;m asked at workshops, webinars, and other presentations.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Being a law professor as well as a writer, what do you see as &#8220;hot topics&#8221; that writers are dealing with now? Have these sorts of issues changed over the past 5 or 10 years?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15075 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/adeolu-eletu-15018-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/adeolu-eletu-15018-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/adeolu-eletu-15018-unsplash-768x509.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/adeolu-eletu-15018-unsplash-1024x678.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Jacqui: A really hot topic at the moment is &#8220;morality clauses&#8221;. Publishers are increasingly inserting clauses into their contracts allowing them to terminate arrangements with authors for breach of often poorly defined moral codes of conduct. A lot of this is an outgrowth of the #MeToo movement and is likely motivated by significant real concerns. However, authors are increasingly worried that their contracts will be cancelled on amorphous grounds based on some random comment they made online. Another issue is preventing digital copyright piracy in the &#8220;cut and paste&#8221; world of the Internet. And then there are concerns about trademarks in the context of book series titles which has been of recent concern in the romance writing industry in particular. I think some of the issues are definitely new (e.g. morality clauses) and some are new iterations of problems we&#8217;ve seen before (e.g. trademarks).</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What are some of the most interesting topics for you that you&#8217;ve enjoyed writing about for the blog?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jacqui: It&#8217;s hard to pick one or two because I really enjoy seeing what&#8217;s of concern out there and writing about it whatever it is. The big debate in the romance industry about the registration (now cancelled) of the &#8220;Cocky&#8221; trademark for romance book series titles was a lot of fun to write about although I know it caused a lot of people real angst. There was a lot of misinformation about that one, and it felt important to try and explain how trademarks really work in the book series title context. Morality clauses are also very interesting to write about because it&#8217;s such early days of using these clauses in the publishing industry even though they&#8217;ve been around in the sports and entertainment industry for a long time. And I always love writing about online branding: internet domain names, hashtags, etc., because that&#8217;s one of my major interests in the legal area from way back.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jacqui: Well, I already mentioned my legal handbook for authors that should be out by early 2020. I&#8217;m also working on a couple of YA sci-fi projects which may or may not see the light of day anytime soon! And I&#8217;ve started delving into personal essay writing and memoirs although this is very early days for me.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Thanks so much for interviewing me for the blog and I look forward to writing more on the law for authors in 2019!</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LSQ Year 10 Special: Blogger Interview&#8211;Meet Wendy Van Camp</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-year-10-special-blogger-interview-wendy-van-camp/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Year 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12605</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Still wearing those party hats in celebration of our Year 10, right? In continuation of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14977 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/kaitlyn-baker-422999-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/kaitlyn-baker-422999-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/kaitlyn-baker-422999-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/kaitlyn-baker-422999-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Still wearing those party hats in celebration of our Year 10, right? In continuation of the festivities today we have a chat with one of our veteran bloggers, Wendy Van Camp. Read on to see what she has to say about writing, blogging, and reading.</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about how you got involved with LSQ&#8217;s blog &#8212; how long have you been a blogger, how did you first learn about LSQ? What made you want to join the blog?</strong></em></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Wendy: I&#8217;ve been a blogger since 2011 with my writing blog, No Wasted Ink. Finding readers for my early work was difficult, as it is for most bloggers when they first start out. One of my post series was writing reviews of classic science fiction and fantasy authors for my blog.  Interest in these articles came from many sources. I started using them not only as blog posts for No Wasted Ink, but reprinting them once a month as a series in a community newsletter for a science fiction writers group I belonged to, on Suvedo, and to publish in various magazines as they were accepted.  In 2015, I saw a call for writers to join the <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> blogging staff on the Broad Universe email list.  Broad Universe is a writing guild that supports women writers in the speculative fiction genre.  Being an old-school feminist, I was intrigued by the message <em>LSQ</em> promoted and thought that I would submit my book reviews as an ongoing monthly column.  My idea was accepted.  In 2017, I expanded to a second column where I reprint interviews with women science fiction or fantasy authors.  Due to time constraints, I am not writing the book reviews any longer, but focus on the author interviews as my main column.</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Your work for the blog in 2019 focuses on interviewing women authors. Can you tell us a bit about your process? Where do you find these authors? What are your favorite questions to ask in an interview? Any interviewing tips?</strong> </em></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Wendy: I interview both male and female authors in speculative fiction for my blog.  I consider myself to be mainly a speculative fiction author and poet, so I want to create content for my writing blog that would attract readers of these genre to my site.  Although I do publish flash fiction and poetry of my own devising on my blog and on Medium, I find that interviews create posts with less work on my part, but still provide a rich content for my readers.  Plus, I enjoy supporting my fellow authors.  It is tough out there and I feel we should stand together and lift each other up.</p>
<p>My interview process is a little complicated and I use a Trello board to keep track of all the steps of where each author I interview is in that process.  I always have plenty of authors who are interested in being interviewed.  I have an outright following of my blog of many thousands and a Twitter following of around 24K where I promote the interviews, so being on No Wasted Ink can drive sales and buzz for any author that I accept in my interview series.  I open a call for authors twice a year and only accept enough writers to fill my available slots for six months.  Sometimes there is a little overflow, but I try my best to accommodate everyone.  My sources vary.  I sometimes put out a call in science fiction writing groups of which I&#8217;m a member in order to help support my fellow members, but other times I approach authors who have purchased a table at a science fiction convention because I feel these authors have a better understanding of the value I offer and are quick to participate and complete their interviews on time.  When a call goes out, I am processing anywhere from 12 to 15 interviews at the same time.</p>
<p>I schedule the authors on my blog by completed interview arrival.  I don&#8217;t hold places for people without an interview in hand.  My goal is to get everyone processed in a short amount of time so I am free to return to my own writing and convention schedule.  Once an interview arrives, I wait until I have four or five in hand and then I schedule and format those interviews into my blog.  Formating includes setting the text, but it also involves working on the photos to clean them up, recut them, and size them for their spaces on the blog.  By doing this, I shrink the time my blog needs to load and use less storage on my blog host.  Finally, once the schedule date and URL is settled, I preload Twitter support posts for a two week time period for each interview.  My backend software handles the delivery for me so I am not chained to my computer to do marketing.</p>
<p><em>LSQ</em> fits in after this process.  I send the women representing author interviews to <em>LSQ</em> in bulk once a year, and let the editors here decide when to schedule them.  I handle all the formatting on the <em>LSQ</em> blog myself, but since the interviews have already been processed on No Wasted Ink, it is just a matter of going to my saved photo files and cut and pasting the text with a few modifications.  I feel a bit bad that I can&#8217;t give a second promotion to my male speculative fiction authors as I do the females via <em>LSQ</em>, but the men have told me that they understand that women don&#8217;t have quite as much representation as they do and they are cool with only being on No Wasted Ink.</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Any advice to others who are interested in writing a blog but don&#8217;t know where to start?</strong> </em></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Wendy: No Wasted Ink is my little home on the internet.  My blog is front and center.  I try and have at least one new post each week, but it can go as high as three depending on my time.  The content varies. I do a writer link post where I list ten writing related articles that I feel have substance for the intermediate or more advanced writer, but beginners often love them too.  It is the most popular and most shared post series that I do.  I also offer author interviews, my own flash fiction, my scifaiku poetry, infographics related to writing, articles about writing, my travels, and other topics.  My blog connects to my other social media arms, including Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, and Pinterest.  I joined Medium as an author in 2017 and many of the articles that I publish there for members only, can later be found for free on my blog.  Medium members get a little preview by following me there.</p>
<p>I highly recommend starting a blog if you are an author.  It gives you a place to list your books for <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14978 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/stefan-stefancik-106115-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/stefan-stefancik-106115-unsplash-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/stefan-stefancik-106115-unsplash-768x1160.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/stefan-stefancik-106115-unsplash-678x1024.jpg 678w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" />sale, but also a place to mark where your short stories and poetry are published. Your readers can more easily find your content on the internet without having to search high and low for it.  The time to start your blog is always NOW.  Don&#8217;t wait.  It is a powerful tool in your arsenal, but it will take a few years to grow and be of value to you when it comes time to launch your novels.  I find that the network of social media arms that I&#8217;ve developed have helped me not only as a novelist, but it supports my short stories and poems too.</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any writing projects other than the blog at the moment? If so, can you tell us about them?</strong> </em></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Wendy: No Wasted Ink does take time off my table, but it is not my main writing.  I am in the process of finishing up a four part novel series based off of Jane Austen&#8217;s book <em>Persuasion</em>.  I use the characters and settings of this book, but not only do I explain what happened before the events of <em>Persuasion</em>, but I will also be taking the characters on a slightly different spin from the old story in the last two books.  These are Regency era historical fictions and could also be considered women&#8217;s fiction.  While there are romantic elements in all the books, I do not follow romance novel tropes.  Book One, <em>The Curate&#8217;s Brother</em>, is available on Amazon and other online book outlets; the rest are in the pipeline.  I am also at work on a poetry chapbook on the theme of Planet Mars. This chapbook will showcase my popular scifaiku poems and also longer poems that I am composing for the chapbook alone.  I participate in open-mic readings on a regular basis, and having a chapbook available to sell at these times is my main goal for the poetry book, but I will also offer it online for the general public when the time comes.</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us a bit about what types of stories you love to read and why. Who are some of your favorite authors?</strong> </em></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Wendy: I&#8217;ve been a hard-core science fiction and fantasy reader for most of my life.  I started with the Heinlein juveniles and then fell in love with the works of Anne McCaffery, Andre Norton, Ursula LeGuin, Vonda N. McIntyre, Robert Jordan, Elizabeth Moon, Robin McKinley, and many others.  Most of my favorite authors tend to be female.  This is by natural selection, not by conscious choice.</p>
<p>I like to read stories that are more character driven and have real people in fantastic settings.  I also enjoy supernatural elements and magic and the way an author can create a natural seeming system of &#8220;science&#8221; for their books that are far from our real world.  Although lately, due to reading <em>The Martian</em> by Andy Weir, I have grown to appreciate hard science fiction more and plan to write stories with real world science in the future.  I also enjoy some romantic elements, but not to the point where they overpower the story.  The real surprise to me is how I fell in love with Jane Austen in my forties, when I had never read a &#8220;romance&#8221; novel in my life.  I think that Austen is up there with my most favorite authors of all time.</p>
<p>LINKS:</p>
<div>No Wasted Ink: <a class="m_168984796321023746moz-txt-link-freetext" href="http://nowastedink.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://nowastedink.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH-rQ6MGJER8chh3j7BZ_UnJagv8g">http://nowastedink.com/</a></div>
<div>Twitter: <a class="m_168984796321023746moz-txt-link-freetext" href="http://twitter.com/wvancamp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://twitter.com/wvancamp&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGKYyIV9prvZEFXr7LmSQ0yowBH6w">http://twitter.com/wvancamp</a></div>
<div>Goodreads: <a class="m_168984796321023746moz-txt-link-freetext" href="https://www.goodreads.com/indigoskye" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.goodreads.com/indigoskye&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGVHUoGetDjJEOUbVou3x7nV4feFg">https://www.goodreads.com/<wbr />indigoskye</a></div>
<div>Facebook: <a href="http://www.facebook.com/nowastedink" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.facebook.com/nowastedink&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFR-yOMKEgb29RaTpyNLGjOx972rQ">http://www.facebook./<wbr />com/nowastedink</a></div>
<div>Instagram: <a href="http://www.instagram.com/nowastedink" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.instagram.com/nowastedink&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEWqyY7CqzYi-zg7Xz_wkE1iEK52A">http://www.instagram.com/<wbr />nowastedink</a></div>
<div>Medium: <a href="https://medium.com/@wvancamp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://medium.com/@wvancamp&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH-JLF-nGzmicjAXUZTdKsql2y4vg">https://medium.com/@<wbr />wvancamp</a></div>
<div>Pinterest: <a class="m_168984796321023746moz-txt-link-freetext" href="https://www.pinterest.com/nowastedink/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.pinterest.com/nowastedink/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFvhcmF9lGhSvxW92BMLfQd6oycWg">https://www./<wbr />pinterest.com/nowastedink/</a></div>
<div>Amazon Author Page: <a href="https://www.amazon.com/author/wendyvancamp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.amazon.com/author/wendyvancamp&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEugHARwNXDuqLNkWztJMxyAoM8rg">https://www.amazon.com/<wbr />author/wendyvancamp</a></div>
<div>My Quarterly Newsletter: <a href="http://eepurl.com/2EfpH" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://eepurl.com/2EfpH&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGkwdbRjkh7stX66apkpvr0Hk3Qxg">http://eepurl.com/<wbr />2EfpH</a></div>
<div>Broad Universe: <a class="m_168984796321023746moz-txt-link-freetext" href="http://broaduniverse.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://broaduniverse.org&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1548171725320000&amp;usg=AFQjCNENqPkq3HJf9aaf1WA3fKujxlyBbQ">http://broaduniverse.org/</a></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LSQ Year 10 Special: Editor Interview &#8212; Meet Cathrin Hagey</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-year-10-special-editor-interview-meet-cathrin-hagey/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 10:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Year 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12541</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we continue to celebrate our tenth year of publication, we&#8217;re highlighting and giving a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we continue to celebrate our tenth year of publication, we&#8217;re highlighting and giving a special behind-the-scenes peek into the minds of the fantastic editors we have here at <em>LSQ</em>. Today, meet editor and blogger Cathrin Hagey!</p>
<p><span class="im"><em><strong>LSQ: How long have you been an editor for LSQ? Tell us a bit about what drew you to the position and what you&#8217;ve learned while in it.</strong></em></span></p>
<div><em><strong>Cathrin</strong></em>: I think I began as an editor early in 2014. I first became aware of <em>LSQ</em> in 2011 and had a story published that year. I was a fan and read all the issues. In 2013, I left my job to care for an ill family member and began working from home. Shortly afterward, Jennifer [ed-in-chief] <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14922 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/liana-mikah-393878-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/liana-mikah-393878-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/liana-mikah-393878-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/liana-mikah-393878-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />advertised for editors and I applied. Editing for <em>LSQ</em> has given me an opportunity to immerse myself in stories written by women-identified authors on a regular basis. Wading in like this makes me feel more connected to women from around the world, their flights of imagination, the issues they care about. The main thing I&#8217;ve learned is that, after centuries of oppression, we have only begun to reveal the stuff we can dream up.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: You&#8217;re not only an editor for LSQ, but also a blogger as well, writing the monthly column &#8220;What&#8217;s in a Fairy Tale.&#8221; Can you tell us a bit about your own writing? What prompted you to start this column?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>Cathrin</strong></em>: I started my own website in 2010 (shameless plug: <a href="http://www.cathrinhagey.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.cathrinhagey.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1547475423191000&amp;usg=AFQjCNENdlzZmsotNxLHFxUmFbpMVz37hA">www.cathrinhagey.com</a>), and as I was fishing for things to blog about, I came across the online archives of the <i>Journal of Mythic Arts </i>(<a href="https://endicottstudio.typepad.com/jomahome/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://endicottstudio.typepad.com/jomahome/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1547475423191000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG3yi24UwPK0qXNvVhewNrj2vQg2g">https://endicottstudio./<wbr />typepad.com/jomahome/</a>), edited by Terri Windling, and the outstanding blog of author and folklorist Katherine Langrish, <i>Seven Miles of Steel Thistles</i> (<a href="https://steelthistles.blogspot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://steelthistles.blogspot.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1547475423191000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFgpD3uSr5WY3Sp-L452M1Kg_SDsg">https://steelthistles./<wbr />blogspot.com/</a>). These two resources not only reawakened my early love of fairy tales, they showed me that such a love is a testament to the power, depth, and significance of fairy tales to our evolution as conscious beings. My own writing has been influenced by this realization ever since.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Where do you think women-identifying authors currently sit at the table of speculative fiction? What about as characters? What about in the future?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>Cathrin</strong></em>: I don&#8217;t claim to know much, but I believe we are in the midst of a renaissance for women-identified authors of speculative fiction. The wave is cresting and it&#8217;s headed for shore. There is no going back.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: As an editor for LSQ, tell us a bit about the top aspects you wish to see in a published story. Are there sub-genres that you feel are over-submitted or under-submitted? Is there a sub-genre or topic that you would like to see more of? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14923 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/cederic-x-494198-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/cederic-x-494198-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/cederic-x-494198-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/cederic-x-494198-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Cathrin</strong></em>: I hesitate to prescribe certain sub-genres or to say that certain ideas have been over or under-submitted. It&#8217;s possible for an inspired author to take something time-worn and make it sing again. Anything can happen when the muse strikes. As far as what I like to see in a story . . .Wow! Where do I begin? A good story is always surprising in some way. It has momentum, a forward energy surge that keeps me reading. Its structure is sound, though it might be subtle. Characters have motivation and make me care whether or not their needs are met. Someone changes, for good or ill. A few sentences will make me stop, reread, savor.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What are the most common errors in manuscripts that you come across (e.g., typos, plot holes, characterizations, worn tropes, etc.)?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>Cathrin</strong></em>: Nearly every story has something that can be improved and at least one thing to recommend it. I&#8217;ve read so many stories now that I really can&#8217;t say what the most common error is. As for my pet peeve, it&#8217;s all about the typos. When there are more than ten, it takes me out of the tale. I hope that doesn&#8217;t sound petty.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have a favorite LSQ-published story, one that has stuck with you? If so, which one?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>Cathrin</strong></em>: A lot of our stories have stuck with me, but the following really got under my skin, for various reasons: &#8220;The Woodsman&#8221; by Jan Stinchcomb for horror; &#8220;The Five Snowflakes&#8221; by Rebecca Harrison for fairy tales; &#8220;Her Data Like Fingerprints&#8221; by Ashley M. Hill for science fiction.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LSQ Year 10 Special Blogger interview: Meet Jen Gheller</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-year-10-special-blogger-interview-jen-gheller/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Year 10]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12753</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The LSQ staff is celebrating our tenth year of publication and along with the streamers&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14804 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/sanjeevan-satheeskumar-1262291-unsplash-214x300.jpg" alt="" width="214" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/sanjeevan-satheeskumar-1262291-unsplash-214x300.jpg 214w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/sanjeevan-satheeskumar-1262291-unsplash-768x1076.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/sanjeevan-satheeskumar-1262291-unsplash-731x1024.jpg 731w" sizes="(max-width: 214px) 100vw, 214px" />The <em>LSQ</em> staff is celebrating our tenth year of publication and along with the streamers and balloons, we&#8217;re featuring a behind-the-scenes look at each of the wonderful women that make up our editorial and blog staff. Today we&#8217;re chatting with blogger and blog editor, Jen Gheller!</p>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about how you got involved with LSQ&#8217;s blog &#8212; how long have you been a blog editor, how did you first learn about LSQ? What made you want to join the team?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jen: I first discovered <em>LSQ</em> way back in 2016 via Tumblr, and it was a blog post about female Native American authors. When I clicked through to the blog and discovered a whole treasure trove of posts and stories by women writers, I decided to stick around. I loved the blog so much that when the call went out for a new blog team I figured, why not join in on the fun? It&#8217;s been a little over a year now since I&#8217;ve been on the blog team and I&#8217;m happy to say the fun continues!</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about your monthly column &#8220;YA Girl&#8221; &#8212; what&#8217;s your inspiration behind it? What are some themes you explore in the column? How do you cultivate fresh ideas? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jen: I&#8217;ve always been drawn to YA, even after I grew out of the target demographic. For some reason, YA tends to be looked down on, at least in my experience. If you write/read it, you&#8217;re dabbling in &#8220;kids&#8217; stuff&#8221; and not &#8220;real&#8221; literature. I never understood that point of view. Most of the YA I&#8217;ve read has been way more imaginative and gripping than the &#8220;adult&#8221; novels I&#8217;ve read. So I wanted to write a column celebrating YA, showing you don&#8217;t have to be a teen to enjoy it, and that it&#8217;s just as important and worthwhile as any other kind of literature.</div>
<div></div>
<div>That being said, I don&#8217;t really have a set list of things I want to explore in my column. Ideas just come based on what I&#8217;m reading at the moment, or what I&#8217;m noticing in the media lately. I especially like to highlight books that have a strong message of hope, because we really need books like that right now.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: As a blog editor, what are some of your favorite topics that the blog has covered and explored? What would you like to see more of in the future?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jen: I&#8217;ve been loving D.M. Domosea&#8217;s &#8220;The S Word,&#8221; which examines what the world might be like if sex never existed. I never understood society&#8217;s preoccupation with sex, and I&#8217;m honestly sick of it, so that column is supremely refreshing! I also appreciate all of our bloggers&#8217; writing tips. It&#8217;s neat seeing everyone&#8217;s different approaches to writing. In the future, I&#8217;d really like to see more about women in horror (either women characters or women creators), and women in animation. I&#8217;ve been thinking a lot about the latter, so maybe you&#8217;ll be seeing more of that from me!</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Your author bio says you love the library with all your heart and soul. Please tell us a bit about what public libraries mean to you. </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jen: LIBRARIES ARE EVERYTHING! Every time I see a &#8220;thinkpiece&#8221; about libraries being obsolete, my blood boils! The public library is the backbone of society. I firmly believe the public library is the last truly democratic institution left. It&#8217;s one of the few places you can go where you&#8217;re not expected to spend money. You&#8217;re not being sold a product or being manipulated by marketing tactics. Aside from saving over $3,000 on books last year alone, I have free access to Rosetta Stone through my library. FREE access to something that costs about $200. How awesome is that?? Not to mention the movies, magazines, ebooks, audiobooks, free museum passes, and countless other services. My library also has clubs and classes like yoga, tai chi, English conversation partners, a genealogy club, a book club, a brand new comic book club, and <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14805 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/becca-tapert-391599-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/becca-tapert-391599-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/becca-tapert-391599-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/becca-tapert-391599-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />weekly crafts. I was really lucky to have a great library in my elementary school, which probably played a huge part in my love for reading. One of the best feelings for me has always been standing in front of the shelves, knowing that all of those stories were mine if I wanted them. I could honestly go on about libraries all day, but I&#8217;ll wrap it up with USE YOUR LIBRARIES, PEOPLE! They love you, so show them some love in return!</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us a bit about what types of stories you love to read and why. Who are some of your favorite authors? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jen: Urban fantasy all day every day. As fun as fantasy worlds can be, I have a lot more fun reading about magical elements in our everyday world. I also have a soft spot for stories with the found family trope, like <i>Six of Crows</i>. Some of my favorite authors are Holly Black, Libba Bray, Stephen King, and Leigh Bardugo.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us about them? If not, do you have any ideas for the future? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jen: I would really like to be published for the first time ever this year, so I&#8217;m trying my best to finish some short stories. All of them involve magic, faeries, the ocean, and a small amount of swordplay.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
