<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pretendy Fun-Time Games and You &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/pretendy-fun-time-games-and-you/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 03:51:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Pretendy Fun-Time Games: Charahub</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pretendy-fun-time-games-charahub/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SE Lenair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 17:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pretendy Fun-Time Games and You]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the nicest parts of living in the Information Age is well, the wealth&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the nicest parts of living in the Information Age is well, the wealth of knowledge at our fingertips. Though naysayers enjoy producing comics that show us all glued to our phones, ignoring conversation and refusing to absorb information due to having Wikipedia on standby, I personally think that&#8217;s a pretty dismal view of things. Dictionaries, articles, and encyclopedias are available to us at the press of a finger against a smartphone screen, and we&#8217;ve all taken advantage of that &#8212; as well we should! Research is never a bad thing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And that, in essence, is the basis of character bibles.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I talked a little about this concept in my <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/pretendy-fun-time-games-stagefright/">last article</a>. A character bible is, in essence, a document you can fall back on when creating a character you roleplay in case you get stuck at any point. It also helps to collect things which remind you of your character, to get a general feel for the fictional person whenever you plan on creating something that involves them. Until recently, character bibles and show bibles (reference materials that contain show canon, settings, and cultures) have been a largely physical affair, constituting a book one can tote around no matter where they&#8217;re at. But the Information Age has added a new layer to the creative bible: digital copies, freely available as long as you have a portable computer or wifi access. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coupled with being able to pull information from the staggering amount of sources available on the internet, and well, you&#8217;ve got a metaphorical stew going!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As this is the first article in a series, I&#8217;d like to use it to go and provide an option you have to start building your bible: a website called Charahub. If this doesn&#8217;t work for what you need, there will be other options explored as we continue, but as a visual representation of all that is bible, this site reigns supreme. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://charahub.com/">Charahub</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I was suffering from extreme altitis &#8212; the creation of several characters because I simply couldn&#8217;t find one to focus on &#8212; Charahub was my go-to website for compiling character information. And if you want a visual representation of a bible without having to hold an actual notebook you&#8217;ve altered, you&#8217;ve come to the right place!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have so much good to say about this website, and I&#8217;m unsurprised its been developed after years of roleplayers attempting to share their character influences through blog posts and compilation websites such as Tumblr. The interface is simple without feeling dumbed down, and the framework of the site is presented as though you&#8217;re writing in a journal for your character of choice. There&#8217;s enough space on your account for one hundred original characters in total, with a limit of ten images for each entry. There&#8217;s an option to increase that limit through their referral program, as well as a Gold Account subscription service, which removes advertises and exponentially increases your character limit (250 characters) and image size. But free users certainly aren&#8217;t missing out on the websites features.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/zombulls2.png"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="center-image aligncenter wp-image-5551 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/zombulls2.png" alt="" width="896" height="641" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When in the actual character creation process, there is an option to share your character with the world or to leave the entry private. The bio tab is fleshed out with basic questions to help prompt you in the creation process, as well as providing an Extra tab for anything you believe is integral to your character that wasn&#8217;t initially included. The image tab allows for pictures to be uploaded that you see as character influences, or even commissions or art you&#8217;ve drawn of their likeness. The links tab is not for URLs but for character connections &#8212; allowing you to link your character to other entries if they&#8217;re sisters, brothers, coworkers, or lovers. There is even an option to add your character to a group, so you never forget which adventurer is in what party! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The snazziest addition that Charahub offers, however, is the Questions tab. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/zombulls.png"><img decoding="async" class="center-image aligncenter wp-image-5550 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/zombulls.png" alt="zombulls" width="900" height="622" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a roleplayer, I absolutely adore being asked questions about my characters, down to the silly habits they&#8217;ve developed as coping strategies towards the world. These questions, compiled by the creator of the website, act as prompts that allow you to flesh out your character. From allergies to their hoarding habits, the questions are a lovely springboard for the character creation process. And if there&#8217;s a question you don&#8217;t prefer or you don&#8217;t want to consider for any of your characters, there is an option to ignore that question in every entry you create.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are drawbacks, of course, but this comes from personal preference. The chief drawback is the lack of customization, especially in the bio section. I enjoy pulling facets and features such as these for my own bibles, but the inability to organize them into categories I prefer, means that every character profile will read the same, instead of being placed in order of importance for that specific person. If you ignore one question on a profile, that will be ignored on every profile as well &#8212; and I&#8217;d like a bit more customization in that area, too. If there was another tab for additional hyperlinks, I would love it, as well&#8211; so I could show others playlists, pinterest boards, and other such organizational websites that I utilize. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next time, Ill be talking about an option that expands on what Charahub offers &#8212; Scrivener. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pretendy Fun-Time Games: Stagefright</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pretendy-fun-time-games-stagefright/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SE Lenair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 17:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pretendy Fun-Time Games and You]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today I&#8217;m going to talk about Roleplay Stage Fright, which is surprisingly more common than&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today I&#8217;m going to talk about Roleplay Stage Fright, which is surprisingly more common than I expected it to be.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I mean, that&#8217;s basically what that anxiety feeling </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">when it&#8217;s put into context. There&#8217;s no stage, there&#8217;s no physical audience, but there&#8217;s no way your fingers are going to let you type out your performance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I discussed this the other night with some friends, and its an aspect of participating in a creative community that&#8217;s important to me. In the last year, I&#8217;ve been suffering from the worst case of RP Stage Fright since I started noodling around with OCs on message boards when I was 10. I wish it was as simple as not wanting to roleplay with others &#8212; because that feels like a personal choice that&#8217;s acceptable. There&#8217;s nothing wrong with taking a break from creative hobbies, and it often benefits the creator. RP Stage Fright, unfortunately, is more insidious&#8230;because despite whatever desire I have to create with others, my anxiety is giving me a sermon on why that&#8217;s a bad idea.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have a clue as to why I&#8217;ve developed it, but I think it&#8217;s inherently tied to/is a form of writers block that comes about from creating in a social space.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I&#8217;ve sort of hammered out the cycle as follows:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Person wants to RP but has been internally processing their writing and something is sticking out to them &#8212; a character trait, metaphor usage, diction itself &#8212; as not being adequate or up to speed with everyone else.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This thought sticks and becomes a background track whenever they write something, RP with someone, or do anything in that creative vein.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In fear/annoyance/disgust/anger/anxiety over this trait, they do not join RP events in order to avoid being criticized, corrected, or shown to be inadequate (do you see, do you see the repetition).</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The power behind the perceived inadequacy grows and becomes fact. Its so obvious to the writer/roleplayer &#8212; it </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">has </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">to be obvious to everyone else.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">RP opportunities continue to be avoided, even if they&#8217;re offered, out of a sense of sparing yourself and others the situation. If the individual does engage, there&#8217;s always a weird sense of internal anxiety about it.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Repeat ad nauseum.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What&#8217;s interesting about observing this, particularly in writing it out, is how closely this reflects how the writers block cycle tends to go. Something presents itself as inadequate/worthless within writing and that builds on itself until it becomes an emotionless shame demon that is literally all you can focus on while you try and scrawl out a chapter. And even if you want to, you can&#8217;t face it down. There is the physical feeling of pressing your hands against a brick wall, pushing desperately but getting nowhere. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This RP form of writers block is a bit more socially active, however, because it involves other people. That&#8217;s where the stage fright factor comes in. Instead of being frozen in front of a word document, you&#8217;re in a conversation with actual people writing in real-time &#8212; and they want you to be a part of it. Immediately. Like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">now. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">And that is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">terrifying. </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think there are a couple ways to not <em>break</em> the habit, but make it a bit easier to ignore the habit. That voice of inadequacy will get quieter over time, but you&#8217;ve got to work on silencing it. It&#8217;s unfair to expect a miracle to happen in one day &#8212; that you&#8217;ll be able to write and roleplay with others like a dam&#8217;s broken. I hate that logic for one reason only, and it&#8217;s that it takes away your agency in the situation. You are so much better than whatever the subconscious shame demon&#8217;s peddling. If you don&#8217;t notice your worth, how can you expect others to?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Things to consider:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Wow, Two Cakes!:</strong> This is from a <a href="http://sqbr.tumblr.com/post/92103436228/the-artist-putting-a-simple-cake-next-to-a-much" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post </a>that goes around on tumblr from user stuffman that breaks down the <em>I&#8217;m not good enough </em>argument pretty succinctly. Essentially, someone brings a cake to a cake contest and is down on themselves for their entry not being as gorgeous as the other contestant&#8217;s. The person who gets to eat the cakes, however, is absolutely delighted that they get to enjoy both &#8212; because regardless of how they look, it&#8217;s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">two cakes.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I&#8217;ve noticed it&#8217;s pretty common for others to judge their work against someone else&#8217;s to prove how inadequate they are in a creative context. But those who love your writing, your characters, and your ideas are not going to come in and try and place them on an imaginary creative metric. No matter how much you think your writing sucks, I can 100% guarantee there are people out there who are going to be so excited to eat your word cake. I am absolutely certain about this.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Don&#8217;t Force Yourself to Do the Thing:</strong> There&#8217;s no question that writing a little each day helps build a creative practice, and practice is the path to succeeding at the craft. That&#8217;s patented fact, and it&#8217;s a tenet I personally ascribe to. However&#8211;and this is a personal opinion as someone who knows how I work&#8211;trying to break down the brick wall with your fists alone will end in blood and anger. Allow yourself a chance to sit back and work through issues! You can work up to producing something creative every day once you&#8217;re back up to speed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Fake It Until You Make It:</strong> Every day say something nice to yourself about your writing, or find something that you like about a scene you were in. There is a trend within RP communities to confuse self-deprecation with humility. Don&#8217;t. Stop that. I will smack you with a newspaper until you stop. Your writing and your characters are just as viable as anybody else&#8217;s, and if someone else has told you otherwise, that is their damage. The more you take pleasure in your writing, your characters, and yourself, the easier it&#8217;ll be to ignore the shame demon.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Okay, Maybe Write A Little Each Day:</strong> Don&#8217;t force it, but it really doesn&#8217;t hurt to keep your mind spry and your vocabulary usage active. It doesn&#8217;t have to be anything important in the moment, but it&#8217;s important you remain active, because it gives you more of an understanding of your character &#8212; and therefore a level of familiarity/comfort. Do prompts. Write drabbles. Find face claims, stuff quotes that remind you of your character in a character-bible type document. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>What is a Character Bible Because That Sounds Culty:</strong> Character Bibles, or Story Bibles, are reference materials put together by the creator that detail a story&#8217;s setting, background, character list &#8212; anything that is important to keep the story&#8217;s canon stable. I started using them about eight years ago, when I had a character with a heavy accent &#8212; I basically started jotting down his lexicon in order to have mannerisms to stick with. Eventually I expanded my bible use and created one for every character, detailing their backstories, their understanding of their world, how they regarded others and why they performed the acts they did. Its much easier to get into the headspace of a character if you have references, just as writing an academic paper is easier with sources. In essence, the Character Bible is a pick-ax to use against the writers block wall, one that doesn&#8217;t come with the innate pressure of creating something to your personal standard. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These are things I&#8217;ve started that have helped me to abate stage fright, and I do hope they work for you! If you have any tips and tricks, please feel free to leave comments down below. There are multiple ways to combat this feeling, and the more tricks you have at your disposal, the better!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pretendy Fun-Time Games: Grimdark</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pretendy-fun-time-games-grimdark/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SE Lenair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 16:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pretendy Fun-Time Games and You]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5011</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Let’s have a talk about the tried and tested tenet of grimdark. I’ve done it,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s have a talk about the tried and tested tenet of grimdark.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve done it, you’ve done it, and nearly anyone who has entertained fandom and original character writing has done it. Grimdark writing within a fandom context envisions a scenario (or several) in which everything is terrible and the light at the end of the tunnel is nothing more than a pair of gleaming, insidious eyes. The world is against your character, and even when they triumph, that victory tends to come with a price. Within my various writing circles and in my gaming groups, I’d be hard-pressed to find someone who doesn’t indulge their dark side by dragging their character through the metaphorical thorn bush. There’s something very intriguing &#8212; and nearly satisfying &#8212; about throwing your new brain child into the grinder.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/grimdark.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-5015 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/grimdark-300x240.jpg" alt="grimdark" width="300" height="240" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It typically starts innocently, laced within the litany of ‘what-if’ questioning a writer goes through when initially building a character concept. It’s fun to think about the possibilities, of what happened in your character’s past to bring their true self to fruition. After all, very rarely is an interesting character built off accomplishments alone. There has to be a drive, a problem that they’ve overcome, something which has left them irreparably </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">changed. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The frequency of this problem/solution varies, but in my case, I tend to err on the side of “realistically horrible”. I personally find more interest in a hero who has dealt with terrible situations and chosen to put that horror behind them in order to champion goodness.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I like to call this creation of character angst the Crucible. The Crucible, no relation to the Arthur Miller play intended, is essentially me throwing the character into the jaws of hell and watching how it warps them &#8212; for even if they succeed, it will. And for good or ill, the character idea I get out of the Crucible is what I run with in the fields of original writing, fanfiction, and roleplaying. The level of ‘crucibility’ varies, but 9 times out of 10 I go with a ‘Man VS Society’ idea. Not only does it provide character depth (and probably character </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">death </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">for my poor subject’s extended family), it allows me to understand where my character lies within the different social boundaries a given universe offers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Say my character is born a street urchin, but they fight their way up to the upper-middle class. What happened in that journey, and what noses or knives were bloodied along the way? What about an upper class fall from grace? Or a soldier who returns from a war, knowing the next one is only slightly down the path? Paladins who question their faith, warlocks who summon evil because they know real monsters hide behind human faces, mages who control time itself because they’ve been a victim of it for decades. Adding grimdark to a character recipe is important! It’s but another tool in the box for creatives to expand on their mind children. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But here’s where I get a little critical, and I say that there </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">such a thing as too much grimdark. While it’s a magnificent tool for backstory and static writing &#8212; that is, writing where you aren’t directly interacting with a partner &#8212; grimdark can be a detriment towards enjoyment of roleplay as a whole. When you douse yourself in everything psychologically dissonant and horrid to think about, things overall tend to turn out, well… grim. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here’s what I mean. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You and your roleplaying friends, after playing the characters for a couple of sessions, decide to build up backstory to better understand mannerisms, day-to-day interactions with others, and to gain a general feel for things. You mention something about abandonment in your character’s backstory, as a hypothetical, and someone else speaks up. Her character has abandonment issues, too, and it would be super interesting to throw her character’s lot in with yours to see how it plays out! Maybe they’ll get romantically attached, or they’ll be stuck together and have to trust the other to help them out instead of leaving them to die. Situations for future roleplay come up, and they’re deliciously dire. It provides a lot of potential for character development and interpersonal attachment, which are always fun scenarios to dabble in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And then &#8212; either in the middle of all of this playing out or near the end &#8212; someone suggests another what-if. Riding the high of the situation, this seems like a great plan, more chances to write angst blurbs for the community website or dramatic roleplay logs to show friends. You can definitely do a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">lot </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">with dark situations in terms of writing, so there’s much more potential for creativity there. The rush of emotion when writing is addictive, too, so why wouldn’t you want to continue to throw your character into the grinder? But there’s another scenario, and another, and while you </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">talk </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">with your partners about happy sunshine moments… they’re pushed to the back of the plate in order to make room for more devil’s food cake. As much as you want to, and even if you’re able to, eating nothing but cake for weeks on end isn’t a smart idea.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I firmly believe that, like meals, roleplay and character interaction are nothing if they aren’t balanced. Though indulging the grimdark side of things does provide a temporary rush, it’s important to take a step back and include what most shows call ‘filler episodes’. Go on random adventures, throw a dumb party, go on whatever adventure the video game or setting you’re in facilitates. You have to do something, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">anything, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">that doesn’t have to do with your characters physically or mentally eviscerating one another, or the grimdark mentality will start to wear. No one wants to be in a terrible situation all the time. Even when you step back from the scenario, those feelings linger, because you’re seeing too much punishment with little reward.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With friends and with others that you’ve entered into a creative partnership with, it’s important to establish a continuous open line of communication. This is especially important when you’re fiddling around with the darker parts of humanity &#8212; mistrust, abuse, and murder. They’re all things people enjoy writing about, but they have to be wholly distinct, discussed only when you know there are other options. The darkness is a bit less dark when you have someone you’re laughing or crying with in the endeavor… and when you know you aren’t going to stay very long. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pretendy Fun-Time Games: Rat Catchers Optional?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pretendy-fun-time-games-rat-catchers-optional/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SE Lenair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 18:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pretendy Fun-Time Games and You]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4748</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whenever I play tabletop roleplaying games with my friends, one of the recurring jokes or&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Whenever I play tabletop roleplaying games with my friends, one of the recurring jokes or statements we bring up is this: nobody wants to be a Rat Catcher.</p>
<p>In Warhammer Fantasy, the classes that people start out as have a bleaker bent than what you would see in an Exalted or Dungeons and Dragons game. The concept for Warhammer Fantasy is highly driven towards the zero-to-hero campaign premise, in which you are pulled from the gutters by your bootstraps and gain a better life through your heroic actions. Unfortunately, the universe appears to be primarily comprised of gutters—and questionable inns complete with back-alleys in which to be shanked—so, for the most part, one starts out in a less-desirable career with the promise of advancement in the future. These range anywhere from Fishermen to Roadwarden, with the unfortunate position of Rat Catcher being one of the more well-known careers.</p>
<p>Rat Catchers, as their name implies, make their living disposing of the considerable amount of vermin that lurk within their universe’s towns and villages. They spend their lives picking off voles and traveling to ply their trade, but it’s not a very good life by anyone’s reckoning. Unsurprisingly within the narrative of the game, you typically end up working as a scout with your adventuring group—sort of a proto-rogue with a rat flail. And I mean this literally. The Rat Catcher career starts out with a rat pole in which you roll a D6 to see how many dead rats it comes with. There are various career exits for the Rat Catcher, but my statement stands: in a bleak, dark world with bleak, dark lore, you start out as something no one in their right mind would want to be with the hazy goal of getting out of that position in the future.</p>
<p>No one in real life wants to be a Rat Catcher. It’s a terrible job with a horrific premise, in which the only goal one has that month is to go to another town and find more vermin to exterminate. However, in the universe of Warhammer Fantasy, this job is <i>needed </i>to an extent that it’s very likely your character will start out as it. The world is built on a medieval premise rather than an outright fantasy one, and it comes with all the ghoulish trappings other fantasy games ignore: plagues, violent acts from day-to-day people, and the very likely death by disease. In that way, the Rat Catcher is a very useful person within the universe they inhabit. And what’s more: they fit directly into the narrative, and their rise from this role into that of a seasoned adventurer makes sense. Your character <i>can </i>grow from this position, even if their backstory is a bit lacking in the valor department. You won’t have to catch moles for the rest of your life. The story is going to make something more of you. Something better.</p>
<p>That promise is a pretty good place to start in terms of character crafting—and I’d be lying if I the premise of starting out as gutter trash and growing into a position of power didn’t appeal to my creative writing senses!</p>
<p>Going back to my <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/pretendy-fun-time-games-and-you-the-mary-sue/">post about Mary Sues</a>, one of the larger problems I see in roleplaying communities is the desire for everyone to be in an important role. I think it’s very understandable that one wants to be acknowledged in their community—and between the Paladin and the Rat Catcher, people in trouble are more likely to flock towards the one covered in holy symbols. Until recently, I wanted to be the important adventurer as well, and it’s a desire the overarching narrative of the game supports. Your character within the game’s story is the hero, the leader of armies, the person spoken of in legend who is going to save the world. And while that does well for the game’s narrative, <i>roleplaying </i>narrative tends to differ to some extent. Not everyone can be the Warrior of Light in Final Fantasy XIV: A Realm Reborn. You aren’t the only person beyond canon characters to witness the Lich King’s fall in World of Warcraft. Your character lives in the universe where that happens of course, but strictly speaking, you aren’t actually that individual who truly rested the weight of the world on your back.</p>
<p>And as much as being the lynchpin might appeal to someone… it’s okay not to be. You can be important in lore without being the be-all end-all commander of the righteous forces.</p>
<p>An important part of making a character that isn’t completely embroiled in the many schemes that surrounds the game is understanding the universe they’re in outside of the obvious. To be an active participant in the changing world and its lore, you’ve got to know that lore—full stop. Though your ideas might differ from what you see in your day-to-day questing, it has to come from a place of logic, as your character will be more believable when others interact with them. It’s like the Holy Trinity cooks have in cajun cooking: though there are many different gumbos and etouffees out there, in the end, they all start with the same three ingredients. It’s why people mock those who bring modern-technology mechas into a world that, for the most part, operates on high-fantasy standards. That character was likely not built from the lore that surrounds it.</p>
<p>With the logic I’m presenting, let’s fiddle around with the start of character creation. Let’s say in the overarching story of the world your character’s in, you participate in a militaristic campaign (which is pretty common in most MMOs). Though the game has you playing as leader of this group of soldiers, you want to do something different when roleplaying with other players in the game. When in character (IC), your character is merely one of the infantry forces of the commander.</p>
<p>So the game’s narrative has told you what the commander does, and you’ve run through that part of the game’s storyline to know the outcome of the battle. But you know not everyone can be that character in the roleplaying narrative. You want to be one of their soldiers, one who survived the battle. This is where questing and leveling your character really helps, because as you play the game, you’re given tidbits for how your character will behave. Quests, if the creative team of the game are worth their salt, will be littered with small nuggets of lore to make their game feel more like a universe and less like a constant leveling slog.</p>
<p>Where did they come from, in what town or settlement were they recruited? What is the history of that town? How long has your character’s family been a part of that settlement? Were your character’s parents a part of this town or did they move from elsewhere? Has that had an effect on why you wanted to join the army?</p>
<p>If you don’t want to go with a militaristic bent, there’s always the path of being an adventurer. In both tabletop and video games, this concept’s pretty common, because you can reasonably throw yourself into the thick of things due to crazy random happenstance. Every game has need for adventurers, and they certainly love to make a name for themselves. Where did the adventurer start their journey from? What made them want to head onward besides their natural wanderlust? If they didn’t naturally want to travel, did something make them run? Look at the different plot points and objectives you’ve experienced in your actual playing of the game. Does something there stand out? As an example, one of my characters has begun adventuring due to her entire race seeking asylum after another empire has taken over their country. Did an insurrection or war happen in your character’s past that they’re attempting to escape?</p>
<p>These are all things that can potentially breathe life into your character concept. More importantly, these ideas will situate your character within the lore directly, making them feel more real not only to yourself but to everyone you interact with. It does take a bit of work to differentiate yourself from the hero, but I promise it’s worth it. You don’t have to start out as a Rat Catcher—but humble beginnings do have a premise, and give you plenty of room to create.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pretendy Fun-Time Games and You: The Mary Sue</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pretendy-fun-time-games-and-you-the-mary-sue/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pretendy-fun-time-games-and-you-the-mary-sue/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SE Lenair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 17:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pretendy Fun-Time Games and You]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mary Sues. The mere mention of the term often sends Creatives scuttling into the rafters, hissing about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mary Sues.</p>
<p>The mere mention of the term often sends Creatives scuttling into the rafters, hissing about tropes and authenticity. It’s a funeral dirge when it’s employed by critics, professional or no — the easiest way to break someone down when they’re first venturing into writing is to call their chosen character overpowered trash. It’s honestly kind of fascinating how quickly others slap the label on what is potentially a person’s first foray into the craft.</p>
<p>For anyone who isn’t familiar with it, a Mary Sue is a character—strictly female—who has more positive qualities than negative and is beloved by the universe itself—which is usually a world preconceived by another author/gaming company*. The term was first used in a Star Trek fanfiction by Paula Smith, in which the titular character was the be-all end-all of the Starship Enterprise, dies, and is mourned dramatically by canon characters at the end of the story. It&#8217;s important to note that, from the author&#8217;s mouth, this character was <em>meant</em> as a parody of<em> </em>similar characters she noticed when reading Trek fic. You can read the interview explaining this <strong><a href="http://journal.transformativeworks.org/index.php/twc/article/view/243/205">here</a></strong>.</p>
<p>Smith&#8217;s story highlights most of the parameters of a Mary Sue as they are judged by members of a fandom. They are as follows:</p>
<p><strong>1.</strong> The character is female.<br />
<strong>2.</strong> The character has direct ties to characters in pre-established canon: they are a sister, a cousin, a daughter, a lover.<br />
<strong>3.</strong> They have an overabundance of positive traits: they are the top of their class, in peak physical perfection, could win a beauty contest after rolling out of bed and speak four languages with a regional accent to boot. The key here is how overtuned these traits are and how many exist. Mary Sues always have a solution to a problem posed by the narrative.<br />
<strong>4.</strong> They are very rarely listed with negative traits, and if they are, they are considered endearing by the rest of the characters (Bella’s clumsiness for good or for ill is often considered the penultimate example of this).<br />
<strong>5.</strong> They are injured in some manner which gives them a problem to easily overcome. Sometimes they’re bed-bound, and others have to find a cure for their dire illness. Sometimes they lose a limb and courageously endure this. It&#8217;s not really character building as much as a slight bump in the road towards the epilogue.<br />
<strong>6.</strong> Death, while not necessary, usually comes at the end of the novel and we are privy to the canon character’s ‘fourth act’ of mourning and learning how to live in a world without the character. If this is within a roleplaying universe, death is a problem typically solved by game mechanics &#8212; Phoenix Downs, Scrolls of Resurrections, in-game rituals, whatever works within context of the universe. No one wants to level up a new character.</p>
<p>The fact that I am able to list these traits without thinking has come from nearly two decades of participating in a multitude of fandoms with a multitude of rules dictating how their canon is to be treated. I’ve made a wealth of original characters, and when I was younger, they were planted into fandoms to act as my voice within the present narrative. It was something I&#8217;d always <em>done, </em>and considering the popularity of sites such as Fanfiction.net and Archive of Our Own, others enjoy doing so as well. When I was starting out, most of my original character fit each of these points. And when I was ten, I really didn&#8217;t see the problem with it.</p>
<p>As with anything that could constitute guidelines for behavior, fandoms took these Mary Sue facets and ran with them. The Mary Sue has become something of a pariah, a label for a character who is so unbelievable they have to be mocked. It’s very easy and incredibly comforting to say, ‘Look at this character and all of the ways it isn’t like mine.” In a way, it really does feel safe; one can be secure in the knowledge that their character isn&#8217;t being called a Sue, and it stands to reason that it means they&#8217;re doing something right. At the end of the day, a writer or roleplayer can sit back and reflect about how their characters are somehow more genuine or true to the narrative they&#8217;re a part of <em>because </em>they aren&#8217;t labeled as an overpowered mockery.</p>
<p>Honestly, that&#8217;s pretty unfair.</p>
<p>One of the most important features of creating in a fandom or roleplaying in a preset universe is feeling as if you&#8217;re contributing to an ongoing narrative. It&#8217;s just like any other academic argument—it&#8217;s a conversation, and one your opinion deserves to be a part of. Even if you&#8217;re not fully informed in parts of the conversation, it&#8217;s up to others to help guide you. Research is always good, of course, but in many cases it&#8217;s fun to jump in feet-first. The use of the Mary Sue as a derisive term effectively cuts many out of the &#8220;conversation&#8221;, or at the very least eliminates the desire to join in. No one wants to set themselves up for failure, and with Mary Sue looming like a neon sign above fandoms and roleplayers, it&#8217;s no wonder creative individuals often keep silent in order to avoid offending the established crowd.</p>
<p>Many writers have discussed &#8220;reclaiming&#8221; the Mary Sue in an attempt to remove it as a negative trope within fandom/RP culture. If you’re particularly interested in academic observations I’d recommend Camille Bacon-Smith’s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Enterprising-Women-Television-Contemporary-Ethnography/dp/0812213793/ref=sr_1_9?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1432144932&amp;sr=8-9&amp;keywords=camille+bacon-smith">Enterprising Women</a>. Her ethnography in specific is the one which got my metaphorical goat, as she discusses fandom and writing within fandoms from a female point of view. Her notion that female writers gravitate towards writing male characters out of fear of undue criticism is of particular note, as it hammers home the idea of terror silencing potential ideas. Out of fear of creating a female character that others will criticize, potential writers simply never start.</p>
<p>I think that&#8217;s why the term bothers me so much—it&#8217;s gendered, utterly, and wielded by all against beginning writers and roleplayers. Worse, other creatives are lambasting <em>younger </em>female writers, artists, and roleplayers &#8212; silencing them before they have a chance to grow. The term Mary Sue applies to female characters in literature typically  written by females (there are of course exceptions to this rule), as they power the creative side of most fandoms through fiction, music videos, art, and photo manipulation. Conversely, when a male character is created that falls into these parameters, they are considered Gary Stus. I don&#8217;t really see this term as often, however, and you&#8217;d think with all of the overpowered male characters in every nerdy Fandom Thing it would be as ever-present as Sues. But that brings up another topic: why is Mary Sue damned while Captain Kirk considered a multifaceted, intriguing character?</p>
<p>While that’s a pet peeve I could go on about at length, my current concern is with emergent writers and roleplayers who are younger women first entering the fandom. They&#8217;re attempting to add their voice to the growing discussion, one that&#8217;s potentially been happening for a decade or more. It&#8217;s one hell of a river to jump into, especially when there&#8217;s an ever-present threat of criticism crocodiles (critodiles?) sleeping in the bulrushes.</p>
<p>Besides the fact that more veteran writers will criticize and inadvertently bully younger writers for the traits they give their characters without exploring why they did so. My own reasoning through creating these characters has a great deal to do with the lack of control I felt in my own life at the time I started writing. Through fiction, which had always represented a safe place, I could create a character who wouldn’t be burdened by my day-to-day and succeeded regardless of the struggles she went through. She was a princess because it gave her control. She was adept at language and school because it meant she was intelligent enough to compete with canon characters. Her negative traits didn’t detract from her glory and of course the canon characters loved her — she was useful, wanted, and adored instead of being ostracized from everything and everyone. My first Mary Sue was a creation of power that I didn’t possess but sorely wished to obtain — and through that, I began to understand the negotiations of control throughout fictional and non-fictional worlds.</p>
<p>The fact that others so desire to ruin that ability to learn power striations and create a conversation about that has become frustrating to me after years of criticizing the Mary Sue entirely. The Sue is an easy person to be annoyed instead of enamored by! In some fandoms they are incredibly prevalent, especially if the overworld is more of a sandbox. I am in several roleplaying communities and there are often blogs dedicated to seeking out overpowered original characters and breaking them down, bullet point by bullet point, as I did earlier in this article. We who have learned how wonderful a nuanced character can be, and instead of using that knowledge to bolster blossoming writers, our understanding becomes a vehicle for scorn. That has to change, and that change can only come from the inside. The Mary Sue must become a logical stepping-stone for female authors to begin to develop their craft.</p>
<p>How can we do this? In the next blog, we&#8217;ll be talking about character traits — and how to give your character balanced traits that reflect the universe they live in.</p>
<p>—</p>
<p>*For male over-powered characters, the moniker &#8216;Gary Stu&#8217; is used.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pretendy-fun-time-games-and-you-the-mary-sue/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pretendy Fun-Time Games and You: An Introduction</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pretendy-fun-time-games-and-you-an-introduction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[SE Lenair]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 17:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pretendy Fun-Time Games and You]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, hello! And welcome to my little corner of the blogosphere. I’m SE Lenair, one&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello, hello! And welcome to my little corner of the blogosphere.</p>
<p>I’m SE Lenair, one of several different names that I’ve gone through since my start on the internet &#8212; which is rather the point of this column, in truth. The world wide web’s been something of a constant in my life since I can remember, and as I’ve grown surrounded by it, my various interests have led me to assume different handles and monickers. Anonymity is a tricky thing to accomplish, and screen names usually make that easier for everyone involved. It’s odd to think that going by ten different names is seen as strange, as doing so has always been a constant in my life.</p>
<p>Why is this? Gaming, mostly. Communities that surround video games and similar media have always relied on handles in order to keep anything questionable from happening to their user base. As wonderful as the internet’s been for allowing people to find friendships around the globe, so too does it open seedy avenues for awful people to spew said awful behavior at folks that don’t deserve it &#8212; so it’s better that wolfpumpkin43 isn’t recognized as 13-year-old Suzie in South Carolina. The blanket usernames present is important, because the safer someone feels to express themselves, the better. (Though this can go in the opposite direction for some, which is another facet I plan on discussing.)</p>
<p>That personal expression within video games and their respective player bases is where I’m focused. Players express themselves in multiple ways: fanfiction and fan art being the top contenders. But there’s another form of fan creation which caught my interests eleven years ago: the idea of creating a character that fits within the universe presented by the game and then <i>playing </i>as that character. And forming interpersonal relationships with <i>other </i>people who are playing as their character.</p>
<p>In video games like Massively Multiplayer Role Playing Games (MMORPGs), one becomes an active participant in a world filled with other active participants from around the world. Though this is possible in console games such as First Person Shooters and the like, those games are often limited to completing an objective with others. Unless you’re on a team, you don’t really hang out with other people after everything’s said and done. MMORPGs, in contrast, provide a water cooler effect: there are dungeons with bosses to conquer and battlegrounds to beat, but after that there’s an overworld in which you constantly run into other players. It’s not unusual to end up chatting with others or partying up with them to do things in the overworld, be it questing or simply standing around and chatting.</p>
<p>Because of that interaction, MMORPGs have become something of a staging ground for a select niche of the player base. Roleplayers, people who create a character and then act out that persona with others, use MMORPG worlds to build upon the spark of a character idea. Typically, people make their characters to fit within the confines of established lore because it’s fun to do so. Because MMORPGs tend to have a fantasy bent (barring the advent of sci-fi MMOs which have become a wonderful thing in the last couple years), it’s no different than sitting around a table with five other people to play a session of Dungeons and Dragons.</p>
<p>The difference, of course, is that you’re sitting down at a table and playing with an upwards of twenty million people.</p>
<p>So with that explanation out of the way, my focus is going to be on the creation of these original characters (OCs) and the different facets roleplaying player bases have within the greater fanbase. It’s an ever-changing thing, in truth, due mostly to the player base of MMORPGs rising in age. I’ve been playing MMOs for eleven years and roleplaying for much longer, so I like to think I have a grip on these concepts. Of course I’ll be tying my topics to other fan expressions such as fanfiction and the creation of original characters within that medium as juxtaposed with MMORPGs. As I’m female, my work will be dedicated to other women who create and express themselves within this medium.</p>
<p>With that said, my first topic I’ll be tackling is the ill-famed and much-maligned archetype of the Mary Sue. For those who don’t know what that is, the best way to explain it is to call it a character created by a fan to fit into the universe for the express purpose of being beloved by it.</p>
<p>I hope you’ll enjoy it! If you have any questions, comments, or concerns, please shoot them my way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
