<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>A Place Where It Rains &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/a-place-where-it-rains/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 01:22:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>We Need to Talk About Luisa</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/we-need-to-talk-about-luisa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I ran into the middle school gym, neck and neck with another harried-looking mom.  “Careful,”&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I ran into the middle school gym, neck and neck with another harried-looking mom. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Careful,” I said, pointing to her purse, “your phone is coming out of that pocket.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Oh, Jesus.” She stuffed it down and zipped the compartment shut. “First time middle school mom?” she asked. She looked frazzled, like dozens of other moms seeking out spots on the bleachers for Step-Up Night. Each one of them represented a fifth grader about to become a middle schooler &#8212; no more recess, seven teachers in seven classrooms, lockers, and gym uniforms all ganging up on their babies at once. The cavernous basketball court buzzed with nervous tension as much as the drone of industrial lighting.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I felt a little guilty.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“No, I have an older son, so I’ve done this rodeo. I wanted to come to Step-Up night so Dee wouldn’t feel like her going to middle school was less important to me. Plus I figured they might have changed some policies because of the pandemic.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Oh, right.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There weren’t seats left in the bleachers, so we milled just inside the doorway with a clump of other latecomers. All of us looked at each other sidelong, shrugging in “what can you do?” embarrassment. Everyone traded stories of what had made them late, half in solidarity, half in apology.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“&#8211; just got off work at 5:30. Why do they schedule these after school things for 6:00 </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">every time</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“So, of course, I had to get the kids fed, and the dogs, and the next thing you know, I’m running out the door to get here and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I still haven’t eaten</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“&#8211; my husband’s car was in the shop, so he had mine all day, and he decided to work late because he forgot I had to be here, so when he finally called to say he was coming home, I was like ‘why don’t you go, you’re driving right past the school?’ and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">of course</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> he’s like, ‘I just got off of work. I want to relax. You worked from home today, so you can go.’ Well, I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">would go</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> if I could </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">get there</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">!”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My story wasn’t so different from theirs. My last class ended at 4:20, then I had an hour drive home, had to pick Deirdre up from her after school program, then get home to feed both kids before leaving just in time to be late, as always. Husbeast wasn’t on deck for this event because he was already on deck somewhere else: the local softball fields, where one of his two league teams was playing a double-header. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I confess I didn’t pay much attention to the opening presentation (sorry, Principal Hundal). In fairness, I’d seen it before. Instead, I was busy trying to tally the room.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">About 150 parents, give or take. Two thirds of the group were women. A few (almost certainly first time middle school parents) had come with their partner or co-parent, but mostly, it was a giant room of nervous moms who seemed to be going it alone. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you live with one half of your brain in stories and the other in social commentary all day, this turns into an article. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Specifically, this turned into an article two weeks later, when Dee finally made Husbeast and me sit down to watch </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Encanto</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We Don’t Talk About Bruno” may have ousted “Let It Go” from the</span><a href="https://screenrant.com/encanto-we-dont-talk-about-bruno-disney-record/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> top of the Disney musical pop charts</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but months after </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Encanto</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">’s release, it’s Luisa people are still talking about. Frankly, the fact that we were all distracted by Bruno when the far more relatable story was </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">right there the whole time</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is, well. . . nothing if not proof of the thesis driving Luisa’s character.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<figure id="attachment_28049" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-28049" style="width: 366px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28049" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Luisa-sword2-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="366" height="206" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Luisa-sword2-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Luisa-sword2-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Luisa-sword2-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Luisa-sword2.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 366px) 100vw, 366px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-28049" class="wp-caption-text">Disney: Middle sister Luisa, being a badass.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Luisa is magically gifted with strength that makes carrying five donkeys or righting the foundation of a slouching house with a passing kick easy, and so her family and community rely on her to carry (often literally) the burden of their work and responsibility. Her signature song, </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tQwVKr8rCYw"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Surface Pressure,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">” is part raison d’etre, part cry for help &#8212; a rare confession of the pressure of expectations, her fear of failure, and her struggle to find self-worth outside of constantly fulfilling obligations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the whole Madrigal family is charming, Luisa has proven to be the </span><a href="https://www.piratesandprincesses.net/luisa-madrigal-has-become-incredibly-popular-with-many-encanto-fans/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">breakout character of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Encanto</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for many viewers. Every viewer has their reasons for loving her&#8211; a body-positive character design; Strong Female Character Vibes (<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />); a powerful character song written for an alto. But for a lot of viewers (many of them women), Luisa embodies the struggle I saw played out in that middle school gym: a life defined by constant demands and expectations. They can all too easily relate to family defaults like the ones Luisa experiences. “[G]ive it to your sister, your sister’s stronger / see if she can hang on a little longer,” Luisa sings, and we immediately hear the familiar unfairness of the request. We recognize why her response is “who am I if I can’t carry it all?” because many of us have responded the same way in the face of relentless pressure.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Luisa’s anthem has driven dozens of other writers to take to their keyboards and claim her struggle as their own. There are essays about Luisa as a challenge to </span><a href="https://www.kcur.org/arts-life/2022-01-09/encanto-disney-luisa-madrigal-surface-pressure-ambition-resolution"><span style="font-weight: 400;">stop defining oneself by one’s accomplishments</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. She’s been</span><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2022/01/13/disney-encanto-luisa-worker-burnout/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> connected to worker burnout</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, especially for the essential workers who have shouldered the majority of the personal and financial risks of the Covid-19 pandemic. She’s even been part of a larger feminist argument that </span><a href="https://www.hercampus.com/culture/encanto-movie-latinx-culture/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">women bear their families’ burdens</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> largely unaided. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am not a crier, when it comes to stories. (Though there are exceptions, and I’ve </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-triggering-townsend-on-writing-the-actual-subject__trashed/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">written about that here before</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.) But I’d be lying if I said my eyes weren’t stinging after Luisa stopped singing. I kept thinking of the harried, unfed mothers racing to get their kids situated at home, just to go back out again and spend their evening in a gym taking careful notes about the hours those same children would spend in school. I thought about my 5:00 AM alarm and waking my son, then my daughter, and then my husband &#8212; giving them breakfast or packing them lunches and sometimes both before finally leaving for my own commute. I thought about hosting every family holiday gathering, and the days of shopping, cooking, and cleaning all absorbed in the whirlwind of a few hours. I thought about driving hours to and from my brother’s group living home so he’d have someone to help read his mail and run his errands. I thought about staying up late to do grading, only to discover a 9:00 PM email alert from my principal announcing a faculty meeting the next morning.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I cried. And once that was done, I was furious.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I grew angry at the film for distracting us with the misunderstood, oddball man (Bruno) when the misunderstood, wounded woman holding the world together through brute force was </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">right there</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, all along. How many women working on </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Encanto</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> loved Luisa, saw themselves in her, and then felt themselves disappear to serve a predictable family non-mystery &#8212; to make the space to showcase a more mysterious character with flashy drama-generating powers? And how much of my anger about that was really anger at my own life?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I won’t lie. I felt some of the anger because I kept seeing myself as Luisa &#8212; as the family pack mule. Every mule has someone driving them. Was I angry at my husband? My brother? My whole extended family? Everyone I worked with? Was there really space in me for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">that much</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> anger? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apparently so. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was the morning after we watched </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Encanto</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Husbeast was checking his work email. I was folding laundry. I still felt raw, like I’d been jerked off my feet and dragged a long distance. I wanted to talk about my anger. I needed a way to start. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Do you suppose </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Encanto</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is going to be Deirdre’s new binge?” I asked, trying to sound light.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It wouldn’t be the worst thing. It was a smarter show than I expected.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I put down one of his shirts, unfolded. I chose a towel, instead. “How so?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It’s funny,” he said. “‘We Don’t Talk About Bruno’ is the song everybody talks about, but the one with the sister is way better.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“. . . which sister?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The strong one? I can’t remember her name.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“‘Surface Pressure,’” I said, obviously too eagerly. “That’s Luisa. That one really got me.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For a minute, we just looked at each other, not saying anything. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Me too,” he said, finally.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I blinked, confused. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“For myself,” he explained. “And for you. We’re always the ones who take care of stuff, you know? The ones who get things done. You, especially, but me at work, and with my mom,” he rolled his hand in the air, like a katamari collecting the debris of responsibility. “It just. . . keeps going, all the time. It almost hurt, how familiar that song was.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The anger wasn’t gone, but it started to take a different shape.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The irony of how we talk about Luisa is that in casting ourselves as her, we forget that almost </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">everyone</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is Luisa, at least once in their lives. In focusing on how much we carry, on our own limits and need for self-care and how often we fail to exercise either of those things, we lose sight of other people. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s that failure to see and understand that put Luisa in this position in the first place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everyone who asked Luisa to hold up a wall, or a world, believed they couldn’t do it themselves because they were already carrying what they could through their own crowded lives. They saw Luisa’s competence and generosity and mistook it for ease, and so asking her to do more seemed reasonable. It might even have seemed fair. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we take on those jobs and only see ourselves as the ones doing it, we carry more than just the weight of the work of the moment: we carry the resentment of it, and the fear of speaking up about it, and the increasing belief that the people loading up the mules aren’t carrying anything themselves. We fall into a solipsistic trap. We start believing we’re the only Luisa in town. I was angry because I rushed through my life to get to Step-Up Night while my husband was playing softball &#8212; but he had come home and put Deirdre to bed and checked Corwin’s math homework, because I was already asleep on the couch and, frankly, the math was beyond me and took them an hour to review together. It had been past 10:00 when they started, but he had still done it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What other things had he done that day that I knew nothing about? Had I even thought to ask?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“We need the kids to fold some laundry this weekend,” I said, dropping the towel, unfolded, on top of the shirt I just gave up on. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My husband nodded. “I’ve been teaching them how. Anything else?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Think we could get dinner out?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Just us?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“No, all of us. I just. .  . want to read a book tonight instead of cooking.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He smiled. “Sure. No pressure.”</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_28050" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-28050" style="width: 356px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28050" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Luisa-relaxed-300x194.png" alt="" width="356" height="230" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Luisa-relaxed-300x194.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Luisa-relaxed-1024x662.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Luisa-relaxed-768x497.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Luisa-relaxed.png 1082w" sizes="(max-width: 356px) 100vw, 356px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-28050" class="wp-caption-text">Disney: A girl can dream, no?</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Return of Problematic Things</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-return-of-problematic-things/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 10:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m in the “teen space” room of the Fountaindale Public Library, sometime in 1994. My&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m in the “teen space” room of the Fountaindale Public Library, sometime in 1994. My friends and I are getting ready to play a </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vampire:_The_Masquerade"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vampire: The Masquerade</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> RPG</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, for which I’ll play Storyteller. It will be my first experience running a game for anyone other than my brother. I’m very proud of all the ideas I’ve jotted down. There’s a pile of NPCs on photocopied </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vampire</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> character sheets in front of me. One of them is a </span><a href="https://whitewolf.fandom.com/wiki/Malkavian_(VTM)"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malkavian</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; vampires that are good at stealth, intuition, and manipulating the minds of others through a power called “Dementation.” All vampires have a weakness linked to their clan origin; for the Malkavians, it’s an insanity that grips them from the moment of their undead embrace. I am both proud of this character, and nervous about it. I’ve decided that this Malkavian will be schizophrenic, because I know what that means. My uncle is </span><a href="https://www.nimh.nih.gov/health/statistics/schizophrenia#:~:text=Schizophrenia-,Definition,be%20both%20severe%20and%20disabling."><span style="font-weight: 400;">schizophrenic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It’s not something I’ve told my friends.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the players is upset at the end of the session because he thinks the Malkavian NPC is a “cheat.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“He didn’t act </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">anywhere near</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> weird enough,” he explains as we walk down the library steps. “You can’t just </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">not roleplay</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> his weakness, Tracy.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“But I was!”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“He should’ve, like, worn a duck on his head and called it Charles or something. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> schizo.”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">###</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few weeks later, I’m hanging out at a friend’s house after school. She is inclined to drama, of the sort that manifests in a mostly-performative appetite for heavy metal, doing her own piercings with a hot needle and an ice cube, and taking scissors to all of her clothes after buying them at Wal-Mart. She’s also a serial liar, not out of cruelty, but out of loneliness, trying to find events or experiences to make herself interesting enough for others’ notice. I’m only fourteen and deeply naive, yet even I’ve caught on to that much.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My friend invited me here because she says she needs to share a very important secret. Megadeth plays (loudly) on her boombox. Over it, she’s bellowing about how she knows she’s insane.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I hear voices,” she shouts. “They tell me to do things. I’m giving them names. I’m up to, like, four now? I think? Oh, wait, I think I hear another one! That’s five!”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This, she insists, is because she is schizophrenic. Also, probably bipolar. Or maybe she has multiple personality disorder? Or is that what being schizophrenic is? (It isn’t.) We’re still a decade away from having the internet in our pocket, so she leaves the question in the air, unanswered, with a shrug.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When she finally turns</span><a href="https://open.spotify.com/track/6i7IXg8j7ZngiEOgBYjkhw?si=0eacdcc604aa44e1"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> “Sweating Bullets” </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">down, I think for a minute before I ask my question.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“How do you feel about this?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Her smile is positively rapturous. “It’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">amazing.</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">###</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Braveheart</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> hits the theaters and my friends and I see it for the billionth time (we like swords, and underdogs, and nobody outside of Hollywood knows yet that Mel Gibson is a monster). Everyone’s favorite character is </span><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112573/characters/nm0641244"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stephen</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the deranged Irish berserker who pledges himself to William Wallace’s cause. He shouts disquisitions to the sky, asserting that “In order to find his equal, an Irishman is forced to talk to God.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Crazy Irish</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">,” Wallace’s sergeant grumbles. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But to the teenage crowd I run with, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">crazy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is an endorsement.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">###</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve written before about </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-loving-problematic-things/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">loving problematic things</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but this time, it’s more than personal. It’s generational. It’s a whole damn phenomenon. And it’s less about “loving” the problematic thing than not understanding it in the first place.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m the last gasp of Generation X. Somewhere in the decades that made us, the idea that mental illness (madness, you’d call it, if you were poetically inclined or a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vampire</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> LARPer) was freeing, or the source of cosmic insight, or funny, took hold. Madness could be encompassed by wearing a duck on your head, if you were that friend critiquing my </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vampire</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> RP, or in the lyrics of a banger song, if you were my self-diagnosing friend. Madness made you </span><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0117509/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Baz Luhrmann’s Mercutio</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, or a Johnny Depp character, or a proto-manic pixie dream girl. Or it turned you into an oracle, a figure of tragic insight. Or maybe a no-fucks-to-give badass (remember </span><a href="https://www.mandatory.com/fun/197187-the-myth-of-macho-lethal-weapon"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mel Gibson in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lethal Weapon</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">? </span><a href="https://www.complex.com/pop-culture/2014/10/fight-club-schizophrenia#:~:text=On%20the%20surface%2C%20Fight%20Club's,t%20express%20on%20his%20own."><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tyler Durden in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fight Club</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">?</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">). Throw in the rise of the internet and an ever-growing army of questionable resources about mental health, a sloppy use of discourse (“ugh, stack the books </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">this way</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, or my OCD will go nuts”), and the entire alternative music scene from 1990-2002, and you’ve basically got a pressure cooker for young people with little understanding of how mental illness works and a deep, fascinated certainty that, actually, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">they do</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> know how mental illness works. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It seems we’ve bled this romanticizing of mental illness into today’s youth, too. A quick browse of YouTube and TikTok makes clear that youth discourse about mental illness is abundant and, to a shocking degree, </span><a href="https://confluence.gallatin.nyu.edu/context/independent-project/a-perspective-on-tiktoks-mental-health-epidemic"><span style="font-weight: 400;">badly misinformed</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. My son (who is 14) has had friends self-diagnose with any number of conditions ranging from depression to Dissociative Identity Disorder, and while some of them have gone on to seek treatment (through which some of them have come to realize that while they needed mental health support, it wasn’t for anything as rare or sensational as they had imagined), others have spiraled deeper into an absolute certainty that they suffer from conditions heretofore undiagnosed and unexplored by professionals. I’ve seen this phenomenon among my students, too: authentic confusion and pain eagerly labeled with the mental disorders that have been dramatized to them in ways that aren’t realistic or helpful. Ways that, frankly, incentivize identifying as ill because it’s a new way of “being special” in a world too big to make most of us feel noticed. In this sea of self-diagnoses and appropriation of the language of mental health advocacy, many people who do need help get lost in the noise of others who are seeking something different in their quest to understand themselves, or make themselves seen.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Somehow, we took the capital-R Romantic notion of the unfettered, tortured individual, the person who lives outside the norms of their society, and transformed it into this, the party that too many people want in on for the wrong reasons. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And that’s why I’m not sure if I’m going to read this copy of </span><a href="https://marvel.fandom.com/wiki/Moon_Knight_Vol_1"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moon Knight, volume 1</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I’ve checked out from the library.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27390 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Moon-Knight-Cover-195x300.jpg" alt="" width="195" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Moon-Knight-Cover-195x300.jpg 195w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Moon-Knight-Cover.jpg 325w" sizes="(max-width: 195px) 100vw, 195px" /> </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">###</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I grew up on Marvel comics. I collected them avidly for about twelve years, pumping God-only-knows how much money and time into my regular pull titles: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">X-Men</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wolverine</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What If?, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">and more. And yet, though I had at least a passing familiarity with Spider-Man, the Avengers, the Hulk, the Punisher, Luke Cage, Daredevil, and even Ghost Rider, I never even heard of Moon Knight before Disney+ announced its plans to develop it, casting Oscar Isaac in the lead.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It wasn’t until the week the show debuted and I pondered watching it that I learned the titular character, Marc Spector, has </span><a href="https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/9792-dissociative-identity-disorder-multiple-personality-disorder#:~:text=from%20Cleveland%20Clinic-,Dissociative%20identity%20disorder%20(DID)%20is%20a%20mental%20health%20condition.,memory%20loss%2C%20delusions%20or%20depression."><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dissociative Identity Disorder</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, colloquially called “Multiple Personality Disorder.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Immediately, my desire to watch the show waned.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My mother’s mental decline, driven by multiple sclerosis, left her with Alzheimer’s-like mental and emotional issues, including depression, suicidal ideation, and obsessive-compulsive habits. My uncle suffered from paranoid schizophrenia beginning in his early adulthood, and continues to deal with its impact on his life today. Other members of my family have suffered from depression, self-harm, and traumatic experiences of various kinds, including domestic abuse and alcoholism.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I grew up watching people portray mental disorders and pain as an art object in my entertainments of choice &#8212; and I grew up participating in that culture, too.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m not sure if I can trust </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moon Knight</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> not to make the same mistake.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_27391" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-27391" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-27391" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Moon-Knight-Dracula-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="900" height="506" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Moon-Knight-Dracula-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Moon-Knight-Dracula-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Moon-Knight-Dracula-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Moon-Knight-Dracula.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-27391" class="wp-caption-text">Not going to lie. . . he DOES seem entertaining.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I thought I could satisfy my curiosity and make that decision by reading up on the source material, but of course, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moon Knight </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">runs from 1980-2018. There’s so much overlap between the pop cultural history I began this essay with and the origins of the character &#8212; is it even fair, or sensible, to expect anything other than what I grew up seeing? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Should we, in 2022, </span><a href="https://screenrant.com/moon-knight-mental-illness-portrayal-representation-crucial/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">demand something different</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regular readers of my columns might be disappointed that I’ve taken you this far without giving you “an answer.” I still haven’t cracked open </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moon Knight</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. I still haven’t queued up the show. I still can’t decide if watching it with a critical gaze is more important to confronting my past with mental illness in media, and in my family, or if not doing either is voting with my attention, pushing the discourse away from treating mental illness as a source of narrative grist and glamor.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I haven’t decided, because all answers are bad answers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At least, that’s what I told myself until I talked to the Husbeast.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">###</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My husbeast is the sort of listener who defaults to problem-solving. Unless you are profoundly clear that you only want to emote or opine, he’ll hear out your latest worries while building a mental flowchart of how you should resolve every element of your problem, or how to avoid such problems in the future.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He saw the copy of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moon Knight</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and me working at this column with a furrowed brow, and after ten minutes of me gesticulating and explaining, he had an answer.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“There’s virtue in thinking about the problems media that entertains us can reinforce, and being aware of those problems helps disrupt the cycle of reinforcement, right?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I frowned. “R-right? Sort of?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It’s the only way </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">to </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">disrupt that cycle: to consume thoughtfully. So, what if you just,” he gestured roundly, “tried consuming </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moon Knight </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">thoughtfully, because you’re aware that mental illness isn’t entertaining or exciting? It’s hard. And it’s often scary, and sad. You already know that. Letting yourself derive whatever pleasure you can from the experience and also putting yourself in a position to talk meaningfully about how the title measures up against your fears is a good thing.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“But I don’t want to reward bad media.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Do you </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">know </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">it’s bad yet?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I hesitated. “I’ve. . . been trying to avoid reviews and spoilers, so I guess I don’t know.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Husbeast shrugged. “Fair. And you know what else is fair? </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Letting yourself be an audience</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You deserve the chance to try something without taking all the possible guilt for it upon yourself. You don’t even know yet if the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moon Knight</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that’s out there is problematic or not. And even if it is, you can still think it through and change your mind about continuing. We’re all going to fail if the goal of entertainment is to find something pure.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All answers are bad answers, until you realize that being aware of the problems in your choices isn’t the same as having your choices taken away. My answers have something to do with a history &#8212; as much private as public &#8212; that needs to be unpacked. It’s a history that, stubbornly, will not unpack itself. And it certainly won’t be unpacked while my back is turned.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s snowing in April now because the Midwest is cruel and makes little sense. It’s a problematic day, full of daffodils and sleet, mingling improbably at the same time. It’s a day I’m prepared to take on with a healthy degree of skepticism. Maybe that’s the best kind of day to start on </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moon Knight vol. 1</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">But he’d better not put a duck on his head, or so help me &#8212; </span></i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Book of Boba Fett: When Your Idea Isn&#8217;t a Story</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-book-of-boba-fett-when-your-idea-isnt-a-story/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26942</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“I’ve decided,” I announced to my husbeast as we lay in bed, post Episode 6&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I’ve decided,” I announced to my husbeast as we lay in bed, post Episode 6 of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Book of Boba Fett</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, “that the Mandalorian’s mustache bothers me.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Husbeast frowned. “He hasn’t taken off his helmet in this show, though.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I’m working under the assumption that he hasn’t changed his look since the end of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Mandalorian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> season 2.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’d just been kissing, which meant mustaches were on my mind.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It bothers me because it is the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">least logical</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> grooming choice possible, given his situation,” I said.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“You’re right.” He was clearly hoping I’d just get back to the kissing. He never agrees with me this quickly under normal circumstances. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“A mustache is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">a choice</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, right?” I plowed on. “Very intentional grooming, but he knows no one is supposed to see his face, ever, so why the hell does he do it? It’s got to get itchy under all that</span><a href="https://dorksideoftheforce.com/2020/11/03/the-mandalorian-beskar-explained/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> beskar</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. A beard might make more sense, in the ‘who cares, fuck it’ way some beards go &#8212; not you, I like yours &#8212; but that would be even worse under the helmet. Like, ‘Covid masking with facial hair’-level uncomfortable, but forever.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Uh huh.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“So, he </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">should</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> just go clean shaven, though that involves work nobody would much care about. But a mustache? It is the worst of both worlds: all the maintenance work, little to no comfort benefit. It’s the stupidest possible decision. Totally takes me out of the moment.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Yes, I’ve noticed.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“It doesn’t bother you?”  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Husbeast shrugged against his pillow. “I assume Pedro Pascal was filming </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mandalorian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> episodes in between something else where he was expected to have a mustache.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sheer reasonableness of this thought snapped my mouth shut.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“You’re thinking about this because you’re not sure you like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Book of Boba Fett</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, aren’t you?” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Husbeast knows me all too well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best part about not being sure if I’m enjoying something is that my brain has permission to get critically engaged with </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">why. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I grew up on all things George Lucas, so </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">why can’t I just be happy to see another star war</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometime between midnight and 2 AM &#8212; well past Husbeast giving up the ghost as I grumbled over geek theory &#8212; I lit upon the answer:</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Book of Boba Fett</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> isn’t actually a story.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Or, put another way, it was founded on an </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">idea </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">which never succeeded in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">becoming</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a story.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I talk to my students a lot about the distinction between an idea and a story. An </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">idea</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> might be the start of a story, but it isn’t a story all by itself. A story requires a setting, characters, some set of stakes, some sense of resolution, and it requires some sense of cohesion and credibility in these various parts. An idea is the shiny starting point. In the world of sff, it’s the speculative thorn that’s dug itself into the creator’s mind. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Book of Boba Fett </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">was born because of an idea from </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Mandalorian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">: “What if Boba Fett was still alive?” From that idea, various questions arise: How did he survive </span><a href="https://www.starwars.com/databank/sarlacc"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the sarlacc</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">? What does he want now?</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, he wants his armor back.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Okay. Cue </span><a href="https://starwars.fandom.com/wiki/Cobb_Vanth?so=search"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cobb Vanth</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, borrowed from </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Wars:_Aftermath_trilogy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chuck Wendig’s</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Aftermath</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> novels</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Set up a side-quest with Mando, continue his redemption journey as he tries to do what’s best for Grogu, etc., etc.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And now, pursuant to that, Boba Fett has regained his armor from Din Djarin, has returned to Tatooine, and has disposed of the imminently disposable </span><a href="https://starwars.fandom.com/wiki/Bib_Fortuna"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bib Fortuna</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So &#8212; now what?</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, he’s going to become the crime lord of Tatooine. </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That might seem like the start of a story &#8212; how will he do it? What will stand in his way? But there are a number of reasons that idea doesn’t yield a story. Instead, it gets us to a premise that, while genuinely interesting, is doomed from the start, the same way virtually any face reveal for Mando was doomed from the start. No face under that helmet quite makes sense because we’ve built our understanding of the character almost entirely </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">without</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> his face. Something similar is true for Boba Fett.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><b>The Three Reasons </b><b><i>The Book of Boba Fett</i></b><b> Can’t Quite Work</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In Boba Fett, the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Wars </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">universe keeps trying to sell us goods that are long out of stock. He was billed as one of the deadliest, most ruthless, most effective bounty hunters in the galaxy in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Empire Strikes Back</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a goon fit for a direct summons from Darth Vader, whose name could by itself could send a vulnerable Han Solo into a panic attack mid-battle. </span><a href="https://www.entertainmentearth.com/news/boba-fett-action-figure-history/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Months of toy sales</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, posters, and teaser images had primed the original </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Wars </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">audience for a vicious, intimidating villain.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead, that tough-guy potential was sacrificed to prove how powerful Luke had become. It was discarded with a Wilhelm Scream and an out-of-control jetpack ride into the mouth of the sarlacc. This gets us to the first reason why </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Book of Boba Fett </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">fails as a story, however much it compels as an idea.</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>One</strong>: You can’t make your audience buy Boba Fett as the next Tony Soprano of Tatooine (his escapades in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Mandalorian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> season 2 aside) because you’ve already pulled the rug out from underneath his character’s power and authority. The story can’t effectively explore Tatooine’s seedy underbelly and Boba Fett’s mastery of it because our central memory of him is a lot of standing around with his arms crossed, then getting owned as a combat afterthought.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, the showrunners tried for a different story &#8212; or, at least, tried to have it both ways. Could their idea lead to a redemption arc? Boba Fett could become a different kind of warrior-leader, one with compassion and a sense of balance and reason. Perhaps happenstance leads him into an encounter with a being or beings very unlike himself, with whom he can’t easily communicate, and drives him to change his priorities and his habits, taking responsibility for their welfa&#8211;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oh. This sounds familiar, doesn’t it?</span></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Two:</strong><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The Book of Boba Fett </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">can’t succeed as its own story if it’s a reskin of the fan favorite elements of its predecessor, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Mandalorian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Wars</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has gained traction in series format because it’s giving its audience a variety of different things &#8212; or at least trying to, if the calendar of upcoming series is to be believed. Focusing </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Book of Boba Fett </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">on its shared characteristics with Mando’s story (even general characteristics, to say nothing of shared recurring characters) doesn’t help distinguish it as Boba Fett’s journey. It turns your titular character into an also-ran.</span></span></li>
</ul>
<p>So, the show tries a third story strategy. Could the series focus instead on how Boba got to this moment alive in the first place? <i>Star Wars</i> has been working all along its timeline with prequels and such for years. The franchise takes for granted that audiences will accept a story whose general outcome is already known if how we got there turns out to be engaging.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is how you get episodes 1-4 of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Book of Boba Fett</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which might alternatively be titled </span><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0099348/plotsummary"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dances With Tusken Raiders</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. While Boba’s engagement with the Sand People gives us more insight into their world than we’ve known before, it’s a very heavy lift for your character &#8212; or, more precisely, for </span><a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm0607325/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Temuera Morrison</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He’s surrounded by characters he can’t communicate with (at least for the first three episodes) and whose emotional affect is functionally inaccessible to him and to us. Unlike working with humanoid aliens with a visible face and expressions, from which you might extrapolate emotive meaning, the Tuskens are swathed, bundled, and masked (Maybe? Are those masks or some kind of cybernetic modifications? Rebreathers? Biological growths that only look mechanical? Something else?) in a way that makes them almost unreadable. Morrison is forced to emote for everyone around him. If he’s to carry off his character and the assumptions we can reasonably make about him (which, to his credit, Morrison does), then this is a real issue, because Boba isn’t exactly a verbose, performative guy.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_26946" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26946" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26946" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Fennec-Shand-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Fennec-Shand-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Fennec-Shand.jpg 667w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26946" class="wp-caption-text">Representing the Women Who Get Shit Done faction of characterization: Fennec Shand</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The early episodes pass primarily in pantomime, Boba’s </span><a href="https://www.inverse.com/entertainment/why-does-boba-fett-sleep-in-a-bacta-tank-star-wars"><span style="font-weight: 400;">bacta-tank flashbacks </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">interrupted by jaunts into the present with Fennec Shand, who seems to be the only one of them who actually understands how to Do Crime and Get Stuff Done.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And at the end of episode four, Boba’s droid valet congratulates him on being fully healed. From that point on, the series shifts its gaze away from Boba Fett and what we thought the show was about to something quite different. Thus:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Three:</strong> A backstory isn’t necessarily a story. Once it catches up to the present &#8212; or at least to the point that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Mandalorian</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> began to tell Boba’s story &#8212; the series abandons Fett as the character of focus, betraying that it wasn’t his story we were being given, only an idea. “What if he lived?” gets us through the hows and whys of his </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dances With Tusken Raiders</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> period and no further. Even the showrunners seem to understand that “what would he do after?” is a story they don’t know how to tell without putting it in other characters’ hands.</span></li>
</ul>
<figure id="attachment_26944" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26944" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26944" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Trojan-Horse-Boba-Fett-300x296.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="296" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Trojan-Horse-Boba-Fett-300x296.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Trojan-Horse-Boba-Fett.jpg 506w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26944" class="wp-caption-text">Hmm. . . nope, checks out, this is fine.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are things I enjoyed quite a lot in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Book of Boba Fett</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Sadly, few of them have much to do with Boba himself. The idea of “what if he survived” might have given way to the premise of “Boba Fett is a stern but fair criminal ruler of his territories, who must fend off far greater threats to himself and others” except that it’s not a premise that seems well suited to his character. We struggle to accept his toughness because it was discarded long before he had a chance to be a fully-fledged character. We struggle to engage with his emotional transformation because it seems reductive and duplicative, given the stories that came before it. We can’t focus solely on his survival because that’s already the given of the series’ premise &#8212; the core idea in its katamari of almost-story-ness. His backstory has to give way to new events at some point, but all of those new events rely on one or both of the other two flawed approaches to the premise. It’s not enough to hold a series up, because it was just an idea, not a story, after all.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Book of Boba Fett</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> might best be viewed as the prequel to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Mandalorian </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">season three. It also has the benefit of getting my mind off Mando’s mustache. But there’s something to be said for the “mustache logic” needed to take the series apart: you have to understand your story, and your character, well enough to keep it internally consistent. Something as small as a mustache can’t by itself break a story, but it can break our sense that a story is a logical whole, and that the people in it are behaving with an understanding of their circumstances.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mando shouldn’t have a mustache. It’s not a choice that makes sense, or suits his circumstances.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Boba Fett probably shouldn’t have had a seven-episode series, because once you subject it to mustache logic, well. . . you start to think a lot more about razors and if you’re really pulling off the look in the first place. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When the Student Becomes the Master</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/when-the-student-becomes-the-master/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 11:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m lucky to have a teenage son who actually listens to me. Not in a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m lucky to have a teenage son who actually listens to me. Not in a “go hang up your coat” kind of way (we’re still working on that), but other ways. Arguably, more important ways. Corwin has always been an attentive listener when it comes to Stuff He Doesn’t Know. He delights in the particular effervescence of an unexpected and relevant discovery, and is good at stowing that kind of knowledge away for later deployment. It’s how he’s become discursive in things like the distinction between pathos and bathos, the history of the goat as a competitive tool in horse-racing, and the basic principles of Kantian deontology. Given his attentiveness to my nerdiness, I’m either raising the world’s most boring fourteen-year-old, or one who could take over a cocktail party at the Smithsonian. It’s anybody’s guess.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a tabernacle of useless knowledge, I have swanned through many a social or academic situation. My passion for trivium, my willingness to dive into obscure subjects, my delight over “aha!” moments, my six degrees of separation instinct for looking at how the world works (fueled by way too much time watching </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Connections_(British_documentary)"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Connections</span></i></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">and </span><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0370117/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Connections 2</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> reruns as a kid) may be part genetic and part environmental, but they’re all Corwin. Recently, this has meant coming to grips with something geek parents sometimes struggle with: </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My son has achieved levels of Nerd Expertise not only far greater than mine, but in areas I have no hope of mastering.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve </span><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-passing-the-torch-or-you-cant-make-them-love-things-the-way-you-do/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">written about being a geek parent before</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8212; specifically, about how my daughter’s experience of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Wars</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> differs from mine, and coming to grips with that being not just okay, but necessary. Lurking in the backstory of that older essay is another fact I don’t think we in the world of sff do a good enough job addressing.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">We really, really like to be right. And we especially like it when that means we know more than the people around us.</span></i></p>
<figure id="attachment_26820" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26820" style="width: 299px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-26820 size-full" style="text-align: center;" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/comic-book-guy.jpg" alt="" width="299" height="169" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26820" class="wp-caption-text">The man, the myth, the Worst. Fanboy. Ever.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The “we” I’m talking about here is sloppy and general. Not everyone in the sfnal community gets off on “well actually” or “oh, let me tell you </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">all about that</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">,” but a lot of us do. It’s a set of behaviors we’ve coded as male, the prototypical </span><a href="https://simpsons.fandom.com/wiki/Comic_Book_Guy"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Comic Book Guy</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> move, yet I’ve met more than my share of women who do the same. These are the folks whose sense of their own va</span>lue in a social interaction is how much authority they bring to it. They find themselves floundering in the face of someone who really does just <i>know more</i> than they do.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And then there’s me. I wanted Corwin to share in that thrill of knowing stuff, so I started him early, sharing every bit of nerd-brain I could muster. Now he’s found a place to direct his hunger to explore and discover minutiae, and it’s clear I’ll never catch up.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corwin loves Gundam. He loves watching the anime s</span>eries (Series-es? There are several, though I struggle to distinguish them. He’s on <i>Unicorn</i> now). He loves building the models even more and over the last two years has built up a huge collection of kits, modeling tools, highlighting media, epoxies &#8212; the works.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I know nothing about Gundam. (I watched </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robotech_(TV_series)"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Robotech: Macross</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> back in the day, but I’ve been assured by a certain authority to whom I once gave birth that while this is adorable, it’s not remotely the same thing.) The very way that information about Gundam is structured seems antithetical to how I learn. For example, </span><a href="https://www.gundamplanet.com/blog/gundam-planet-top-sales-2020-gunpla-model-kits.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here’s a list of 2020’s top selling gunpla</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (that’s “Gundam + plastic” = Gundam mobile suit model kits). My eyes hit the pile of letter/number designations and something like a computer heat sink whirring to life happens in my brain, trying to save me from a burning wave of confusion. There are High Grades and Real Grades, and while a Real Grade is better than a High Grade, a Real Grade is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">not </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">as good as a Master Grade, and let’s not even get started on a Perfect Grade. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cue my mental fans whirring.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And yet, I watch Corwin build his gunpla, camped out at the kitchen table while his dad’s on Playstation and his sister binges </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Good Place</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the 800th time on her iPad (which is probably where he picked up on deontology, if I’m being realistic), and it’s frankly amazing. He stops and pokes me out of a flurry of grading to show me, in fine detail, how the joints work under the concealment of armored plates, and how the frame beneath is the same chassis as a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">[lots of words here I don’t understand]</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> but with more points of articulation than a typical </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">[something something letter number</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">]. He’s memorized whole builds &#8212; knows the fictional history behind how one mobile suit evolved into the next, and how mobile suit pilots train to use them &#8212; and, well,</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> everything</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A good parent should let themselves be taught by their children, at least in some things. The fact that what it takes to be a good parent is at odds with the nervous, grasping, insecure instincts of the sort of geek I’ve often been &#8212; a know-it-all, a polymath, and all too proud of it &#8212; has been. . . let’s say “instructive.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I tried to make interested noises. I thought of questions to ask, trying not to let on that I didn’t understand the answers. Sometimes, I’d just stick with observations: “I like the symmetry here, how the blade on its arm sort of matches this thing over here.” That kind of thing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But kids are smart.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corwin calls his gunpla “diaper robots,” in part because of how the anthropomorphic ones do look like they’ve got some junk in their trunk, and in part because that’s slang from the gunpla building community &#8212; the kind of defensive, self-effacing term you adopt because if you tease yourself first, whatever other people say next can’t hurt as much. He’s heard me mutter in confusion over his Christmas and birthday kit requests: “This looks </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">exactly</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> like the last one you got, seriously?” He’s heard my skepticism. He’s watched me grumble about the piles of kit boxes in his closet and their conspiracy to take over his bedroom floor.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I walked in the room and Corwin was watching a Gundam anime on Netflix, he’d rush to pause the show and ask what I wanted. He’s not a secretive kid. He’s not shy. And he knows me too well to imagine I’d censor his entertainment, if I saw a few minutes of it and things got weird. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I started to wonder if he was aware of my half-engagement. The answer was obvious, once I tallied up my behaviors, benign and curmudgeonly alike. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course he knew</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He cared about Gundam and his gunpla more than almost anything, and I was, at best, pleasantly nodding along in the face of that passion. Even when sentences started with riveting gems like, “The thing to remember about capitalism is. . .,” he’d always really, truly listened to me. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Didn’t I owe it to him to do the same?</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">***</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We were in our basement exercising just the other day, and it was Corwin’s turn to put a couple of miles in on the treadmill. I hopped on the recumbent elliptical, both of us pointed toward the small mounted flat screen that was meant to keep us from giving up too fast out of sheer boredom. Corwin looked bored. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Worse, he looked like he didn’t want me to be there. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Dad’s got the Fire TV stick set up down here,” I pointed out. “You could restart the Gundam anime you’ve been  watching and knock out a couple of episodes.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">clearly</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> what he wanted to do. And yet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Um. . .”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Look, if you’re afraid I’ll think the show is dumb or silly or something, I won’t. Honestly.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corwin blinked. He’d never </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">said </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">that was what he was afraid of, but I was at least close to the mark. He already had the controller in his hand. He’d wanted to get back to the show, but was embarrassed to watch it in front of me. Maybe because I’d think it was stupid, or &#8212;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Worse, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">because I wouldn’t care</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I don’t understand the show,” I added quickly, “But I’d like to try, if you’re okay with that. I’m really proud of you, actually.”</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_26821" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26821" style="width: 212px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-26821 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Gundam_Unicorn_Poster-212x300.jpg" alt="" width="212" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Gundam_Unicorn_Poster-212x300.jpg 212w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Gundam_Unicorn_Poster.jpg 350w" sizes="(max-width: 212px) 100vw, 212px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26821" class="wp-caption-text">The exact title, I have learned, is MOBILE SUIT GUNDAM UNICORN</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fourteen-year-olds are excellent at skepticism. “For having a bunch of diaper robots and being a weeb?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“For knowing so much about something and caring about it. For having something that’s totally yours. I like seeing you like things.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Corwin hesitated a moment longer, then queued up the next episode.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Okay,” I said. “Basic background?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Oof. Um, well, it’s a lot, but there are these two factions at war with each other . . .”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Turns out there’s something in the show called Laplace’s Box. It’s the McGuffin everyone is struggling to find. Recognizing the reference, I texted him a link to the concept of </span><a href="https://www.scienceabc.com/pure-sciences/what-is-laplaces-demon-definition-explanation.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Laplace’s Demon</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> when our workout was done. </span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looks like the writers of the show really did their homework</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He sent a gorilla emoji back. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don’t ask me to translate that one, I’ve got nothing. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">***</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We talk a lot about how we in the sfnal community relate to one another. We worry about who is silenced and marginalized, about what old habits and ingrained assumptions have driven people away from fandom, about “real sff” or whether such a thing even exists. We have gate-kept, and we have blown gates off their hinges, and begun the cycle anew. We have shamed the “well actually”-s among us and have scolded each other for not listening for expertise where it can actually be found. We want to bring everyone in, no matter where they are in their fandom journey &#8212; and we want to see a certain baseline respect for the genre. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What we don’t talk about enough is a baseline of respect for the habits of mind that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">are</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the genre. For the curiosity that makes her love web serials, and him love sub-Reddit culture, and them love alternate history, and all the points of mental adventure between. We celebrate a family of genres, and yet don’t respect the off knowledge, curiosity, inventiveness, and associative leaps that make them all part of the same intellectual family treat. Whose knowledge, curiosity, inventiveness, and associations do we value? And why can’t the answer be “everyone’s”?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, I’m doing my part.  I’m trying to learn Gundam. Lucky for me, Corwin’s a patient teacher. I’m not sure I’ll thrive in the pursuit the way he did, absorbing all of my nonsense. But I can try. I can show him I appreciate his mastery and be the one doing the listening. It’s a habit we all need to cultivate. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Zeigarnik Finish Line: Tricking Yourself Into Finishing Stuff</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-zeigarnik-finish-line-tricking-yourself-into-finishing-stuff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 12:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you want me to abandon something I’m writing, this conversation is almost guaranteed to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want me to abandon something I’m writing, this conversation is almost guaranteed to do the trick:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>You:</strong> Writing anything interesting lately?</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Me:</strong> Oh, I’ve got a few things I’ve been tinkering with.</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>You:</strong> Okay, could you tell me about one of them? What’s it about?</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Me</strong>: Um, well, it’s sort of like [launches into an awkward three minute x-meets-y pitch, followed by describing a few characters, the arc of the plot, and how I think it’s going].</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>You:</strong> Well, I hope it goes well for you!</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">**</span><b><i>Narrator voice: It will not go well for me.**</i></b></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I can’t pitch my unwritten ideas to you in any meaningful detail (by which I mean “I can’t say anything beyond ‘it’s a dark fantasy novel’ or ‘it’s a near-future sf thing’”) without my brain cache dumping the intent to write, formatting all associated files, and moving along as if the deed were already done. Something about talking through doing a thing triggers the “mission accomplished” wiring of my brain, a psychological trick I’m </span><a href="https://www.petershallard.com/why-telling-people-your-goals-is-a-fatal-mistake/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">apparently not alone in playing on myself</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is especially frustrating in a field defined by creative collaboration, shared enthusiasm, and general entrepreneurship like writing. It’s also bitterly ironic for me, as a teacher of writing. “Talk through your ideas with your critique partners and workshop peers!” I encourage my students, all too aware of how that advice frequently backfires on me.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve wondered if I’m a writing hypocrite, preaching the gospel of transparency, all the while knowing that it only works for me if the whole project is open and collaborative, top to bottom, with others fueling a constant awareness of what actually is done and what needs to be done. Otherwise, talking about </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">things I will do</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> turns into </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">things I’ve done</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Then I have to engage entirely new protocols of self-deception to get back behind the keyboard. Is it fair of me to ask others to do what I know I can’t? Does it present a false version of what it means to work on your writing, and of how I work on my writing, if I can’t follow my own advice?</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_24863" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-24863" style="width: 341px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-24863" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Frodo-It-Is-Finished.jpg" alt="" width="341" height="254" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-24863" class="wp-caption-text">Actual image of my brain when I talk about my works in progress too much</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve tried to untangle this web of irony by picking at technicalities. For instance, I can take a draft, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">show it</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to others to read, get their feedback, and then continue working. That’s never so much the problem. The snare that always catches me is sharing the idea when it’s in its aetherial state, more intention than execution, without a “something” to show for it yet. So, maybe it isn’t unfair of me to ask students to share their works-in-progress with each other, since I can do at least that much.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maybe. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most of the time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After a bit of research, I found the name of the real thing I’m struggling with, a phenomenon psychologists refer to as </span><a href="https://www.mentalhelp.net/stress/the-zeigarnik-effect-and-completing-everything/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the Zeigarnik Effect</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You can read about the Zeigarnik Effect as it applies to daily life yourself in more detail using the previous link, or read into its history </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zeigarnik_effect"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. In essence, experimentation with interrupting people as they complete a task suggests that the human brain is wired to prioritize and focus on unfinished work. You’re less likely to remember the tasks you complete than the task you didn’t </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">quite </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">complete, because that incompleteness nags at you. On the other hand, the more something feels complete, the less priority it takes up in our mental queue because &#8212; quite reasonably &#8212; it no longer feels urgent. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You see where I’m going here. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If talking through a project before it is complete trips my “project complete!” switch, then actually </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">doing</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that project, taking its work seriously: all of that falls to the back of my mental queue. My brain will already have decided it’s not a priority anymore. So the solution is actually simple.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To be a better writer, I need to finish fewer things, and keep more secrets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let me explain.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On its face, a resolution to “finish fewer things” seems no different than the mental cache dump I experience now. But it is. The life-hack some people have adopted through a better understanding of the Zeigarnik Effect is to get work started, and to do it in more stages, specifically because that ongoing incompleteness will force the work to the front of their minds. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A colleague of mine who has also helped coach some of our students through the YWP NaNoWriMo experience likes to advise people to stop writing when they still know what the rest of the scene should contain. Finish your writing session with the moment itself unfinished and you’ll have something to jump back into, he says. I used to preach the opposite approach, urging them to break things up into units they could complete, a kind of checklist. Now it seems my brain has gotten wise to that trick. Tidying up a scene and then tucking the laptop away doesn’t help me jump back into the text the way it used to. Often, it leaves me blank on what to do next when I sit down to write, even if I have an outline to draw off of because (surprise, surprise) the outline </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">also</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> flips my “it is finished!” switch. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Zeigarnik Effect, though, means that if I leave a scene trailing, or a plan only half-written, or whatever else, the sheer, nagging awareness of that unfinished state will keep the work I have yet to do fresh in mind. I’ll mull over how many words I might need to finish the arc up, or what comes next, or consider if the moment needs another beat. Whatever the mulling leads me to, it’s the product of that unfinished state, and it feeds my desire to return. If I don’t have closure &#8212; not even the rounded-up feeling of closure my brain gets from describing where I’m going and how I’ll do it &#8212; then I have a problem. I have unfinished business, and with it, a desire to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">actually</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> make things complete.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24864 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Keep-It-Secret-300x126.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="126" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Keep-It-Secret-300x126.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Keep-It-Secret-768x323.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Keep-It-Secret.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is why I need to get out of the habit of answering questions like “what are you writing now?” with anything beyond a smile and vague tease. I need to keep my secrets if I’m going to keep my writing process safe. It runs counter to so much advice I’ve used in the past &#8212; used, and even used to thrive in. Accountability buddies. Telling people about stories so they’d follow up with me later. Telling people things because that would make them “real.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, the joke’s on me. I’m apparently so powerful, I speak my own ideas out of existence. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So the next time we meet, do us both a favor: don’t ask me what I’m writing. I’m going to have to lie to you, anyway. In fact, you try some gentle deflection, too, the next time someone wants to know about what you haven’t finished. It might just make the difference between whether you reach “The End” or not. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Triggering Townsend: On Writing the Actual Subject</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-triggering-townsend-on-writing-the-actual-subject__trashed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 04:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When it comes to emotional events, I’m notoriously dry-eyed. I don’t get misty at funerals,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to emotional events, I’m notoriously dry-eyed. I don’t get misty at funerals, or weddings, or graduations. I didn’t cry when my kids were born, or when my pets died. It’s not that I’m truly unmoved. I’m often a raging sea of emotions at these moments. It’s more that it doesn’t register in any visible way. Maybe that’s why I’m fascinated by how the human mind links objects or moments that seem so small to much larger, much more profound experiences. Take, for example, the time in the spring of 2018, when my son’s 5th grade music teacher dragged me into a dark alley and pummeled me within an inch of my life.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Emotionally speaking, I mean, though Ms. Spielman is certainly a woman not to be messed with. To this day, if I encounter the trigger that takes me back to the moment she destroyed me, I’ll still dissolve into goo.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The trigger is the song </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CjxugyZCfuw"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This Is Me” from </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Greatest Showman</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_24575" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-24575" style="width: 182px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-24575" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/greatest-showman.jpg" alt="" width="182" height="268" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-24575" class="wp-caption-text">THE GREATEST SHOWMAN movie poster (2017)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the end of 5th grade, on the eve of moving up to middle school, my son and his peers gave a concert directed by their beloved elementary school music teacher. It ended with a finale number not listed in the program &#8212; “This Is Me” &#8212; performed, according to Ms. Spielman, “as a tribute to the wonderful people these children have become and all they have to be proud of.” First I got misty, then weepy, and finally full-on sobby watching Corwin belt the lyrics up on those auditorium risers. He’s not a magnificent singer. It was the principle of the thing. Something about a declaration of courage and pride felt singularly necessary in that moment, especially after the frankly exhausting school year he’d had. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The local Meijer grocery likes to keep “This Is Me” at the top of its canned music rotation. It’s inevitably playing whenever I’m there, which means once every ten days or so I get to be the weird lady sniffling and snuffling in the sliced bread aisle. As you might imagine, that goes over </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">just peachy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with neighboring shoppers in a pandemic. I’ve started doing more curbside pick-up orders just to avoid the song, but it’s (hilariously?) also part of their “call to tell us you’re here!” hold music playlist.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The point isn’t that a show tune has laid me low so much as what this demonstrates about how the human mind works &#8212; and how thinking about this can improve our writing.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_24574" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-24574" style="width: 201px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24574" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Triggering-Town-201x300.png" alt="" width="201" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Triggering-Town-201x300.png 201w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/Triggering-Town.png 334w" sizes="(max-width: 201px) 100vw, 201px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-24574" class="wp-caption-text">Cover of Richard Hugo&#8217;s THE TRIGGERING TOWN</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In his 1979 collection of essays on poetry, </span><a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/articles/69402/the-triggering-town"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Triggering Town</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Richard Hugo writes about how the connection between a poem and its subject is both more complex, and more simple, than it appears. Hugo’s essential thesis across all these essays is that rather than seeking to describe something or “communicate” about it in poetry, a poet should look at the world around them as a source of potential “triggering subjects” &#8212; that is, objects, ideas, images, and words that lead down an associative train that invites speculation and invention. That tulip you see on the first of May, for example, could feature in a poem you write, but it shouldn’t be what your poem is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">about</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, in the sense of being its only object of reflection. Rather, the way the tulip leads you to remember your grandmother’s gardening habit, or her chain-smoking, or maybe even her funeral and how the flowers set around her casket would have been a disappointment to her &#8212; </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">these</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> things are the actual subject, the place your mind should feel compelled to go when you free yourself from the tyranny of literalism and pure description. I talk about Hugo’s theory of the triggering subject and actual subject a lot when teaching my students to write poetry, but it’s also useful for writing fiction or personal essays or, really, just about anything. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hugo’s advice works as a </span><a href="http://www.languageisavirus.com/creative-writing-techniques/free-association-active-imagination-twilight-imaging.php#.YHhN0OhKiLI"><span style="font-weight: 400;">method of brainstorming ideas</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, as a tool for </span><a href="http://mrwildnersenglishwebsite.weebly.com/uploads/1/3/3/8/13380073/poetry_packet.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">revising writing that seems to have only glazed the surface of a moment</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and as a lever for prying open and developing characters. Just as we, as flesh and blood humans, respond to ordinary things in seemingly extraordinary or disproportionate ways, compelling, realistic characters will have their own triggering memories and ways their experience of everyday life interleaves with them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It should be noted that in talking about “triggering memories” </span><a href="https://keck.usc.edu/adolescent-trauma-training-center/treatment-guide/chapter-11-trigger-identification-and-intervention/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don’t think we creatives should immediately assume traumas</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Even in my weeping over show tunes, I’m not weeping out of sadness or pain, exactly (despite my melodramatic lede). I’m weeping out of the powerful sense of my son being </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">seen </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">in those lyrics, and my equally powerful desire for him to feel about himself everything the song proclaims. It’s not a pain trigger, but a love trigger, and though the word “trigger” has been co-opted and proliferated in ways that have diluted its usefulness, we’re talking about a different associative experience, where the wiring of the brain doesn’t necessarily trip on trauma, but on a rhizomatic system of memories, associations, emotions, and musings.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I sometimes do an exercise with my students where I challenge them to walk around campus for awhile and find what I call “unpoemable objects.” By this time, they’re familiar with Hugo’s theory of triggering and actual subjects and have started to dabble with their own poetry. Still, they tend to worry that they’re not “doing it right” when they’re challenged to think about what they’re writing in terms of both surface and substance. The Unpoemble Objects exercise is meant to be fun &#8212; “Find me the worst, most aesthetically empty, most un-moving objects you can find! Take pictures of them, and bring them back here so we can do something weird!” &#8212; and also a lesson in modeling associative thinking. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here’s an example of things students come back with:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Toilet seat</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Not an Exit” sign above door</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Weird stain on carpet</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">An abandoned tennis racket next to a garbage can</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lunch tray with stacked, half-eaten bowls of cereal</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And so on.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once I have the students shout out their absolute worst unpoemables, and I’ve written about ten of them on the board, I tell someone who looks mostly trustworthy to put me on a three minute timer. “In the next three minutes,” I tell them, “I’m going to brainstorm out loud how I’d use each of these objects as a trigger to help build toward an actual subject in a theoretical poem I’m not going to write.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ll tell them about the time I spent struggling to potty-train my kids, or maybe about the year I worked as a janitor in a ritzy health club as I talk about toilet seats and carpet stains. I speculate about what the door that isn’t an exit might actually be &#8212; and I go as deeply science fictional as I can get in thirty seconds. I talk about my father’s failed ambition for me to become a great tennis player, and my fraught relationship with the balls I could only ever seem to serve completely backward, rocketing off behind me in defiance of physics. I riff on my summer morning ritual of cold cereal on the front porch with my grandfather and how I can’t smell corn flakes without also smelling White Owl cigars. It’s a wholesale unpacking of the unexamined corners of my psyche, and &#8212; if I’m doing it right &#8212; a model that shows young writers that there is no hopeless object, no dead end, when you give yourself permission to wriggle free of literal constraints and let your triggered mind take over. It’s an exercise in hope, and imagination, and giving your brain credit for containing multitude because, well. . . it does. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Usually, I don’t quite make it through all ten umpoemable objects, but I get close. My students are kind enough to believe that the effort still counts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The next time you’re not sure what to do with a character that won’t open up to you, or how to make a scene resonate the way you want it to, it may be that you’re thinking too hard about what has to be literally present for something to be compelling. Have you thought about how to chase a small trigger, a little memory, a tiny detail down through a story&#8217;s rabbit holes or into a character’s life? Have you considered what might make them happy-cry in the bakery aisle? Have you considered the poignance, or even the comedy, of the abandoned tennis racket?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It may be that the answer to your next writing block, no matter what you’re writing, lies in something that at first seems unpoemable. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Soon May the Wellerman Come&#8221;: Lived-In Worldbuilding in SFF</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/soon-may-the-wellerman-come-lived-in-worldbuilding-in-sff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24362</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I write this, I am 364 days into my family’s pandemic experience. Tomorrow marks&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As I write this, I am 364 days into my family’s pandemic experience. Tomorrow marks exactly one year since I last saw my students in person, taught in a real classroom, met a friend for lunch, or shopped in a grocery store without a mask. The quarantine began with what my teaching colleagues and I thought would be an extra week of spring break, and then, we’d be back in April.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last month, with the year-mark creeping ever closer, my daughter (who, at nine years old, has now spent just over 10% of her life in varying states of lockdown) got into sea shanties. She was about a month behind the trend, at that point, but don’t blame her. She’s not on TikTok.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We were playing a board game about stuffing fantastical rescued cats on a boat before a maniac comes to attack the cat sanctuary island (yes, </span><a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/281259/isle-cats"><span style="font-weight: 400;">that’s a real thing</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">) and we always listen to music while gaming. “We need boat music,” my husbeast declared and so I found a Spotify playlist.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ten thousand rotations of  </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UgsurPg9Ckw"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The Wellerman”</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/0Oe9AaM9QqMoMf63o05qmi?autoplay=true"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“A Drop of Nelson’s Blood” </span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> later, Deirdre was hooked.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Put aside for a moment that neither of these songs are actually sea shanties (they’re folk songs, and “The Wellerman” in particular is a ballad) and you might find yourself focusing on the phenomenon of the “sea shanty” itself rising to unlikely prominence one long year into lockdown. And, if you suffer the same ailment as me, where nothing can be thought of for even five minutes without thinking of how it relates to storytelling, then you might reach this same conclusion:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 2021 Rise of the Sea Shanty is pretty god-damned amazing worldbuilding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the world of science fiction and fantasy, we sometimes talk about constructing worlds that feel “lived-in.” “Lived-in” is the je ne sais quoi of sff, but it comes down to something like </span><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/verisimilitude"><span style="font-weight: 400;">verisimilitude</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> meets story development. If we call a world “lived-in” we might mean that the world of the story has followed a believable arc. If you put its events and peoples and technologies in context, it “adds up.” It has a history (even if we don’t see it all). And, perhaps most importantly, people in that story world behave as if they know that history, their customs, and so on, throughout the course of the story.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m fascinated by 2021’s obsession with the sea shanty and folk songs of labor and despair inflected with hope because it’s an example of what the people of a lived-in SFnal world might do, if they found themselves in similar circumstances.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These songs are, after all, monuments to hard, often thankless tasks performed either in isolation or with a small, staunch crew stuck in the same circumstances. There’s the question of whether the tides will ever take you home. Whether you’ll see your ma and da again. Whether the world you finally reach when the sailing is done is the one you hoped to arrive at. There’s the tedium of drinking to make the long nights end a bit sooner, the tyranny of a captain who is just as trapped as you, the fickle storms that come around when things are already bad and knock you on your ass just as you’ve picked yourself up. Everything is repetitive, numbing, endless.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.thecut.com/2021/01/sea-shanty-tiktok-whats-the-deal-with-the-shanty-trend.html"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course we got into sea shanties</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-24363 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Wellerman-Tweet-250x300.png" alt="" width="395" height="474" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Wellerman-Tweet-250x300.png 250w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Wellerman-Tweet.png 525w" sizes="(max-width: 395px) 100vw, 395px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And, of course, we got </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">most</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> into the (not quite) shanty </span><a href="https://www.polygon.com/2021/1/12/22226992/tiktok-sea-shanty-wellerman-longest-johns-of-thieves"><span style="font-weight: 400;">that went viral on TikTok</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a whole worldwide crew of people editing themselves into the video, giving their voices to the layers of frustration and hope woven through all our lives. Of course we got most of all into the song that cries out for small comforts and good cheer. The Wellerman supply ship rep was the DoorDasher of his era. There’s something in a song &#8212; a whole body of songs &#8212; about repetitive labor, endless-seeming journeys, solace found in long-distant rewards and far-flung friends &#8212; that speaks to our present moment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fact that we found these songs all over again is an example of deeply lived-in worldbuilding. The current obsession reflects our own awareness that the world goes through cycles of crisis, and that people in crises (private and small or vast and pandemic-shaped) create things as a way to speak their truth about it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Does the SFnal world you’re building have evidence of how its people created art in response to things larger than themselves? Does it have a cultural legacy built up through its art? Does it have protest music? Legends of famous, tragic lovers? Work songs? Famous historical figures and their speeches? Scientists who researched the technologies that define the world? Doctors who treated its maladies? Curse words born of its slang or its bigotry? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The reader doesn’t need to know the origin story behind all of these things (how many people knew before they Googled it what it means for “the tonguing” to be done?). Readers may not need to know </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">anything</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about these histories at all. (For that matter, you probably need to know less than you fear you do, but that’s a whole other article.) But readers do need to have the distinct feeling that the story world </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">has </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">a history and a culture, a body of art and expression both in the present moment and for describing its past. If you can incorporate such things, you have not just a lived-in world, but a new way to deepen narrative motifs, new kinds of epigraphs to add from poets and politicians who do not exist (consider </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/112296-the-broken-earth"><span style="font-weight: 400;">N.K. Jemisin’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Broken Earth</span></i></a> <span style="font-weight: 400;">trilogy for a whole host of these), and new ways to explore cycles of lived experience for the people of your story world. You can empower your characters to speak organically of their world, without pausing for exposition. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Or, if you’re like me with the sea shanties and the cats-stuffed-into-boats game, you get to watch your nine year old expand her vocabulary in surprising ways.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Roll the old chariot along, friends. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We Can Rebuild You: Fanfic and Character Development</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/we-can-rebuild-you-fanfic-and-character-development/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 11:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As John Appel pointed out recently, writer Twitter can be counted on to have a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As John Appel </span><a href="https://twitter.com/oldscout/status/1350598513902673920?s=20"><span style="font-weight: 400;">pointed out recently</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, writer Twitter can be counted on to have a flare up of Bad Takes and Reactions to Bad Takes like the rising and setting of the sun (just with more memes and gifs). One of the most recent takes to garner a lot of attention &#8212; exactly as its author knew it would &#8212; was about fanfiction,</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">which the thread author defined as</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">“a form that actively teaches you to write worse.” (I will spare you a link back to the original thread; a little Google homework should reveal the full argument, in all its snide tones.) This particular flare-up of The Discourse is timely, at least for me. I’m preparing the first weeks of my creative writing workshop course, a class in which I actively encourage students to write and read fanfiction.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_22741" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22741" style="width: 359px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-22741" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Bad-Takes-Tweet-300x203.png" alt="" width="359" height="243" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Bad-Takes-Tweet-300x203.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Bad-Takes-Tweet.png 598w" sizes="(max-width: 359px) 100vw, 359px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22741" class="wp-caption-text">John Appel wants to check the schedule for what the next Bad Take Discourse is, please and thank you.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Writer Twitter has by now come out in force to box the original thread’s ears. The fisticuffs cover all sorts of exasperations about why it’s wrong to say fanfiction “is bad” or “teaches you to write worse.” Why crap on other people’s joy? Why not learn the mechanics of writing a scene or dialogue in this way, the better to use them in your own original work later? Why not celebrate different imaginings of characters and storylines that speak to larger communities? Why not praise a medium that actively draws writers together and may constitute a first workshop experience for many of them? Why insist on categorizing everything as “good” or “bad”? Why pit the literary world against the commercial? Why deny the meta-references, fanservice, and “retellings” rampant in famous texts of the literary world? (Hell, </span><a href="https://geekandsundry.com/6-great-works-of-literature-that-are-actually-fanfiction/#:~:text=Paradise%20Lost%20%E2%80%94%20a%20retelling%20of,some%20of%20its%20blanks%20himself."><span style="font-weight: 400;">I teach </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Paradise Lost</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as biblical fanfic</span></a> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">because it’s true</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.)</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why argue about any of this?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One rhetorical “oh, for f*ck’s sake” rebuttal I haven’t seen yet is the core reason I recommend fanfiction to anyone looking to improve their craft:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Writing fanfic can help you create deeper, more fully realized characters.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, let’s agree on something basic: writing characters is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">hard</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Sure, they’re fun, these imaginary friends and frenemies, but they’re slippery, too, full of potential contradictions and worrisome gaps in backstory. They demand faces, voices, points of view, attitudes. They’re an awful lot of work. For many young writers, they’re the most elusive work of all. Constructing a better understanding of characters by reverse-engineering from what already exists, though, can put the elusive within reach.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the same way that writing fics can help you practice the elements of writing we might otherwise take for granted (“How should I handle a scene transition? What dialogue tags actually work? How do I work description or exposition into this moment? Where’s a good place to end this chapter?”), they can help you explore elements of stories and characters the original creators themselves may have taken for granted. In order to write that </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slash_fiction#:~:text=Slash%20fiction%20(also%20known%20as,characters%20of%20the%20same%20sex."><span style="font-weight: 400;">slash fic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> between two characters who aren’t paired up in canon, you have to understand them well enough to imagine what </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">would</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> make them partners. Even if you skip the whole “how do they end up together?” arc and jump straight to them being together, you have to think about what character traits make them an interesting, successful &#8212; or maybe deeply fraught &#8212; couple. In order to explore a “what if?” story that </span><a href="https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/FixFic"><span style="font-weight: 400;">fix fic&#8217;s</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> something in the core narrative, you need to think about what the characters want, need, are willing to do, are afraid of &#8212; all the emotional baggage that goes into their decisions, and therefore, the consequences of their decisions. You can’t “fix” the story until you understand deeply how we arrived at that moment in the first place and deconstruct it, informed by some other theory of character and plot.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_22742" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22742" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22742" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fanfic1-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fanfic1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fanfic1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fanfic1.jpg 970w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22742" class="wp-caption-text">image copyrighted by American Libraries Magazine</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I tell my students not to be ashamed of their fanfic work, if they have any, and if they don’t have any, to daydream about what they </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">would</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> write. Writing characters and giving them satisfying arcs (not always “happily ever after” stories, but </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">earned </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">stories, satisfying stories) is perhaps the hardest thing to do when you’re a writer. It requires not just building characters from the ground up, but building up the circumstances that will challenge and shape them. By taking a character (or characters) who already have a groundwork to explore, early career writers can think more closely about character motivation, growth, change, and challenge without worrying about whether the basic character design itself “works.” That bedrock can provide the traction needed to take longer, more challenging writing leaps.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rewriting a scene to produce a different outcome requires careful reading and dissection of that scene and the characters in it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A self-insert that interacts with the canon characters can encourage the writer to explore group dynamics and character chemistry.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Friends-to-Lovers or Enemies-to-Lovers-ing characters require a deep understanding of their inner worlds and close thought about what it would take to change them.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.themarysue.com/more-coffee-shop-aus-pls/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A coffeeshop AU</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> might show us who a character is when their guard is down.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A fanfic with </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">no observable conflict at all</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> could be an exercise in perfecting character voice as the canon characters enjoy a night of pizza and witty banter.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every bit of writing you play with &#8212; every idea, every character, every notion &#8212; teaches you something. And, as with most learning, you start with some text or goal or idea outside yourself to work on. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You give yourself something to work toward.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I wish I could say it’s surprising that “let people enjoy writing and learning how to write” has to be argued for, or that another writer would cheerfully dunk on others for believing something so decent and mundane. But, if there’s anything writing reminds us of time and again, it’s that everyone wants an audience. It would be nice if certain writers didn’t decide setting themselves on fire was the best way to get one. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well. Everyone needs a hobby, I guess. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Machine, Stopped</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-machine-stopped/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-machine-stopped/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 11:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Changing the content of the courses I teach is normal, as ordinary as grading papers.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Changing the content of the courses I teach is normal, as ordinary as grading papers. Some semesters, I do it radically, overhauling the whole ship from stem to stern. Other times, I tweak the syllabus, change some assessments, maybe try out a new grading policy. Without fail, I end up changing at least some of the texts we read. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The reasons for adding or dropping readings range from the quotidian to the philosophical. I’ve realized I assigned too much and need to cut back. Or, a text bounces off students and I can’t find a way to make it stick. Selfishly, I might just long for something new. And, sometimes, my understanding of something critical about a text changes &#8212; I come to recognize problems that might be more harmful to students than would be empowering and useful to deconstruct. Those judgment calls are always tricky. I never expected to have to make one because, in a science fiction and fantasy course, the readings had suddenly become </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">too true</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_22536" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22536" style="width: 220px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-22536" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/James-Tiptree-Jr-1-220x169-1.jpg" alt="" width="220" height="169" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22536" class="wp-caption-text">Alice Sheldon (aka James Tiptree, Jr.)</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In February in 2020, I was more giddy than I had been in years to assign my students </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">James Tiptree Jr.’</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">s <a href="https://www.lightspeedmagazine.com/fiction/last-flight-doctor-ain/">“The Last Flight of Dr. Ain.”</a> It’s a reconstruction-of-the-crime narrative following the movements of the titular character, a biologist we realize by the end has been jet-setting a circuitous path to a scientific conference in order to expose himself to as many people as possible. Ain is Patient Zero in a viral pandemic cooked up in his own lab. An ecological terrorist, Dr. Ain has designed a “leukemia virus” that transmissible by all warm-blooded creatures, fatal to all higher-order primates, and armed with a 90% recovery rate for all other species. It’s a biological superweapon designed to cleanse the earth of its human blight. And somehow, “The Last Flight of Dr. Ain” is also a love story, one man’s retribution for the sake of the planet. The reader watches, powerless, seeing every step of his plot to ensure human destruction. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oh, and because he’s thorough, Ain feeds birds on his layovers. Because birds are warm-blooded.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tiptree’s story reconstructs how Ain got away with it &#8212; how he revealed his plan to the world, when it was already far too late to stop him. How, even after he was captured, no one understood well enough what he had done and how powerful it was, because the police  let him feed birds in the park in between legs of goose-stepping him back home to face legal consequences that don’t matter anymore. With the virus needing just three days of incubation and less than three weeks to achieve fatality, everyone is already done for. Through ignorance of the meaning of their choice and misplaced empathy, </span><a href="https://www.charlotteobserver.com/news/local/article25394389.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the police help Ain become the Dylann Roof of specicide</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was excited to share this story at the end of February 2020 because coverage of COVID-19 had just started to penetrate the daily news cycle. About half of my students had heard of it. A few had talked about it in their bio classes. Some had relatives in China, sharing their own firsthand experience with a pandemic the rest of the world had yet to see. I teased them gleefully, playfully about this literary viral apocalypse and its mournful, existential vibe. They chuckled along with me &#8212; a little tensely sometimes, but that’s what Tiptree’s writing makes you do.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Two weeks later, our school transformed from a residential academy to fully remote learning. Students scattered back to their homes across the state, on lockdown until (we thought) March 31. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We thought wrong, of course. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve been in fully remote teaching and learning since then, ending one year and beginning another with software and hardware bridging the gap between us. Over the summer, one of the students from my speculative fiction class wrote me a lovely thank-you email and mentioned offhandedly thinking about “The Last Flight of Dr. Ain” a lot since February. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve thought about it a lot, too. Mostly, I’ve wondered if I was wrong to teach it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Medical doctors (we are at a time where, apparently, </span><a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/is-there-a-doctor-in-the-white-house-not-if-you-need-an-m-d-11607727380"><span style="font-weight: 400;">it is especially important to some to specify medical doctoral achievement over other doctoral achievements</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">) take the </span><a href="https://www.medicinenet.com/hippocratic_oath/definition.htm"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hippocratic oath</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, so often cited in cultural shorthand as the vow to “do no harm.” Teachers don’t have a formal, equivalent oath. If we did, it might be, “We recognize that learning is challenging, and sometimes challenge is painful, but we must not create pain out of malice, indifference, or by design.” I’m not entirely sure that in assigning “The Last Flight of Dr. Ain” &#8212; doing it because I was </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">specifically excited </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">to point out its eerie relevance to the present moment and the fears surrounding it &#8212;  that I didn’t do my students some disservice or harm.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the pandemic, few people have been more disempowered and disenfranchised than students. Whether learning fully in person, in a hybrid environment, or fully remote, students are largely subject to policies designed by adults, policies into which they have limited (likely zero) input. The pandemic teacher takes on a keen importance in students’ lives. Especially for students in fully remote learning environments, like the one I’ve been working in since March, teachers have the power to dictate the circumstances under which they “see” their classroom peers (Cameras mandated, or no? Breakout rooms? Synchronous or asynchronous work? Group projects, or solo work?). Teachers stage students’ conversations, create the questions they are supposed to process together, and often dictate what happens as a result of that processing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However timely, maybe prescient, elements of Tiptree’s story was, with another semester of remote learning about to begin &#8212; one in which I know from the start my students will see me through Zoom and interact with me through email, and Canvas, and a chat room, all because of a real pandemic and a woefully uneven national and global response to it &#8212; can I justify prodding that wound by assigning it?</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_22535" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22535" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22535" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/The-Machine-Stops-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/The-Machine-Stops-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/The-Machine-Stops.jpg 333w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22535" class="wp-caption-text">Cover for ebook version of Forster&#8217;s &#8220;The Machine Stops&#8221;</figcaption></figure>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The problem doesn’t stop there, of course. A colleague in my department asked if I would be teaching </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Machine_Stops#:~:text=9%20External%20links-,Plot%20summary,by%20the%20omnipotent%2C%20global%20Machine."><span style="font-weight: 400;">E.M. Forster’s “The Machine Stops”</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> this spring. I often do. “I want to see you not through the Machine . . . I want to speak to you not through the wearisome Machine,” he noted, was a line of particular poignance under our present circumstances. He planned to reference it at the start of his Digital Literary Studies class.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And it </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">a striking bit of dialogue. Kuno’s agonized desire to relate to his mother &#8212; to anyone &#8212; without technology as a mediator is the same yearning I see in my students when they end classes, almost on reflex, by waving at the screen, or typing “*hugs!*” into the chat. Given that my students’ normal isn’t just </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">going </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">to school, but literally living there for weeks and months at a time, to be separated from their roommates, wing mates, study partners, “big sisters” and “big brothers,” residence life counselors, and &#8212; yes &#8212; even their teachers is more than just painful. It’s an amputation of a limb holding up their collective identity. Zoom, and Google Hangouts, and Facebook chats, and Discord, and Slack offer ill-fitted prostheses, one-size-fits-some solutions not designed for how this wound has hobbled each student differently. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the one hand, academics teach texts that confront difficult issues because in confronting them with our students, we hope to create deeper understanding. Perhaps useful reflection will follow that confrontation, or even the ideas needed to chart a solution. When the solution isn’t there, we hope that dismantling our assumptions surrounding it by confronting the problem head-on will offer its own compensation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And, sometimes, the confrontation is that and nothing more: an assault on the reader. The pain or the problem doesn’t change just by being held up in class. Our </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">understanding</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of it doesn’t magically change. Often, living through such problems has already taught a student more than a dramatization of them could. I’m used to weighing the difficulty of such confrontations, calculating the cost-benefit to the best of my ability, in matters of race, sex, gender, ableism, violence.  . .</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am not used to struggling with the question, “Has this science fiction become too real to be instructive?”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In “The Machine Stops,” Kuno escapes the Machine because he’s willing to accept the possibility of his own destruction in the world “outside.” He is recaptured and forced to endure the Machine’s slow, steady decline and deterioration, knowing that there was a world beyond the Machine that a system much larger than himself forbade him to touch. Finally, he and his mother perish, realizing together that accepting and connecting to the natural world should have been their highest value all along, rather than surrendering themselves to be dependent on the Machine. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is it ethical to suggest to my students that they should reject “the Machine” circumstance has thrust them into, when public safety demands that we endure it? Is it fair to tease them with this eco-libertarian vision when I am part of the very system that confines them, part of “the wearisome Machine” myself?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s possible that this reading experience could plunge my students into a deeper reflection on the costs of the pandemic. But I would be fooling myself if I claimed they haven’t had these thoughts already. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And yet, reading is an outlet for empathy, and for recognizing oneself and others. Would it help them to see themselves in Kuno? To see themselves in his technology-dependent mother, Vashti? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Or would it just grind salt into that wound? Would it be another scary bedtime story, another Tiptree triumph for me to regret, apt in the moment but without much to offer beyond “I guess we have to trust the Machine, for now, despite feeling its harm firsthand”? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Would the story </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">actually help</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is no Hippocratic oath of teaching, but at times like this,  I wish there was one. I’m out of answers. Like a good science fictionally-minded person, all I have left are questions.   </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-machine-stopped/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Avengers, Assemble!:  Reading Teams &#038; NaNoWriMo Revisions</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/avengers-assemble-reading-teams-nanowrimo-revisions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tracy Townsend]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 12:54:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Place Where It Rains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’re a first-time NaNoWriMo author (or second, or third, or beyond), you’ve probably heard&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re a first-time NaNoWriMo author (or second, or third, or beyond), you’ve probably heard a dozen versions of the “why you shouldn’t send your manuscript out to agents or publishers in December” argument. Regrettably, relatively few of these arguments actually follow up with advice about how to make that NaNo baby a fully-fledged, ready-for-the-world manuscript. Most encourage you to complete your story, sit back from it for a few weeks, then return to edit and polish. Some go a bit farther, though not much. “Share your work with other writers” isn’t a bad starting place, but it presumes you know where to find other writers. “Get feedback from friends” is another take, but it assumes you know how to make the best use of those friends </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">without</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> them feeling as if they’re being used.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, here’s the post-NaNo article you’ve perhaps been needing: the one that assumes you </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">will </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">step back from your November panic-child, come back to it with clear(ish) eyes, do the work needed to complete its story, and even do a pass of your own edits before sharing that work with others. Doing all of those things won’t guarantee success, but it will help you make much better use of those reading and writing friends so many other advice-givers urge you to find. And that gets us to the focus of this article:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“How do I get help revising my NaNo writing and still have friends at the end?”</span></p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">1. Recognize different friends function best in different roles.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most of us collect friends who are a mix of complementary and contradictory qualities. Loud friends, quiet friends, contemplative friends, spontaneous friends, friends within and across various hobbies and fandoms. Similarly, we tend to collect friends with differing skill sets. As a writer, you can make this social variety pack useful. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consider which friends might be good as </span><a href="https://thewritepractice.com/beta-readers-can-revolutionize-writing/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">beta readers</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (people who give your book a first read and offer up reactions from their perspective as a reader) and which might be better as </span><a href="https://www.well-storied.com/blog/finding-your-ideal-critique-partner#:~:text=A%20critique%20partner%20is%20a,little%20critical%20feedback%20during%20edits."><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">critique partners</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (also called “CPs,” fellow writers who can exchange work with you and offer constructive criticism using their skills and experiences writing). Betas are great at helping you get outside of your own love of your writing and your worries over craft and style, instead focusing on the needs of your reader. CPs are great at taking those gut-level experiences and translating them back into craft and technique. Combining beta readers with CPs helps me maintain a balanced perspective on my work and get answers to a wider range of questions about what to do in my next editing pass.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Similarly, consider which friends might have knowledge that directly influences the work you’re doing. Someone with experience handling firearms in a military setting would be a good choice for combat scenes in a modern, militaristic context. Someone with knowledge of anthropology or history might be a good reference for writing that plays with world-building or alt-history. Or, someone who has read widely in your genre might help you spot tropes you’re using well, and ones that are holding you back. </span></p>
<figure id="attachment_22152" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22152" style="width: 323px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-22152" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/wendig-writer-graphic-190x300.jpg" alt="" width="323" height="510" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/wendig-writer-graphic-190x300.jpg 190w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/wendig-writer-graphic.jpg 647w" sizes="(max-width: 323px) 100vw, 323px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22152" class="wp-caption-text">In case calling yourself a writer or author is making you nervous, take some advice from Chuck Wendig</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2. Guide your readers with useful questions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No matter who comprises your revision reading team, they’ll need guidance about what you really want. Unless you’re handing your manuscript off to a beta reader for a blank-slate reaction, “Read this and tell me what you think” probably isn’t enough to help you, or them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Especially in the case of CPs, you should formulate questions relevant to your concerns about the manuscript. Staggering reads so that you start with beta reader friends who give you their raw reactions, then using their thinking to help you form questions for CPs can be a great strategy. No matter how you choose to sequence readings or recruit folks for feedback, though, remember: the more specific your questions are, the more likely you’ll get actionable feedback. “Is this good?” is a binary, and often uselessly subjective (even more than most things about writing are subjective). But “How can I make certain elements of my story less cliche?” is much more precise and, hopefully, likelier to get you where you really want to go.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">3. Establish reasonable parameters for feedback.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This doesn’t mean you dictate the precise terms in which people respond to your writing (“You may address me as sir, reader!”). There’s no need for a Google Form, a rubric, or a set of conversational ground rules. But you should think about how best to accommodate both your needs and the needs of your reader.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Timeliness: If you’re asking for someone to give you feedback on an adult novel-length manuscript, that’s a heavy lift. Assume they’ll need </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">at least</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a month to do this, probably more. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Format: Some betas and CPs like to work off electronic documents and do in-line feedback. Some will write up an email with their thoughts, or will ask for a printed copy they can scrawl on and send back to you. Remember, you’re asking for help from them, and so, unless there’s a reason you physically cannot take feedback in a certain way, or provide your manuscript in a certain format, you should be prepared to accommodate your friend.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Scope: Some betas get awfully excited about their role and may start offering CP-style feedback about how to fix things. On the one hand, you might recall here </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/477087-remember-when-people-tell-you-something-s-wrong-or-doesn-t-work#:~:text=%E2%80%9CRemember%3A%20when%20people%20tell%20you%20something's%20wrong%20or%20doesn',they%20are%20almost%20always%20wrong.%E2%80%9D"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Neil Gaiman’s famous maxim</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about when readers tell you things are wrong, then tell you how to fix it. On the other, it’s entirely possible that this beta reader really has a good idea you can work with. It’s also possible that a CP might under-advise in terms of “how” to fix certain things in a manuscript, focusing more on what works or doesn’t work for them. That, too, can be useful, so if the scope of a reader’s feedback is different than you expected, you might need to be generous and think about the fourth directive, below. . .</span></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">4. Accept feedback with grace.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This may be the hardest bit of all.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maybe one of your readers roasts something in your story you’re really proud of. Maybe someone encourages you to add something you’re not comfortable with. Maybe some comments hit a little close to home, or suggests that your work wasn’t read as closely as you would’ve liked. Maybe a reader’s comments indicate some set of biases you find genuinely worrisome &#8212; things about them you hadn’t noticed before, or had tried to ignore.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take a breath and think about how to accept these comments with grace.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, you should understand that accepting feedback with grace </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">does not mean</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> you need to take suggestions that are destructive to your work or your sense of self and adopt them into your writing. It doesn’t mean you have to pretend that worrisome or hurtful things weren’t said and just move on. What it means is you need to think about the right time and place to </span><a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.ca/marcia-sirota/how-to-talk-to-your-frien_b_974629.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;">have a conversation about this feedback &#8212; or even consider that a conversation might not help</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are some things you might say when something about the feedback you’ve been given is just plain off:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Thanks for taking the time to read this. I really appreciate your perspective.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I had not considered this idea before.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“You’ve given me a lot to chew on here. Do you mind if I come back to you with questions later?”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you see the pattern in these responses? Each of them acknowledges something factual and clear, and (in the case of the last one) leaves the possibility of further civil discourse open.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another version of accepting feedback with grace is to let comments that trouble you go (perhaps temporarily) and not revisit them as part of a discussion of your work. That doesn’t mean if something toxic, racist, sexist, ableist, or otherwise concerning emerges that you have to pretend you never saw it. But it does mean that the conversation you might want to have with your friend should occur separate from discussions of your writing. Otherwise, your feelings may be discounted as a product of your attachment to your work rather than considered as part of a larger and much more important conversation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Accepting feedback with grace doesn’t mean running away from or ignoring what hurt you. It means putting it in its proper context, and proceeding from there.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">5. Remember, when it comes to CPs, what goes around comes around.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Beta readers usually engage with your writing because they’re friends, without needing more prompting or persuasion. (Though you really should consider DoorDashing them a pizza or sending a gift card to thank them for their time.) Critique partners, on the other hand, get that label because the relationship is assumed to be reciprocal. If they read your weird, malformed word baby today, (eventually) you’ve got to read theirs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes, this agreement is made on the spot: your CP has a manuscript ready for action, too, and so you read one another’s work simultaneously. Other times, there’s an understanding that if they read for you now, you should expect to hear from them later. It may seem rude or awkward to bring this topic up directly, but really, you should. Demonstrate that you value your CP’s time by being up-front with how you’re prepared to spend yours: when you are available, about how fast you can read, the kind of work you feel you’re most helpful reading, and so on. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I tend to be extremely streaky in my own CP reading duties. I don’t send things for review often, but when I do, they tend to be massive, and that means the reading requires a lot of payback from me. My CPs are more prolific writers than I am, and faster, too, so I tend to end up reading every other project they put out, or read stages of those projects: the synopsis and query or outline for one, a first draft for the other, but maybe not a final draft for either. Often, my CP-ness comes out through email exchanges and phone calls where we brainstorm writing issues together rather than strictly read and critique manuscripts. Whatever your case may be, it’s important that you find a way to give back to your CPs in a way they value, even if it’s not always reading 70,000 words on their behalf twice a year. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I wish you a happy PerNoWriMo (Personal Not Writing Month &#8212; get some rest now, wouldja?) and a triumphant return for revisions in January. Who knows? You may even be ready to use this advice to recruit your own critique crew by the spring.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maybe. Nobody says you have to rush it. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
