<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Write Space &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-write-space/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 20:19:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Setting the Write Goals</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/setting-the-write-goals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katrina Schroeder]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 10:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Write Space]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This probably already sounds obvious, but setting actionable writing goals will help you get closer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This probably already sounds obvious, but setting actionable writing goals will help you get closer to your writing dream. These goals can be anything from 500 words a day to 5,000 words a week to “I will have a completed manuscript in six months.” Some writers I know well set a goal of “I will write one hour a day.” This way they account for those inevitable days of writer’s block. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28362 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/isaac-smith-8XlMU62ii8I-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/isaac-smith-8XlMU62ii8I-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/isaac-smith-8XlMU62ii8I-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/isaac-smith-8XlMU62ii8I-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/isaac-smith-8XlMU62ii8I-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/isaac-smith-8XlMU62ii8I-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />But something to keep in mind is that you’ll want these goals to be SMART. Why did I do that in all caps, you ask? Because this is an acronym. I stole this tool from my business management days, and I find it really useful in other aspects of my life. Especially my writing life and as a coaching tool. Let’s break it down. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">S &#8211; This stands for “Specific.” This means your goal can’t be vague. Nothing like “I’m going to write a story.” If you’re not sure how to make it specific, think about everything that needs to be involved. Consider not only what</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">you’re trying to do, but also why it’s important to you, and what you need in order to get there. What kind of story do you want to write? What tools do you need? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">M &#8211; This stands for “Measurable.” You need to set an indicator of success. How will you determine that you’ve written that story? Is it a short story that needs to be under 10,000 words? You need a scale of measurement that shows you’ve accomplished your goal. This means you’ll need to track your progress as well. Check in regularly to see where you are. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A &#8211; This stands for “Attainable” or “Achievable.” This goal needs to be something you can do. You want to be ambitious with your goal-setting, but not so ambitious you can’t actually achieve it. Otherwise, you’re immediately setting yourself up for failure. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">R &#8211; This stands for “Relatable.” This means that your goal needs to be relatable to your bigger goal. If your big, hairy, audacious goal (or a BHAG, pronounced “bee-hag”) is to be a published author, then you want your smaller goals to be related to that. Consider what action steps you need to take to reach your BHAG. If you want to be a published author, some of those goals will need to include writing a query letter and submitting to agents. I’ve also seen variants of there where people use “Realistic” instead of relatable. Pick which works best for you and your BHAG. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">T &#8211; This stands for “Time-bound.” You need to set a due date or end date for your goal. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">When</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> will you have your story written by? This sets a deadline for you and helps hold you accountable and keeps you on track. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1-SvuFIQjK8"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here’s a nice video that breaks it down visually for you if you’re that kind of learner! </span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28363 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/s-o-c-i-a-l-c-u-t-6iYb1BWWbV0-unsplash-300x205.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="205" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/s-o-c-i-a-l-c-u-t-6iYb1BWWbV0-unsplash-300x205.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/s-o-c-i-a-l-c-u-t-6iYb1BWWbV0-unsplash-1024x700.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/s-o-c-i-a-l-c-u-t-6iYb1BWWbV0-unsplash-768x525.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/s-o-c-i-a-l-c-u-t-6iYb1BWWbV0-unsplash-1536x1050.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/s-o-c-i-a-l-c-u-t-6iYb1BWWbV0-unsplash-2048x1400.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Setting SMART goals will help you stick to your writing plan. If you’re a daily journaler, schedule time into your days or weeks to work towards your goal. Add it to your Habit Tracker!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Earlier I mentioned something called a BHAG, or a big, hairy, audacious goal. This is the big kahuna, the big dream you’re working towards. Set your sights here and then make your SMART goals smaller, so they help you reach your big goal. By breaking it down into manageable pieces, you’re far more likely stay on top of it and make some progress. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I recommend that your first goal should be “Determine my one BHAG and my five SMART goals by ten o’clock tonight.” You got this!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Do You Write?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/why-do-you-write-pending-review/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katrina Schroeder]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 10:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Write Space]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28129</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every writer has a story to tell. This is why they write. J.R.R. Tolkien’s Lord&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every writer has a story to tell. This is why they write. J.R.R. Tolkien’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lord of the Rings</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a great example of this. His adventure is filled with his experiences as a child and the war. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But what&#8217;s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">your</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> particular story? What&#8217;s the driving force behind your deep urge to put pen to paper (or fingers to keyboard nowadays)? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28131 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/erik-mclean-f1CFb_Ek-is-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="pixar's wall-e" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/erik-mclean-f1CFb_Ek-is-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/erik-mclean-f1CFb_Ek-is-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/erik-mclean-f1CFb_Ek-is-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/erik-mclean-f1CFb_Ek-is-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/erik-mclean-f1CFb_Ek-is-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Something I’ve been thinking about and reading about often lately is Pixar’s storytelling process. Honestly, as I was walking out of the theater after seeing Lightyear, I was stunned. They’ve </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">really</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> mastered proper storytelling. How do they do it? And every time? There’s a formula and they follow it to a T. What makes their stories truly compelling are their characters. But what’s the driving force behind these characters you quickly learn to love? How do they do it? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I’ve started reading and researching and eventually came across </span><a href="https://www.aerogrammestudio.com/2013/03/07/pixars-22-rules-of-storytelling"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pixar’s 22 Rules of Storytelling</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. (Also, check out </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Creativity, Inc. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">by Edwin Catmull</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">if you haven’t already). And their 14th rule? “Why must you tell THIS story? What’s the belief burning within you that your story feeds off of? That’s the heart of it.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">WOW. Yeah, you’re right, Pixar. That IS the heart of storytelling. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What’s your why? We’ve all seen Simon Sinek’s TedTalk, but if you haven’t, <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/simon_sinek_how_great_leaders_inspire_action/transcript?language=en">I’ll leave it right here for you.</a> You can–and should–apply this to your creative writing as well. In a nutshell, we all know our whats and hows. How are you writing? Cool, paper or laptop. What are you writing? Yes, I can’t stop writing dragon stories. But what about your why? </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> you’re writing is where the passion and the heart comes in. Readers react to the emotion of your story and how it makes them feel. Words alone don’t drive their love for your story. It’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">why</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> you write your story, because your soul just pours out onto the page.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28136 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mika-baumeister-LaqL8nxiacc-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mika-baumeister-LaqL8nxiacc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mika-baumeister-LaqL8nxiacc-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mika-baumeister-LaqL8nxiacc-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mika-baumeister-LaqL8nxiacc-unsplash-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/mika-baumeister-LaqL8nxiacc-unsplash-2048x1368.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I encourage you to start thinking about your why. If you’re not quite sure, start asking yourself more questions. What prompted this idea? Was it something someone said or a cool thought experiment? Then ask, why is it compelling to you? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why does this story haunt you? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I recently just started working with a new author and when I asked her why she felt she needed to tell this particular science fiction story, she thought for a second and then proceeded to tell me about a really important and meaningful time in her life. Reflecting on that time, she realized that this small story idea now had essence. She found it easier to outline and to write. There is now an authenticity to her writing that wasn’t there before.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Understanding the why behind your story means you can start to consider what specifically makes you feel passionate about it. When you understand the nuances of your why, not only will your story be easier for you to tell, but your readers can start to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">feel</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the heart and soul you’re putting into it. Once you know your why, you can start considering your whats and hows.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s Only the Beginning</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/its-only-the-beginning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Katrina Schroeder]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 10:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Write Space]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At its core, story is about change. You can’t have a compelling story without change&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27793 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/etienne-girardet-EP6_VZhzXM8-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/etienne-girardet-EP6_VZhzXM8-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/etienne-girardet-EP6_VZhzXM8-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/etienne-girardet-EP6_VZhzXM8-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/etienne-girardet-EP6_VZhzXM8-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/etienne-girardet-EP6_VZhzXM8-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At its core, story is about change. You can’t have a compelling story without change or a transition to a new status quo. No one reads a book because the character stays the same or nothing happens to them. We read books because we need an escape, want to see the world from a different perspective, or even “experience” something different without having to actually go through the risks or challenges ourselves. But in order to make the change or challenge interesting or impactful, we first need to see the protagonist in their day-to-day life. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s important to have a snapshot of life for your protagonist before change happens–before your inciting incident. This allows the reader to spend a little time with your hero before their life goes off the rails. They get to understand your main character, how they handle the day to day, and whether or not this is someone the reader can live with for the remainder of your story. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jessica Brody, in </span><a href="https://www.jessicabrody.com/books/non-fiction/save-cat-writes-novel/about/"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Save the Cat! Writes a Novel</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, calls this the Opening Image. In your Opening Image, you’re setting your readers’ expectations for the rest of your story. Show us what life is like before you create the change that will push your protagonist off their usual path. Use this time to show us their internal conflict before throwing in an external conflict. What keeps them up at night? What are their needs, goals, or motivations? Where are they currently in their lives? And by that I don’t mean location–where are they mentally and emotionally? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Check out this video about Opening Shots in movies. It’s centered around filmmaking, but this applies to all storytelling in general. </span></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Opening Shots Tell Us Everything" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CZhFtd1QZWc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The start of your story needs to show us not only what normal life is like for your character, but also what their current struggles or goals are. But keep in mind, you need to show us, not tell us. Don’t tell us your protagonist is struggling with her confidence. “Cassandra felt unsure of herself.” Show us how she’s struggling. “Cassandra wrung her hands and looked down as she tried to find the right words to say.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In </span><a href="http://wiredforstory.com/wired-for-story"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wired for Story</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Lisa Cron says that a story “is how what happens affects someone who is trying to achieve what turns out to be a difficult goal, and how he or she changes as a result.” As readers, we want to see how our heroine will change and grow for the better, or you know, fall deeper into their internal conflict. How does she handle the change or the problem that is your inciting incident that causes her to change herself? <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27795 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/suzanne-d-williams-VMKBFR6r_jg-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/suzanne-d-williams-VMKBFR6r_jg-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/suzanne-d-williams-VMKBFR6r_jg-unsplash-1024x680.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/suzanne-d-williams-VMKBFR6r_jg-unsplash-768x510.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/suzanne-d-williams-VMKBFR6r_jg-unsplash-1536x1020.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/suzanne-d-williams-VMKBFR6r_jg-unsplash-2048x1360.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s look at an example. In </span><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/27712.The_Neverending_Story"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Neverending Story</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, our first chapter follows Bastian as he’s running inside a bookstore. The bookstore owner questions him, eventually finding out that Bastian is running away and hiding from other kids who are bullying him. During this scene, we learn that Bastian is a young boy, he’s bullied regularly, and that he’s weak and frightened, even though he doesn’t want to be. This one scene provides us with a quick look at Bastian’s every day life while showing us his internal conflict. We get an idea that this story is going to be about how he grows courageous, more confident in himself, and better able to handle and control his fear. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To summarize, stories are about change, so it’s key that we understand what normal is for your character so that the change is far more impactful and compelling. And if you’re a writer who’s anything like me, I like to make my characters suffer before they grow!</span></p>
<p>Want to buy the books discussed in this post? <a href="https://bookshop.org/lists/luna-station-quarterly">Support local bookstores by buying here</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
