<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 048 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-048/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 14:52:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 048 Author Interview: Jen Mierisch and &#8220;Jane and the Crows&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-jen-mierisch-and-jane-and-the-crows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 11:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 048]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;ve reached our final Issue 048 author interview, and what a journey it&#8217;s been! Our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;ve reached our final <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-048/">Issue 048</a> author interview, and what a journey it&#8217;s been! Our authors have told us so much about their inspirations and writing processes, and now Jen Mierisch is here to send us off with the answers to our questions about &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/jane-and-the-crows/">Jane and the Crows</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: “Jane and the Crows” has the feel of a folktale, where magic and crows are part of<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27011 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-1-300x201.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="201" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-1-300x201.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-1-1024x686.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-1-768x514.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-1-1536x1028.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-1-2048x1371.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> the everyday world. How did you decide to set a story here, in this beautifully rendered place?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jen: <span id="m_-2856052626587318683ydpe63e4decyiv9823577836gmail-docs-internal-guid-69c9640a-7fff-e1eb-4c3c-4b201b5d5fa5">This story sprang from a writing contest where I had to write a sequel to a fairy tale called &#8220;<a href="https://fairytalez.com/the-crows/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://fairytalez.com/the-crows/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1645852611502000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1ZZV6BRwKC4RGSZjzyjAKP">The Crows</a>.&#8221; I had never read that tale before, but there was something intriguing about the man&#8217;s mysterious past, his wild dreams, and of course, the fateful crows. Jane didn&#8217;t get much of a role in the original story, so I decided she needed to star in the sequel. My first draft of the story bombed in the contest, but I went back and revised and added to it over the years.</span></p>
<div dir="ltr">I love fairy tales and folktales. It&#8217;s always fun to read the old Grimm&#8217;s Fairy Tales&#8211;their simple morality and classic characters are satisfying, and they&#8217;re always more gruesome than I remember. I love how brief they are, wrapping up everything neatly in a little package, like a sitcom, but with lots more witches and talking animals and revenge.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Jane knows that something is wrong between her dreams and the crows waiting for her on the widow’s walk, but not how to fix it. What trepidation did she feel before going to the old woman?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">Jen: I think she must have been pretty nervous, but she went anyway because she was desperate. When nothing rational can explain away your troubles, time to consult the wisewoman! I imagined this tale to be set, like most fairy tales, hundreds of years ago, before machines, when any scientific advance might have seemed like sorcery. Surely many &#8220;wisewomen&#8221; were simply skilled in herbal medicine, but it&#8217;s fun to imagine that some of them knew a thing or two about magic as well.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: John’s downfall seems not that he drank the potion, but that he didn’t take care of the families afterwards. Tell us more about the plotline of payment and retribution in your story.</strong></em></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">Jen: If there&#8217;s one thing fairy tales are great at, it&#8217;s showing how choices have consequences. In this story, I definitely wanted to imply that the Moroccan merchant felt cheated by the extended days of price haggling, so he deliberately gave John a potion that would make him hallucinate. But then it had horrifying results, which left John so disturbed that he lied about what he&#8217;d done. So the crewmen lost not only their lives, but also the ability to have the true nature of their death be known. John could have redressed one of his crimes, by telling the truth later, but he chose not to, and so the crew came back as crows and haunted him until his death (and haunted his widow after his death). In the original &#8220;Crows&#8221; story, John drops dead very suddenly; I pictured his secret eating away at him until his tormented heart collapsed.</div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Jane didn’t take any gold for herself. Was this at all important for her future happiness? Also, is there anything else you would like to share about this story or your current writing?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">Jen: If I were Jane, having finally heard her husband&#8217;s story, I&#8217;d be thoroughly spooked, and very motivated to make sure the gold got distributed as fairly as possible <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />  Jane didn&#8217;t really need the gold herself, since, having married a merchant, she already had a house and was well taken care of. What she really needed was to discover the truth and break the curse, after which she was free to move on with her own life. So, even though she didn&#8217;t bring the haunting onto herself, she used her own agency to seek answers and to remedy past wrongs, making her the hero of the tale.</p>
<div dir="ltr"></div>
<div dir="ltr">If you liked this tale, I have another fairy tale up at Fudoki Magazine called &#8220;<a href="https://fudokimagazine.com/the-clever-chef/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://fudokimagazine.com/the-clever-chef/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1645852611502000&amp;usg=AOvVaw3VBKzK5L7KTlxUIYKUBSTf">The Clever Chef</a>&#8220;! Thanks for reading!</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 048 Author Interview: Jenna Hanan Moore and &#8220;Birds of a Feather&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-jenna-hanan-moore-and-birds-of-a-feather/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 19:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 048]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26984</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When was the last time you stopped to take note of the emu at your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When was the last time you stopped to take note of the emu at your local coffee shop? If your answer is &#8220;never,&#8221; then please let <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-048/">Issue 048</a> author Jenna Hanan Moore enlighten you to the magic of noticing the small wonders in life, such as in her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/birds-of-a-feather/">Birds of a Feather</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story was delightfully quirky! Tell us about the origins of this story.  Is there a parallel with emerging from lockdown?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26995 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/rajyavardhan-singh-aQ3ZJFULvAA-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/rajyavardhan-singh-aQ3ZJFULvAA-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/rajyavardhan-singh-aQ3ZJFULvAA-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/rajyavardhan-singh-aQ3ZJFULvAA-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/rajyavardhan-singh-aQ3ZJFULvAA-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/rajyavardhan-singh-aQ3ZJFULvAA-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/rajyavardhan-singh-aQ3ZJFULvAA-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Jenna: Thank you so much. The story originated from a writing prompt: imagine an animal sitting in a coffee shop sipping a coffee and no one else notices. I imagined the scene taking place in a real coffee shop in my neighborhood, and a funny thing happened: the characters did what real people do in real life. That includes being desperate to be back out around people, and then being too busy or too wrapped up in what we’re doing to take the chance to make a connection. It also includes overlooking the interesting things that are all around us if we’d pay a bit more attention. I’m often guilty of both of those things. When I wrote the first draft of that first scene, emerging from lockdown was itself a bit of a fantasy. As badly as I wanted to be able to sit inside my favorite coffee shop, the thing is, when I can do that, I usually sit alone or with my husband reading the morning paper.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What did the birds symbolize, if anything? Are there emus and peacocks everywhere, if we but stop for a moment and pay attention?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Jenna: I didn’t intend them to be symbols, but yes, I wanted to show that there are all kinds of wonderful things to experience if we just stop to pay attention. In the story, the two birds act as catalysts to get the people they encounter to notice things, but these two fantastical talking birds aren’t the only things the people notice – there are also ordinary birds, and there are ordinary people and things. In the coffee shop, they talk about Emma’s travels, but they also talk about Janice’s pet parrot. On the subway, they talk about the unusual peacock, but they also talk about homing pigeons and hawks.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: By the end, this story leaned into a positive encounter–Janice wasn’t the only one who acknowledged and talked to birds. Explain a bit more what you meant about how she didn’t look back to see if the peacock was still there?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Jenna: I wanted it to be positive, and I wanted the experience to be something Janice would carry with her after the encounter, even though she wouldn’t always have a talking bird around. What I imagined was an army of anthropomorphic birds descending on the city to help people to open their eyes and talk about what they see, the way Emma and the peacock do, but I wanted to leave things a bit vague to let readers decide for themselves what to imagine. In the end, Janice is not sure whether she really saw what she thinks she saw. If the talking birds aren’t real, she doesn&#8217;t want to know that. She doesn’t want the magic to end.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us a bit about the last line, pun and all. Did you think of the ending first, or did it come to you as you were writing?</strong></em></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26997 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/andre-mouton-_d3sppFprWI-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/andre-mouton-_d3sppFprWI-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/andre-mouton-_d3sppFprWI-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/andre-mouton-_d3sppFprWI-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/andre-mouton-_d3sppFprWI-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/andre-mouton-_d3sppFprWI-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Jenna: I thought of the line after I’d written most of the story. It wasn’t meant to be anything more than a  humorous pun, although to be honest, the birds in the story acted as catalysts for me too, in a way. Originally, the scene in the coffee shop was the whole story. When I expanded the focus from Emma to include all sorts of birds—the peacock, the pet parrot, the red-tailed hawks, and the homing pigeons—it freed me to write about more than just the absurdity of a talking bird drinking a coffee in a café.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 048 Author Interview: Nikki Blakely and &#8220;Blackbird&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-nikki-blakely-and-blackbird/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 048]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Who likes their birds with a little side of horror? Read on as Issue 048&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26954 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ingemar-johnsson-7gOZfvShhLg-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ingemar-johnsson-7gOZfvShhLg-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ingemar-johnsson-7gOZfvShhLg-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ingemar-johnsson-7gOZfvShhLg-unsplash-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ingemar-johnsson-7gOZfvShhLg-unsplash-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/ingemar-johnsson-7gOZfvShhLg-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />Who likes their birds with a little side of horror? Read on as <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-048/">Issue 048</a> author Nikki Blakely tells us about her inspiration for her chill-inducing story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/blackbird/">Blackbird</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Y</strong></em><strong><em>our story is terrifying! What was the inspiration behind this particular version of blackbirds?</em></strong></p>
<p>Nikki: I am an avid science fiction and horror reader, and for this piece I was initially inspired by HG Wells &#8211; <em>War of the Worlds</em>, and the idea that the aliens had actually been on the Earth for a very long time before they made their presence known. Usually when aliens are depicted in movies and books they are human size, or of a huge monstrous size, and I wondered what it might be like if they arrived in a much smaller package, one that would make them easily overlooked, until it was too late. I always thought the song &#8220;Blackbird&#8221; by the Beatles had an eerie, haunting quality to it, and the lyrics “all your life, you were only waiting for this moment to arise”, made my think of my alien creatures. Originally, I had wanted to include some of the actual lyrics in my story, but unfortunately for copyright reasons that was not a possibility.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The neighbor initially thought the pods were seeds from China. Do you think including contemporary urban elements brings the story closer to home?</strong></em></p>
<p>Nikki: I first heard about the seeds from China from gardening group a few years back, and it seemed like everyone had their own theory about what they were, and why they were randomly being sent to people. I wanted to portray the neighbor as a conspiracy theorist type of person, the kind that no one really pays attention to because they come off as being slightly unhinged. I think we all know someone like that. I do think that including contemporary urban elements, such as the seeds from China, and the Pinterest garden labels, definitely brings the story closer to home. I think it helps people to imagine this is something that could happen in their own neighbored, maybe even to them.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Adding to the psychological terror is Rachel’s undoing from the loss of her child. Tell us about how that affects Eric, who now has to face danger from outside and inside.</strong></em></p>
<p>Nikki: This story initially originated from a writing prompt where one of the characters had to suffer a mental breakdown, and I wondered of what sort of thing might cause a mental breakdown that someone just could not come back from, and I imagined the death of a child would be just such a thing. Rachel doesn’t want to believe that Em is dead, so she lives in a fantasy world where she carries around a blanket wrapped pillow that she believes to be her daughter. Eric humors her, because what else can he do? He’s only holding on, day by day, trying to survive, hoping that somehow, something will improve, while at the same time living with his own grief over the loss of his daughter and the loss of his wife, who he’s not sure he will ever<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26955 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dea-piratedea-av3JGaR-0RY-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dea-piratedea-av3JGaR-0RY-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dea-piratedea-av3JGaR-0RY-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dea-piratedea-av3JGaR-0RY-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dea-piratedea-av3JGaR-0RY-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/dea-piratedea-av3JGaR-0RY-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> get back.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your ending leaves no room for a happy ever after. When starting this, did you know the blackbirds would win? How do you feel about happy endings in general?</strong></em></p>
<p>Nikki: I did know from the beginning that things were not going to end well for Eric and Rachel. In my mind I saw the closing scene where Rachel is rocking the baby, that isn’t really the baby so I knew how it was going to end before I even started writing the story. I do enjoy a happy ending, but I also enjoy stories that are a bit ambiguous, where not everything is tied up in a neat little package. Sometimes I’m aware of the ending before I write the story, as in this one. Other times, I have no idea what&#8217;s going to happen, and I’m along for the ride just like everyone else.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 048 Author Interview: Kristina T. Saccone and &#8220;The Hawk and the Wren&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-kristina-t-saccone-and-the-hawk-and-the-wren/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 048]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do we have any alternate history lovers in the house? Today&#8217;s Issue 048 author interview&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do we have any alternate history lovers in the house? Today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-048/">Issue 048</a> author interview might interest you! We&#8217;re talking to Kristina T. Saccone about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-hawk-and-the-wren/">The Hawk and the Wren</a>&#8221; and how she used real historical events to produce a magical tale.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: You were able to seamlessly incorporate magic into an alternate history of Russia in World War II. How did you decide on this detail when writing the story?</em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26929 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/elisa-stone-IZfFGVDrdgM-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/elisa-stone-IZfFGVDrdgM-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/elisa-stone-IZfFGVDrdgM-unsplash-682x1024.jpg 682w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/elisa-stone-IZfFGVDrdgM-unsplash-768x1153.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/elisa-stone-IZfFGVDrdgM-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/elisa-stone-IZfFGVDrdgM-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/elisa-stone-IZfFGVDrdgM-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1706w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Kristina: Thank you for including my story and for asking these questions! As a child, I loved reading books about World War II, like <em>Number the Stars</em> by Lois Lowry and of course <em>The Diary of Anne Frank</em>. I also devoured C.S. Lewis’ books in <em>The Lion, The Witch, and The Wardrobe</em> series, which is completely magical and, when set in our world, takes place during World War II. I’m inspired to find magic – whether everyday magic, the magic of our imaginations, or true witchery – when writing stories rooted in war, terror, and grief.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: One of your themes in this story was that of flight. It framed the way the sisters played as children and also defined their eventual choices in life: one mainly grounded, the other soaring. Tell us about this use of opposites and how it defined their relationship as well as the story.</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kristina: I’ve always wanted to write a story about a nurse in World War II. In Great Britain, which is where my mother grew up and my grandparents were during part of the war, those nurses were called “Wrens.” Though they weren’t named for the birds (it’s a pronounced acronym: WRNS for Women’s Royal Navy Service), I always imagined them as such.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I also have two older sisters, and in many ways, we are very different from each other. I sought to show some of those opposites here, and how we are still innately connected because we’re sisters. I did research on the characteristics of a wren versus predatory birds like the hawk, and it felt like the right kind of contrast for a story taking place in the history of the Night Witches.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: Building on the question above, how important to you was it that each sister found their place?</em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kristina: This is a great question because I believe this is the heart of the story. I wanted to show the value and power of both women’s work: one medical, a caretaking role that’s specifically focused on women’s health, and the other fighting on the frontlines of war with all the associated dangers. I am in awe of those who defend countries against the horrors of fascism, and I deeply respect the doctors, nurses, and others on the frontlines – across history, including war nurses and medical professionals still on the front lines of the Covid-19 pandemic.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The true story of the Night Witches is pretty amazing. Did the thought of the historical group start you on the path to your story, or was it something else? What else would you like us to know about your story or about your writing?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kristina: Apparition Lit is one of my favorite journals (alongside Luna Station!) for inclusive, feminist speculative stories, and they offer a terrific monthly flash competition. In 2021, the prompts were all historical women figures, and that included the Night Witches. The prompt itself took me down a rabbit hole of learning all about these brave fighters, the Russian front of the<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26928 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/amee-fairbank-brown-92iTtUsa8bs-unsplash-300x218.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="218" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/amee-fairbank-brown-92iTtUsa8bs-unsplash-300x218.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/amee-fairbank-brown-92iTtUsa8bs-unsplash-1024x744.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/amee-fairbank-brown-92iTtUsa8bs-unsplash-768x558.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/amee-fairbank-brown-92iTtUsa8bs-unsplash-1536x1116.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/amee-fairbank-brown-92iTtUsa8bs-unsplash-2048x1488.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> war, and a little about what it was like to be a young woman during that time. I really enjoy the research aspect of writing, and I always root my speculative fiction with facts to keep the reader a bit grounded. The result here is “The Hawk and the Wren,” which was a finalist for Apparition’s competition and found a wonderful home with Luna Station Quarterly, one of my dream journals!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 048 Author Interview: Heather Del Piano and &#8220;A Murder of Crows&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-heather-del-piano-and-a-murder-of-crows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 11:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 048]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How are you feeling, bird-lovers? Can&#8217;t get enough of Issue 048? Here&#8217;s another treat for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">How are you feeling, bird-lovers? Can&#8217;t get enough of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-048">Issue 048</a>? Here&#8217;s another treat for you: an author interview! Read on for Heather Del Piano&#8217;s answers to our questions about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/a-murder-of-crows/">A Murder of Crows</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: At the start of the story, Edith’s desperation for a child is tangible. When she is asked to chop the head off of a crow and save its blood, things turn dark quickly. If she knew how the story would end, do you think Edith would have gone through with this first sacrifice?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26887 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-300x201.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="201" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-300x201.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-1024x686.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-768x514.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-1536x1028.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/jj-shev-CcsYl5bcNEo-unsplash-2048x1371.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Heather: Edith’s desperation for a child is so strong that I do believe she would have gone through with the first sacrifice no matter what. Even if she had been warned how it would end, she’d still be blinded by that desire. Also, many people like to feel that they have some control over their fate. It reminds me of the movie <em>Practical Magic</em> when Sally’s love interest at the end talked about curses only having power if we believe in them. Since Edith does try to shield Luna even without knowing that tragedy, she most likely would have tried to control and protect her even more to prevent that final tragedy.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: As Luna is growing up, she is sheltered with her mother: “Feeling like a caged bird, both in her home and in her own body, made it hard for Luna to breathe”.  We discover that in all ways except one, she is a normal child who wishes for friends. When writing Luna, how did you decide what qualities of normal and other she would possess?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Heather: It doesn’t have to take much for a person to feel different from others. I wanted Luna to feel very relatable just with that one touch of magic. Many kids feel like an outsider with their peers. Although we don’t have crows escape from us when we have strong emotions, we all experience overwhelming feelings at times. If we bottle up our feelings for too long, they are bound to come out in some destructive ways.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: In so many ways, this story is a beautifully told tragedy. How do you feel about fairy-tale and folk-tale inspired tragic endings? Do you prefer them over “happily ever afters”?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Heather: When I shared my story with friends and family, I always prefaced it by saying, “It’s a fairy-tale, but a dark one.” In popular culture, there is such an association between fairy-tales and happily-ever-after. I grew up on happy fairy-tales and have always been a big Disney fan. I definitely love a happy ending, though I do not feel that all fairy-tales should end that way. Some stories simply don’t end happily. As I’ve grown older, I’ve become more intrigued by the darker ones. In a graduate class I took, Fantasy in Children’s Literature, we discussed how fantasy can be a safer way for people to explore fears and issues. I often find when I’m writing these short stories that I delve into some darker themes that are on my mind.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us about your other writing. Do you prefer dark fairy tales and fantasy, or do you have other influences? What inspiration did you draw on when creating this tale?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26889 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/sergio-ibannez-W9dFbDmb1Lc-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/sergio-ibannez-W9dFbDmb1Lc-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/sergio-ibannez-W9dFbDmb1Lc-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/sergio-ibannez-W9dFbDmb1Lc-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/sergio-ibannez-W9dFbDmb1Lc-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/sergio-ibannez-W9dFbDmb1Lc-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/sergio-ibannez-W9dFbDmb1Lc-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">Heather: When I read Melissa Albert’s <em>The Hazel Wood</em>, the short tragic tales referenced in the book inspired me to try to pen some of my own. Up to that point, I had written a few picture book drafts and a few scenes from a potential novel. Once I switched to fairy-tales, my writing really started to flow. As most writers, I’m an avid reader and take inspiration from a variety of sources. I pull from folklore, but also try to work out any pressing issues on my mind. The first seed of an idea for “A Murder of Crows” was the title. I love that a group of crows is called a murder and I developed the story from that title.  Although I do not have that desperation for a child, I think part of my inspiration for the story was all the societal pressure for women my age to have children. Lately, I’ve been working on a historical fiction novel based on a fact I learned during a virtual tour of Scotland. However, I do plan on continuing to work on these shorter fantasy pieces as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 048 Author Interview: Elizabeth Hinckley and &#8220;Ornithomancy&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-elizabeth-hinckley-and-ornithomancy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 048]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Did you know February is National Bird-Feeding Month? What better way to celebrate than grabbing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know February is National Bird-Feeding Month? What better way to celebrate than grabbing some birdseed and reading <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-048/">Issue 048</a> aloud to our little feathered friends? Elizabeth Hinckley&#8217;s story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/ornithomancy/">Ornithomancy</a>&#8221; is a good place to start!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This is such a journey of a story. I love the far-future setting combined with the ornithomancy. What drew you to write about this particular form of divination? Was it part of the original idea for this story, or did you figure that part out later?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26846 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/t-a-t-i-a-n-a-hi6tEJgqDkY-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/t-a-t-i-a-n-a-hi6tEJgqDkY-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/t-a-t-i-a-n-a-hi6tEJgqDkY-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/t-a-t-i-a-n-a-hi6tEJgqDkY-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/t-a-t-i-a-n-a-hi6tEJgqDkY-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/t-a-t-i-a-n-a-hi6tEJgqDkY-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Elizabeth: I have a deep love of birds, and my relationship with them comes from both my work as a naturalist, and a connection to them spiritually. They’re endlessly fascinating, whether I’m handling birds of prey at work, or watching sparrows in the snow. They have the capacity to capture our imaginations through the sheer variety of bird life, the parallels of the life experiences we share with them, and the fascinating differences between us that help us see things that we may not see in ourselves right away. And throughout human history we’ve seen them as representing beauty, freedom, and many other archetypal concepts. If a good divination system has to have a language that speaks to the most important concerns of our lives, then birds provide us with quite a vocabulary.</p>
<p>I hadn’t set out to write a story about divination; originally I started to write a story about the deeper connections that are possible between humans and birds, but I found I couldn’t quite get there without a lengthy scientific, anthropological, and spiritual explanation. I think those things are worth talking about, but this was a short story, not a novel or a thesis! So I went back before the beginning and it took me to a whole other place and person, whose simple story told so much more. Tirza’s experience with birds is from a distance &#8211; much like the reader’s may be. She doesn’t need to be a bird expert to have a meaningful encounter, and ornithomancy connects her to them.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: </strong></em><em><strong>It’s both painful and kind of compelling to read Tirza’s journey of emotional distancing from her father. It’s sad, but also it’s clear that she’s doing what she needs to do. Was it challenging to decide how much resolution, or lack thereof, to give Tirza with regards to her dad?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26848 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/j-dean-e2jLLKGL3MU-unsplash-300x240.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="240" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/j-dean-e2jLLKGL3MU-unsplash-300x240.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/j-dean-e2jLLKGL3MU-unsplash-1024x819.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/j-dean-e2jLLKGL3MU-unsplash-768x614.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/j-dean-e2jLLKGL3MU-unsplash-1536x1229.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/j-dean-e2jLLKGL3MU-unsplash-2048x1638.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Elizabeth: It was important for me to have Tirza go through the experience with her dad to tell something a little different, and real, than we believe about difficult relationships. (I’m sorry,  dear Tirza &#8211; I know it was painful, but you did well!) By all means, if a person can heal a damaged relationship to the benefit of all, that is a wonderful thing. But there’s also something liberating about letting go of what how we think a relationship should be and accepting how it is &#8211; how a person is. I have observed many different versions of people not getting what they need from someone who “should” give it to them, and it’s painful. They become the victim of someone else’s shortcomings, or collateral damage to that person’s own pain. I thought it would be special for Tirza to discover that when life isn’t “fair”, you don’t have be the victim in someone else’s story, and that it’s ok to not fix everything.  You can also live through it with intention and dignity, and without resentment.</p>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: </strong></em><em><strong>I’m intrigued by the idea of distant Sumeria. Have you considered following Tirza to her new home and telling us a story of her life there?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Elizabeth: Yes, I have! In fact, I really started to write a story about birds and people on Sumeria in the first place, and got hung up on building that world to the point that it got in the way of just telling a good short story. If I ever get around to figuring that out, then Tirza’s story will just be the beginning of a very interesting life for her there! Right now, someone in a Sumerian forest is looking up as a transport ship enters the atmosphere. I wonder if she will ever look back one day and realize that she saw the moment that Tirza arrived…</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 048 Author Interview: Leanne Howard and &#8220;Seven Beacons Burning&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-leanne-howard-and-seven-beacons-burning/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-leanne-howard-and-seven-beacons-burning/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 13:09:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 048]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26695</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We love getting insight into our Issue 048 authors&#8217; inspirations, and Leanne Howard does not&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We love getting insight into our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-048/">Issue 048</a> authors&#8217; inspirations, and Leanne Howard does not disappoint! Today she talks with us about &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/seven-beacons-burning/">Seven Beacons Burning</a>&#8221; and how she crafted such a vivid tale.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Oh wow, I can’t even tell you how lovely I found this. You manage to evoke so much imagery and emotion in such a short span of time. Where did your idea for this story come from?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26721 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/igor-lepilin-fjmPfKvayzA-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/igor-lepilin-fjmPfKvayzA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/igor-lepilin-fjmPfKvayzA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/igor-lepilin-fjmPfKvayzA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/igor-lepilin-fjmPfKvayzA-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/igor-lepilin-fjmPfKvayzA-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Leanne: Thank you so much! Honestly, one of my ideas for this story came out of one particular scene in <i>The Return of the King </i>(the movie): the scene when all the beacons of Gondor are being lit. I&#8217;ve seen it so many times, and every time I found myself thinking, what is life like for those beacon keepers? How are they living in such isolated places? How are they able to watch the next beacon over at any given time? These things got into my head, and the narrative situation of this story was born from that. But ultimately, I knew my version of this story was not going to be in a world at all like Middle Earth.</p>
<div>By contrast, I think the characters in this story came partially from the situation I was experiencing in my own life at the time. When I first started writing this story, my dad had just been diagnosed with esophageal cancer. So I was thinking a lot about the comfort of being able to eat, and eat well, along with the relationship between a father and a daughter. These things came out in the story, even though the characters are ultimately different from my dad and me.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: I loved how visceral your descriptions of taste and touch and sight were—the flower stains on the bottom of their shoes, the taste of ash and knowing where it came from, the sounds of drums and heartbeats. It read so beautifully and naturally. What for you is easiest about writing, and what parts do you have to focus on?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Leanne: I love to write tastes and smells and touches. I think part of that comes from my efforts to appreciate those things in everyday life (it&#8217;s not always easy for me to be mindful of them!). At the same time, these details are how I get to know my characters. When I start thinking about their lives, I find myself trying to come up with the material reality that makes up their existence. What do they smell/taste/touch every day? What is new to them? The answers to those questions can be fun to discover. One part that is harder for me is figuring out the shape of a story. Deciding when it should end, what note I want to finish on&#8211;these things take me a lot of time and a lot of iterations.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: </strong></em><em><strong>You do a great job of hinting at a much larger world, but for most of this story the characters seem to be living a fairly small life—there are the Beacons, a few other people mentioned, wonderful descriptions of food and memories of longing. Have you pictured any other stories set in this world?</strong></em></p>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26722 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/karo-kujanpaa-YTfSdXKFec-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/karo-kujanpaa-YTfSdXKFec-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/karo-kujanpaa-YTfSdXKFec-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/karo-kujanpaa-YTfSdXKFec-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/karo-kujanpaa-YTfSdXKFec-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/karo-kujanpaa-YTfSdXKFec-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
</div>
<div>Leanne: I would love to return to this world in a future story. Little bubbles of ideas managed to pop up while I was writing this particular tale. At the moment, though, those ideas don&#8217;t have any particular character attached. It is usually this way for me with stories, although I don&#8217;t always want to go back to a place I&#8217;ve written in before. Sometimes a vague sense of things will sit and steep in my head for a long time, and then one day I might encounter something else from an entirely unexpected direction that springs a character into being&#8211;and bam! I have a story. It&#8217;s not a very scientific process, but it&#8217;s why I encourage following all thought-threads to their end destination. Who knows what could come of them?</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-leanne-howard-and-seven-beacons-burning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 048 Author Interview: Andrea Goyan and &#8220;A Feather&#8217;s Weight&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-andrea-goyan-and-a-feathers-weight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 11:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 048]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In today&#8217;s Issue 048 author interview, Andrea Goyan gives us some bonus content for her&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-048/">Issue 048</a> author interview, Andrea Goyan gives us some bonus content for her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/a-feathers-weight/">A Feather&#8217;s Weight</a>&#8220;. Are you excited? We are!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story has a lot of weight (pun intended) for something so short. I love how Josie looks at Emma, and the glimpse we get of her past. What was your inspiration for this story?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26706 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/evie-s-DSGP650z8rM-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/evie-s-DSGP650z8rM-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/evie-s-DSGP650z8rM-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/evie-s-DSGP650z8rM-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/evie-s-DSGP650z8rM-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/evie-s-DSGP650z8rM-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/evie-s-DSGP650z8rM-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Andrea: This began its life from a writing prompt where I needed to include some kind of hidden<br />
treasure. I wrote it during the first six months of the pandemic. So much of that time remains a blur to me, but I remember deciding I didn’t want the item to be an obvious treasure. Instead, I<br />
wanted it to be something relatively common whose secret wouldn’t be visible and could easily be overlooked. I landed on a magic feather. In part because in those dark days of 2020, I wanted to find something beautiful and hopeful.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: As someone who worked for a long time with medically complex seniors, I really felt<br />
Josie’s dilemma when it came to how much to believe. I love the way you insert doubt into<br />
the narration. We get a feeling for the stories Emma carries inside of her, and yet there’s<br />
more magic there—magic that let her know Josie was coming. How did you decide on the<br />
magic you wanted to use in this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Andrea: I’m happy to hear you were left wondering a bit about the truth of everything. It’s kind of a recurring theme in several pieces I’ve written over the years, wrestling with the truth and<br />
perception. Anytime I’m ready to dismiss someone’s tall tale as false, I stop and wonder, “What if…?”</p>
<p>The magic in this tale evolved as I wrote it. The story was very different in early drafts. But I<br />
always knew Emma would die, so I needed another character to narrate the story. My first draft<br />
began from that narrator’s POV, and it was something I heard her say about Emma. Something<br />
which helped me define Emma’s character.</p>
<blockquote><p>Most people don’t know when they’re going to die. Emma Cooke wasn’t most people. Nearing her eighty-fifth birthday, she’d been around long enough to recognize the signs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>“Oh, they’re different for each person,” she told me. “The only thing keeping me on this side of the grave is a bit of unfinished business.”</p></blockquote>
<p>That opening changed by the final draft, but not Emma’s determination and power to stave off<br />
death until she could find the right person to take up her mantle. Her belief a worthy person<br />
would appear to follow in her footsteps gave us a glimpse about how the feather’s magic<br />
illuminated her.</p>
<p>Deciding what magic the feather contained became clear as I learned more about Emma’s<br />
character and past. I often mourn the stories we lose when someone dies. Sit and chat with just<br />
about anyone, but especially our elders, and you’ll be amazed by the things they’ve done and<br />
seen in their lives. Even the most stayed individual has surprises to share. I think all the death<br />
swirling around the pandemic brought that home even more and wanted the feather’s magic to<br />
revolve around saving stories.</p>
<p>Ultimately, the piece became about kindness, knowledge, storytelling, and their powers to affect<br />
positive change in the world. Which, for me, is magic.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The scene with the magpies coming to greet their lost brother is so lovely, and then what happens next is haunting! If you were to pick another story of Emma’s to briefly share, what might it be?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emma stood at the fence, watching Delphine forage with another elephant in the sanctuary’s<br />
field. For all Delphine’s days in the circus, she’d always been the only elephant.</p>
<p>“Oh, Delly,” Emma said, grateful to see her friend wasn’t alone anymore.</p>
<p>Delphine’s ears flapped. She turned toward Emma and ran, stopping short as she reached the<br />
barrier between them. Emma caressed the trunk that first touched Emma’s face with its moist,<br />
sensitive tip before Delphine plunged it into Emma’s pocket, where Emma had stowed a banana. As the elephant peeled and ate the treat, Emma told her about the magpie.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26707 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photos-by-beks-QGofHoPnjCc-unsplash-285x300.jpg" alt="" width="285" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photos-by-beks-QGofHoPnjCc-unsplash-285x300.jpg 285w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photos-by-beks-QGofHoPnjCc-unsplash-974x1024.jpg 974w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photos-by-beks-QGofHoPnjCc-unsplash-768x808.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photos-by-beks-QGofHoPnjCc-unsplash-1461x1536.jpg 1461w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photos-by-beks-QGofHoPnjCc-unsplash-1948x2048.jpg 1948w" sizes="(max-width: 285px) 100vw, 285px" /></p>
<p>Emma didn’t know whether the magic would work with an animal, but she removed the feather<br />
from her purse to show Delphine anyway. The elephant sniffed at the white pinion resting in<br />
Emma’s palm; her breath made the down near the feather’s shaft quiver. Then, she looked at<br />
Emma with her soulful eyes and placed her trunk against Emma’s bare wrist.</p>
<p>The day the reserve’s manager of elephant care called to notify Emma of Delphine’s death,<br />
Emma removed the silk bag from her dresser and opened it.</p>
<p>“Delphine?” she said.</p>
<p>The snow-white feather twinkled its reply, telling Emma that new memories awaited her. Emma<br />
smiled, and as she laid a finger on the downy plumage, she laughed, then said, “Ah, there you<br />
are, old friend.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 048 Author Interview: Katrina Carruth and &#8220;Omen&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-katrina-carruth-and-omen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 20:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 048]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26676</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s the first Tuesday of the new year, and we have a brand new Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s the first Tuesday of the new year, and we have a brand new <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-048/">Issue 048</a> author interview to share! Get a little insight, and perhaps a little inspiration, from Katrina Carruth as she talks with us about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/omen/">Omen</a>&#8220;.</p>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Wow, I’m both terribly impressed and a little creeped out by this story, I loved it! What was your inspiration for writing &#8220;Omen&#8221;?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26682 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photoholgic-d8EIcAjOCmo-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photoholgic-d8EIcAjOCmo-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photoholgic-d8EIcAjOCmo-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photoholgic-d8EIcAjOCmo-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photoholgic-d8EIcAjOCmo-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/photoholgic-d8EIcAjOCmo-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Katrina: Honestly? It ended up as my very therapeutic projection of my current attitude towards the world. Everyday when I turn on the news it just feels like things are so bleak, and I almost feel guilty wanting more for myself. There&#8217;s a moment in the story where the main character is fed up with her suffering and prepared to take things into her own hands. While I haven&#8217;t quite hit the point she has, I frequently find myself struggling to push through and remember my own power. I liked the idea of her surrendering completely to her transformation regardless of what&#8217;s happening around her. It&#8217;s something I have to remind myself to do pretty often.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: This story is an emotional rollercoaster—I felt like the emotions you evoked from me as a reader were perfectly mirrored by the pacing and action too, from curious and calm in the beginning to a much more excited ending. Did you work a lot on pacing when you were writing this story? What about writing it came easily, and what was more challenging?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p>Katrina: Actually yes, I have been working on pacing quite a bit! For the last two years I&#8217;ve been writing more short stories because it&#8217;s really difficult for me to keep scenes in my novels condensed. Practicing pacing in short story form has taught me a lot about pacing in novels that are well over 100k words.</p>
<div></div>
<div>The idea for a story is always what comes easiest to me. I have more ideas than I&#8217;ll ever know what to do with! But the element of writing I find most challenging is description. My first drafts are typically just dialogue and very vague descriptions, so for this story I wanted to push myself to write something that focused more on the world. It really took me out of my comfort zone, but I&#8217;m so glad I did it.</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: This feels beautifully complete for such a short work. Do you think you’ll ever revisit this omen in a future story?</strong></em></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26683 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/vern-ooi-aLAtdjYtjus-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/vern-ooi-aLAtdjYtjus-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/vern-ooi-aLAtdjYtjus-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/vern-ooi-aLAtdjYtjus-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/vern-ooi-aLAtdjYtjus-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/vern-ooi-aLAtdjYtjus-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div></div>
<div>Katrina: I briefly considered it as the new shiny idea I could work with (typical behavior for me) but, for now I&#8217;ve got it on the back burner so I can prioritize other projects. I would love to see the world expanded one day, so.. maybe in the future I&#8217;ll revisit it. (And, being the total shiny object spaz that I am, I&#8217;ve just thought of a way to incorporate this world into my current novel and I&#8217;m feeling a bit brilliant. I probably wouldn&#8217;t have thought of it without this question so, thank you!)</div>
<div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 048 Author Interview: Emma Schmid and &#8220;The Nix Trial&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-048-author-interview-emma-schmid-and-the-nix-trial/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 12:19:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 048]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s myth-inspired Issue 048 story takes us to the Greece! Find out where author Emma&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s myth-inspired <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-048/">Issue 048</a> story takes us to the Greece! Find out where author Emma Schmid&#8217;s ideas came from for her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-nix-trial/">The Nix Trial</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: As a fan of Greek mythology, I have to say I LOVED it when I finally figured out what was going on with your story! What drew you to Harpies?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-26645 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Harpij_-_I.I_Schipper_1660_graveur_Matthius_Merian_naar_J.Jonstons_Naekeurige_Beschryvingh_van_de_Natuur-276x300.jpg" alt="" width="276" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Harpij_-_I.I_Schipper_1660_graveur_Matthius_Merian_naar_J.Jonstons_Naekeurige_Beschryvingh_van_de_Natuur-276x300.jpg 276w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Harpij_-_I.I_Schipper_1660_graveur_Matthius_Merian_naar_J.Jonstons_Naekeurige_Beschryvingh_van_de_Natuur.jpg 552w" sizes="(max-width: 276px) 100vw, 276px" />Emma: I&#8217;m so glad to hear you enjoyed the mythology aspect. I&#8217;m a Classics major and my favorite classes were about myths. Harpies aren&#8217;t featured a lot in stories, and when I first read about the Harpies in Hesiod years ago, I didn&#8217;t think much of them. They show up occasionally, listed as insatiable and vicious, but they&#8217;re not huge players, like the Gorgons or even nymphs. When I started to write this story, thinking about a goddess who would give her blessing, I realized I wanted it to be a bit unexpected. The Harpies are unique because of their bird-bodies and women&#8217;s facial features; they&#8217;re not exactly human and not exactly bird, and I felt that a god&#8217;s blessing would be something very much like that. I like the idea that the conquerors of the trial are able to walk in both worlds; in my mind, they&#8217;re sort of like demi-gods. They have the unique ability to be part of the god&#8217;s world and the human world at the same time.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The description of the trial itself was great, but the description of <i>preparing</i> for the trial was even more compelling to me somehow. You did such a wonderful job of evoking the pain and hope and resilience necessary for such a feat. How did you come up with this idea?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: Thank you so much! I actually started this story as a writing prompt for a class I was taking &#8211; I believe we had to use the word summit somehow, either as a theme or actual word in the story. At first, this was just Ida climbing, changing forms, and leaping off the cliff to spread her wings. A while after writing it, I thought it was too easy. I really wanted to show how dangerous and difficult this kind of trial would be without safety equipment. For me, the idea that these young women are willing to sacrifice their youth, their limbs, and their lives to the possibility of the goddess&#8217; blessing was so fascinating. Besides myth, the classes I enjoyed most in university usually involved rituals, sacrifices, and festivals. I really enjoyed learning about types of things that people in the ancient world would do to appease the gods. There are a lot of strange things <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-26646 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/trail-l4MwmH8QIxk-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/trail-l4MwmH8QIxk-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/trail-l4MwmH8QIxk-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/trail-l4MwmH8QIxk-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/trail-l4MwmH8QIxk-unsplash-1229x1536.jpg 1229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/trail-l4MwmH8QIxk-unsplash-1638x2048.jpg 1638w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/trail-l4MwmH8QIxk-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />done to become initiated into priestesshoods. The Eleusinian Mysteries in particular are shrouded in theories, one of which is that after sacrificing a piglet to the goddess Demeter, initiates would rappel down a cliff to a river bank, and pick up the bones of previously sacrificed animals. In my story, though very different, Ida is still willing to break bones, crack her fingernails, and learn to survive in the thin oxygen of the mountain, just for that chance to be blessed. Even though she&#8217;s watched over by the goddess, there&#8217;s no guarantee that she won&#8217;t get hurt &#8211; and even when she does, she overcomes her injury. Anyone who can survive an injury as devastating as a broken spine, whether they simply live on, or push themselves back to their peak condition, like Ida, has the most incredible resilience and strength, and I&#8217;ve got to say that I&#8217;m truly in awe of that.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I’m intrigued by your mention of the trial to appease Lord Talos. Have you considered writing another story in this world? Would it be about Ida, or someone else if you did?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: I&#8217;ve actually been thinking more and more about this world since writing the story. I think I&#8217;d really like to continue on with the idea of these trials, but I would probably use a new character. I&#8217;ve been toying with the idea of the Lord Talos trial being more like spelunking &#8211; exploring, maybe mapping underwater caves to prove one&#8217;s resilience, strength, and bravery. I&#8217;m fairly claustrophobic myself, so it would be a feat of strength for me to get into the head of this new character, but I&#8217;d love to try it out.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
