<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sara Lundberg &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/sara-lundberg/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 22:34:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>November is National Novel Writing Month</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/november-is-national-novel-writing-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sara Lundberg]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 19:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anyone can write a novel. This November is your chance to try. November is National&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Anyone can write a novel. This November is your chance to try. November is National Novel Writing Month (NaNoWriMo).</p>
<p>NaNoWriMo is a writing contest where the goal is to write a 50,000 word novel in 30 days. Although “contest” is a bit of a misnomer. The competition is only with yourself. It&#8217;s you versus your inner critic. It’s you versus your busy life.</p>
<p>To a lot of people, this contest might sound impossible. But believe me, thousands of people win every year. And even those people who don’t “win” by reaching 50,000 words still come away with something just by making the attempt.</p>
<p>Who am I to speak with such authority on the subject?</p>
<p>Well, as of this year, I’ve participated in NaNoWriMo every year for a decade. I have also been the Lawrence region Municipal Liaison for the last six years.</p>
<p>As ML, I have two jobs. The first is to organize events and make sure my Wrimos have plenty of pep throughout the month &#8211; lots of baked goods, encouraging words, cat-wrangling, pep talks, answering questions, and trying to figure out where to cram twenty or so people with laptops who need power and coffee for hours.</p>
<p>My second job is to recruit any and all potential writers to give NaNoWriMo a try. I knew I was right for the job because any time anyone mentions a passing interest in writing, I immediately try to bamboozle them into participating. Thus why I am writing this blog post.</p>
<p>Because, as I said, anyone can write a novel. And anyone can write 50,000 words in a month. You can win because NaNoWriMo gives you the ingredients for success:</p>
<ol>
<li>A hard deadline with a specific goal. No more someday. You have 30 days to write 50,000 words. Go.</li>
<li>An excuse &#8211; nay, a reason &#8211; to make the time in your already hectic life to write. It&#8217;s only 30 days. Give yourself permission to let some things (TV, housework, friends) go for a month and write instead.</li>
<li>And, in my opinion, the most important thing: a community of people who are doing the same crazy thing you are. You can write a novel alone, but your fellow Wrimos will make the journey more enjoyable.</li>
</ol>
<p>More than that, NaNoWriMo teaches you to develop a writing practice. After a month of making time to write every day, you can carry that practice into the months that follow. Maybe you didn’t miss that TV show you cut out as much as you thought you did, and you liked starting your day with a twenty minute word sprint or winding down your day by freewriting for half an hour before bed. I’ve heard it said that it takes 21 days to form a new habit. NaNoWriMo gives you 30 to make sure it sticks.</p>
<p>So, you might ask, what has become of all of those novels I’ve written? Surely I’ve published a book by now, right? My answer to that is no, and I’ll tell you why. Just because I wrote a novel in a month doesn’t mean it’s ready for the world to see. More often than not, those novels need to be hidden from the light of day at all costs.</p>
<p>And to that you might ask, why bother, then? Please do bother. I bother for three reasons.</p>
<p>First, because I use NaNoWriMo as a writing exercise. Each year I learn something new about myself as a writer. Once I knew I could reach the 50,000 word goal, each year I started challenging myself to an additional goal. Some years it was to write 60,000+ words. Some years it was to actually finish the story by the end of November. I’ve experimented with genre, I’ve played around with multiple point-of-view characters, and I’ve filled my life with other extracurricular activities on top of writing. And each year I become a better writer. I had to get those early novels out of my system to free the good stories and my creative muse from the rubbish.</p>
<p>Second, I do it to hang out with my friends. Every year I end up with a bunch of new friends, even if I only see them in November. Some of the people I met during NaNoWriMo are the people I hang out with now. Every year we absorb another person or two into our group. These people keep me accountable. They keep me inspired when I’m feeling empty and motivated when I’m feeling down. They have become my writing support group.</p>
<p>And finally, I do it because it is the one month out of the year where I have an excuse to put writing before all of the other crazy life stuff. Every year I get a thrill of excitement because I get to write for a whole month with no guilt. Every year I end up with another potential novel. A starting point. Something I can work with. And I can tell people, even if it&#8217;s only for one month a year, yeah, I am a writer. Yeah, I’ve written a novel. I write a novel every November.</p>
<p>You can write one, too. Go to <a href="http://www.nanowrimo.org/">www.nanowrimo.org</a>. Create an account. Find your local region. Or come visit mine, here in Lawrence, KS. We adopt folks from all over the country. Stop by our forum and say hello!</p>
<p>And then go and write your 50,000 words.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
