<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 052 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-052/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 05:01:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 052 Author Interview: Sarah McPherson and &#8220;Shadow and Ash&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-052-author-interview-sarah-mcpherson-and-shadow-and-ash/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 11:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 052]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=29009</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We hope today&#8217;s Issue 052 author interview can be a spot of respite in your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We hope today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-052/">Issue 052</a> author interview can be a spot of respite in your busy week. Come sit with us a moment as Sarah McPherson tells us about the inspiration behind the soothing trees in her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/shadow-and-ash/">Shadow and Ash</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The sense of foreboding you&#8217;ve crafted here is incredibly palpable. How did you do it??</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-29013 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/jonathan-larson-5-Bi902rd_E-unsplash-222x300.jpg" alt="" width="222" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/jonathan-larson-5-Bi902rd_E-unsplash-222x300.jpg 222w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/jonathan-larson-5-Bi902rd_E-unsplash-758x1024.jpg 758w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/jonathan-larson-5-Bi902rd_E-unsplash-768x1037.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/jonathan-larson-5-Bi902rd_E-unsplash-1138x1536.jpg 1138w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/jonathan-larson-5-Bi902rd_E-unsplash-1517x2048.jpg 1517w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/jonathan-larson-5-Bi902rd_E-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1896w" sizes="(max-width: 222px) 100vw, 222px" />Sarah: The kind of scary stories I enjoy are the ones where it’s all about the atmosphere; ghost stories, stories that are a bit uncanny, a bit unsettling. So when I try to write scary (or even just a little bit ominous), that’s what I aim to recreate. The monster you know is there but can’t see &#8211; the longer you go without actually coming face to face with whatever it is you’re afraid of, the more the tension builds. I was also aiming for a slightly dreamlike quality to this story, like in those nightmares where you’re trying to get away from something undefined that’s chasing you but you can’t, so you’re just constantly fleeing until you wake up.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Alternatively, I could also feel the peace given by the ash trees wash over me. Have you ever been to a place like this? What was your inspiration?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Sarah: Being in the woods and surrounded by trees is something I have always found incredibly calming and peaceful. There are some urban woodland spaces near where I live that have this almost magical ability to make you forget that you’re in the middle of a city and that there are actually only a handful of trees between you and houses and roads. So I suppose that’s what I’m drawing on when I write about trees in that way. The contrast was also important to balance the story &#8211; so the peace of the trees had to be powerful enough to stand against the darker elements that threaten the character.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Please tell us a bit more about your choice of imagery for this story.</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Sarah: I’ve been writing a lot about trees and folklore recently as part of a larger project, so all of this stuff is very much at the forefront of my mind. For this story in particular I started with the choice of tree &#8211; ash &#8211; and then looked at folklore, traditions, and associations that could work as a jumping off point. Ash trees are very long-lived, and have a place in some mythologies as a tree of life (such as the Norse world tree Yggdrasil). Ash wood was also traditionally burned to ward off evil spirits, as it is in this story. They have winged seeds called keys, which I played on to give the character a moment where she realizes she can make a change, by turning a key. And then once I had established that what she has on her side is fire and light and life, it makes sense for what she faces to be the opposite of that: darkness, shadows, and the threat of death.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: What is your favorite kind of tree and why?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Sarah: That’s a really hard question! I like all sorts of trees for all sorts of reasons. I love rowans<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-29014 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/annie-spratt-CBK82c09Nkw-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/annie-spratt-CBK82c09Nkw-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/annie-spratt-CBK82c09Nkw-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/annie-spratt-CBK82c09Nkw-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/annie-spratt-CBK82c09Nkw-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/annie-spratt-CBK82c09Nkw-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/annie-spratt-CBK82c09Nkw-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /> for how delicate they look and for the fact that the red berries stay on the tree after the leaves have fallen, which makes them particularly striking in winter. I love twisty, ancient hawthorns that look like they’ve been lifted straight out of a fairy tale. Both rowans and hawthorns have lots of folklore surrounding them too! And there’s a white poplar near my house that I love because the silvery undersides of the leaves are beautiful in the sunlight when a breeze shakes them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 052 Author Interview: Chana Kohl and &#8220;The Warrior Tree&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-052-author-interview-chana-kohl-and-the-warrior-tree/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 052]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome, dear readers, to our Issue 052 author interviews! This issue is all about trees,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome, dear readers, to our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-052/">Issue 052</a> author interviews! This issue is all about trees, and we can&#8217;t wait to see how each of our authors brought this theme to life. We&#8217;re starting off with Chana Kohl and her enthralling story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-warrior-tree/">The Warrior Tree</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: By the time I reached the sci-fi ending, I forgot I was reading a speculative fiction magazine because I was so engrossed in this story! Why did you decide to save the sci-fi for the end?</strong></em></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28988 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/lucas-myers-9J6vcrYE9fA-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/lucas-myers-9J6vcrYE9fA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/lucas-myers-9J6vcrYE9fA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/lucas-myers-9J6vcrYE9fA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/lucas-myers-9J6vcrYE9fA-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/lucas-myers-9J6vcrYE9fA-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Chana: Thank you! In the original draft, the sci-fi portion was the opening scene and Faiza was the backstory. After some feedback, I realized my message needed to focus, and the spotlight had to be completely on her, so I switched things around. Also, I wanted the reader to be as unaware as Faiza was in the moment how her raw determination would manifest in the future.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I will admit, trees aren&#8217;t the first things I think of in association with Morocco. Why did you choose to set your tree-themed story there?</strong></em></p>
<p>Chana: Yes, I can definitely see that. Especially if you live in a place where trees and water are so abundant you might never consider what would happen if they were no longer there. If you live at the edge of the Sahara, they feel more precious. Desertification is a far more vast and visible problem in the stretch of Middle East where I live and Africa all-around. I’m just flabbergasted how argan trees are able to thrive, literally, as the last line of defense between these habitable and inhabitable areas.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What drew you to this issue&#8217;s theme?</strong></em></p>
<p>Chana: I’d been working on the idea since spring, drawing a parallel between one of these *warrior* trees and a young woman stuck in an impossible situation due to her culture, her economic status, her difference from the norm. I thought about all the traditional ways we define a champion, and neither of them fit the mold. What they did have in common was the ability to endure whatever conditions they found themselves and somehow draw strength from that. Some battles won’t be won in a single generation, but if you can plant the seeds, time will do the rest.</p>
<p dir="ltr">When I read the submission call, it was a happy coincidence that my title and theme seemed to match.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Who and what inspires your writing?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28989 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/rabah-al-shammary-eRuP4BTnDWQ-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/rabah-al-shammary-eRuP4BTnDWQ-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/rabah-al-shammary-eRuP4BTnDWQ-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/rabah-al-shammary-eRuP4BTnDWQ-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/rabah-al-shammary-eRuP4BTnDWQ-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/rabah-al-shammary-eRuP4BTnDWQ-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">Chana: As far as reading, there are so many classic authors I loved growing up, A. C. Clarke would be at the top of that list. Later I discovered Le Guin. I read so many amazing, new and established authors from all over the spectrum&#8230;but I have to say I’m in awe of Ted Chiang at the moment.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As far as story ideas&#8230;I try to write a 20-minute sprint each day from a story prompt. This usually results in a hodgepodge of foolishness, but sometimes there are one or two sentences I can use down the line. The majority of my story ideas come from interesting science articles I keep in a database or images in my media feeds from historical, archeological and architectural websites.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 052 Release!!! Meet Cover Artist Samantha Lee</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-052-release-meet-cover-artist-samantha-lee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 052]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome, dear readers, to the release of our annual themed issue! 052&#8216;s theme is Trees,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_28937" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-28937" style="width: 240px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-28937 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/lost_swords_by_kloir_df0v43o-fullview-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/lost_swords_by_kloir_df0v43o-fullview-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/lost_swords_by_kloir_df0v43o-fullview-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/lost_swords_by_kloir_df0v43o-fullview-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/lost_swords_by_kloir_df0v43o-fullview.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-28937" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Lost Swords&#8221; by Samantha Lee</figcaption></figure>
<p>Welcome, dear readers, to the release of our annual themed issue! <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-052/">052</a>&#8216;s theme is Trees, and we&#8217;re so pleased by how our eighteen authors shaped their stories around it. Imbue a little nature into your reading life right here on our site, or you can grab a copy of your very own in either print or digital!</p>
<p>Of course, this wouldn&#8217;t be a new issue of LSQ without some breathtaking cover art. This issue&#8217;s cover has been graced by <a href="https://www.samanthamleeart.com/">Samantha Lee</a>, tree-lover and landscape extraordinaire. Samantha was kind enough to share some thoughts about her art with us, as well as her thoughts on the importance of trees!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Please tell us about the cover image for this issue. Is there a story behind this image? What was your thought process while creating this image?</strong></em></p>
<p>Samantha: For the &#8220;Lost Swords&#8221; illustration I wanted to tell a story without featuring any people. I feel sometimes the story behind props and environments hit harder than one without them. The overall feeling of the painting was meant to be something warm and melancholy. With the swords in the background, I like to leave it up to the viewer to decide if it was a sweet or sad memory.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Trees are the theme for this issue, and they seem to appear often in your art. Why do you choose trees as subjects? What stories do you try to tell with them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Samantha: I absolutely love painting trees. They come in so many different shapes, sizes, colors, and variations. The possibilities with them are endless. I typically either use them as the main focus of a painting or to frame my compositions. In this case, the tree symbolizes something that is constant. From the time when the owners of the swords were there, the tree was present, and hopefully when they are long gone, the tree will remain.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your landscape work is truly stunning. How did you hone your skills when it comes to portraying nature in your art?</strong></em></p>
<p>Samantha: I&#8217;ve always loved depicting nature in my artwork. Landscapes and nature are both things I think people will always have a soft spot in their heart for. Witnessing a beautiful sunset, strolling through a lush forest, climbing the heights of a mountain, or admiring the silent snow of a fresh storm. These are some of my favorite scenes that I try to reimagine. I&#8217;ve stuck with landscapes because they truly make me happy and practicing them brings me immense joy.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do you have a personal favorite of the projects you’ve worked on? Or one that was</strong></em></p>
<figure id="attachment_28938" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-28938" style="width: 240px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28938" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/12-WisteriaLantern-Tree-240x300.png" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/12-WisteriaLantern-Tree-240x300.png 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/12-WisteriaLantern-Tree-819x1024.png 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/12-WisteriaLantern-Tree-768x960.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/12-WisteriaLantern-Tree-1229x1536.png 1229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/12-WisteriaLantern-Tree.png 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-28938" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Wisteria Lantern Tree&#8221; by Samantha Lee</figcaption></figure>
<p><em><strong>memorable due to its challenges? If so, can you tell us a bit about it?</strong></em></p>
<p>Samantha: One of my favorite pieces was this magical willow tree. I was messing around with the idea of giving the dog a birthday hat and I didn&#8217;t have the heart to erase it, so I kept it in. I always giggle to myself whenever I see this painting, I can&#8217;t help it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
