<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Celestial Queerscapes &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/celestial-queerscapes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 11:47:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>&#8220;Between Words and Pictures&#8221;: A Review of Trung Le Nguyen&#8217;s &#8220;The Magic Fish&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/between-words-and-pictures-a-review-of-trung-le-nguyens-the-magic-fish/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Renn Tan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 11:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Celestial Queerscapes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24322</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“To me,” says Tiên’s mother, “language is a map to help you figure out where&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24326 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fish-212x300.jpeg" alt="" width="212" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fish-212x300.jpeg 212w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fish.jpeg 494w" sizes="(max-width: 212px) 100vw, 212px" /></p>
<p>“To me,” says Tiên’s mother, “language is a map to help you figure out where you are. If you can’t read the map, you’re lost.” So how can Tiên, who speaks mostly English, find his way to his mother, who speaks mostly Vietnamese? How can he come out to her when he doesn’t even have the right words?</p>
<p>The answer, as it turns out, is fairy tales, which Tiên’s mother asks him to read to her every evening. Though the tales Tiên reads are different from the ones his mother grew up with in Vietnam, his mother can see that their bones are the same. She sees her own experience reflected in these tales, too: the fear of fleeing her war-torn country, the hardship of working long hours to make a living, the joy to be found in marriage and in this new, relatively safe land. The familiar patterns and vocabulary of fairy tales form a comfortable middle ground for mother and son, a meeting place between cultures, between languages, and—as it sometimes seems to Tiên’s mother—between worlds.</p>
<p>Tiên is the first in his family in multiple ways: first to grow up in America, first to go to a school dance, first to come out as gay (as far as he knows). The timelessness of fairy tales, then, is both a comfort and a hindrance. Neither Tiên nor the librarian he consults is able to find the word for “gay” in Vietnamese; in English, Tiên doesn’t know how to get through to his mother when the only vernacular they share is fantasy. At the same time, his mother can sense that there are things Tiên doesn’t think he can tell her, and as she struggles to reach for him across the oceans and continents she cannot help but see between them.</p>
<p>All this, told in the sparse narration of a graphic novel—in this case, one of the most gorgeously illustrated graphic novels I’ve ever seen. I didn’t want to spoil anything by including pages from the book, so here is a page, singular, that demonstrates author and artist Trung Le Nguyen’s color-coding technique without revealing any of the sumptuous fairy tale outfits before you have the chance to find a copy of <i>The Magic Fish</i> for yourself.</p>
<figure id="attachment_24323" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-24323" style="width: 714px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-24323 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_url_https___static.onecms-714x1024.png" alt="" width="714" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_url_https___static.onecms-714x1024.png 714w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_url_https___static.onecms-209x300.png 209w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_url_https___static.onecms-768x1102.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_url_https___static.onecms-1071x1536.png 1071w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_url_https___static.onecms.png 1394w" sizes="(max-width: 714px) 100vw, 714px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-24323" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Trung Le Nguyen</figcaption></figure>
<p>The panels are color-coded by timeline, yellow for past, red for present, and blue for fairy tale. It’s simple, yet ingenious: In addition to keeping the timelines straight, the color-coding amplifies the divide between mother and son on the page. Tiên does not appear in the yellow panels of his mother’s past, and she does not appear in some of the red panels, when Tiên is at school or with his friends. Even the blue panels differ in their depiction of fairy-tale maidens depending on who is telling the tale. Nguyen draws from Hong Kong wuxia films, Audrey Hepburn, and the áo dài to reflect the imaginations of various characters, resulting in the kind of gowns you absolutely have to wear to your wedding, even if you’re not at all a gown- or wedding-type of person. Did you think I was kidding when I said “sumptuous fairy tale outfits”? Nguyen pulled out all the stops, and then, for good measure, also peppered in lots of stars and celestial imagery, which is always a win in my space-enthusiast book. The amount of thought and care that went into every single page of this graphic novel is evident in the addendum at the end of the book (from which this review draws its title), which details the inspirations behind the fairy tales and fashion therein.</p>
<p>There is something inarticulately sad and hopeful about a child seeking to convey an important message to his mother through fairy tales because it is the only lens through which he knows she understands him, when fairy tales are so often used by parents to convey important messages to their children because it is the only lens through which they know their children will understand them. Nguyen’s deft hands have crafted a beautiful narrative that will make you nostalgic for the fairy tales of your own childhood while simultaneously queering and subverting the two-dimensional, fairy tale-like trope of the immigrant success story.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Indelible Queerness of Captain Philippa Georgiou</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-the-indelible-queerness-of-captain-philippa-georgiou/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Renn Tan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Celestial Queerscapes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22878</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Warning: the following contains spoilers for Star Trek: Discovery. It has been nearly three and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_22879" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22879" style="width: 730px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-22879 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ready-1024x913.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="651" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ready-1024x913.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ready-300x267.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ready-768x685.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/ready.jpg 1068w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22879" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: CBS</figcaption></figure>
<p><em><strong>Warning: the following contains spoilers for </strong></em><strong>Star Trek: Discovery</strong><em><strong>.</strong></em></p>
<p>It has been nearly three and a half years since the premiere of <i>Star Trek: Discovery</i>, when the hype surrounding Captain Philippa Georgiou—widely promoted as the first Asian captain since Hikaru Sulu and the first Malaysian in Trek, ever—ended abruptly in her death just two episodes into the series. Many fans who had been excited to see a woman of color at the helm were <a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2018/02/star-trek-discovery-michelle-yeoh-interview-emperor-georgiou-1201926766/">shocked and disappointed</a>, not just that the show had fridged her so quickly, but also when her body was later revealed to have been cannibalized by Klingons, and a twisted version of her character revived for the next two and a half seasons.</p>
<p>When asked about prime Georgiou, showrunner Alex Kurtzmann stated, “<a href="https://ew.com/tv/2017/09/24/star-trek-discovery-premiere-interview/">Yes, 100 percent, she’s really dead.</a>” Yet she lives on in the show in countless little ways: her heirloom telescope visible in the background of Saru’s quarters, Michael sharing a memory of her with Tilly as the latter prepares to take the conn for the first time. But it’s not her leadership style or beloved possessions that have garnered her a devoted following in fandom spaces. It’s the unmistakable air of queerness about her character.</p>
<p>When we’re first introduced to Georgiou and <i>Discovery</i>’s leading woman, Michael Burnham, they’re taking a walk alone on a desert planet, which is pretty gay. They’re having light banter that could be read as flirtation about whether or not they’re lost, which is very gay. If they don’t make it back to the ship in time, the colossal storm brewing overhead is going to strand them on the planet with nothing and no one but each other for 89 years, which is extremely gay. Burnham questions her with increasing frustration as Georgiou calmly finds them a way out, which ends up working, resulting in Burnham directing a look that’s halfway between frustration and wonder at her. Basically, Georgiou immediately comes across as a soft dom who loves to tease her long-suffering sub, a dynamic so sapphic that <a href="https://www.autostraddle.com/every-major-star-trek-character-ranked-by-lesbianism-452811/?fbclid=IwAR0zZ1AouyK4p1E8OSn1Y1syE_aGxL8Q2euMUcLNKfWmXg2zQbPkWy61gjE">this definitive ranking of Star Trek women by lesbianism</a> put Georgiou at #4, behind only Tasha Yar, a couple of extras seen dancing together, and actual canon lesbian Jett Reno.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22880" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22880" style="width: 1000px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22880 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/crepusculan.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="581" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/crepusculan.jpg 1000w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/crepusculan-300x174.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/crepusculan-768x446.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22880" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: CBS</figcaption></figure>
<p>As if her character’s introduction wasn’t enough, the tension between Georgiou and Burnham flies off the charts in later scenes, in a series of charged confrontations that unintentionally spark the Federation-Klingon war. Though you could argue that a large part of that is simply the power difference inherent in any superior/subordinate relationship, Georgiou’s reaction to Burnham’s act of mutiny is an emotional lashing out, betraying deep personal hurt. The show makes no attempt to hide the fact that Georgiou and Burnham’s relationship goes beyond that of a captain and her first officer—in fact, that was the writing team’s intention. Unfortunately, the writing team later ruins this by deciding that Georgiou sees Burnham as a daughter, which, if anything, is an indicator of society’s inability to view older women as anything other than maternal figures. (This happens again with mirror Georgiou’s departure in season 3; Burnham describes her as “like a mother, almost; like a sister, almost,” which is really just kind of weird.)</p>
<p>Despite this “mothering,” Georgiou/Burnham remains the most popular ship for fans of her character, who cheerfully ignore canon in favor of imagined worlds where Georgiou is alive and well and never thought of her first officer as her daughter. The age difference between the characters is no barrier, either: after all, the hallmarks of sapphic pop culture include the movie <i>Carol</i> (2015) and power couple Holland Taylor and Sarah Paulson, the former featuring a comparable age gap, the latter, an even greater one. Even those who don’t ship Georgiou with Burnham overwhelmingly headcanon her as queer, despite the franchise’s best efforts to straightwash her with an ex-husband and a male lover in the <i>Discovery</i> novel tie-ins. But perhaps the most compelling evidence (to non-sapphics, at least; I maintain that the desert scene is peak lesbianism) is the threesome mirror Georgiou is shown having with a couple of Orions, one male, one female. If this Georgiou is meant to resemble her prime universe counterpart in every way save tendency towards murder, then surely prime Georgiou, too, is bi- or pansexual.</p>
<p>Why does it matter that Georgiou is queer? Simply put, it matters because her character is groundbreaking in so many other ways. Georgiou is neither white nor male and speaks with a distinctly Malaysian accent without it being a caricature of her ethnicity or nationality. She is sarcastic and playful, which makes her funny in a way Asian characters aren’t often allowed to be. Most of all, she’s in a high-ranking leadership role, something real-life Asian Americans continue to be barred from. Her being queer doesn’t just help to combat the dearth of sapphic Asian representation in media. It allows queer people of color to see themselves in positions of power where they can affect real change in the world, turning the principle message of her character—“I was a human who had seen a life of loss, but still chose hope”—into a rallying cry to retain tenderness for themselves and others even as they fight viciously for what is right.</p>
<p>It matters, too, that prime Georgiou is queer as well as mirror Georgiou, because mirror Georgiou is a genocidal dictator and a walking leather fetish, which feeds into the the <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2015/10/tvs-evil-bisexuals-still-live/412786/">evil bi stereotype</a> and hypersexualization of East Asian women and is therefore arguably terrible queer representation. It matters that prime Georgiou is queer so we remember to be outraged at her death as the first in a series of <a href="https://www.syfy.com/syfywire/star-trek-discoverys-trans-representation-is-both-groundbreaking-and-heartbreaking">heartbreaking writing decisions</a> regarding the show’s queer and trans characters. It matters that prime Georgiou is queer because her name appears on the list of <a href="https://comicbook.com/startrek/news/star-trek-best-captains/">Starfleet’s most highly decorated captains</a>. In our present, where so much of queer history and so many queer people in history are only just starting to be remembered, Georgiou’s name on that list symbolizes a future where neither the person nor their queerness is forcibly erased from memory. Where the contributions of queer people of color are not simply acknowledged, but celebrated on a universal scale.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22881" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22881" style="width: 730px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-22881" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/georgiou-1024x512.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="365" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/georgiou-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/georgiou-300x150.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/georgiou-768x384.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/georgiou-1536x768.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/georgiou-1110x555.jpg 1110w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/georgiou.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22881" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: CBS</figcaption></figure>
<p>It has been nearly three and a half years since Georgiou’s appearance on <i>Discovery</i>, but she has left an indelible mark on the lives of those who saw themselves represented in her for the first time. Through her legacy, the hope of a brighter future lives on: a world where a Malaysian woman can be a captain, command respect, playfully sass her first officer-slash-girlfriend, and bestow nuggets of wisdom upon her crew in the same breath.</p>
<p><em>Written in honor of <a href="https://wearecaptaingeorgiou.tumblr.com/post/639977157676892160/captain-georgiou-january-february-january-15">Captain Georgiou January &#8211; February</a>, a month-long event organized by the team at <a href="https://wearecaptaingeorgiou.tumblr.com/">We Are Captain Georgiou</a> (who are also putting together an appreciation fanbook). The event ends on February 15, but the fanbook will continue accepting submissions after that. All are welcome—come join in the festivities and/or submit to the fanbook!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dystopian Sci-Fi As the World Ends: Relevant Wisdom from Three Soviet-Era Works</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dystopian-sci-fi-as-the-world-ends-relevant-wisdom-from-three-soviet-era-works/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Renn Tan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 15:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Celestial Queerscapes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In March 2020, life as we knew it ground to a halt. Schools closed, businesses&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In March 2020, life as we knew it ground to a halt. Schools closed, businesses meetings transitioned to Zoom, and people started panic-hoarding toilet paper.</p>
<p>I was neck-deep in the process of writing (or, more accurately, thinking about writing) my undergraduate senior thesis. For the most part, my life didn’t really change in lockdown: I had planned to shut myself in my room all semester to crank out that thesis, anyway. There was, however, one notable change. Whenever I told someone my thesis was on science fiction, their response—which, pre-lockdown, had ranged from “Uh, okay” to “That sounds awesome!”—was some variant of, “Oh. That must be interesting, considering, you know,” followed by a vague gesture clearly meant to encompass, well, everything.</p>
<p>If you’re here reading <em>LSQ</em>, I don’t have to tell you just how timeless and relevant science fiction as a genre tends to be. That said, here are some nuggets of wisdom from two Soviet-era novels and a short story I was studying as the world seemingly came to an end.</p>
<h3>Yevgeny Zamyatin’s <em>We</em> (1924)</h3>
<figure id="attachment_22694" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22694" style="width: 659px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22694 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/we-659x1024.jpg" alt="" width="659" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/we-659x1024.jpg 659w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/we-193x300.jpg 193w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/we-768x1193.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/we-989x1536.jpg 989w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/we-1319x2048.jpg 1319w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/we.jpg 1549w" sizes="(max-width: 659px) 100vw, 659px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22694" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Modern Library</figcaption></figure>
<p>Set in the distant future, Zamyatin’s totalitarian One State rules the world with mathematical precision. Enter D-503, Builder of the Integral, a spacecraft meant to conquer other planets. He is a model citizen until the day he meets I-330, an anarchic femme fatale who introduces him to the possibility of a way of life other than the Vulcan-like logic prescribed by the State. Spiraling in existential dread, D-503 is helpless to resist his feelings for her, becoming tangled in a web of resistance and rebel activity.</p>
<p>When I-330 asks him to help her steal the Integral, he balks, stating that the One State cannot be overthrown. I-330 asks him to name the final number. When he cannot, she explains that, just as there is no final number, there is and will never be a final revolution. It is the nature of society to change and evolve, and that change must come through protest, resistance, and dissent.</p>
<p>With the endless bad news that seems to pour in through every outlet, any small advance or improvement may be swept away in a current of pessimism. It’s especially difficult to think of change when our very lives depend on not doing anything. But it’s important to remember that, right now, every day that you wake up and get out of bed is an act of resistance—even the days when you don’t, but decide not to beat yourself up about it. We stay indoors and try our best, and we continue to fight for what we believe in when we can. Maybe it doesn’t look like it’s doing anything right now, but, in a few years or decades or even centuries, you may be surprised to see just how much change came out of your small daily acts of revolution.</p>
<h3>Mikhail Bulgakov’s <em>The Fatal Eggs</em> (1925)</h3>
<figure id="attachment_22695" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22695" style="width: 667px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-22695" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fatal-eggs-667x1024.jpg" alt="" width="667" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fatal-eggs-667x1024.jpg 667w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fatal-eggs-195x300.jpg 195w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fatal-eggs-768x1179.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fatal-eggs-1001x1536.jpg 1001w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fatal-eggs-1334x2048.jpg 1334w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fatal-eggs.jpg 1524w" sizes="(max-width: 667px) 100vw, 667px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22695" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Alma Books</figcaption></figure>
<p>When Professor Persikov discovers a “red ray” capable of accelerating the rate of binary fission, the Soviet government is quick to seize it as a quick fix to the ongoing chicken plague (which resulted in the extermination of all chickens within the Soviet Union). What begins as a well-intentioned, if hasty, idea—importing chicken eggs from Germany and irradiating them with the ray—soon turns disastrous, when the chicken eggs are mistakenly sent to Persikov, and the ostrich and snake eggs that Persikov ordered for a different experiment are sent to the government farm and unknowingly irradiated. The resulting giant ostriches and snakes go on a rampage through the countryside, costing many innocent lives and nearly destroying Moscow in the process.</p>
<p>Satire of Soviet leadership aside, this novel provides a timely reminder that there is no quick and instant fix to a large-scale problem. Keep your masks on and continue social distancing after you’ve gotten vaccinated, kids—and beware of rampaging snakes in the meantime.</p>
<h3>Sever Gansovsky’s “Vincent Van Gogh” (1970)</h3>
<figure id="attachment_22696" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22696" style="width: 730px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-22696" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/potato-eaters-1024x722.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="515" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/potato-eaters-1024x722.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/potato-eaters-300x212.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/potato-eaters-768x542.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/potato-eaters.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22696" class="wp-caption-text">The short story only appears in English translation in &#8220;Aliens, Travelers and Other Strangers: New Science Fiction from the Soviet Union&#8221; (1984), which I couldn&#8217;t find a good cover photo of. Instead, here&#8217;s Vincent van Gogh&#8217;s &#8220;The Potato Eaters,&#8221; which is an important plot device in the short story.</figcaption></figure>
<p>In a world where time travel has been invented, but is strictly regulated, an enterprising man illegally travels back in time to try and obtain van Gogh’s paintings before they were famous in order to make a fortune in the present. Unfortunately, something goes wrong with his plan each time, and he finds himself returning again and again to different points in Van Gogh’s life. Somewhere along the way, the get-rich-quick scheme turns into a surprisingly poignant piece on memory, suffering, and the value of art. At its core is the message that we as individual human beings are fleeting, but our actions, intentions, and self-expression live on long after we are gone.</p>
<p>May 2021 be filled with your own creation in whatever form that takes, be it writing, art, knitting, making space and time for the things you love, or creating a self you feel comfortable in. I leave you with what is not necessarily a piece of wisdom, but a spot of encouragement from “Vincent Van Gogh” in the concluding paragraph of my senior thesis:</p>
<p>“We look to science fiction for reassurance of a tomorrow, but science fiction is rooted in the past, in experiences already lived. It falls to us, now, to build the world of our future. In the words of Gansovsky, ‘So don’t ask what tomorrow will be. If you want it to be glorious and beautiful, make it that way.’”</p>
<p><em>For more recommendations of Soviet sci-fi authors to read, see <a href="https://www.rbth.com/arts/332685-best-soviet-sci-fi-writers">here</a>. For recommendations of contemporary post-Soviet dystopian novels, see <a href="https://www.rbth.com/arts/2014/12/10/best_russian_dystopian_novels_40265">here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Speculative Fiction Anthologies by BIPOC Authors to Give to Your Favorite Niblings This Holiday Season</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/5-speculative-fiction-anthologies-by-bipoc-authors-to-give-to-your-favorite-niblings-this-holiday-season/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/5-speculative-fiction-anthologies-by-bipoc-authors-to-give-to-your-favorite-niblings-this-holiday-season/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 16:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Celestial Queerscapes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Still looking for the perfect gift for a loved one this December? Not celebrating any&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Still looking for the perfect gift for a loved one this December? Not celebrating any holidays at this time of year, but want to diversify your shelf with more quality BIPOC reads? LSQ has got you covered with this handy-dandy list of titles that your speculative fiction-loving <a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/words-at-play/words-were-watching-nibling">niblings</a> are sure to enjoy as much as you will!</p>
<p>All five titles on this list are anthologies written by multiple authors, and published in either 2019 or 2020. This is to ensure that the recipient of the book is presented with a range of styles and themes, so they’re more likely to find something in there that they like—and a more recent publication date decreases the likelihood that they own the book already.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>Love After the End: An Anthology of Two-Spirit and Indigiqueer Speculative Fiction</em></h2>
<figure id="attachment_22456" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22456" style="width: 683px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22456 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/love-1-683x1024.jpg" alt="" width="683" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/love-1-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/love-1-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/love-1-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/love-1.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22456" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Arsenal Pulp Press</figcaption></figure>
<p>This collection of nine stories by as many writers—all of them Indigenous and 2SQ (Two-Spirit and queer)—takes decolonizing the genre one step further by centering Indigenous perspectives in boldly imagined worlds. These stories question the colonial nature of space exploration and settlement, challenge the whitewashed face of technological development, and highlight the devastating future that will result from present-day ecocide. All this, with casts of all-gendered characters who use a variety of pronouns and find queer love that doesn’t end in tragedy. Found families and 2S and trans validation abound. If there is a single point this anthology proves, it is that the future is both unabashedly Indigenous and gloriously queer.</p>
<p>For me, the strength of the individual pieces varies somewhat between “not bad” and “this author cleverly addressed so many complex issues that I feel the need to lie down after reading this,” which is to say I liked it very much and wished the collection was twice as long.</p>
<p><strong>Standout story: </strong>“How to Survive the Apocalypse for Native Girls” by Kai Minosh Pyle<br />
<strong>Contributors:</strong> Joshua Whitehead (editor), Nathan Adler, Darcie Little Badger, Gabriel Castilloux Calderon, Adam Garnet Jones, Mari Kurisato, Kai Minosh Pyle, David Alexander Robertson, jaye simpson, Nazbah Tom</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>A Phoenix First Must Burn: Sixteen Stories of Black Girl Magic, Resistance, and Hope</em></h2>
<figure id="attachment_22457" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22457" style="width: 683px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22457 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/phoenix-683x1024.jpg" alt="" width="683" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/phoenix-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/phoenix-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/phoenix-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/phoenix-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/phoenix-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/phoenix.jpg 1650w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22457" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Viking</figcaption></figure>
<p>Rife with ancient spirituality, mermaids, and physics-defying superpowers, this anthology is crammed full of the most spectacular stories you’ll read this year. Though some are more fantastical than others, every single one of these stories is deeply rooted in history and tradition, from the first major slave revolt in the Americas to a Yoruba goddess. There are space orcs and boo hags. There’s a familial curse and an app designed to perfectly predict your future. In keeping with centuries-long speculative fiction tradition, there’s even <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lesbian_vampire">a WLW vampire</a>.</p>
<p>What I love most about this collection is the diversity of Black cultures and experiences it represents. Enslaved Afro-Latinx people, Black people in the Old West, Black students at a majority-white school, a retelling of a Greek myth through the lens of hair-braiding, Caribbean lore, Gullah/Geechee lore, Southern folk magic—there are as many unique and creative perspectives as there are bestselling, award-winning authors. i.e. all sixteen of them.</p>
<p><strong>Standout story:</strong> “Gilded” by Elizabeth Acevedo<br />
<strong>Contributors:</strong> Patrice Caldwell (also editor), Amerie, Elizabeth Acevedo, Rebecca Roanhorse, Alaya Dawn Johnson, Sumayyah Daud, Justina Ireland, L.L. McKinney, Dhonielle Clayton, Danny Lore, Ibi Zoboi, Danielle Paige, Ashley Woodfolk, Charlotte Nicole Davis, Karen Strong, J. Marcelle Corrie</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>New Suns: Original Speculative Fiction by People of Color</em></h2>
<figure id="attachment_22458" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22458" style="width: 670px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22458 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/suns-670x1024.jpg" alt="" width="670" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/suns-670x1024.jpg 670w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/suns-196x300.jpg 196w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/suns-768x1174.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/suns-1004x1536.jpg 1004w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/suns-1339x2048.jpg 1339w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/suns.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22458" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Solaris</figcaption></figure>
<p>This anthology is a bit more varied, as it features seventeen authors of different races, ethnicities, and cultural backgrounds. Which is not to say that the overall quality of the book is any less, only that the stories aren’t as interconnected without underlying themes that are common to all of them. I would argue that <em>New Suns</em>’ variation is actually its strength: anyone could pick this book up and find a story inside it that they like, because so many different faces, traditions, and beliefs are represented in it.</p>
<p>These stories run a whole gamut of tones and styles, from the depressing hilarity of alien tourists in an even more over-commercialized Manhattan to a softer, lyrical voice in a piece on devouring children. Some stories tend towards horror; others, comedy; still others, mythology. The one area in which the anthology does not vary is in quality: the authors range from established to emerging, and it is both a testament to Nisi Shawl’s curatorship and the barriers to publication for BIPOC that, if you did not know which authors were which, you would think they all fell into the former category.</p>
<p><strong>Standout story:</strong> “The Freedom of the Shifting Sea” by Jaymee Goh<br />
<strong>Contributors:</strong> Nisi Shawl (editor), LeVar Burton (foreword), Tobias S. Bucknell, Kathleen Alcalá, Minsoo Kang, Steven Barnes, Chinelo Onwualu, Alex Jennings, Alberto Yáñez, Jaymee Goh, E. Lily Yu, Karin Lowachee, Silvia Moreno-Garcia, Indrapramit Das, Anil Menon, Andrea Hairston, Hiromi Goto, Rebecca Roanhorse, Darcie Little Badger</p>
<p>I’ll be honest: I haven’t read these next two books yet, but I feel confident in recommending them anyway. (You&#8217;ll see why.)</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>Latinx Rising: An Anthology of Latinx Science Fiction and Fantasy</em></h2>
<figure id="attachment_22459" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22459" style="width: 683px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22459 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rising-683x1024.jpg" alt="" width="683" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rising-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rising-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rising-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rising.jpg 907w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22459" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Mad Creek Books</figcaption></figure>
<p><em>Latinx Rising</em> was clearly a labor of love for editor Matthew David Goodwin, whose work on this anthology grew into his most recent project, <em><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/fordreamers/speculative-fiction-for-dreamers">Speculative Fiction for Dreamers</a></em> (forthcoming in August 2021), which is described as “the book that we wish had existed when we were younger and certainly want to exist for our children as they enter adolescence and begin to navigate their identity in the ever-shifting cultural landscape of the U.S.”</p>
<p>The anthology contains a whopping 20 stories—all previously published, many from prominent Latinx writers such as Carmen Maria Machado and Kathleen Alcalá. I’ve read some of these stories and some of these writers in other places, and just knowing that they’re a part of this project makes me excited to read it in the hopefully-not-too-distant future. In a fun crossover event, Richie Narvaez’s story, “Room for Rent,” was <a href="https://omny.fm/shows/levar-burton-reads/room-for-rent-by-richie-narvaez">read on <em>LeVar Burton Reads</em></a> by, well, LeVar Burton, who also wrote the foreword of <em>New Suns</em>, which also includes a story by Kathleen Alcalá.</p>
<p><strong>Contributors:</strong> Matthew David Goodwin (editor), Frederick Luis Aldama (introduction), Kathleen Alcalá, Pablo Brescia, Pedro Zagitt, Sabrina Vourvoulias, Daína Chaviano, ADÁL, Ana Castillo, Ernest Hogan, Junot Díaz, Richie Narvaez. Edmundo Paz-Soldán, Steve Castro, Alex Hernandez, Carmen Maria Machado, Giannina Braschi, Carlos Hernandez, Alejandra Sanchez, Daniel José Older, Carl Marcum, Marcos Santiago Gonzalez</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><em>Broken Stars: Contemporary Chinese Science Fiction in Translation</em></h2>
<figure id="attachment_22460" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22460" style="width: 663px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22460 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/stars-663x1024.jpg" alt="" width="663" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/stars-663x1024.jpg 663w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/stars-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/stars-768x1187.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/stars-994x1536.jpg 994w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/stars-1325x2048.jpg 1325w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/stars.jpg 1650w" sizes="(max-width: 663px) 100vw, 663px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22460" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Tor Books</figcaption></figure>
<p>I may not have read the sixteen stories in <em>Broken Stars</em>, but I devoured Ken Liu’s previous anthology of Chinese science fiction in translation, <em>Invisible Planets</em>. Ken Liu is not only a masterful author in his own right; he’s a formidable translator and editor. One of the highlights of <em>Invisible Planets</em> for me was the inclusion of three nonfiction essays on Chinese science fiction, by Chinese authors. <em>Broken Stars</em> likewise includes three new essays, and—<em>if Invisible Planets</em> was anything to go by—I am certain they will make me reconsider the genre and its Western-centrism, as well as the very nature of writing as an art form.</p>
<p>Despite all the stories in the book being translated by the same person, the breathtaking depth and breadth of range across the stories in <em>Invisible Planets</em> proved beyond doubt in my mind Ken Liu’s mastery of both Chinese and English, and his prioritization of the author’s voice above all. I can only imagine his skill has grown in the three years between <em>Invisible Planets</em>’ publication and <em>Broken Stars</em>’.</p>
<p><strong>Contributors:</strong> Ken Liu (editor, translator), Xia Jia, Zhang Ran, Rang Fei, Han Song, Cheng Jingbo, Baoshu, Hao Jingfang, Fei Dao, Liu Cixin, Anna Wu, Ma Boyong, Gu Shi, Regina Kanyu Wang, Chen Qiufan, Mingway Song</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/5-speculative-fiction-anthologies-by-bipoc-authors-to-give-to-your-favorite-niblings-this-holiday-season/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shoots for the Moon, Lands… Mostly In Pieces: A Review of Netflix’s “Over the Moon”</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/shoots-for-the-moon-lands-mostly-in-pieces-a-review-of-netflixs-over-the-moon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Renn Tan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 13:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Celestial Queerscapes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22126</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was so ready to hate Over the Moon (2020). Mulan (1998) set the bar&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was so ready to hate <em>Over the Moon</em> (2020). <em>Mulan</em> (1998) set the bar for Chinese representation in film low, and the 2020 live-action remake, despite its claims of greater authenticity and representation, somehow managed to lower the bar even further. Even the acclaimed <em>Crazy Rich Asians</em> (2018) fell flat in its attempt to highlight the diversity of Chinese diasporic experiences to me. Having thus been disappointed repeatedly by Hollywood, I went into this film with low expectations, even though the premise—local girl builds rocket ship, flies to moon in search of goddess—sounded like a dream come true.</p>
<p>I was prepared to be let down. And I was. But I also found myself crying less than eight minutes into the film—the first of several times I’d shed tears within the hour-and-a-half runtime.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22127" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22127" style="width: 455px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22127" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/poster-691x1024.jpg" alt="" width="455" height="674" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/poster-691x1024.jpg 691w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/poster-203x300.jpg 203w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/poster-768x1138.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/poster-1037x1536.jpg 1037w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/poster-1383x2048.jpg 1383w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/poster.jpg 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 455px) 100vw, 455px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22127" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Netflix</figcaption></figure>
<p>Produced by Netflix, <em>Over the Moon</em> is an animated film based on <a href="https://mythopedia.com/chinese-mythology/gods/chang-e/">the legend of Chang’e</a>, who drank the elixir of immortality and flew up and away from her lover, tragically parting them forever. That’s not the only legend in the film: The director is Glen Keane of Disney animation fame, and the star-studded cast includes Phillipa Soo (Hamilton), Ken Jeong (Crazy Rich Asians), and John Cho (Star Trek), with <a href="https://deadline.com/video/over-the-moon-trailer-cast-ken-jeong-john-cho-sandra-oh-netflix-video/">even more familiar names</a> in blink-and-you’ll-miss-it roles. The story follows Fei Fei, a spunky teenage engineer who clings to the legend of Chang’e like a lifeline after her mother passes away. If this feels tropey and derivative—how many animated mothers have we lost to an undefined (but strongly suggested to be cancer) disease?—it’s because it is. To show how much Fei Fei is obsessed with all things lunar, she’s given a pet rabbit (a reference to the rabbit in the moon), and her room is full of space-themed paraphernalia. In case you still didn’t get the point, her family’s bakery is also famous for their Mid-Autumn Festival mooncakes. (This film is many things, and “subtle” isn’t one of them. More on this later.)</p>
<p>Fei Fei wants to go to the moon to prove Chang’e is real and still pining after her lost love, because this will prove to her father that love is true and eternal, and he’ll remember he’s still in love with her dead mother and won’t move on with the woman he’s now engaged to. Clearly, what Fei Fei really needs is grief counseling. Instead, she MacGyvers together a rocket ship, straps in with her rabbit and a couple of stowaways (her annoying soon-to-be-stepbrother and his pet frog), and takes off.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22128" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22128" style="width: 384px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22128" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-9.38.27-PM-300x165.png" alt="" width="384" height="211" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-9.38.27-PM-300x165.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-9.38.27-PM-1024x563.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-9.38.27-PM-768x422.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-9.38.27-PM.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 384px) 100vw, 384px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22128" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Netflix</figcaption></figure>
<p>Up to this point, the slices of life in Fei Fei’s Chinese village—and by “Chinese,” I mean actually set in a China that is modern, real, and both beautifully and accurately detailed—have been visually stunning, sweet and homey in the sort of way that makes you miss your grandmother’s cooking. But the lunar landscape she crash-lands on is an abrupt turn into neon wonderland. Think <em>Just Dance</em>, with its simple outlines, pop tunes, and bright colors. Add Chang’e, moon goddess-turned-K-pop star (complete with <a href="https://www.thestar.com.my/lifestyle/entertainment/2020/06/25/new-animated-musical-039over-the-moon039-features-designs-by-chinese-couturier-guo-pei">couture clothing</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UXgJrZnchwQ">snappy choreography</a>), and you’ve got the moon-city of Lunaria. It’s bright, fun, cutesy, and soulless. Apart from Chang’e, the aforementioned rabbit on the moon, and some sentient mooncakes, there is nothing even remotely Chinese about it. Though I’m sure it was intentionally styled as such, the animation even looks flat and unfinished, more 2- than 3D in its rendering of background shapes.</p>
<p>I’m not really going to get into the second half of the film, partly to avoid spoilers, partly because, well, nothing much happens. Fei Fei spends most of her time talking to a dorky, lovable glowworm, having been split up from both her rabbit and her stepbrother, which seems somewhat counterintuitive to the film’s message: that you can’t get back what’s lost, only move forward with the family who have rallied around you in support. Every opportunity to hammer this message home is taken, up to and including having the big, angsty climax revolve around it. I could see it coming from miles away. 238,856 miles, to be exact—the average distance from Earth to the moon.</p>
<p>I was about to honest-to-god roll my eyes when a slight twist—somehow both utterly predictable and gut-wrenching—had me tearing up instead. Then Philippa Soo’s golden voice started singing through Chang’e in Mandarin, and let me tell you: Reader, I bawled my eyes out.</p>
<p>Maybe it was the song, with its lyrics seamlessly weaving between Mandarin and English. Maybe it was how the three-minute-long scene was styled to look, sound, and feel like it came straight out of a Chinese folktale. Whatever the case, everything snapped together in that moment, and I realized that the flat emptiness of Lunaria had been crafted with this return to the heart of the Chang’e legend in mind. The contrast helped the emotional beat land, and land hard. I still wished we hadn’t spent quite so much time in that neon landscape, but I could see through my tears that it had had its desired effect.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22129" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22129" style="width: 290px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22129" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-9.37.29-PM-1024x551.png" alt="" width="290" height="156" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-9.37.29-PM-1024x551.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-9.37.29-PM-300x161.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-9.37.29-PM-768x413.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Screen-Shot-2020-11-13-at-9.37.29-PM.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 290px) 100vw, 290px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22129" class="wp-caption-text">Copyright: Netflix</figcaption></figure>
<p>I’m not sure if I would recommend this movie. The songs, apart from the one I mentioned above, are neither catchy nor memorable. The storytelling remains formulaic and trope-ridden. I absolutely adore Fei Fei and her brilliant engineering mind and affinity for space, but I can’t say the same for any of the anthropomorphic animal sidekicks, of which there are several too many. The film certainly doesn’t cheapen Chang’e, but I didn’t think it did her full justice, either. It’s a shame, because I can see how much potential <em>Over the Moon</em> had to be incredible, if only the second half were more purposeful, more character-driven, more grounded in its Chinese roots.</p>
<p>I’ll say this: if you’re looking for vapid whimsy with a generous helping of grief, or if you live with a child of Disney age, or if you—like me—are a sucker for space and solid Chinese representation and scruffy-haired girls in STEM, this is a decent movie for a lazy night in. Fair warning, though: you might want to keep the tissues handy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
