<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>E. Young &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/e-young/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 03:20:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Review: &#8220;Graverobbing Negress Seeks Employment&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-graverobbing-negress-seeks-employment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[E. Young]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Editor&#8217;s note: this post was originally written in spring 2017, when FIYAH, a literary magazine&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>[Editor&#8217;s note: this post was originally written in spring 2017, when <a href="https://www.fiyahlitmag.com/issues/">FIYAH</a>, a literary magazine of black speculative fiction, had just published its second issue. This post is blogger E. Young&#8217;s review of what she found in that second issue. LSQ is happy to note that FIYAH continues to publish on a quarterly basis and is in its second year.] </em></p>
<p>First, I want to mention how robust the issue is this time around. They&#8217;re getting bigger! We have a novel excerpt, an indie spotlight corner, some sweet merch (THAT COVER ART THO!), and a Spotify playlist going on so please <a href="http://www.fiyahlitmag.com/issues/issue-2-spilling-tea/">check out the website</a>. With that being said, of course we&#8217;re here for the stories and they are excellent but I wanted to single one out in particular because it&#8230;well, it vexed me!</p>
<p>&#8220;Graverobbing Negress Seeks Employment&#8221; by Eden Royce takes the theme of spilling tea, to me, in a few different directions. If you&#8217;re not up to date on your genteel slang, to spill tea is simply to gossip mightily or in some instances tell a cold, hard truth about something (usually someone). The literal tea element is here, of course, with the Life Everlasting tea which does&#8230;well, guess. Then there is the rumor or gossip element that chugs the meat of the plot forward. And then there&#8217;s the twist at the end that reveals a cold, hard truth that shakes the reader and Prosper to the core. I had about as many questions as she did, the biggest one being &#8220;WHY?&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/beth-tate-188119-unsplash.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10301 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/beth-tate-188119-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>Now of course, in stories and cinema we are used to asking ourselves why knowing damn well there is no real why, and here is pretty much the same. There&#8217;s no why to senseless violence against one&#8217;s own people under the cover of racism, and that freaked me out a bit. It freaked me out a bit but I also wished it could have been expanded out a bit. Not in the name of making a grand political statement or some deeper meaning, but the chill still felt a bit short. But at the same time I wouldn&#8217;t ask for a series or a longer novella or novel, because the impact is captured in the shortness of a single night and one (probably) last mission.</p>
<p>But in the end, this ended up becoming one of my favorite stories in the issue. The atmosphere was very <em>Eve&#8217;s Bayou </em>meets <em>Candyman</em>. And I&#8217;m sure you all know by know how hard I pop for American South lit that isn&#8217;t all ooga-booga Hollywood voodoo, although there are subtle traces of voudou represented here. And it&#8217;s written in first person dialect? Hell yeah. Give it a read and the rest of the stories here in this issue, pick up issue #1 (<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-fiyah-issue-1-rebirth/">my thoughts on it</a>) if you haven&#8217;t, I know <em>FIYAH</em> is only going to get bigger and better from here on out!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Q-T-Pies, by Balogun Ojetade</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-q-t-pies-by-balogun-ojetade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[E. Young]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 15:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8376</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was gonna talk to you all about all sorts of topics related to this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft" src="https://images.gr-assets.com/books/1490705133l/34715254.jpg" alt="" width="318" height="412" />I was gonna talk to you all about all sorts of topics related to this book, like intra-race relations, misogyny, black women in horror, all those good things&#8230;but the more I read <em>Q-T-Pies</em> the more I just kept thinking&#8230;</p>
<p>&#8220;This isht is [bleep] up.&#8221;</p>
<p>Repeating over and over again like a broke record. Now, that&#8217;s not a bad thing—in fact, that was pretty much my first thought reading <em>Beloved</em> as a teenager. Yes, with swear words. Well, probably more like &#8220;this mess is [bleep] up.&#8221; But you know what, I like it.</p>
<p><em>Q-T-Pies</em> is book zero in the Savannah Swan files. Who that glorious person is you&#8217;ll learn later, but for now let&#8217;s talk about this early case. The novel starts out with a poignant short essay regarding the emergence of black horror in the current United States administration, and regardless of what side of the spectrum you fall on if any, it&#8217;s a good read. From there, we learn this story is set in Atlanta, and a new pop-up restaurant has opened. Run by three incredibly intelligent, alluring, sexy, beautiful black women, this new joint specializes in selling barbecued pot pies&#8230;wait a minute.</p>
<p>Barbecue pot pies? A pop-up diner? Atlanta? Wow, this may be the southernest I&#8217;ve felt in a while. In previous reviews of horror works set in the south, I have advocated doing something a lil&#8217; different&#8211;no more bayou witches and oversimplified witches for a while. So for a story to take place in modern Atlanta and tackle with the issue of fad dining and gentrification? Fantastic. Oh, if you&#8217;re not sure what a pot pie is, well, it&#8217;s&#8230;a pastry dish filled with veggies and or meats. Damn, I made myself hungry. The first half of the novel deals with feedings of various kinds and does a great job of assaulting your senses with smells, tastes, and interesting visuals that will make your mouth water and occasionally make you gag..</p>
<p>Forgive me for straying, but we learn that our intrepid hero reporter Derrel Lacey is on the beat. At this point you might be thinking, &#8220;hmm, we focus on female-centric works here&#8221; and yes, the protagonist is a man. But this plot is very much driven by women to the point where poor Derrel might as well be a side character in his own story. Ojetade gets us involved and does the great trick of revealing who the real protagonist here is as we start the second act into the third. Hint, but it ain&#8217;t the three aforementioned ladies&#8230;</p>
<p>Oh yes, what about these alluring sirens? Well, would it be a spoiler if I told you these immaculately described creatures are up to something shady? How about they are evil? Okay, they&#8217;re&#8230;well, they&#8217;re not vampires. I wish the book had expounded more upon their true natures because as described, they are basically perversions of science and magic wrapped up in mythology and it&#8217;s a little much. All I&#8217;m saying is I can see us hashtagging this on Instagram in the future. But how do we know they&#8217;re evil Because they are repeatedly described as inhumanly beautiful and intelligent.</p>
<p>Okay, that&#8217;s not fair. I don&#8217;t think it was Ojetade&#8217;s intention to set up these successful black women as the antagonists to the not-very-successful and kind of bumbling black man. This had me going back and forth for a bit&#8211;we have seen the trope before of ambition making people evil, but something weird happens when it&#8217;s implied to women. It implies that if women start reaching beyond their means, some kind of vicious karma and/or demon is going to smack them back to earth like a &#8220;oh no you don&#8217;t!&#8221; This can be spun around as symbolism like, say, patriarchy or aspects of kyriarchy holding women down. Here, it&#8217;s kind of an accident but just looks&#8230;well, it looks that way. Fortunately, as I said this book is very female-driven, so we are presented with a number of character archetypes that will let you focus on Ini, Dalmilola, and Chioma as the villains.</p>
<p>So, you might be wondering by now, seems pretty stock but good so far. What&#8217;s the messed up part? The isht being bleeped up is when we start to unravel just what the three sirens are, and their plans for Derrel. They&#8217;re not good plans. Similar to when I mention <em>Beloved</em> above, the messed up part is the cruelties inflicted upon Derrel and other characters is pretty shocking. Would it be more shocking if this involved white characters? Not more shocking but definitely on a different level. <em>Q-T-Pies</em> exists in a very real universe where we don&#8217;t have hashtag-woke conversations about supporting black business and community. No, here we have three black&#8230;beings inflicting damage on another black person, and a black female hero to save the day (that is Savannah Swan, if you haven&#8217;t caught my drift).</p>
<p>Unfortunately, we meet Savannah proper quite late in the novel, so to talk too much about her would be massive spoilers. And that would suck, because I definitely think <em>Q-T-Pies</em> is worth picking up. It is a quick read and will give you plenty to think about, salivate over, and maybe keep you up at night the next time a hot, trendy new restaurant opens up in your neighborhood. You just never know sometimes&#8230;pick it up from <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B06XWSXCDS/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1493081819&amp;sr=1-1">Amazon here</a>, and if you&#8217;re ready to just delve into the weird world of Savannah Swan, start here with <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B06XR4YGDD/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">A Haunting in the SWATS</a>. </em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Re-re-review: Wolf-Alice, by Angela Carter</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/re-re-review-wolf-alice-by-angela-carter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[E. Young]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 16:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I won&#8217;t lie, the first half of any new year is usually pretty tough for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I won&#8217;t lie, the first half of any new year is usually pretty tough for me mentally. Getting my financial biz together is usually the easy bit, then there&#8217;s adjusting to time changes, seasonal changes, seasonal depression going back to regular depression, and frankly by May I&#8217;m just tired of any contact besides wet kitty noses on my face.</p>
<p>A friend &amp; I recently had a conversation &#8230; see, she hates modern literature. I can&#8217;t say I blame her. If you don&#8217;t like to engage a text too much and you&#8217;re not here for envelope-pushing, genre-warping, and/or boundary pushing, most modern and postmodernism media isn&#8217;t going to be for you.</p>
<p>Me &#8230; well, as a reader, writer, and reviewer, I have a lot of issues in real life to work out through fiction. I will often use literature and TV (and music, but don&#8217;t make me sing y&#8217;all) to explain my condition. You know, a reference guide. Like, &#8220;gender is kind of like a werewolf, you know?&#8221;</p>
<p>(Nod if you&#8217;ve seen <em>Ginger Snaps</em>)</p>
<p><a class="left-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/49011.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-8299 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/49011.jpg" alt="" width="256" height="400" /></a>I love it when gender and especially womanhood are described in the monstrous. It&#8217;s one of the reasons why, when I&#8217;m having Stupid Identity Issue Time (trademarked yo) I keep turning to Angela Carter&#8217;s short story collection, <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49011.The_Bloody_Chamber_and_Other_Stories"><em>The Bloody Chamber</em></a>. I&#8217;m not going to say Carter always handles gender representation well but the wolf-themed short stories are sort of my reference guide to get myself back on track. Why &#8220;Wolf-Alice&#8221; in particular though? Well&#8230;</p>
<p>As a non-binary person, my journey through womanhood was basically a sprint through falling buildings. I just wanted to get out of it already and see what the fuss was about. Changes that I understood but disagreed with were happening anyway. I thought by becoming feminine, boys would treat me differently. If I learned the rules of humanity, people would respect me.</p>
<p>Even as an adult I am still learning these things are not &#8230; true. The Wolf-Alice learns there are many caveats to this strange human world. There&#8217;s a lot of rules and so much to learn, and so damned much of it makes no sense. It&#8217;s restricting and it&#8217;s all self-imposed. What I&#8217;ve always liked about this story is she is transforming <em>back</em>. It&#8217;s easy to decide you want to eschew the comforts of society and go buck wild. Eventually you&#8217;ll come back and get it out of your system. But if you were born outside? Your whole sense of normal and community is flipped upside down to something completely foreign. I often complain about having to shrink and morph myself daily to fit expectations, and I need queer spaces to stretch. Trying to maintain some sort of normalcy is draining. But I don&#8217;t know if people without my lived experience are really feeling me. I&#8217;m not saying there&#8217;s no common ground but when I&#8217;m talking to allies, I can&#8217;t think of a way to explain it. It&#8217;s like the creature from the Black Lagoon deciding to live on land or a feral girl-child coming back to society.</p>
<p>Then I go back to my conversation with my friend. Yeah, there&#8217;s a lot of modern literature that can&#8217;t hold up to the classics. But I don&#8217;t see myself in Victorian gothic novels. I may <em>want</em> to but most of the time it&#8217;s a reach. I continue to read modern lit and specifically spec-fic because my form of escapism is actually being validated and seeing my experiences, no matter how monstrous, represented. So when I&#8217;m down, I end up right back here in these pages. Like Wolf-Alice, I&#8217;m looking at my own reflection and pawing at it, trying to understand what I&#8217;m seeing.</p>
<p>(PS if you have never read <em>The Bloody Chamber</em> I can&#8217;t pressure you but <a href="https://www.bookdepository.com/Bloody-Chamber-Other-Stories-Angela-Carter/9780099588115">here&#8217;s a link</a>)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REVIEW: FIYAH Issue #1: Rebirth</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-fiyah-issue-1-rebirth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[E. Young]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yes, the whole anthology. I tried to pick just one story to talk about out&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/fiyah-scale-banner.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-8176" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/fiyah-scale-banner.png" alt="" width="998" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Yes, the whole anthology. I tried to pick just one story to talk about out of this issue but I quickly realized&#8230;nah. I have to tell you about them all. You know how sometimes in an anthology you&#8217;ll have some faves, and the rest are pretty good? This was all killer no filler.</p>
<p>For a little background, <em><a href="http://www.fiyahlitmag.com/">FIYAH</a></em> is a sort of spiritual successor to the experimental black literature magazine <em>FIRE!!</em>, first published in 1926. Now,<em> FIRE!!</em> only lasted one issue due to, tragically, the magazine&#8217;s headquarters burning down. But, it&#8217;s still possible to unearth reproductions of the original print &amp; I know for a fact most, if not all, of the stories are dispersed in other modern anthologies. So all is not lost!</p>
<p>Now, to tie into <em>Fiyah</em>, the original <em>Fire</em> was not a landmark simply because it was a collection of black authors and artists (although obviously that&#8217;s important). It was a space for black creatives to create freely without the restrictions of appealing to the mainstream or what is/isn&#8217;t black art. It dealt with sexuality, sex work, colorism&#8230;when I read it, I thought this isn&#8217;t just a magazine it&#8217;s a home.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s how I feel when I started to read the stories in <em>Fiyah</em>. These are, of course, stories that deal with contemporary issues. But they aren&#8217;t meant to educate. They&#8217;re weird because they can be, because that&#8217;s what the author wants. They&#8217;re beautiful and coherent and terrifying. That&#8217;s my kind of writing; when you&#8217;re completely unfettered (except by matters of taste&#8230;maybe) and free to explore worlds of your choosing.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a fairly short issue, but as for standouts my personal favorite and probably most relevant to me was &#8220;Long Time Lurker, First Time Bomber&#8221; by Malon Edwards. Set in a futuristic Chicago, this story was refreshingly hard on the science and cyberpunk (body mods? Sign me up!) but never felt too over my head or weighed down in technobabble. My other personal best was &#8220;Revivial&#8221; by Wendi Dunlap, which is honestly horrifying in any political climate. You know those <em>Twilight Zone</em> episodes that basically tell you human nature doesn&#8217;t change whether we&#8217;re on Earth or Venus? It&#8217;s true. Curious how it affects women of color? Don&#8217;t be shocked.</p>
<p>As the old saying goes, if you&#8217;re trying to get free like the rest of us definitely give <em>FIYAH</em> a read. And if you&#8217;re curious as to its origins and the original <em>Fire!!</em> magazine, <a href="http://poczineproject.tumblr.com/post/54610448518/izm2013-zine-must-read-fire-devoted-to-younger">POC Zine Project has you covered. </a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: &#8220;Ten Days&#8217; Grace&#8221; (Foz Meadows)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-ten-days-grace-foz-meadows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[E. Young]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 17:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had a chance to view Nocturnal Animals, directed by Tom Ford, and I had&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>I had a chance to view <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4550098/"><em>Nocturnal Animals</em></a>, directed by Tom Ford, and I had a few &#8230; thoughts.</div>
<div></div>
<div>(No spoilers promise)</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Nocturnal Animals Official Trailer 1 (2016) - Jake Gyllenhaal Movie" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-H1Ii1LjyFU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>This movie isn&#8217;t as gimmicky as I thought it would be and wow this actually accurately depicts how women are treated in unfaithful relationships.</div>
<div></div>
<div>That&#8217;s not to say it was the best, most progressive movie of all time. In fact, initially I didn&#8217;t like it until I gave it some thought. Then I realized I at least understand what Ford wanted to accomplish. As you may or may not know, there&#8217;s some kind of double standard in the world in which men &amp; women (on a binary scale anyway) are treated differently. Even in romantic relationships. Shocker, I know. There are many stories, spec fic or not, that deal with this paradox&#8211;women are either malicious perpetrators of infidelity, or hapless victims. And of course there are more thoughtful, complex portrayals as well. And then &#8230; there are the painful, accurate ones where lopsided punishment is doled out and there&#8217;s nothing done about it.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I was thinking about all this as a sort of background context when almost by pure accident, in the middle of composing another review, I came across &#8220;Ten Days&#8217; Grace&#8221; by <a href="https://fozmeadows.wordpress.com/">Foz Meadows</a>. I remember this short story making the rounds in 2014 when it was published and I was intrigued but don&#8217;t recall actually reading it. Now, it&#8217;s like in my confused post-movie haze I was subconsciously searching for it. I have also been curious about their young adult work but as I like to do with all authors unfamiliar to me, I&#8217;ll read something shorter first.</div>
<div></div>
<div>So, you might be wondering, &#8220;how are you going to put this in the context of a Tom Ford movie and stuff about infidelity?&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div>Because, well &#8230; uh, I didn&#8217;t like this story a whole lot at first for much of the reason I didn&#8217;t like that movie at first. The infidelity subplot here&#8211;like in <em>Animals</em>&#8211;is one of many themes in this story but it weighed heavily on my mind because it tied the ending together. In a way that I realized was intended to make me think: why is this happening to her? It just seems excessively unfair.</div>
<div></div>
<div>And, you know, &#8220;Ten Days&#8217; Grace&#8221; explores just how excessively unfair and cruel society is towards marginalized groups. There is no winning here. As Julia&#8217;s young daughter Lily cries out upon discovering she must have a new father as mandated by law, &#8220;why can&#8217;t they leave us alone?&#8221; And it&#8217;s painfully accurate.</div>
<div></div>
<div>At times it feels like we&#8217;re not <em>that</em> far off from a society that dictates nuclear family roles. After all, aren&#8217;t we already living under oppressive cis-heteronormative guidelines? As a child of a single parent (and later co-parents) the message that a two parent household is always better&#8211;no matter who the parents are&#8211;really struck me. This is something I&#8217;ve heard directly. I&#8217;ve witnessed my single mother be blamed needlessly for my development. That&#8217;s the fear. That Julia&#8217;s infidelity, her black mark on society, would not only negatively drag down her social status but her daughter&#8217;s. In this story that is literally against the law. I could not only imagine but feel her horror as she stared down a list of &#8220;candidates&#8221; just so her child won&#8217;t be taken away.</div>
<div></div>
<div>This story was short and exhausting to read, and I still just kept thinking &#8220;why is this happening?&#8221; The answer, of course, is it simply is what happens. The State has its own rhyme and reason of maintaining families and this is how we keep marginalized groups in line. And I thought to myself, &#8220;wow, that is a pretty accurate depiction of how women are punished for having outside relationships.&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div>I made a blink of a connection when I finished reading the story for the second time. I didn&#8217;t like it for being <em>right</em>. I hated that the happy ending involved just dealing with things and rebelling from the inside. But it&#8217;s right. That&#8217;s just what happens. I let it stew for a bit and got over it, and now I can fully recommend it if you want to read it and have some thinky-thoughts like I did. As for <em>Animals</em>, eh, well. It&#8217;s&#8230;an experience with an interesting ending. But definitely check out &#8220;Ten Days&#8217; Grace&#8221; instead, from <em><a href="http://www.apex-magazine.com/ten-days-grace/">Apex magazine</a></em>.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: &#8220;Red Dirt Witch&#8221;, by N.K. Jemisin (and people of colo(u)r destroying more things)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-red-dirt-witch-by-n-k-jemisin-and-people-of-colour-destroying-more-things/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[E. Young]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I finally downloaded my copy of People of Colo(u)r Destroy Fantasy, I sped through&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/index-1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7769" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/index-1.jpg" width="300" height="451" /></a>When I finally downloaded my copy of <a href="http://www.destroysf.com/people-of-colour-destroy-fantasy/"><em>People of Colo(u)r Destroy Fantasy</em></a>, I sped through most of the stories in half a day. One in particular I was really excited to talk about was &#8220;Red Dirt Witch&#8221; by N.K. Jemisin, for a few reasons. First, well, <a href="http://nkjemisin.com/">look at the author</a>. Think about it. Second: southern magic.As a black southerner I don&#8217;t really need anyone to tell me why the southern United States might get a bad rap. I mean&#8230;I know. I think at this point almost all of us know. But fantasy authors do love picking our bones when they need voodo0 or other such non-European mystical elements. And you know what? That&#8217;s okay. I&#8217;ve reviewed a couple of novels and short stories that handle that topic well and, yes, they&#8217;re all set in Louisiana.</p>
<p>But what about the folk magic of Appalachia? What about old slave traditions that toe the line between common sense and otherworldly? Jemisin brings us an eerie supernatural story where this is daily life. Visions. Midwives and healers. Average tools accessible to everyone who needs it. No pedestals or altars here. Magic for the people!</p>
<p>&#8220;Red Dirt Witch&#8221;, however, isn&#8217;t just about that. I debated on how to approach this. It wouldn&#8217;t be fair to dismantle it down to &#8220;this is what this really means&#8221;&#8211;yes, it&#8217;s commentary on a specific conversation that has popped up in these days of black and brown murdered bodies constantly on the news. The old guard says stand down, the new guard says stand up. In that sense, you could say it&#8217;s a changing of the guard trope. But it&#8217;s more than that. It&#8217;s about sacrifice, the action of choosing and growing into your own power, and truly seeing the future&#8211;a future that is NOT good and still very hard, but there are parts more than worth fighting for. But to distill this story down to mere symbolism is a disservice. It was a very emotional experience for me that evoked the question, &#8220;what would I do for a future I can&#8217;t even participate in?&#8221;</p>
<p>I felt like this was an insular conversation and maybe only a few of us are privy. Some are eavesdropping. But does that mean you shouldn&#8217;t read it if you&#8217;re not &#8220;in the know&#8221;? Of course not. This southerner&#8217;s heart soared with many references I understood and related to, in fact I bet many of us of a certain age probably can.</p>
<p>I would say the only downsides of this story was that it was a little&#8230;too on the nose for me. Whether that&#8217;s bad or not is kind of up in the air, but there were times when I didn&#8217;t like it. The White Lady was interesting and devious, but I wasn&#8217;t always sure how she fit in. I felt like if this got expanded to a bigger story it would provide a lot more context. Maybe I just want to read it forever? If you want to as well, bind yourself to <a href="http://www.destroysf.com/">People of Colo(u)r Destroy Fantasy here</a>, and pick up the previous issues as well!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: &#8220;An Offertory to Our Drowned Gods&#8221; (Teresa Naval) + destroying everything!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-an-offertory-to-our-drowned-gods-teresa-naval-destroying-everything/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[E. Young]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 16:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have two things to tell y&#8217;all about today, and those things are: offerings to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have two things to tell y&#8217;all about today, and those things are: offerings to the ocean trying to kill you, and how to destroy every genre.</p>
<p>Okay, that first point may be a little melodramatic. What I&#8217;m actually talking about is a piece of flash fiction from author Teresa Naval. This story comes from the <a href="http://www.destroysf.com/"><em>People of Colo(u)r Destroy Science Fiction</em></a> collection, brought to us by <em>Lightspeed</em> magazine. For a little context on this story, I personally live in a landlocked state (we&#8217;ve had ONE serious flood but that was &#8230; a weird case) but I have many friends who have been effected by the damages of flooding. To me, flood damage is horrifying on many levels as someone who has never gone through it, so I can&#8217;t even begin to imagine how terrifying it is for people that live in places where it happens yearly or more.</p>
<p>What really strikes me about Naval&#8217;s story is that it&#8217;s not about flooding per se. If you&#8217;re like me, you might even think it&#8217;s a little Lovecraftian (well, it might be). It describes the aftermath of a flood that is implied to be unnatural&#8211;and an epidemic, quite possibly swallowing up the world. But that&#8217;s not the focus. The focus is life after. How to survive and everything the damage takes from you. The hopelessness. It even touches on religion and class status. There were times when I felt water clogging up my lungs and the urge to breathe slowly because Naval&#8217;s writing is so vivid and personal. We are given hints about the setting through language and the author&#8217;s background, but there are definitely times when this could be anywhere and that makes it all the more mysterious and horrifying. At a modest 1200 words this is easily at least my very, very close second story in the whole collection, and that&#8217;s nothing to snuff at considering how packed this is with awesome.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yeah, that&#8217;s cool,&#8221; I hear you say. &#8220;But what&#8217;s this about destroying everything? I wanna destroy stuff.&#8221;</p>
<p>Well, I&#8217;m glad you feel that way because it means you, reader, need to check out the entire __ Destroy __ series. This is a series of special issues focusing on underrepresented groups wrecking your genre. Horror! Sci-Fi! The upcoming fantasy edition! There are even specials dedicated solely to women and queer folx. If that doesn&#8217;t get you excited to destroy* stuff I don&#8217;t know what will.</p>
<p>I enjoy having issues that hyper-focus on a specific group because in all honesty that is the only way to discover people like/look like you writing things you like. Yes, there&#8217;s more women included in sci-fi lit journals, more POC publishing fantasy. But it&#8217;s been a struggle and issues highlighting these writers help, not hurt. Sometimes you have to destroy and deconstruct things to make them better. Don&#8217;t be scared! <a href="http://www.destroysf.com/">Check out the entire series here </a>and the <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01EVZB6ZM">Sci-Fi edition here</a>.</p>
<p>(*please respect property and don&#8217;t actually destroy anything)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Shatterproof (Xen Sanders)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-shatterproof-xen-sanders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[E. Young]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 15:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For this month, I wanted to do something a little different and look at a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>For this month, I wanted to do something a little different and look at a more <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Womanism">womanist</a> issue that&#8217;s close to my heart, and that is mental illness as it affects specifically black men &amp; boys. Unfortunately, we still live in a society where black and brown bodies are villainized as we are seeing at an increasingly visible and alarming rate. To condense my thoughts a bit, for me womanism still gives allotment to discuss the ways in which men are impacted by discrimination.</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Shatterproof_600x900.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7341 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Shatterproof_600x900-200x300.jpg" alt="shatterproof_600x900" width="200" height="300" /></a>You might say, that&#8217;s heavy but what&#8217;s that got to do with <a href="http://riptidepublishing.com/titles/shatterproof"><i>Shatterproof</i> </a>and <a href="http://riptidepublishing.com/authors/xen-sanders">Xen Sanders</a>? To me, speculative fiction is at its best when it comments on social issues. However, I&#8217;ve avoided stories that deal with the topics of mental illness because the stories I was exposed to early in my life were &#8230; well, bad. Like, real bad. Usually reflecting the problem that mental illnesses are poorly understood in real life. I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ve all seen the tropes, ranging from &#8220;mentally ill people are evil&#8221; to &#8220;depression is magic!&#8221; And, really, until recently a lot of those stories were focused on white men. So, nah.</div>
<div></div>
<div>So how did I end up with <i>Shatterproof</i>? In recent times, reading these kinds of stories has gotten a lot better. You have to support what you want to see more of, so despite my painful history I wanted to give this a chance. Did I mention paranormal romances are my guilty pleasure? Is it really guilty if I&#8217;m not sorry? Anyway, I read the synopsis and loved the premise, so I dove in.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Not wanting to die &#8230; wanting to die. The extreme difficulties of just <i>living</i>. Thoughts I admit I have struggled with. I never thought that I would say a book that starts with a suicide attempt would make me happy, but I&#8217;ve had a personal month of dealing with draining personal issues and my own depression, so this ended up being very cathartic for me to read. Saint and Grey&#8217;s relationship is EVERYTHING. The paranormal aspect is thoughtfully handled and never feels like it&#8217;s going to swallow up the plot, which despite the characters, is very human and down the earth. The prose is visual and lush but doesn&#8217;t veer into purple territory and just made me nostalgic for the overstuffed books of my youth before everything became &#8230; minimal (not saying minimalism is bad, but sometimes I need coffee described in four dimensions, you know?). Even the author&#8217;s notes made me cry. At some point I muttered to myself, wiping my tears away, &#8220;this is ridiculous&#8221;. It&#8217;s not all tears, though, as there is some seriously good world building here and it actually got scary at points. Did I mention accurate portrayals of voudou? Now I have. Oh, one more thing: shout out to Nuo for being awesome. Oh, you thought there were no women in this book? Wrong. Sanders definitely knows how to craft a female support character that doesn&#8217;t just disappear in the background or show up when someone needs a pity party. Basically, the friend you need in real life.</div>
<div></div>
<div>It&#8217;s so rare to see something that reflects a part of my life that I rarely talk about because it&#8217;s so heavily stigmatized. This is even commented on at times by Grey. At first, I thought maybe the self-harm and suicide would be too triggering for me to handle. Unfortunately, that&#8217;s just at my discretion sometimes. But there were many subtle touches here to portray the individual experience and at no point did I think love and/or magic was somehow going to fix everything. And that&#8217;s a good thing. It really felt like people working on themselves with their own coping mechanisms. In fact, my only true complaint about this book is sometimes Saint and Grey contemplate their navels too much (this is actually very realistic in my experience, haha).</div>
<div></div>
<div>I&#8217;m very glad I was able to read <i>Shatterproof </i>all the way through; in the larger scheme of things, finding even something I relate to a little makes all the difference and reminds me of why I got into fantasy and sci-fi in the first place. I definitely feel encouraged to keep finding things that reflect my whole experience, like it&#8217;s really out there and I don&#8217;t have to be afraid (or groan) anymore. You can buy Shatterproof directly from <a href="http://riptidepublishing.com/titles/shatterproof">Riptide Publishing</a> and feel free to check out <a href="http://www.blackmagicblues.com/">Xen&#8217;s website </a>for more.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Abiku: A Battle of Gods</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-abiku-a-battle-of-gods/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[E. Young]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 16:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7047</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I first encountered Abiku: A Battle of Gods by Elizabeth Salawu as a press release&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Abiku-A-Battle-Of-Gods-Amazon-Book-Cover.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7177 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Abiku-A-Battle-Of-Gods-Amazon-Book-Cover-188x300.jpg" alt="Abiku-A-Battle-Of-Gods-Amazon-Book-Cover" width="188" height="300" /></a>I first encountered <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/31296422-abiku"><i>Abiku: A Battle of Gods </i></a>by Elizabeth Salawu as a press release on my Twitter timeline. I read the synopsis and thought, &#8220;that sounds like something different&#8221; and sometimes that&#8217;s all the reason you need, so I took the plunge and requested an advance review copy.</div>
<div></div>
<div>What I got was something pleasantly different indeed! <i>Abiku</i> starts off with a &#8220;dear reader&#8221;, to which I said out loud, &#8220;ooh, me?&#8221; and takes off from there. This is a short read, but don&#8217;t let that fool you&#8211;I was fully engaged the entire time, flipping each digital page with anticipation of where the story was going next.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I have to say my favorite thing about <i>Abiku</i> is Dayo herself. Dayo is interesting to me because&#8230;wait for it&#8230;we didn&#8217;t have much in common at all! She&#8217;s everything I wish I was at her age. In tune with herself! Exciting! Outgoing! Witty! Well, I can be witty, but. It&#8217;s not a bad thing to read protagonists much different from ourselves, in fact I loved living vicariously through her. She reminds me a bit of Alex from <i>A Clockwork Orange</i> (went there) when the narrative switches from being pensive and philosophical and then back to breezy, sometimes salacious storytelling.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Ah, the story. I was very happy to read something featuring Yoruba religious customs and myth, and Dayo guides us along without too much exposition but I also didn&#8217;t feel lost. And for personal reasons I get excited for anything involving Pidgin.</div>
<div>
<p>Now, as awesome as this book is it isn&#8217;t a read for everyone&#8211;it features sexual elements that make it a bit saucier than your average lunch break read (unless you can do that kind of thing where you are, then carry on). But I would say it was well integrated into the plot so as not to feel superfluous, and I appreciated the focus on Dayo learning who and what she truly is, and exploring her own desires.</p>
</div>
<div>Sometimes things just fall into your lap at seven in the morning before your first cup of coffee&#8211;I&#8217;m glad I took a chance on Dayo&#8217;s story, and I hope you&#8217;ll give it a chance as well. It&#8217;s not due out until September 16th, but you can pre-order it <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Abiku-Battle-Gods-Elizabeth-Salawu-ebook/dp/B01IMMZ8FO/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1471825678&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=abiku#nav-subnav">here</a>.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: The Historian, by Elizabeth Kostova</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-historian-by-elizabeth-kostova/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[E. Young]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 16:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So, my mother&#8217;s church group is having a book drive and I have tons of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>So, my mother&#8217;s church group is having a book drive and I have tons of books to purge and give away as it turns out.</div>
<div> (I know, shock and horror. Why would I ever give away books?! It&#8217;s for a greater cause.)</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/index.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6923 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/index.jpg" alt="index" width="180" height="279" /></a>While cleaning off my shelves, I came across <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10692.The_Historian"><em>The Historian</em> </a>by Elizabeth Kostova. You might remember this book was a pretty big deal when it came out way, way back in 2005. It won several awards, shot straight to the top of the coveted <em>Times</em> best seller list, and was just all over the literary world for a while. And this was a debut! It wasn&#8217;t the first female written horror book I&#8217;d ever read, but it was the first one that had this much press and was this mainstream. In fact, my mom proudly presented me the book as soon as it came out wanting to know my thoughts on it pretty quickly, despite the size.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I was excited! A modern Gothic horror novel, with vampires. Written by a woman! I delved into the book over the summer immediately, completely bypassing any hype so I could have my own expectations.</div>
<div></div>
<div>So I read&#8230;and I read&#8230;and I read&#8230;then I stopped. Why? Because [stage whisper] I really, really didn&#8217;t like it.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Yes, I made it a heroic quarter of the way through before I realized this just wasn&#8217;t working out for me. I felt bad my mother spent money on a hardback that I wouldn&#8217;t finish, and when she asked me my thoughts I gave an uninterested shrug and said, &#8220;Well&#8230;it&#8217;s okay.&#8221; I felt even worse because, at the time, there were nothing but good reviews for the book to be found. Not even a wishy-washy one. Clearly, the best readers in the world enjoyed it so I was losing my mind, right?</div>
<div></div>
<div>Now, I&#8217;m not here to tell you that story nor am I here to tell you about a book I half-finished when I was a teenager. I want to talk about perspective and change. Years later in college, I wandered into the community kitchen and saw someone I vaguely knew reading a familiar book. I hadn&#8217;t thought about it in a long time by that point, but I asked her about it. We talked and I explained that I didn&#8217;t like it when I was younger and she told me she loved it. I was like, &#8220;hmm.&#8221; So, when I laid my hands on that dusty, naked book (I have a habit of removing my dust jackets) I thought, you know I didn&#8217;t give this a fair shake. I&#8217;m older now so maybe there&#8217;s concepts in the book I just didn&#8217;t get. And I&#8217;m finally ready to join the discussion group!</div>
<div></div>
<div>So, I went a few chapters back from where I left off to refresh my memory and finally finished the book. Right off the bat, I can tell you the imagery and story were still so strongly embedded in my head eleven (!) years later it didn&#8217;t take much to put me back into the world of <em>The Historian</em>. When I finally got to the end, it was pretty rewarding.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Surprise, turns out I didn&#8217;t hate the book as much as I thought. I do think part of it is due to just evolving in my reading habits and age, and in retrospect I feel back then my expectations were way too high. Even though I managed to avoid the first round of hype, I was still let down by unrealistic expectations. Now, older, I&#8217;ve tempered myself to reality so I enjoyed the story for what it is. Yes, it&#8217;s long but very well told with excellent descriptions of far away places and heavy, old world Gothic intrigue. And it&#8217;s a refreshingly traditional vampire story without excessive gore or even violence and sex. As a fan of Dumas and Indiana Jones, I really loved the travel and adventure, and the sense of danger around every corner with no super powers for protection.</div>
<div></div>
<div>However, even now I understand what put me off about the story at first. The characters&#8211;especially the Historian herself&#8211;struck me as &#8230; well, Mary Sues. Even before that term became overused. There seemed to be an awful lot of plot devices of pure convenience. The prose was good, but somehow purple and stiff at the same time. And there seemed to be a lot of shallow motivations. I think all of this just came together to annoy me a lot, but looking back on the story I realize a lot of those were just Gothic fiction tropes coming into play. Not necessarily a bad thing, but it can be taxing especially in a book so long. I wasn&#8217;t sure how I felt about the choice of narrator&#8211;a young girl, never named provides intrigue and was an interesting twist, but sometimes left me thinking it was &#8230; too unnecessarily mysterious. With all the other mysteries going on.</div>
<div></div>
<div>But still, hopefully young!me is relieved to have finally finished <em>The Historian</em> after all this time. I can understand why I didn&#8217;t enjoy it as much then, but I can definitely appreciate it a lot more now. Maybe after that, I&#8217;ll finally get around to finishing that Stephen King novel (long story). But, now that my mission is accomplished, I think I&#8217;ll give up <em>The Historian</em> so someone else can discover it over what&#8217;s left of the summer! And if you want a copy of your own, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000FCK6EI/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1">try here</a>.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
