<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lordy Lordy Look Who&#8217;s 40+ &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/lordy-lordy-look-whos-40/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 02:43:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tools of the Trade</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/tools-of-the-trade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrea Hull]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 12:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lordy Lordy Look Who's 40+]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Clearly, this is somewhat a matter of procrastination from the actual writing, but it is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Clearly, this is somewhat a matter of procrastination from the actual writing, but it is still true that we must have the proper tools to do anything. With writing, this can be as simple as pencil and paper, of course, but there are more things to consider &#8211; and they are fun to consider, in my opinion, though that is partly the librarian in me talking. See, I mean books. Well, and also software and keyboards and workplace set-up, etc., but today, I just mean books.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-25071 size-medium" title="right-image" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/bird-196x300.jpg" alt="" width="196" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/bird-196x300.jpg 196w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/bird.jpg 261w" sizes="(max-width: 196px) 100vw, 196px" />Everyone recommends many of the same non-fiction books, and for good reason: Stephen King’s <em>On Writing</em> and Anne Lamont’s <em>Bird by Bird</em>, for example, are fantastic. There are <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/list/show/1714.Best_Books_on_Writing">dozens more</a>, if not hundreds more, that people like. I particularly enjoyed Ursula K. Le Guin’s <em><a href="https://www.ursulakleguin.com/steering-the-craft">Steering the Craft</a></em> for clearly explaining how to write beautifully, concisely, and purposefully. Jeff Vandermeer’s <em><a href="https://wonderbooknow.com/">Wonderbook</a></em> is inspiring just to flip through as it is beautifully illustrated by dozens of artists, but it is also well-written with essays by many well-known authors as well. <em><a href="https://chireviewofbooks.com/2016/02/15/jessa-crispins-creative-tarot-will-change-the-way-you-write/">A Creative Tarot</a></em> by Jessa Crispin is a dark horse, I know, but really helpful on a day-to-day basis when you just feel stuck in a rut &#8211; check it out! <em><a href="https://juliacameronlive.com/the-artists-way/">The Artist’s Way</a></em> by Julia Cameron is <a href="https://www.thecut.com/2016/01/artists-way-self-help-book.html">a bit of a cliche</a> but it really spells out, in a simple twelve-week program, how to kickstart your creative journey while figuring out what has been holding you back all these years.</p>
<p>However, there are other books that I also find extremely helpful and encouraging in my writing life and in my writing aspirations: the books that made me want to be a writer in the first place. I’m talking about the stories that made you clutch your blanket while reading, the books that made you gasp and/or laugh and/or cry, and the books that you hugged to yourself after reading the last page.</p>
<p>So, starting with the D&#8217;Aulaires <em>Book of Greek Myths</em>, Alan Garner’s wonderfully sparse yet fae writing, Susan Cooper’s eminently re-readable <em>The Dark is Rising</em>, and all the books I loved so much as a child. Then, the newer books, be they more literary, like Ali Smith, David Mitchell, and Jeanette Winterson; more genre, like Kim Stanley Robinson, Ted Chiang, Nnedi Okorofor, or N.K. Jemisin; or classics, like Virginia Woolf and Doris Lessing. And then there are the non-fiction writers, the ones that make me starry-eyed at the wonder of the world and worry for the future, like Robert Macfarlane, Amitav Ghosh (his literary works are wonderful, too), Marcia Bjornerud, Ed Yong, Peter Brennan, and most recently, Merlin Sheldrake with his exciting book on the life of fungi. (Sounds like a joke, but hands-down, the most fascinating book I’ve read in a while.)</p>
<p>The point here is not to make list after list, but to show and remember that there is so much that inspires our writing and hopes. I am sure the same is true for you, although undoubtedly your list of books will differ from mine by a lot. Looking at these stacks of books surrounding me as I write, I feel encouraged. They were all written by humans like me who also had to force themselves to sit down sometimes, and who also railed at their own limitations, and despaired of finding the right word and the right ending and so on and so forth. We all know the feelings!</p>
<p>I also have a small collection of early or first books by some of my favorite writers, like Francis Hardinge, Lucy Wood, Laini Taylor, Joy Williams, and Mary Rickert. These books are especially inspiring because they <em>did</em> it. They were also bewildered and discouraged at times and yet &#8211; they did it. They wrote that first book. They wrote beautiful, challenging, first-rate stories that surely they doubted at times or even all the times. They were like us &#8211; aspiring writers, perhaps uneasy at even calling themselves a writer yet. But, they did it &#8211; they wrote and they published and they endured. Therefore, so can we. We really can. Good luck this month.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-25072 size-medium" title="left-image" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/swim-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/swim-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/swim.jpg 263w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" />P.S. Just started George Saunder&#8217;s <em><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jan/06/a-swim-in-a-pond-in-the-rain-by-george-saunders-review-rules-for-good-writing-and-more">A Swim in a Pond in the Rain: In Which Four Russians Give a Master Class on Writing, Reading, and Life</a></em>, which is like taking a Russian lit class with Saunders as the professor. As a Russian lit major, I&#8217;m a bit biased of course, but just one chapter in already, I can guarantee any writer would find it fascinating and helpful. Check it out.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Join the conversation</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/join-the-conversation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrea Hull]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lordy Lordy Look Who's 40+]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I want to join the conversation. That&#8217;s what I keep reminding myself on days where&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24507 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fotografierende-jw3xbuelpKM-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fotografierende-jw3xbuelpKM-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fotografierende-jw3xbuelpKM-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fotografierende-jw3xbuelpKM-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fotografierende-jw3xbuelpKM-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fotografierende-jw3xbuelpKM-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/fotografierende-jw3xbuelpKM-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />I want to join the conversation. That&#8217;s what I keep reminding myself on days where I groan and shake my head and wonder why in the world I thought writing was a good idea. And, of course, that is on <em>all</em> the days. I&#8217;ve learned so many hacks in my life, ways to get things done, ways to think through problems&#8211;but this writing thing is the most daunting of all so far. It&#8217;s just so personal: here, World, here is the inside of my head, do you like it? I remind myself that of course I will make mistakes, sound stupid, not know, not be slick at times, or ever, maybe, but I want to join in. Finally. People I started following on Twitter or even on their own small blogs years&#8211;no, decades ago&#8211;are now well-established authors. It&#8217;s like those &#8220;If you lived here, you&#8217;d be home by now&#8221; signs I used to see on the seemingly-endless commute to my job when I lived in California. If only I&#8217;d started then.. but that&#8217;s an easy thought to follow, a slide into envy, hopelessness, and full of comparisons and competition and ending in nothing being written at all. I&#8217;ve been there countless times. Much better is: I want to join the conversation. And I do, the urgency pushes in on all sides. Not in a scary way, but more like an &#8220;It&#8217;s time! Now is the time!&#8221; kind of way. There is space in my life, in my days, and in my head and heart. It <em>is</em> time.</p>
<p>So, I have indeed been writing. Two stories I have been nurturing for a long time are now growing into their own real-ness, but countless others remind me they are there, waiting. As of yet, those two stores are terrible in production but wonderful in thought and I get excited thinking about their worlds and what will happen. That&#8217;s got to be a good thing, that excitement. I&#8217;m trying to ignore the terrible aspects for now and remind myself that editing is a glorious thing that every writer always acknowledges, even the super-wonderful ones. Deep breaths always help here, too.</p>
<p>This is a bit scattered, but that is my mind lately&#8211;I blame the gorgeous spring weather and the general hope for the future that comes with it. A few more tips: <a href="https://jamesclear.com/goals-systems">Systems help more than goals</a>, i.e., small and consistent steps. Finish the story. Finish it, no matter how badly. Because bad finished can be worked with, but unfinished or worse, unwritten, can not be. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=am8qrrZAtP4">&#8220;Don&#8217;t be afraid it won&#8217;t be perfect. The only thing </a>to be afraid of really is that it won&#8217;t <em>be</em>.&#8221; Create a list of 30 things you like to see in stories and put a handful (or more!) into your own. Mantras can work; see Octavia Butler&#8217;s <a href="https://www.theparisreview.org/blog/2018/03/23/so-be-it-see-to-it-from-the-archives-of-octavia-butler/">&#8220;So be it! See to it!&#8221;</a> And with that comes, hopefully, the comforting reminder that even the most famous authors in our field and beyond have questioned and wavered and wondered, and the answer to all that, of course, as ever, is to push through and not give up.</p>
<p>This has been your monthly pep-talk, so get to it. Let&#8217;s go and join the conversation.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recognizing Patterns</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/recognizing-patterns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrea Hull]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lordy Lordy Look Who's 40+]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=23085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pattern recognition is something we all learn as children and is, in fact, a crucial&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23236 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/woman-3373173_1920-300x222.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="222" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/woman-3373173_1920-300x222.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/woman-3373173_1920-1024x757.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/woman-3373173_1920-768x568.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/woman-3373173_1920-1536x1135.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/woman-3373173_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Pattern recognition is something we all learn as children and is, in fact, a crucial step in early childhood development, such as recognizing our parents&#8217; faces. As we get older, we learn to read, we learn to understand what traffic lights mean, what signage all over the place means, we learn to decode jargon and spot sarcasm and irony, and so on. In other words, our ability to spot patterns grows. Some say that this ability is an integral aspect of humanity and that, for example, until robots can achieve high levels of pattern recognition, they will never be able to surpass humans. Some interesting readings on A.I. and pattern recognition can be found <a href="https://bigthink.com/endless-innovation/humans-are-the-worlds-best-pattern-recognition-machines-but-for-how-long">here</a> and <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/ray-kurzweils-dubious-new-theory-of-mind">here</a>. However, today I want to look at a layer to pattern recognition that isn&#8217;t often talked about and I believe for the older writer, is something that we can use to our advantage when plotting, writing, and editing a story.</p>
<p>How many times have you read a book or watched a movie and thought, ah, I know what is going to happen here &#8211; and, for the most part, you are correct? Besides being a fun parlor trick, this is also a level of pattern recognition that takes years to accumulate. For me, it means 30plus years of reading thousands of stories and books, watching entire weeks-worth of movies and TV shows, listening and singing along to endless hours of songs, etc. And yet, without meaning to, I have &#8211; like I think all bookworms and media-consumers of a certain age have &#8211; developed a high pattern recognition level when it comes to tropes, motifs, archetypes, and themes in our cultural creations. I mean, that is the whole point of them, right, but it really rings a bell at a deeper almost intuitive level now that I am older. So, this is not quite as sweeping as it sounds, which means here come the caveats: of course, I am somewhat a creature of my environment, which means there are large swaths of the world whose culture I know very little of, much less the commonly-told tropes in their stories. I am also a child of the 80s, a cis-gendered white woman to boot, and I like the genres and categories of media that I like, so lots of limitations there as well. Still, the pattern recognition goes deep.</p>
<p>It is one thing to recognize which wooden block goes where in a child&#8217;s game, but it is another thing to be able to spot a love triangle a mile away, to recognize a rags to riches story in just <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GOGru_4z1Vc">a few words</a>, to see aspects of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hero%27s_journey">the Hero&#8217;s Journey</a>* or <a href="https://sharonblackie.net/the-fools-journey/">the Fool&#8217;s Journey</a> being played out or attempted to be played out by friends or to realize that you yourself have been following these well-worn steps too. This ability reminds me of the book <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13982.The_Fairy_Godmother">The Fairy Godmother</a> by Mercedes Lackey where the titular godmother is constrained to follow &#8220;The Tradition,&#8221; aka fairy tale archetypes, or else. This means, for example, when she spots a would-be &#8220;Cinderella&#8221; then she must make sure that the girl&#8217;s life follows the steps of the Cinderella tale, no deviations allowed. Same as girls with long hair must be Rapunzels, young men must be helped with quests, and so on. It&#8217;s a fairly fluffy and fun read, but I really enjoyed and remember the godmother&#8217;s reaction and recognition of those tropes and how they could be manipulated *because* she knew them so well.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23237 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/craft-2728227_1920-300x213.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="213" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/craft-2728227_1920-300x213.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/craft-2728227_1920-1024x728.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/craft-2728227_1920-768x546.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/craft-2728227_1920-1536x1092.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/craft-2728227_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>This is just the tip of the iceberg if you want to study these patterns that we recognize in our stories. For example, there are <a href="https://storygrid.com/story-beats/">story beats</a> that are used with pacing issues particularly. There is also the whole study of folklore, starting with the Russian folklorist Vladimir Propp&#8217;s <a href="https://monoskop.org/images/f/f3/Propp_Vladimir_Morphology_of_the_Folktale_2nd_ed.pdf">Morphology of the Folk Tale</a> and continuing with the works by Maria Tatar and Jack Zipes. And of course, there&#8217;s the study of the Tarot, aka the Fool&#8217;s Journey mentioned above, as well as Campbell if you really must.* But just by perceiving this ability you have been long cultivating, there is already a lot that can be done. Look at your writing and see if you recognize any characters or plots that are familiar to these patterns and see how that can be turned around, subverted, or uplifted and expounded on. In other words, be aware of the patterns in your own writing. Or, if you haven&#8217;t started, find one that particularly resonates with you and use that as a jumping-off point. If you haven&#8217;t seen it before, delve into the exhausting richness that is <a href="https://tvtropes.org/">TVtropes.org</a>. You will be sure to make connections, see patterns, and start writing. This all may be boringly obvious to many writers, but for me, it has been a real a-ha moment.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>* It must be noted that there are all kinds of problems with Campbell&#8217;s <em>monomyth</em> theory, <a href="https://www.salon.com/2015/11/07/the_heros_journey_the_idea_you_never_knew_had_shaped_star_wars/">of course</a>, and anyhow the theory itself has been played out, in my opinion, particularly in movies, partially due to the deluge of screenwriting books that are structured around this Hero&#8217;s Journey idea. Still, it is undeniably <a href="https://miro.medium.com/max/3000/1*1x7vo8tyRSGWG4k0xcUKww.png">a deep part of the culture</a> and thus recognizable in the stories we are told.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing ourselves into the story</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-ourselves-into-the-story/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrea Hull]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 12:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lordy Lordy Look Who's 40+]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Representation matters. This is not a controversial statement, or at least should not be. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Representation matters. This is not a controversial statement, or at least should not be. The famous <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bechdel_test">Bechdel test</a>, which has been applied to all manners of creative work, beginning with movies, stipulates that</p>
<ol>
<li><em>The movie has to have at least two women in it,</em></li>
<li><em>who talk to each other,</em></li>
<li><em>about something other than a man.</em></li>
</ol>
<p>I propose there should be a variant of this test (I am not the first to think of this, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/shortcuts/2016/sep/14/more-celia-imrie-fewer-grandchildren-bechdel-test-ageism-films">of course</a>, though my take is simpler) which adds the word &#8220;older&#8221; to #1 and &#8220;or young people, incl. children&#8221; to #3. Why? Think back to when was the last time you have seen an older female protagonist in a book or movie. (I am leaving a lot of leeway here for the term &#8220;older&#8221; too. Currently, older for me is 40+ but I am sure 50-year-old me would scoff and change that number, as would 70-year-old me, etc.) Now, imagine it is a movie or book with not just one old lonely soul who is perhaps the comforting grandma, the nosey neighbor, the eccentric teacher, the funny unmarried aunt, but instead there are two of them. With names. And they talk to each other. Not about children or how young people don’t blah blah blah [insert finger-wagging old-people cliches here]. Can you think of films or books that do that? If I really sit and think, I can &#8211; but they are few and far between, and they are notable because of it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-22868 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/trumpet.jpg" alt="" width="223" height="300" />Some book examples of this that I have lately been purposefully seeking out: Leona Carrington’s <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/the-hearing-trumpet/9781681374642">The Hearing Trumpet</a>, Kij Johnson’s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29635545-the-dream-quest-of-vellitt-boe">The Dream-Quest of Vellitt Boe</a>, Elizabeth Moon’s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/96284.Remnant_Population">Remnant Population</a>, Tove Jansson&#8217;s <a href="https://www.nyrb.com/products/the-summer-book?variant=1094932625">The Summer Book</a>, and N.K. Jemisin&#8217;s <a href="https://bookshop.org/books/the-broken-earth-trilogy-the-fifth-season-the-obelisk-gate-the-stone-sky/9780316527194">The Broken Earth Trilogy</a>. Lists of similarly-minded books can be found if searched for, but here are some from four websites: BookRiot <a href="https://bookriot.com/novels-about-older-women/">1a</a>, <a href="https://bookriot.com/books-with-strong-female-characters-over-50/">1b</a>, the Guardian <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/booksblog/2019/jun/28/over-40-loving-it-celebrate-fiction-positive-older-characters">2</a>, Nature <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-03618-w">3</a>, and Tor.com <a href="https://www.tor.com/2013/01/29/sleeps-with-monsters-where-are-the-older-women/">4</a>. Many of the books don’t completely fulfill the new rules I am proposing above (and they often only feature white cis-gendered women, as well) but they come closer to it, which in our deprived days, is not nothing.</p>
<p>Why this dearth? My take today is that it is largely due to the single-purpose roles we are all <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-22869 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/quest-188x300.jpg" alt="" width="188" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/quest-188x300.jpg 188w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/quest.jpg 297w" sizes="(max-width: 188px) 100vw, 188px" />variously assigned and Must Not Deviate From. There is an interesting short Diane Keaton <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R8tHW1uX1qk">interview</a> where, in explaining why she decided to adopt a child at age 50, she says that she “wasn’t propelled to do [it] earlier because, quite frankly, [she] liked being a daughter.” After her father died, she realized she had no choice but to take on a new role. We are told there are these roles for us, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xVOJla2vYx8">‘to everything… there is a season’</a>, and yes, surely there is to some extent and it is not a bad thing. But there is more to all of us, a multiplicity which too often is ignored. I don’t blame Keaton or anyone for holding tight to a particular role &#8211; I also loved being my father’s daughter and, once he died, I felt this un-grounding of who I was and how I viewed myself because of how much that role meant to me. This is also not to say we can’t embrace the changing of our lives and ourselves. I am not who I was and, largely, I am glad for it. But I also don’t want to be boxed in and assigned a role I did not choose or things taken from me that are still very much me.</p>
<p>I have long loved a Lloyd Alexander <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/30786-child-child-do-you-not-see-for-each-of-us">quote</a>, so much that I used to write it at the beginning of my yearly journal: “Child, child, do you not see? For each of us comes a time when we must be more than what we are.” Recently, I have felt this push to accept, or at least acknowledge the inevitability, the forthcoming of this new role of&#8230;what? That is part of the problem. The crone? No &#8211; and yet, my reproductive days are over. The mother? Somewhat, though see above, and also, my eldest is sure to be taller than me in the not-so-distant future. The maiden? I am certainly no longer the maiden. So then what am I? This <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triple_Goddess_(Neopaganism">triple goddess</a> imagery is all too familiar, but like so many things, the basic idea of it &#8211; that women have all three aspects in them, and are all the more powerful because of it &#8211; has been lost in the general culture. I don’t have to be just the mother. Or just the crone. There is power in each role, and the great power of the crone, really, comes from combining them, from insisting on inhabiting all of them in one form, if so wished.</p>
<p><em>Those</em> are the women I want to see, who I continue to look for, and thrill when I find them. To see the ways I can maybe one day be like them, cohabiting my skin and heart with all the former selves of me wrapped together. So, fellow writers, let us all be “more than we are” and let us write <em>those </em>selves in our stories.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It is 2021 and the future is now so let&#8217;s start writing.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/it-is-2021-and-the-future-is-now-so-lets-start-writing/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/it-is-2021-and-the-future-is-now-so-lets-start-writing/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrea Hull]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 20:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lordy Lordy Look Who's 40+]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Initially, when I was thinking of writing here, I thought this would be a column&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22648 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/prateek-katyal-FcdtuGf7TEc-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/prateek-katyal-FcdtuGf7TEc-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/prateek-katyal-FcdtuGf7TEc-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/prateek-katyal-FcdtuGf7TEc-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/prateek-katyal-FcdtuGf7TEc-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/prateek-katyal-FcdtuGf7TEc-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/prateek-katyal-FcdtuGf7TEc-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Initially, when I was thinking of writing here, I thought this would be a column where I would sometimes talk about grammar or finding your voice or where to submit. But truly that is not what has kept me from writing. What has kept me from writing is something far less practical. So that is what I keep returning to in every column. If you are in your 40s especially (or older or younger, even!) and you haven&#8217;t taken your writing seriously as of yet, the odds are good that it is not because you are unsure of grammar or because you don&#8217;t know where to submit. It is something else, something inside of you, unfortunately. I say unfortunately because of how much easier it is to review various journals&#8217; submission requirements or brush up on grammar than to really face your inner critic, that dismissive voice inside as well as the coping strategies you&#8217;ve developed over the year to avoid that voice which can hinder more than they can help sometimes. It just seems too much so it is easier to just not write. So, you don&#8217;t. It is always, &#8220;Well, sometime in the future maybe..&#8221;</p>
<p>Well, we are now in the future. It is 2021. If Prince&#8217;s &#8220;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rblt2EtFfC4">1999</a>&#8221; still sounds fresh and exciting even though 1999 was 22 years ago, then 2021 is very much the future. And a la <a href="https://www.loc.gov/programs/poetry-and-literature/poet-laureate/poet-laureate-projects/poetry-180/all-poems/item/poetry-180-133/the-summer-day/">Mary Oliver</a>, what *are* you going to do? I don&#8217;t mean resolutions, though if that works for you in some way&#8211;be it in <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/3040289/why-90-day-goals-are-better-than-year-long-ones">smaller chunks</a>, the negative route (<a href="https://lithub.com/what-collecting-100-rejections-taught-me-about-creative-failure/">collecting 100 rejections</a>, etc.), how you want to feel (<a href="https://www.verywellmind.com/make-lasting-life-changes-3144686">subordinate and superordinate goals</a>, etc.)&#8211;go for it. Goal-setting is a great tool and for some, the big yearly resolutions are a great way to set them. But I mean more like using that perspective you have earned after decades on this planet and being realistic about what you want to do with this life of yours. Do you want writing to be included in it? Do you really? Then you must start and you must sustain. It is that simple and you already know it, really. One tip that I <em>have</em> recently realized is that it doesn&#8217;t have to be big. Big gestures and efforts can be wonderful but often fizzle out. Much better to do just a few minutes a day, 15 minutes three times a week, whatever, and then grow from there. Also, if you stop for a day, for a week, it doesn&#8217;t mean it was all for naught or that you have Failed with a capital F. Leave the drama be and just brush yourself off and get back up on that horse. Lastly, you don&#8217;t need some big or perfect idea. Don&#8217;t wait for inspiration to strike, but just get the muscles and gears moving and you will surprise yourself.</p>
<p>I hope this is the push you needed to pick up that pen or open that Scrivener document. You know you won&#8217;t regret it once you start, so go ahead. I&#8217;ll join you. Let&#8217;s write.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/it-is-2021-and-the-future-is-now-so-lets-start-writing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Routine &#038; Ritual</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/routine-ritual/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 01:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lordy Lordy Look Who's 40+]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I remember in college having a discussion with a friend whose creativity I admired, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I remember in college having a discussion with a friend whose creativity I admired, and she said that she just forced herself to be creative at a set time every day, or on some regular basis. The <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-22324 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/artem-riasnianskyi-8fvDJw3jrcI-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/artem-riasnianskyi-8fvDJw3jrcI-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/artem-riasnianskyi-8fvDJw3jrcI-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/artem-riasnianskyi-8fvDJw3jrcI-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/artem-riasnianskyi-8fvDJw3jrcI-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/artem-riasnianskyi-8fvDJw3jrcI-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/artem-riasnianskyi-8fvDJw3jrcI-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />concept was new to me, as I&#8217;d grown up with an artist mom who seemed to always be squeezing out bits of creative time when she could, but never with any stability. Plus I had, as many do growing up in the late 20th century, the overblown romantic view that the muses can&#8217;t be forced, art is fickle, creation came down to the inescapable need and talent of the creative person, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artistic_inspiration">and so on</a>. In other words, my friend&#8217;s comment kind of blew my mind.</p>
<p>I told her that I didn&#8217;t think creativity could work this way, and anyhow it seemed impossible to face that kind of pressure to create and actually make anything worthwhile. And yet, I couldn&#8217;t deny the truth that with this surprising approach, she was the one creating tangible, real things. Twenty-five years later, I think we were both right, though she was more right, ha! See, it&#8217;s simple: routine creates the fertile ground. It allows for the possibility of chance, good luck, serendipity, the stars, whatever you want to call it, to take hold and grow.</p>
<p>Some people are more inclined to routines, but I have never been one of them. Once I became a mom a decade ago, I was even less inclined. My once-sweeping freedom had been crushed to stolen minutes here and there, just as I remembered my mom having had. The last thing I wanted to do was impose some kind of routine that would tie me down even more. Once we got past the toddler years though, and I&#8217;d been forced to adopt a semi-routine by my tyrannical but adorable babies, I began to see the advantages. A caveat though: for my personality type, there must always be a hidden trapdoor of some type that lets me escape any routine, however briefly. The important thing is that it&#8217;s there, so I rarely use this trapdoor. (This also was some hard-won knowledge, but so important in figuring out how to make a routine work for me.)</p>
<p>There are many books out there on the creative routines of writers; so many in fact that it seems almost to be a sub-genre, but some popular recent-ish ones are the two <a href="https://bookshop.org/books?keywords=daily+rituals">Daily Rituals</a> books by <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-22325 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/daily-202x300.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/daily-202x300.jpg 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/daily.jpg 318w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" />Mason Currey. He also has a <a href="https://subtlemaneuvers.substack.com/">newsletter</a> that discusses routines. There&#8217;s another good <a href="https://lonelyvictories.substack.com/">writers&#8217; routines newsletter</a> by Hurley Winkler. Of course, there is no one routine to suit everyone, and routines, like everything in life, adapt and evolve as time goes on. Still, a big step in the writing life is to create one. It sounds so mundane, but there is no denying that when I brush my teeth, pop out my contacts, and wash my face, my mind and body know that sleep comes next and it tends to get me started on that road. The same is true for the creative parts of me, or whatever it is that comes up with ideas. I can get fancy and add coffee, incense, a lucky notebook, a favorite spot in the cafe, whatever, but the base of (this) writer&#8217;s life is routine. Be it thirty minutes a day, a la Gertrude Stein, 6000 words a day (famously Stephen King), three hours before lunch like Alice Munro, or writing followed by a 10 km run like Haruki Murakami, the important thing is you create a schedule and you stick to it.</p>
<p>So, that covers the routine aspect of that long-ago college discussion. And the unpinnability of creativity? The magic of ritual helps here, I think. Light that incense. Have a lucky pen. Save some music that is only to be played when you write. Go on that short hike through the woods, collecting pine cones or small stones that draw your attention. Eat that bit of bitter chocolate. One tip: the more senses involved, the better. Let your mind and the world, the muses, whatever there is, know that you are ready and are now entering the world of possibilities and creativity.</p>
<p>Hope this helps, and good luck.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pep Talk #3</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/pep-talk-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrea Hull]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lordy Lordy Look Who's 40+]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=21954</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Confession time: I haven&#8217;t been writing. This should not come as a surprise to me,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Confession time: I haven&#8217;t been writing. This should not come as a surprise to me, as I&#8217;ve done this same thing basically for two decades now, and yet it is. In my heart of hearts, I know I should be writing, but I can still somehow never really write. Not regularly. Not the way I imagine it &#8211; and what I imagine is not some romantic every-day-or-else-I&#8217;ll-die-I&#8217;m-a-writer-see kind of way. (Nothing wrong with that, of course, but that will never be me.) The way I imagine is a realistic and painful &#8216;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=petqFm94os">time to make the donuts</a>&#8216; kind of way that, hopefully, ultimately creates the satisfaction and enjoyment of *having* created. So my expectations are realistic. I know it will be difficult and frustrating, but I&#8217;m also positive it will be wonderful to have it be done. Similar to how I feel *having* run, *having* done something challenging, or *having* conquered something long feared and built up to be impossibly difficult. Yet even having that realistic vision, I am failing every day in making it happen.</p>
<p>I can visualize myself as a writer, I even have a few perfect dedications in my mind all ready for those first books (lol, what &#8211; doesn&#8217;t everybody do that?), but I can&#8217;t get my pen to paper or fingers to keyboard in any kind of regular sustaining way. And this is after I wrote two public pep-talk columns. It&#8217;s embarrassing. There are always excuses, and 2020 has provided an easy array of extraordinary excuses. However, it has also been a wake-up kind of year. Not to be too morbid, but entering my mid-40s, I&#8217;m starting to hear more and more of sickness, disease, and death from family friends, extended family, and even high school and college friends. It&#8217;s no longer random, tragic accidents, but an accumulation of stress and wear and tear. I&#8217;m seeing more and more stars from my parents&#8217; generation, and even some from my older sibling&#8217;s generation, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2020#Deaths">dying</a> or falling sick. And then, personally, I&#8217;m feeling my own once-seemingly-boundless energy decreasing, however slightly. More aches. More worries. More awareness that time is ticking along. I&#8217;m lucky to have it ticking at all, I know. And yet, I don&#8217;t write.</p>
<p>Part of the problem is that I don&#8217;t deal well with pressure. For example, I&#8217;ve been a vegetarian/vegan/whole-food plant-based eater for most of adult life, with a large gap when I was <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-22038 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/sharon-pittaway-KUZnfk-2DSQ-unsplash-300x207.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="207" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/sharon-pittaway-KUZnfk-2DSQ-unsplash-300x207.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/sharon-pittaway-KUZnfk-2DSQ-unsplash-1024x706.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/sharon-pittaway-KUZnfk-2DSQ-unsplash-768x529.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/sharon-pittaway-KUZnfk-2DSQ-unsplash-1536x1059.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/sharon-pittaway-KUZnfk-2DSQ-unsplash-2048x1412.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />pregnant a decade ago. This was only able to be maintained because I kept my eating habits flexible and never made it about the label or about &#8216;purity.&#8217; For some, that makes me a wishy-washy whatever, but whereas many are hardcore vegans for a year or strict vegetarians for three, I&#8217;ve mostly avoided meat, etc for twenty three years now. In real terms, that means something. My point is: this flexibility and non-pressure is the strategy that works for me. It is the way that works for my head and how it is wired. Conversely, I do well with plans, but they have to be broken into small, non-threatening bits and pieces. The most I&#8217;ve ever written is during NaNoWriMo in 2012 when my youngest was a newborn. Not quite sure how that happened, but I was determined and I had an idea for a book. I aim to do NaNoWriMo (btw, check out this archive of<a href="https://nanowrimo.org/pep-talks"> pep talks</a> which are wonderful in more hopeful moments) again this year &#8211; which by the time this is published I should be halfway through &#8211; but the outcome is not looking too bright right now.</p>
<p>Okay, well, how do I apply this self-knowledge to writing? What is the *rest* of the problem? How do I not just write another pep-talk column? How do I avoid once again failing to deliver or even just make an honest attempt at delivering? I have made promises (here! right here, on this website I have made them!). I have played games (write and you get x). I have not told others (so there&#8217;s no pressure). I have told others (so there is accountability/pressure). I have made <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-22037 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/daniel-alvasd-NItozEcUPrw-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/daniel-alvasd-NItozEcUPrw-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/daniel-alvasd-NItozEcUPrw-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/daniel-alvasd-NItozEcUPrw-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/daniel-alvasd-NItozEcUPrw-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/daniel-alvasd-NItozEcUPrw-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />location lists, personality lists, scenario lists (to pull out ideas easily). I have downloaded apps and bought a wide collection of pens in many colors and one is even a fountain pen. I have read numerous writing books and <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/365-you-have-to-write-the-book-that-wants-to-be">written</a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/1398-i-love-deadlines-i-love-the-whooshing-noise-they-make">down </a><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/4956-you-must-stay-drunk-on-writing-so-reality-cannot-destroy">meaningful </a><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/34036-there-is-no-real-ending-it-s-just-the-place-where">quotes</a> .</p>
<p>And still: no writing.</p>
<p>So, I sit here. Notebooks at the ready. Laptop cursor blinking. Can I start? And then, can I continue it? Can I even -gasp!- finish it? Each part is crucial, each is filled with its own dangers and demons for the new writer, and perhaps also for the experienced writer. I can&#8217;t be peppy today about something that yet again I am not doing so let me end with someone else&#8217;s wise and perhaps peppy words: &#8220;A person is a fool to become a writer. His only compensation is absolute freedom. He has no master except his own soul, and that, I am sure, is why he does it.” — Roald Dahl</p>
<p>Hm, and like that: hope surges. Let&#8217;s be fools. See you in a month.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Excuse #152: Maybe I need to learn more first</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/excuse-152-maybe-i-need-to-learn-more-first/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrea Hull]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 12:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lordy Lordy Look Who's 40+]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19750</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the long line of Reasons Why I Can&#8217;t Write Today, this one pops up&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-19805 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />In the long line of Reasons Why I Can&#8217;t Write Today, this one pops up often and unfortunately hasn&#8217;t diminished much, or at least enough, with age. That has got to change if I am ever to write, much less publish, a story. There are some strategies for handling, or ways of looking at it rather, that I think could work for me and probably for many.</p>
<p>Women especially are made to feel like we can’t or shouldn’t speak up unless we are experts on the thing at hand. It’s packaged into the whole female over-apologizing thing that resurfaces every few years as a source (see Amy Schumer’s <a href="https://vimeo.com/253499468">&#8216;I’m sorry&#8217; skit</a>) of entertainment and head-scratching (for some, while for others it is painfully relatable). We all need to reject that mindset, understanding that it is an expedient way to keep us quiet and letting the dominant narratives stay in place. This is hardly new territory here but we need to, and <em>I</em> need to, make it personally applicable in my writing ambitions. We know more than we realize and we have more to offer than we may realize.</p>
<p>For instance, logically, I can see that now, in my 40s, I am so aware of patterns of behavior, not only my own but others&#8217; too. This is because I have decades of experience in dealing with people, trying to figure out my own reaction to situations, and so on. It&#8217;s been hard work! And now I get to reap some extra benefit from it in my writing&#8211;but only if I&#8217;m aware of it and purposefully cultivate and use it. Another thing is that knowledge that seems commonplace to me is a surprise, and even considered expertise, to others. One example: my husband and I watch movies and documentaries often, a pretty wide range of them, and for about twenty years now. As a result, I know about actors, directors, film history, cinema styles, etc., and that without being <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19803 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/nights-242x300.jpg" alt="" width="242" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/nights-242x300.jpg 242w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/nights-824x1024.jpg 824w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/nights-768x954.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/nights-1236x1536.jpg 1236w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/nights.jpg 1288w" sizes="(max-width: 242px) 100vw, 242px" />at all a movie buff or even a particular fan. (Top two though, because I can&#8217;t help myself: <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0050783/">Nights of Cabiria</a> and <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0074605/">Harlan County USA</a>. More recently, loved <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt6751668/">Parasite</a>, though who didn&#8217;t?). Now, no real film fanatic would call me anything near an expert, but the average 20-year-old might and in fact a few, surprisingly, have. This is knowledge again that I can and should incorporate into my writing, be it in the stories themselves or in the story structure.</p>
<p>Then there are the skills I *have* worked hard to acquire, like graduate work in Library Science and a lifetime of reading widely and regularly. This causes problems, of course, because I am so very aware of the limitations of my writing, especially when compared to favorites like Ursula K. Le Guin, Oscar Wilde, Ali Smith, Jeanette Winterson, Ted Chiang, Clarice Lispector, Ray Bradbury, and so on. It gets humbling very, very quickly. However, I do know when there is a spark of good stuff. A line, a phrase, some imagery. This is invaluable and hard-won as well.</p>
<p>(I always remember the scene in <a href="http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/61236">Emily of New Moon</a> when her teacher tells her, after reading some of her poetry, that she has &#8220;ten good lines out of 400&#8221; and she is crushed but then he says that ten good lines mean it is worth pursuing poetry and she should try. I took comfort in that, even at the time when I didn&#8217;t even dream of writing because it made this horrible dichotomy between &#8220;gifted&#8221; and &#8220;not-gifted&#8221; seem less rigid and impermeable. Since then, wiggle room and flexibility have been saving graces in all aspects of life.)</p>
<p>All this does not mean there is no space for researching and learning more. It just means time&#8217;s up, you must write. There is a pressing need for more stories. I&#8217;m dead serious about that. Now more than ever, or more than ever in my lifetime, we need storytellers of all kinds to help our world, our society, our times. The U.S. is in dire straits. Earth is at an ecological turning point. And we are just humans who need stories when facts alone don&#8217;t and haven&#8217;t affected us enough to make the changes we need. It&#8217;s a sobering end, but what can I say&#8211;it&#8217;s true. As Lloyd <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-19804" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cauldron-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="273" height="273" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cauldron-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cauldron-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cauldron-550x550.jpg 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cauldron.jpg 700w" sizes="(max-width: 273px) 100vw, 273px" />Alexander writes in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Black_Cauldron_(novel)">The Black Cauldron</a>, &#8220;Child, child, do you not see? For each of us comes a time when we must be more than what we are.&#8221; Now is that time, for me, and I suspect for many others too. These excuses have had a lifetime of running me ragged, but by seeing with fresh eyes all that I *can* offer and *do* know, maybe this time I can turn off that voice in my head that demands Mastery and instead write what I (yup) know.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>Homework: Write. How did it go since last time? Scribbles, but not enough and not dedicated or serious enough. Relying still too much on this idea of a muse or inspiration needing to come. Change that mindset&#8211;and remember, it&#8217;s not all doom and gloom. It&#8217;s like running. I don&#8217;t particularly love the first mile, but then the second mile comes and I&#8217;m smiling and nodding to the birds in the trees. Writing so far seems to be the same. Writing begets more writing, so my homework is just five minutes but it has to done daily or&#8230; (searches for horrible punishment) or no <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1n3xXuEyr40">Aggretsuko</a> game playing that day (the horror!).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A beginning &#038; some homework</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-beginning-some-homework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andrea Hull]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lordy Lordy Look Who's 40+]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19420</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over 80% of Americans want to write a book. The vast majority of writers &#8211;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over 80% of Americans want to write a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2002/09/28/opinion/think-you-have-a-book-in-you-think-again.html">book</a>. The vast majority of writers &#8211; that is, people who regularly write with the intent to publish &#8211; don’t ever complete a manuscript. Of those who do, less than <a href="https://link.medium.com/ryxUrvjm28">25%</a> of them will be traditionally published. According to one <a href="http://www.jimchines.com/2010/03/survey-results/">study</a>, the average age of first publication for an author is 36 years old.</p>
<p>There’s a lot to argue about what is not included here, such as the impact of the self-publishing revolution; the race, gender, and class issues that prop up some groups unfairly, publishing them<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19599 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vintage-2168174_1920-300x187.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="187" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vintage-2168174_1920-300x187.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vintage-2168174_1920-1024x638.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vintage-2168174_1920-768x479.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vintage-2168174_1920-1536x958.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/vintage-2168174_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> and ignoring others; the uneven value given to books over short stories, flash fiction, poetry, plays, and so on. Still, the facts remain that the hurdles are large and looming. Add in being a never-published wanna-be writer in your 40s who has two young children and little time, lacks sustained self-discipline when it comes to personal goals, and who has successfully subsumed any writing ambition for decades. That’s just to start with.</p>
<p>And so, that, or rather, this, is where I am and where I must start. See, the siren call to write has gotten too strong to deny. It’s still a surprise to me, but to deny it is impossible. For decades, I’d heard people say they can’t help but write. That you shouldn’t try to be a writer unless you feel this undeniable urge that makes you scribble away for hours and years on end. That made it simple: I didn’t feel that urge. A bookworm since I was little, I knew the power of books, I loved them like I love nothing else, but I never imagined writing one much less being a Writer. That was the narrative in my head for so many years. I could rest easy and say to others, oh I’m just not ambitious like that. I was a librarian, an archivist, a webmaster, an intermittent blogger. All jobs &#8211; great ones, don’t get me wrong &#8211; that danced around the real ambition that lay underneath. It seems painfully clear to me now.</p>
<p>I want to write. I want to be a writer. It feels bold to even type that out, future tense and all, but can you imagine, I made myself say it out loud a few times. Surely to some at this moment, I sound like a shrinking violet, but the thing is, when something matters a lot, you don’t say it cavalierly. This matters a lot to me, so I mutter it, I whisper it, and on the fourth or fifth audible try without a laugh at the absurdity of this all, it finally sounds like me, like the words aren’t rocks in my mouth.</p>
<p>The hope for a regular column is that I can share one individual’s example of the process of how to become a writer. Of course, part of the reason is to hold myself accountable so that I actually do what I know(/think) in my head I can do but have never done yet. Another large, larger even, reason though is that this is the kind of content I would spend a whole weekend rabbit-holing in <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19597 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/female-865110_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/female-865110_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/female-865110_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/female-865110_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/female-865110_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/female-865110_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />the best way. Best-case scenario, it’s like a montage scene in a movie where the protagonist becomes a star athlete or gets an amazing life makeover. That’s the goal at least. Worst-case scenario, I crash and burn but at least I try and some writing will occur, like here, for example. That is no small thing. Really, it’s win-win really, as long as I try. Do I sound confident yet?</p>
<p>At times, in this column I will also discuss the practical aspects (caveat: as I’m learning them), such as tone, evaluating drafts, which tenses to consider and why, and how to figure out where to submit stories. The focus, of course, will be on speculative fiction, my own home in the literary universe and, I imagine, for LSQ readers as well. Beyond the practical though is the heart of the column. First: the whys of becoming a writer, the doubts, the encouragement, the rallying, and so on. Second: it’s not too late! It’s carpe diem time. You have to know that seeing lists called “Best 5 New Authors Under 35” or “It’s Not too Late to Start Writing in your 30s” doesn’t equate to a death knell of your own aspirations at age 40+, 50+, and beyond. Women must help each other by sharing these experiences and showing we are not alone in our dreams, our worries, and our realities. I’ve been keeping a list of <a href="https://lithub.com/20-debut-works-of-fiction-by-women-over-40/">older female</a> <a href="https://www.bustle.com/p/women-writers-who-published-their-first-book-after-they-turned-70-18701995">debut</a> <a href="http://www.randysusanmeyers.com/blog/2016/01/debut-novels-by-writers-over-40/">authors</a> for a decade now for exactly those reasons. It’s time for me to flesh out those inspirations and hopefully maybe even inspire others.</p>
<p>So, please join me as I invariably stumble around, trying to become a writer and, dare I say, a published speculative fiction author. Of course, this feels quite lofty at this point. It’s all <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19600 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/notepad-1276779_1920-300x196.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="196" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/notepad-1276779_1920-300x196.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/notepad-1276779_1920-1024x670.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/notepad-1276779_1920-768x502.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/notepad-1276779_1920-1536x1005.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/notepad-1276779_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />possibilities and projects &#8211; all talk, really. I’ve been here many times before, in countless journals, and self-talk as I ride the bus or go to sleep. Nothing has ever happened much beyond that. I’m determined to make this time the real deal. This column today is the first step in holding myself accountable to truly become what I have wanted to be for a very long time. I’m excited and nervous as can be, but here goes. Wish me luck. Let’s go.</p>
<p>Homework: Write twenty minutes every day. Call them <a href="https://juliacameronlive.com/basic-tools/morning-pages/">morning pages</a>, <a href="https://medium.com/@afoxrouch/5-takeaway-tips-from-dorothea-brandes-becoming-a-writer-9ad3f178e0cc">freewriting</a>, whatever. Just write, and write <em>about</em> whatever: story fragments, ramblings, frustrations, and half-remembered dreams. They are all acceptable and encouraged. Get comfortable with your own words.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
