<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Greta Hayer &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/greta-hayer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 22:32:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Five Things To Do While Querying Your Novel</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/five-things-to-do-while-querying-your-novel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greta Hayer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 12:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search of the Dream World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So you’ve done it. You’ve written a book. You’ve sent it to friends, bribed those&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So you’ve done it. You’ve written a book. You’ve sent it to friends, bribed those friends to read it, and made edits and revisions. All that long, painful work. You’ve even sent it out to agents, thinking now you’ve hit the easy part, the lull. A chance to relax without having to think about your plot, your character arcs, and your descriptions. But you’re wrong. Querying is hell, a wait that often ends with form rejection, and only sometimes, rarely, a request. </span></p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26608 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/james-lee-t-xjwyHwY8o-unsplash-300x190.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="190" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/james-lee-t-xjwyHwY8o-unsplash-300x190.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/james-lee-t-xjwyHwY8o-unsplash-1024x649.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/james-lee-t-xjwyHwY8o-unsplash-768x487.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/james-lee-t-xjwyHwY8o-unsplash-1536x973.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/james-lee-t-xjwyHwY8o-unsplash-2048x1298.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But maybe these five fun things will help relieve that long, terrible wait.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Eat! You’re going to need to eat, anyway, since you’re going to be waiting up to a hundred years. If you eat through your anxiety until the point of being so full you’re in pain, you won’t know if your stomach troubles are anxiety-related or from all the cheese.</span></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Read your book again! As soon as you submit it to the wide world, you’re going to find all the typos you missed the first twenty times you read your book!</span></li>
</ol>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26610 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-300x197.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="197" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-300x197.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-1024x673.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-768x505.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-1536x1009.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/siora-photography-hgFY1mZY-Y0-unsplash-2048x1346.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<ol start="3">
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Watch a show you’ve seen a hundred times before. It’s supposed to be good for anxiety, knowing what will happen to all the characters. Unfortunately, knowing what happens to the characters in your book doesn’t lessen your anxiety at all, just makes you think of all the weakest moments of your book, and that industry professionals are probably reading those parts right now. </span></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Cry! You’re going to get rejections. Everyone gets rejections. It’s best to get the crying out of the way early, so you can face the rest of the rejections with a kind of vague numbness. </span></li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Start your next book. This may feel like giving up, but in the 2-12 months it’ll take to hear back from all your queries (if you hear back at all), you’ll have another draft to work with. You might even have a book ready to start this whole process again!</span></li>
</ol>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26611 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/parker-byrd-gxD8hCmi0IQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/parker-byrd-gxD8hCmi0IQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/parker-byrd-gxD8hCmi0IQ-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/parker-byrd-gxD8hCmi0IQ-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/parker-byrd-gxD8hCmi0IQ-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/parker-byrd-gxD8hCmi0IQ-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Power of Games</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-power-of-games/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greta Hayer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 17:20:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search of the Dream World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26297</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In absolute seriousness, games saved my life.  &#160; Years ago, I was in a really&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In absolute seriousness, games saved my life. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Years ago, I was in a really dark place. I was in undergrad, struggling with anxiety and grown-up life, trying to keep my head above water with classes and failing friendships and the fresh, poignant pains of early adulthood. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26351 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aksel-fristrup-w7eaCH6ShR4-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="506" height="285" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aksel-fristrup-w7eaCH6ShR4-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aksel-fristrup-w7eaCH6ShR4-unsplash-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aksel-fristrup-w7eaCH6ShR4-unsplash-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aksel-fristrup-w7eaCH6ShR4-unsplash-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/aksel-fristrup-w7eaCH6ShR4-unsplash.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 506px) 100vw, 506px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But I had a cure that worked better than my Prozac prescription. Games. I spent my weekends eschewing parties for basement game nights, playing everything from Dungeons and Dragons to Risk. Board games kept me from sinking too deep into the dread. Instead of feeling frustrated, bored, sad, or angry about the slow progress of life, my studies, and my relationships, I could pretend to be a settler on the distant island of Catan, building roads for the honor and glory of my people.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was pretty good too; I won one Settlers of <a href="https://www.catan.com/">Catan</a> tournament, and I made the semifinal in another. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve recently gotten into more computer-based strategy games because *gestures to COVID* and, thanks to the patient coaching of my husband, started playing <a href="https://magic.wizards.com/en?gclid=CjwKCAiAm7OMBhAQEiwArvGi3DMiaJSm8uTr6UvCWYQuiFbccr01bQAz44y8qw2LHjc2mV51jLBUQxoCxEwQAvD_BwE">Magic the Gathering</a>. Before the world as we have always known it ended, he and I did some formal drafting and informal EDH games, and I really enjoyed it before someone in the all-male playgroup made a weird comment about my breasts, and I decided I wasn’t comfortable enough continuing to play with those guys. After that, I switched to playing Magic online. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m not the only woman in the game world to have been the target of uncomfortable comments, sexist language, and unwanted sexualization. Gamer friends often feel pressure to either lean into the “sexy nerd girl fantasy” or repel against it by dressing “down” and trying to appear as unsexy as possible. One Twitch streamer I’m friends with talks about how she tries her best to avoid unwanted comments and sexualization by beating her mostly-male views to it, making self-deprecating comments on her own intelligence, or drawing notice to sexual innuendos herself so she can help direct the conversation.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But it seems like, no matter what women do, our bodies are commented on and judged. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And yet, somehow amid this misogynistic weirdness, there seems to be an incredible diversity in gaming, especially among the LGBTQ+ community. I don’t have statistics more than anecdotes and experience, but I’ve noticed a huge amount of gamers who identify as something other than straight, cis, and heteronormative. Something about the escapism of games lets one play around with identity and preferences without making full commitments. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26352 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wayne-low-OvN4OkhkTLo-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wayne-low-OvN4OkhkTLo-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wayne-low-OvN4OkhkTLo-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wayne-low-OvN4OkhkTLo-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wayne-low-OvN4OkhkTLo-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/wayne-low-OvN4OkhkTLo-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This, I believe, is the true magic of games. How, even in a rough, tough reality&#8211;whether that’s a dark phase or an identity crisis or even a weird comment from a weird dude&#8211;gamers find joy, creativity, and expression in their games. </span>Reality can be dark and strange, but in a game, the rules are clear, and everyone has a chance to succeed. Games, from classics like Dungeons and Dragons, to trusty Catan, offer a different world, even for a moment, and that world can be good.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Warlock: Master of the Arcane is the Best Game, and I Won’t Hear a Word Against It</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/why-warlock-master-of-the-arcane-is-the-best-game-and-i-wont-hear-a-word-against-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greta Hayer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 10:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search of the Dream World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the first computer games I ever played came on a CD that came&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the first computer games I ever played came on a CD that came free with some other game, and it was called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Majesty:_The_Fantasy_Kingdom_Sim"><em>Majesty</em></a>. It might have even been a bonus gift with my dad&#8217;s <a href="https://www.vox.com/2015/5/12/8594049/aol-free-trial-cds">AOL disk</a> (Yes, this old.) This was back in the days when I gamed in my parents&#8217; basement on a shared computer with the whole family. The only music on it was a playlist my big brother had pirated song-by-song, with Hendrix, Ry Cooder, and Steely Dan. The only strategy games I’d played before were <em>Lords of the Realm</em> and chess, both of which I was not very good at.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26106 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/wizard-4417511_1920-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/wizard-4417511_1920-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/wizard-4417511_1920-1024x1024.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/wizard-4417511_1920-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/wizard-4417511_1920-768x768.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/wizard-4417511_1920-1536x1536.png 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/wizard-4417511_1920-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/wizard-4417511_1920.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />But <em>Majesty</em> was great. You played as a fantasy king, recruiting heroes and building guilds. Monsters spawned around you, and each level started you pretty much from scratch as you reclaimed your kingdom from the evil creatures. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best part of the game was the heroes. Each type had little catchphrases they’d say when you interacted with them. The knights were “Ready to serve,” and the rogues warned players not to touch their gold. I liked the creepy skeleton priestesses of Krypta the best. When they died, they whispered, “At last.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2012, the makers of <em>Majesty</em>, <a href="https://www.paradoxplaza.com/">Paradox Interactive</a>, came out with another game in the same world. Though I wouldn’t discover it until I finished undergrad in 2016, I fell in love with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Warlock:_Master_of_the_Arcane"><em>Warlock: Master of the Arcane</em>.</a> You play as a Great Mage, rather like the king in <em>Majesty</em>, only you get direct control over your armies and get to cast spells as you expand your research throughout the game. It’s a turn-based strategy like the <em>Civilization</em> games, but instead of historical units, they’re fantasy ones. There are ogres and vampires and dragons, plus all sorts of elves and dark elves and goblins. And, to my delight, the developers included all the same temples from <em>Majesty</em>, including my creepy priestesses. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The game has simple diplomacy, complex spellcasting, and multiple ways to win. Mostly, though, it’s about making war on the other Great Mages and building cities. I love the race for resources, the endless quest of expansion, tempered with random monster encounters and side quests. I mostly love the part when I take my dragon army across the world and burn everything in its path. Plus there’s a monster called “Cockroach of Hell,” and I’m pretty sure I’ve defeated that in real life, too. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve played this game a lot in the past year and a half. I can waste a week of pandemic time, focusing on a game, and when I win or lose, just start a new one. I’ve won on the “impossible” difficulty setting, but there’s an “armageddon” mode that I’ve never beaten. The game is difficult and sometimes annoying, and there are definitely some AI flaws, but I love the character of the game. It’s the proper mix of nostalgia and complexity, and, even though there are newer games with better graphics, I keep coming back to <em>Warlock</em>. I believe it to be the best game, and I won’t hear a word against it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, during my research for this post, I realized that there’s a sequel game, called <em>Warlock II</em>, and so maybe I’ll have a new favorite game in a couple of weeks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What’s your favorite game? Do you have a classic go-to that you keep coming back to, or are you always seeking new games? </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of &#8220;Trash Fantasy&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-trash-fantasy/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-trash-fantasy/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greta Hayer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 14:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search of the Dream World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I don’t know if I could have gotten through quarantine* without my books. I think&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25674 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I don’t know if I could have gotten through quarantine* without my books. I think a lot of people were/are in the same boat as me. I’ve read more books than I have since high school, back when I used to devour inches-thick fantasies in a matter of days. During quarantine, I fell back into some of those habits, and my bookshelves have borne the weight of my renewed hobby with silent distress. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But this past year, I haven’t exactly been reading “good” books. Not the deep, complicated epics the genre is known for, or even the thoughtful and acclaimed literary novels I got used to in graduate school. Sure, I’ll pick up one or two like that and slip it into my To Be Read shelf, but the majority of what I’ve been reading is what I lovingly call “Trash Fantasy.”</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trash Fantasy, as I define it, are those lighthearted fantasy books full of tropes and romance that aren’t necessarily well-written in a literary sense. Sometimes, they seem like they should have gone through one more round of revisions to close up plot holes or explain this point or that one. The characters are the focus, and the most compelling part, rather than the world or some grand political plot. Sometimes, they’re called YA, but I think that’s often a misnomer.**</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another way to define it? Comfort reads. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s just that during this time of upheaval, plague, and injustice, I want to see happy endings. I want the knight to rescue the princess, or the princess to rescue herself. I want the kings to rule fairly and the gods to be just, and I want the enemy mages to kiss at the end, all problems fading away before their love. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don’t know if I have the internal strength to read about another grand library burning down, or the lovers torn apart, or an empire falling into dust. Things like that seem too real. Too close to home. So I&#8217;m reading more and more books to escape, and rediscovering my love of lighthearted, charming stories. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though I still love deep, thought-provoking novels, even sad ones, taking breaks between them<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25676 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920-300x138.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="138" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920-300x138.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920-1024x470.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920-768x353.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920-1536x706.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> by reading &#8220;trash fantasy&#8221; books has certainly helped me this past year. It&#8217;s w</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">hat’s kept me afloat&#8211;knowing I can crack the spine of one of my beloved “trash fantasy” novels and believe that there will be a happily ever after.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you have any favorites that could fall into my affectionately titled “trash fantasy” genre? Let me know in the comments!</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">*I know Covid’s not over. It’s complicated. Please get vaccinated.  </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">**A lot of adult fantasy books written by women are considered YA even though they aren’t. It’s a sexism thing. It sucks. Other people have written about it <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/shortcuts/2019/jan/30/women-write-fantasy-for-grown-ups-too">here</a>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-trash-fantasy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What’s in a Name? Naming Strategies in Fantasy and Science Fiction</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/whats-in-a-name-naming-strategies-in-fantasy-and-science-fiction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greta Hayer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search of the Dream World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have agonized over names. Boy names, girl names, names that slip between binary genders.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25438 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jon-tyson-566CgCRSNCk-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jon-tyson-566CgCRSNCk-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jon-tyson-566CgCRSNCk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jon-tyson-566CgCRSNCk-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jon-tyson-566CgCRSNCk-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jon-tyson-566CgCRSNCk-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I have agonized over names. Boy names, girl names, names that slip between binary genders. I have spent hours pouring over baby name websites, writing potential combinations in notebooks, crossing some out, and circling others. No, I’m not pregnant, much to my mother’s eternal frustration; I’m a writer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All writers struggle with names, and I think fantasy and science fiction writers have it the hardest. After all, it’s a bit of a letdown if the hero saving the world is called something like “John” or “Abby.” What would the Hunger Games be like if Katherine was the representative from District 12? Or if the wizard Gordon picked up the hobbit Bob to destroy the One Ring? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The naming of places and characters in fantasy and science fiction presents unique challenges and solutions. First and foremost is the sheer number of names a science fiction or fantasy novel needs. When building a world from scratch, a writer has to figure out names for countries, cities, neighborhoods, and streets, as well as all the characters. Numerous websites are dedicated to fantasy or science fiction name generators, which spit out suggested titles for everything from elves to spaceships. Many fantasy books include an appendix with lists of characters and places, sometimes absolutely essential. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The nomenclature of a world can give hints to the kind of cultural echoes it intends to evoke in the reader. For example, <a href="https://www.naominovik.com/">Naomi Novik</a>’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Temeraire </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">books are set in an alternate version of our world, and the dragon breeds are perfectly chosen to reflect the time and culture. The English dragons have names such as Regal Copper or Winchester, and the French dragons are, well, French, like the Fleur-de-Nuit, which is dangerous in night attacks, or the Flamme-de-Gloire, a firebreather. These types of names give the reader a handhold into the writer’s imaginary world so that they can more grasp a picture of the setting and character. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other series like <a href="http://www.robinhobb.com/index.htm">Robin Hobb</a>’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Farseer Trilogy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, use the same kind of culturally representative names, but their significance is woven into the lore of the world. The first king, “Taker his name was, quite simply, and perhaps with that naming began the tradition that sons and daughters of his lineage would be given names that would shape their lives and beings&#8230;but history shows us this was not always sufficient to bind a child to the virtue that named it” (</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assassin’s Apprentice</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, 1). Thus the series is populated by characters who either exemplify their names, such as the honest King Verity, or show a stark contrast between the intended virtue and the character’s nature, like unfaithful Prince Chivalry and truly awful Prince Regal. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not all fantasy names are so structured, but few are chosen thoughtlessly. I recently read </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gideon the Ninth</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tamsyn_Muir">Tamsyn Muir</a> and was absolutely delighted by the care taken with every character’s name. For the titular character, she writes, “There are a lot of reasons as to why Gideon is called Gideon. The warlike prophet of God who really messed up the Midianites is part of it. Gideon is a prophetic name: someone named their own demise in her” (468). And Harrowhark, another major<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25439 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/waldemar-brandt-qqxDmJpMhAk-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/waldemar-brandt-qqxDmJpMhAk-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/waldemar-brandt-qqxDmJpMhAk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/waldemar-brandt-qqxDmJpMhAk-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/waldemar-brandt-qqxDmJpMhAk-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/waldemar-brandt-qqxDmJpMhAk-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> character, is named “very specifically for the harrowing of Hell” (468). This kind of Biblical root casts an ominous, gothic spell on the novel, and though not all the names for this book are strictly religious, many draw allusions to ancient texts that gave me a deeper sense of the atmosphere of the book. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Of course, not all fantasy or science fiction has developed naming strategies, and I’m sure some authors pluck names from thin air and fit them perfectly into their stories. I believe, however, that names in fantasy and science fiction carry power. They can determine a character’s fate or help build a world. They can be on-the-nose or only vaguely reminiscent of the real world. Either way, they often have to do more work than names in non-genre fiction, but when crafted with grace and creativity, names in fantasy and science fiction can help guide readers through strange and wondrous lands by using real-world languages and cultures to inform the readers or build atmosphere while the writer sweeps them away on the grandest of adventures.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Write What You Know, But Remember What You Don&#8217;t</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/write-what-you-know-but-remember-what-you-dont/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/write-what-you-know-but-remember-what-you-dont/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greta Hayer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search of the Dream World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25099</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early in a writer’s education, they are told this maxim: Write what you know. Later,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/505eectw54k-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25276 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/505eectw54k-300x200.jpg" alt="person holding ballpoint pen writing on notebook" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/505eectw54k-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/505eectw54k-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/505eectw54k-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/505eectw54k-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/505eectw54k-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Early in a writer’s education, they are told this maxim: Write what you know. Later, when a writer finds Twitter, they learn more about what that means. Don’t write about people or cultures that you aren’t a part of (or, if you do, research extensively, and then research some more). Don’t coopt a story from a minority group you’re not a part of, which can take away a story from a minority voice and lead to damaging stereotypes. Write your own experience rather than pushing that experience onto others. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This gets a little trickier for fantasy and science-fiction writers. Of course, none of us (that I know of&#8230;?) are androids or aliens or elves, and yet plenty of writers have made compelling and emotional stories based on experiences that they can and never will have. Some do it by drawing parallels between fantasy equivalents and real-world distinctions and problems, and some writers use history or imagination to craft something unique and uniquely real, even if it has dragons, too. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">(</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because dragons mean something, damn it! </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I shout, somewhat insane, as I add dragons to everything I write.)</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But one thing that’s got me thinking is when writers write about sexual identity. Does one have to be gay to write a gay character convincingly? It certainly should help. Especially in this moment of <a href="https://www.brodartbooks.com/newsletter/posts-in-2019/what-is-ownvoices">#ownvoices</a>, there is a call for LGBTQ+ characters written by LGBTQ+ people. Obviously, this is something I want to see expanded. I want all readers to be able to connect to characters that make them feel seen, special, and alive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And yet, please allow me one slight tangent before I ask a question. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was recently reading the Masquerade series by Seth Dickinson (<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/topple-empires-with-these-anti-colonial-sapphics/">which another blogger wrote about here!</a>). The main character is a lesbian, and Dickinson, as far as my limited research shows, identifies as a man. I tried to look up his sexuality to “prove” to myself that he could write a convincing lesbian, but then I stopped. Why was I prying into his personal life when I could simply look at his writing? Baru, our main girl, is conflicted and damaged and absolutely brilliant and dangerously flawed, and her love carries all those layers. Her feelings seem authentic and read powerfully, and I’m not the only one who thinks that. His AMA on Reddit holds comments by self-reported “real lesbians” who found Baru to be convincing and interesting and thoughtfully created. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I stopped trying to pry into Dickinson’s real life and asked myself this question: must a queer-identifying writer “come out” in order to prove that they have the right to write about queer characters?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are a myriad of reasons that people might choose not to come out. Maybe they’re intensely private. Maybe they have family members who wouldn’t approve. These days, it’s getting easier and easier for people to be themselves fully and honestly, but that doesn’t mean it’s easy for everyone. Do we, as readers, demand that sacrifice of privacy from authors? Should we? Do we not get enough of the writer, woven into the text and characters, all formed from their mind? If a character can touch a reader’s heartstrings, does it matter?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m ultimately unsure what is the right answer. I want authentic, diverse characters, and I want<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hgfy1mzy-y0-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25277 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hgfy1mzy-y0-300x197.jpg" alt="woman covering her face with white book" width="300" height="197" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hgfy1mzy-y0-300x197.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hgfy1mzy-y0-1024x673.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hgfy1mzy-y0-768x505.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hgfy1mzy-y0-1536x1009.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/hgfy1mzy-y0-2048x1346.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a> writers from marginalized groups to have a platform to write about their experiences (and their imaginary experiences). But I don’t want writers to have to reveal the details of their relationships and relationship histories, or there to be a call for them to bear their desires to the crowd just so they “are allowed” to write about a thing. This can call into question not only the privacy of the writer but of their partners, and outside scrutiny of a relationship is rarely accurate or helpful. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maybe there’s some middle ground. A writer who wants to keep their sexual identity under wraps could perhaps tell their agent or their editor, though writing a query letter can be hard enough without needing to explain something as intimate as one’s identity. But even then, a writer could be called out by readers and asked to reveal something about themselves that they didn’t intend to reveal. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But maybe that’s the risk of writing anything. Every word written and read draws us a little closer toward the writer’s heart. If they’re writing what they know, then the risk of learning about the person behind the story grows immeasurably.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’d love to see what you think about this issue in the comments. I don’t have a clear answer, and I don’t know if there is one. I hope that we can someday live in a world where people don’t have to fear coming out or revealing that side of themselves, but change takes time. Until then, write what you know and remember what you don’t. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/write-what-you-know-but-remember-what-you-dont/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hope, Fear, and the Stories We Can Tell Each Other</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hope-fear-and-the-stories-we-can-tell-each-other/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greta Hayer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 10:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search of the Dream World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have a deep-clutching fear of coming out of quarantine. I’m an introvert, if this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24942 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/books-2385402_1920-300x164.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="164" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/books-2385402_1920-300x164.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/books-2385402_1920-1024x561.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/books-2385402_1920-768x421.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/books-2385402_1920-1536x842.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/books-2385402_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I have a deep-clutching fear of coming out of quarantine.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m an introvert, if this past year has taught me anything. I like my time alone; I like my quiet. I love the long days of nothing, even as it coaxes me into anxiety-rich isolation. I do so much more writing when I have nothing planned, nothing to look forward to but my work and the pleasure of my pen on the page, the way the words bloom beneath my hand. In this solitude, my characters lean in, whispering about their next adventures, the next thing I should&#8211;no, must&#8211;write. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But as restrictions let up and we all emerge back into the light, that strange space of creative isolation is falling away. I have to field party invitations and coffee dates, and even as I ache for human contact and hugs and all the things I’ve missed, I find myself shying from it as well. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It started with the<a href="https://www.vaccines.gov/"> vaccine</a>, a room full of people brimming with nervous energy. My husband made bad jokes to the volunteers, laughing as he asked staff about the “lizard-like side effects” and his new desire to buy Windows products. In New Orleans, even a medical emergency is an excuse for a party, and trippy jazz music played loud over the speakers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“How are you feeling?” the attendants asked. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I have no idea,” I said, wondering if this was the way my body always felt, buzzing and jumping and skittish. Perhaps I had forgotten how to behave in public, how to remember to just be me. Was I the only one? Everyone in the hall looked so beautiful and so strange. One woman had blue hair. She looked like every young woman I’ve ever seen. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m fully vaccinated now, trying to step lightly back into the world. I watch my husband jump back into game clubs and friendships, forming new ones with an ease I envy. I feel rusty when I talk. I can’t remember who my friends are until I see their Twitter handles rolling through my feed. We plan a party, my husband and I, but I don’t know who to invite. Who’s left in the city after the retreat from the storm? Who’s rooted enough to return? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The other night, we went to a bar and sat outside. At the table next to us, a birthday girl wore a puffy dress and a safety pin bursting with dollar bills <a href="https://www.nola.com/opinions/article_f057776d-04cd-51cf-ad52-6484cb500479.html">(a New Orleans birthday tradition).</a> Everyone looked beautiful, and I smiled at strangers and joked awkwardly with a woman who asked to borrow the ashtray on our table. I fumbled for words to talk to strangers, from my drink order to the response when a stylish lady complimented my hair. Small talk is excruciating; I’ve forgotten how to do it. I want to ask the kind of questions I read in books, what it means to be human, what androids feel when they fall in love. I want to discuss magics and philosophies and politics. I don&#8217;t remember what normal people talk about in normal situations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we return home, I felt intoxicated by not only the too-strong drinks (bartenders in this city make sure you get your money’s worth) but the presence of others, a weird energy that has me buzzing and excited and thoroughly nervous. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All the while, my stories slip around me, too slick to grab onto. I grasp for a plot on a novel and<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24943 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/freedom-4216533_1920-300x160.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="160" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/freedom-4216533_1920-300x160.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/freedom-4216533_1920-1024x546.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/freedom-4216533_1920-768x410.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/freedom-4216533_1920-1536x819.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/freedom-4216533_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> give up in chapter two. I write the first paragraphs of a short story, then lay aside my pen. The return to humanity is too distracting. My imaginary elves and wizards and dragons can’t compete with the reality unfurling around me. Maybe that says something about the inherent magic in all of us, in the power of the stories we can tell each other, not just tell ourselves. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I can’t be the only one with this potent mix of hopes and fears. What do you look forward to, this side of the plague? What do you fear? And what has you grappling back and forth, unsure which instinct to trust?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coming back into the world is scary and daunting, and I’m afraid of all the changes it will bring, but there’s something enchanting about it, too, something absolutely magical. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Multiclassing in History</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/multiclassing-in-history/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greta Hayer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 12:16:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search of the Dream World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24536</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The weirdness of our past never fails to amaze me.  &#160; I studied history in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The weirdness of our past never fails to amaze me. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I studied history in undergrad. I always knew I wanted to be a writer, but I wanted to prove that I could do something else, too. Philosophy was fun, but there were too many people in the classes who liked using nearly nonsensical words in order to sound like they did the reading, and I spent too much time decoding statements that were much less profound in translation. So not philosophy. I dabbled, briefly, into the sciences and left with a C in Psych 101 and a Pass/Fail in Astronomy. So I went back to books, looking for the places where storytelling branched between truth and fiction. After Herodotus and Sir John Mandeville, and a myriad of other “historians” who clearly made stuff up, I decided I definitely liked history.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I take a lot of inspiration from history when I write. In my story published here, at Luna Station, I began with a fascination with Early Empire Rome and twisted it to fit my needs. In the novel I’m finishing up (and if you’re a literary agent, it’s totally ready, and I’d love to send it to you), the whole plot wraps around a collection of bizarre, little-studied fairy tales. I stole all the best images, from a husband laying down a sword in the marriage bed between him and his wife, to women born out of fruit trees. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I absolutely love finding other writers who take from the past and weave it into distant worlds or magic systems. Sometimes, writers include the note from history for style, but this multiclass in history often adds an unexpected layer of harmony into a magical world. It can help orient or disorient readers, depending on the author’s goal, and resonates with something profoundly human and deeply magical. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I want to point out a couple of books I’ve read recently that take the magic from the past and build it into something magnificent. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-24730 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/sin-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/sin-198x300.jpg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/sin-677x1024.jpg 677w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/sin-768x1161.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/sin-1016x1536.jpg 1016w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/sin-1355x2048.jpg 1355w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/sin.jpg 1399w" sizes="(max-width: 198px) 100vw, 198px" /></span></p>
<p><a href="https://www.megancampisi.com/sin-eater"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sin Eater</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> by Megan Campisi begins with a note about the historical inspiration for her premise, which involves women who eat foods upon the graves of the dead in order to absolve them of their transgressions. There’s little known about these historic sin eaters. Still, it’s enough to seed the book, and Campisi’s novel is an incredible, lyrical story set in a world just different enough from Elizabethan England that the echoes make the past that much stranger.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Or take </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Memory Called Empire</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, by <a href="https://www.arkadymartine.net/">Arkady Martine</a>. Martine is a historian of the Byzantine Empire, and you can see the reach of her knowledge in the richness and depth of her world. In an interview with NPR, she talks about how her Teixcalaan Empire <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-24731 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/empire-194x300.jpg" alt="" width="194" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/empire-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/empire.jpg 307w" sizes="(max-width: 194px) 100vw, 194px" />takes aspects of the Byzantines, ancient Rome, Mexica, and Aztec history. The Teixcalaan names, a number-noun combination that produces characters such as Three Seagrass and Six Direction, are inspired by the Mixtec people of Oaxaca, who had spiritual names based on their day of birth and a series of twenty signs. It’s those names that I found so fascinating and lush&#8211;they gave the book an incredible depth of culture&#8211;and when I learned they were inspired by real-world practices, I got all geeky and squealy inside. I highly recommend the book, the<a href="https://www.npr.org/2019/04/07/710356506/questions-for-arkady-martine-author-of-a-memory-called-empire"> interview with NPR</a>, and <a href="https://www.torforgeblog.com/2021/02/15/whats-in-a-teixcalaanli-name/">this post</a> about how to find your Texicalaan name. (I’m Sixteen Sapphire by their rules, but in my heart, I’m One Hundred Book.)</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I could mention so many more books that channel the magic of our past and put it into the magic of the written word, but I will run out of internet page space. It’s something I love to see. It reminds me that we’re all living in a world so much more complex than it appears on the surface, that living memory is only a surface, a facade over the strange, beautiful, wild, and wonderful world from which we all came. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moon Landing</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/moon-landing/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/moon-landing/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greta Hayer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search of the Dream World]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I was a child, I went to the moon. We did it in an&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I was a child, I went to the moon. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24466 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ju-guan-D-jLxBtEwaA-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ju-guan-D-jLxBtEwaA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ju-guan-D-jLxBtEwaA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ju-guan-D-jLxBtEwaA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ju-guan-D-jLxBtEwaA-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ju-guan-D-jLxBtEwaA-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We did it in an afternoon, my preschool class and I. We entered the shuttle through the airlock, pressed buttons, and watched on the monitor as we took off. The shuttle rocked around, then smoothed, then shifted again when we landed. On the moon, we examined rocks in sealed chambers with thick plastic gloves, and I remember watching the Earth through the shuttle window. I tried to find Iowa (North America) or Minnesota (South America), but I couldn’t see them through the swirls of clouds. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before it was time for our parents to pick us up, we headed back to Earth and ate <a href="https://astronautfoods.com/">astronaut ice cream</a> on the journey home. The texture was strange, and it made me thirsty, but it tasted so sweet. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was one of the best days of my life. I had been to space. I was an astronaut. I told everyone who would listen. I told friends and teachers. When reading about space exploration, I’d sigh over <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/">NASA’s</a> conservative goals about landing on the moon again in the future. “I’ve already been there,” I said to my friends, proud and smiling. I’d been to so many places. Iowa, Minnesota, the moon. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not until years later did I realize my mistake. I wasn’t an astronaut but a dumb kid, tricked by the clever ruse created by the Science Center, where the model shuttle performed moon-trips for everyone with a ticket and a dream of the stars. I remember quite vividly the gut-wrenching pain of disappointment, coupled with the flush of embarrassment. Not only was I a liar against my will, but my greatest adventure was revealed to be nothing but an educational simulation. I loved going to the moon and having gone to the moon and now what was I without it?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was the idea of the moon that made me an astronaut. I believed it so fiercely that, for a while, it was nearly the truth. Or </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">my</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> truth, at least. Perhaps it was this twist of truth that led me to fantasy and science fiction. It’s the same truth that lets me forget that I’m a normal human when I read, and I can be a hobbit or an elf or the heir to an ancient and powerful throne. Something otherworldly. Something </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">off-world</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The older I get, the harder it is to tap into those other worlds. Most of my time is wrapped up with normal, mundane things, and I find little magic in the endless taste of adulthood, like loading the dishwasher and paying my mortgage. Adulting is hard, but the worst part about it is the grind of truth against imagination, of reality and news cycles and work schedules against the place within yourself that believes you can do anything, even go to the moon. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24467 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/johannes-plenio-DKix6Un55mw-unsplash-300x195.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="195" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/johannes-plenio-DKix6Un55mw-unsplash-300x195.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/johannes-plenio-DKix6Un55mw-unsplash-1024x665.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/johannes-plenio-DKix6Un55mw-unsplash-768x498.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/johannes-plenio-DKix6Un55mw-unsplash-1536x997.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/johannes-plenio-DKix6Un55mw-unsplash-2048x1329.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />These days, I have to consciously choose the dream world. It’s hard finding time to let my imagination roam, and I end up going on long, solitary walks around my neighborhood, listening to music and searching for a way back into the dream. It’s more exciting there, more beautiful and magical. People go to the moon all the time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once a month, I’ll be searching for the dream world in some way, pointing out little pieces of  magic I find as I make my way through life. Sometimes, it might mean talking about a great book or playing a fantastic game, and sometimes my journey might look like this post, musing about the past and future and what enchantments lie between. Either way, I hope you’ll join me on my quest, and perhaps we might find something magical together. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/moon-landing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
