<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Flesh and Bones of Fantasy &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-flesh-and-bones-of-fantasy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 02:15:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Defining Character: the Mary Sue</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/defining-character-the-mary-sue/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabrielle Lissauer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 17:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Flesh and Bones of Fantasy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you think there’s going to be any rhyme or reason to these posts, then&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you think there’s going to be any rhyme or reason to these posts, then you’re sadly mistaken.</p>
<p>Today, after looking at some things, I wanted to talk about character types. Or to be more exact, one particular character type: The Mary Sue. I’m sure many people have heard of the Mary Sue and have hated the Mary Sue. And because of this hatred I feel it’s necessary to talk about her, or him. At least when it comes to fantasy fiction and not fan fiction. It’s only in published fiction that I think a Mary Sue is a problem.</p>
<p>In fan fiction they’re essentially harmless. Yes, they may completely break the rules of reality for the world, but it’s not like they’re canon. And they’re written for fun. They’re written by people trying to make themselves worthy to be with their favorite characters. After all, you have to be pretty impressive to get the attention of someone like Harry Potter or Legolas or Loki. Admittedly the characters are often out of character, but it’s wish fulfillment. It’s wish fulfillment and learning how to write. I think the Mary Sues in fan fiction might be a bit more acceptable if they were well written.</p>
<p>Lots of things are excusable if they’re well written. Including Mary Sues. In fact, if they are well written they no longer become Mary Sues. Which is what’s found in a great deal of published fiction. In fact a great deal of published characters would fail the Mary Sue test going straight into the abort and redo from start territory.</p>
<p>But they’re not.</p>
<p>Why?</p>
<p>Because of context.</p>
<p>Not so much the context of the story, but the context of the world itself.</p>
<p>Deep down, a Mary Sue’s biggest problem is that they don’t fit in. They’re exceptions to the rules and laws of reality and morality. Or the story’s reality and morality.( If we were to deal with things on our reality alone then nothing would work.) Because of this, while Wonder Woman could be considered a Mary Sue if she were in, say, the Firefly or Harry Potter universe, she’s not in the Superhero universes because they deal with things just as bizarre and ridiculous. In her universe alone there’s aliens who somehow manage to get super powers by being on Earth because the color of our sun is different, a ring that gives its wearer the ability to create constructs out of green (or other colored) energy, aliens that can ride motorcycle space ships without needing any protective clothing from the emptiness of space and so on and so on. And all sorts of characters that run around in tight costumes that shouldn’t really be possible. So, a woman who is made of clay and given life by a Greek goddess and has a lasso that lets her make people tell the truth isn’t so out of place.</p>
<p>She’s able to do things that other people in her universe can do.</p>
<p>So, not a Mary Sue.</p>
<p>However, if there is corollary to this, as mentioned with the second part of the definition of a Mary Sue &#8211; that is dealing with the world’s morality. A favorite example of mine is from Christopher Paolini’s Inheritance series and involves comparing two characters: Eragon and Lord Barst. At one point in Brisingr, Eragon and Ayra run into a patrol of Galbatorix’ soldiers. They could have easily avoided them as they had about an hour’s leeway to find a place to hide or turn themselves invisible, as Eragon had done so a few chapters earlier. Their magical elven senses were able to pick out the patrol before the patrol could pick out them. Instead they end up deciding that they can’t do anything but wait for the soldiers to catch up with them and then they attacked the men, brutally killing them in manners that included punching one of the men through the ribcage. Then Eragon chases after a lone soldier who made a break for freedom and, though the man begs for mercy, claiming he was forced to join the army and he didn’t want to be there, Eragon snaps his neck, complete with the line “this will hurt you more than it will hurt me”.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Lord Barst is accused of ripping a man’s head off and burning the man’s family alive when he defied the order to join Galbatorix’s army.</p>
<p>Both of these actions are reprehensible, but we’re supposed to be okay with Eragon’s actions because he’s the Hero. The writing doesn’t get down upon Eragon for doing these things, but it does get down on Lord Barst for doing what he did. This fact that there’s nothing considered wrong with what Eragon does is what makes him a Mary Sue. He does something just as horrible as Lord Barst &#8211; if anything it’s worse because he could have avoided the situation &#8211; but we’re supposed to laud him and still condemn Lord Barst. Eragon only gets away with it because he’s the hero. And by making him the exception to the laws of morality, he becomes a creature out of place in his world and pushes him into becoming a Mary Sue.</p>
<p>There is nothing wrong with what Eragon does because he’s the protagonist. The protagonists in George R. R. Martin’s Song of Ice and Fire series do things just as horrible as Eragon did, but we’re never expected to think they’re doing good things. A great many times the reader is utterly appalled at what happens and the other characters in the book are, too.</p>
<p>Thus it shows that it’s not the actions of the characters that make them a Mary Sue so much is the reactions of others. Especially when they contradict similar reactions to the same actions done by other people. The Mary Sues in fan fiction works follow this same pattern, however it’s more important that the published works should avoid the Mary Sue.</p>
<p>Published works are creating worlds with rules that the readers expect to be followed. They are creating the foundations of lives and stories. They have a higher standard to follow. Using a Mary Sue in a published work is a form of laziness and selfishness. The author doesn’t care that their pet character breaks the rules. The character is more important than the story and the laws. If they can’t find a way to create the same story without creating a Mary Sue then perhaps they should learn their craft a bit better.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fantasy Expanded</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fantasy-expanded/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabrielle Lissauer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 14:40:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Flesh and Bones of Fantasy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2073</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Now that fantasy itself has been defined some other definitions might be useful. These definitions,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now that fantasy itself has been defined some other definitions might be useful. These definitions, once again, are purely personal and purely done for personal reasons and to create a common language and vocabulary. The first thing is the different kinds of fantasy. These are the subgenres of the over-reaching fantasy umbrella. Often times it is a sliding scale and at the edges things can blur and blend. It’s not clear cut, but instead a beautiful rainbow of mushiness.</p>
<p>Our first two sub-genres are related to each other and often are hard to tell which one is which, especially since one often has shades of the other. Those are high fantasy and low fantasy.</p>
<p>High fantasy stories contain worlds with excessive amounts of magic leaking out of people’s ears. Unicorns are abundant; people see and experience magic in their every day life; learning to be a magic user is an accepted career choice for a person. At times it feels like rainbows and pointy wizard hats. Magic is <em>showy</em>. Some example of high fantasy worlds include Terry Pratchett’s <em>Discworld</em> series, Mercedes Lackey’s <em>Heralds of Valdemar</em> and <em>500 Kingdom</em> series, Dungeons and Dragon’s <em>Forgotten Realms</em> setting and Jim Butcher’s <em>the Codex Alera. </em>Here magic is everyday. It’s visible in the world and effects how people live their daily lives. The Heralds with their Companions patrol the lands to help protect it and there are people with Gifts that allow them to do anything from magic to telepathy. In the Discworld there are witches and wizards – whose librarian is an orangutan and no one finds this odd. Death walks among people and buys curry. The Codex Alera series is set in a world where everyone has magic – or at least the ability of some sort to manipulate “furies” or elemental creatures. In each of these examples magic is there and in everyone’s face.</p>
<p>On the other hand, in low fantasy stories magic isn’t as evident. People will still know about it but it’s more abstract at times. <em>The Lord of the Rings</em> by J.R.R. Tolkien and <em>A Song of Ice and Fire</em> by George R. R. Martin are both good examples of these kinds of worlds. Here magic is subtle. In the Lord of the Rings, there is magic in the elves and the wizards, but you could easily take the world ‘elf’ out of the books and nothing truly would be lost. Magic isn’t visible in large ways. There’s the ring, but for most people in Middle Earth they can live their entire lives without seeing an elf or meeting a wizard or an orc for that matter. <em>The Game of Thrones</em>, up until the very end of the book, doesn’t appear to have a single <em>hint</em> of magic. Sure they discuss dragons and there are dragon eggs, but they’re treated like stones and dragons like stories. The only thing that separates this book from any other medieval story set on Earth is that it’s on a different world. <em>Then</em> the dragons are born and suddenly any doubt of the book being fantasy is tossed to the dragons’ dinner.</p>
<p>So, for me it is the impact of magic on the ordinary people’s lives that makes a story high or low fantasy.</p>
<p>The next question would be: what is the difference between epic and non-epic fantasy stories? To answer this question one must look at what is at stake. The higher the stakes the more epic a story is. Epics are large stories that span the world and have consequences that resonate to almost everywhere: the bigger the impact and larger the stakes the grander the epic. (If well written, of course.)</p>
<p>It’s not the number of <em>books</em> or episodes in the work that makes a story epic, but the scale of things. How big are things? How big are the stakes? Or at least how big do the stakes feel to the readers? A story can try for epic all it wants but if the readers don’t feel like there’s much at stake, then the story isn’t very epic.</p>
<p>Here again, is a sliding scale. Individual stories that are in a series can even move up or down the epic scale depending on how the stakes are raised and how personal the stories are.</p>
<p>That is another thing that can make an epic story. The more personal ones are generally less epic feeling than the ones that spawn multiple view points. The more view points, the more things become at stake because the readers can see more things happening in the world around the characters. The authors can easily transport their readers to all over the globe without having to actually move the main character around all the time.</p>
<p>Urban fantasy is a strange creature. While it generally seems to apply to stories that take place in Modern Day Earth, personally I think it could apply to any story where the city it takes place in could be considered a “character”. The story is so setting – so city specific – that it couldn’t happen in any other city. Especially for stories that take place on secondary worlds. So the first Mistborn Book could be considered an urban fantasy because the city itself is an important part of the story and a character in and of itself as much as the Dresden Files could.</p>
<p>That is possibly the major categories of fantasy fiction. There are, of course, always exceptions to the rules. But with this groundwork it&#8217;s easier to find those exceptions and to see why they do or don&#8217;t work.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Naming of Dwarves</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-naming-of-dwarves/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gabrielle Lissauer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 17:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Flesh and Bones of Fantasy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=1970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the important and first things that must be remembered when dealing with fantasy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the important and first things that must be remembered when dealing with fantasy or with any other genre- or even any subculture-is they all have their Own Vernacular that outsiders might not understand. Concepts someone well versed in the subject might take for granted can be confusing to a stranger. An excellent example of this happened when I was talking to someone about one of the chapters in my book about fantasy tropes. She is not at all versant in fantasy. Harry Potter, the Lord of the Rings, these are things that she’s heard of vaguely, but not actually read. She prefers non-genre novels and the closest she gets to fantasy is Magical Realism. I was discussing dwarves.</p>
<p>The short and hairy folk with a fondness for gold and hammers and axes. At least, that’s what dwarves means to me. They’re a separate race of people.</p>
<p>She, on the other hand, thought I was talking about people with dwarfism.  And the entire time I was going on about how they were a separate race completely confused her. After all, they&#8217;re humans, too, aren&#8217;t they? I can&#8217;t even imagine what she thought of me when I was talking about them!</p>
<p>But the reason for the confusion was because, though we were using the same words, we speaking in two different languages.</p>
<p>I was speaking the language of the knowledgeable expert and she was listening with the ears of a lay  person.</p>
<p>Because of this we entered confusion. It doesn’t seem like there would be such confusion, but the experts often times take it for granted that everyone else knows what they’re talking about. After all it seems so natural and obvious to us, shouldn’t everyone know that dwarves are a separate race than humans and elves?  Look at the Lord of the Rings or the D&amp;D Games or mythology even for proof of this. Unfortunately, that doesn’t help if the other person hasn’t actually <i>read</i> any of the proof providing material</p>
<p>The particular language of fantasy is one with deep roots. One that goes back to the earliest days of storytelling. It’s why people say that all fantasy stories are the same. Which in a way is completely true, but only because fantasy stories require certain elements to be fantasy stories. It may not necessarily be dwarves that are needed, but there are still certain aspects that are repeated throughout.</p>
<p>It is these sorts of things that I shall mostly be discussing within this space.</p>
<p>Before we go on any further I would like to get some important definitions out of the way. These are <i>my</i> definitions of these words and concepts that I’ll be using throughout my writing here. Are they the be all, end all of definitions? No, but these are what I consider to be useful and are presented here so that we may have a common point of reference and don’t end up with a dwarf misunderstanding.</p>
<p>Fantasy:  This is the important one, isn’t it? Fantasy is any story that involves magic. There can be technology involved, but it still has to involve magic. This definition doesn’t include time travel stories where the guy from the future goes into the past with technology and wows the poor backwards people into thinking that his objects are magic.(IE.  Clarke’s third law.)  Unless said time travel was <i>caused</i> by magic. Considering the existence of Urban Fantasy, this is entirely possible. It could even be possible that the “technology” used to wow the poor people of the past is <i>magical</i>, but if it’s not, then it’s not fitting into my definition of fantasy.</p>
<p>Magic: Which then leads one to ask, “what then is magic, if significantly advanced technology doesn’t count even though the technobabble certainly sounds like magic?” For me, magic has always been something inherent in the world since primitive times. Not everyone may have it. Not everyone may know about it. But it is this force, energy, something that has been around that can be wielded by individuals, be it through technology or their blood. Technology is things that have yet to be, magic is things that have always been.</p>
<p>Primary World: The primary world is Earth. Our world. Sometimes it’s the setting with magic, sometimes it’s the starting place before the adventure begins. Most Urban Fantasies are primary world stories.</p>
<p>Secondary World: This is a world that is <i>not</i> Earth. A great deal of fantasy stories take place in secondary worlds. Some stories, like the Chronicles of Narnia, may start out in the primary world and end up in the secondary world. Other stories, like the Wheel of Time always exist in the secondary world.</p>
<p>Admittedly, some worlds are a bit tricky to place, like the Lord of the Rings which, according to the author’s conceit, is Earth, but ages ago.  But these definitions don’t have to be hard and true. They’re here to create a common language.</p>
<p>Other definitions may be added as time goes on, but for now these are good enough to start a discussion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
