<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Redefining Superheroes &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/redefining-superheroes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 03:33:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Fearless Thoughts: Part 2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fearless-thoughts-part-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AnnaOKeefe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 10:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Redefining Superheroes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Editor&#8217;s note: this two-part debut series for Anna O&#8217;Keefe&#8217;s column &#8220;Redefining Superheroes&#8221; began yesterday with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/phil-hearing-747731-unsplash.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11456 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/phil-hearing-747731-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>[<em>Editor&#8217;s note: this two-part debut series for Anna O&#8217;Keefe&#8217;s column &#8220;Redefining Superheroes&#8221; began yesterday with Part 1.</em>]</p>
<p>My great-great-grandmother, Anna O&#8217;Keefe, came to the US, an Irish immigrant, with nearly nothing. We have no record of her life except for a few personal items and a couple of lines in census records. I hold tight to the tangible proof that there was a real person as it&#8217;s easy enough to shroud her in a mist bigger than life. But I cling to her finding a way to make a good but hard life for herself, her husband Frank, and their children; to me, this is the meaning of a true superhero.</p>
<p>She became the only solid thing in my life after my mom died when I was 12. Over the years I have constructed a life for her. I see her as brave and strong and able to move through sadness, heartbreak, and deep longing for her homeland and family. My grandmother told me once she never heard her grandmother ever speak of Ireland. It simply was not her life any longer. I like to think in her new life there was also love, happiness, and joy.</p>
<p>My mom’s death ripped our family apart. The pain it brought to all of us blew us into a thousand little pieces. Today there would be support staff and counselors to help a child get through such a loss. But not back then. In a matter of months I was alone with my dad. A lifelong alcoholic who allowed his grief to take him into the same grave we laid mom in, it just took him another six years to die.</p>
<p>During those long, dark, scary years I had one place I could go to find soothing and peace. I would take Anna’s bible or cross and sit with it. And even at that age I would tell myself that I could make it through another day. If Anna could do it all those years ago, I could too. And somehow that would get me through the next day, and the next, never thinking of an end to that hard part of my life. When dad died I found myself on my own. But I still had Anna with me. I would cry to her when someone hurt my feelings. I would whisper to her when I began to feel like a woman and had no one else to talk to. I would imagine us having these wonderful conversations. She had been a mother, grandmother, and great-grandmother during her lifetime. She would certainly know how to soothe a scared, worried child and later an equally scared and worried young women.</p>
<p>Years have passed. I no longer find I need to cling to her bible or cross for solace, but she is always with me. And I would like <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/cristian-newman-63291-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11457 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/cristian-newman-63291-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a>to think she would be proud of who I am and what I have made of my life and how I continue to grow and find the enjoyment and enchantment that life can hold. I can still hear her whisper in my ear when I am scared or facing a new challenge and how I tell her story in the stories I write: “You can do this. You are my daughter. And my blood is yours. So there is nothing we have not already overcome together. Now go show the world who you are.”</p>
<p>And afterwards, when things are settled or I have more control of them, I know the wind brings me her voice: “I always knew you could do this. I am proud of you. I love you.”</p>
<p>She is my superhero. No comic book character or Hollywood invention could ever be more powerful.</p>
<p>That is why when I first contemplated writing this blog I knew I would use her name to sign off each posting. She and I hope to explore many wonderful topics in this blog.</p>
<p>I would love to hear who your superhero is and what she has meant to your life. If you have not thought about a superhero lately, I hope you take a few moments to thank them for what they have given to you. If you are lucky enough to still do it in person then add a deep long hug.</p>
<p>Listen to the stars; the words they speak might just change your life</p>
<p>With love,</p>
<p>Anna O’Keefe</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fearless Thoughts: Part 1</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fearless-thoughts-part-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AnnaOKeefe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 10:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Redefining Superheroes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Editor&#8217;s note: this is the first in a two-part debut of Anna O&#8217;Keefe&#8217;s column &#8220;Redefining&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/lena-rose-491551-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11452 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/lena-rose-491551-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>[<em>Editor&#8217;s note: this is the first in a two-part debut of Anna O&#8217;Keefe&#8217;s column &#8220;Redefining Superheroes.&#8221; Come back tomorrow for Part 2.</em>]</p>
<p>Superheros and anti-heroes have exploded off the pages of comics and graphic novels in spectacular fashion in the past several years. <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/markhughes/2017/11/27/how-2017-became-the-greatest-year-for-superhero-movies-of-all-time/#301106f513e6"><em>Forbes</em></a> pronounced that, “2017 became the greatest year for superhero movies of all time. . . Even <em>The LEGO Batman</em> <em>Movie</em> showed a whopping $311 million in box office sales worldwide.&#8221; No doubt about it: superheroes are in and clearly will be for a while since they rake in major bucks for the studios and publishing companies, not to mention the millions made off licensed merchandise.</p>
<p>This explosion of comic driven movies often has women showing up in the role of kick ass and yet sexy characters in cast ensembles. Some of these roles can be classified along the traditional superhero roles but many more are <a href="https://www.ranker.com/list/best-anti-heroes-in-comics/ranker-comics">anti-heroes</a> like Margot Robbie&#8217;s power-driven, crazed Harley Quinn in the 2016 <em>Suicide Squad</em>. Robbie brought a new level of scary crazy to Harley, a fan favorite and totally fun character to watch. I would imagine the role was a lot of fun to play. Sadly in the world of superhero leads, women have rare title roles. Graphic novels have done better in gender roles with many female-centric stories coming from the pages of smaller avant-garde publications.</p>
<p>All of this started me to wonder:</p>
<p><em>Where are the superheroes in my life? In the lives of my female friends? Whom do we think is stronger and more capable than any pretend character? Where do we go to find female role models that are badass, powerful, and blazing a trail for us to follow?</em></p>
<p>In my own life I do not need to search too deeply to find my own superhero. In fact, in the whole fictional superhero persona, something very different comes to mind. I think in terms of my own life and the superheroes that have been instrumental in shaping who we are; those powerful and often unsung superheroes that molded our thoughts, gave our spirits freedom to fly, and allowed us to build our own opinions of this big world we live in.</p>
<p>These quiet superheroes are women who did not get chosen for the job, never set out to impact another woman&#8217;s life in such a manner. They went about being who they were: women of substance making the best of what life offered, often with little <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/anita-jankovic-606752-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11453 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/anita-jankovic-606752-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>means but never letting their situation in life define or constrict them. Some of us have been lucky enough to have more than one in our life. Often one is enough to inspire us. One has been enough for me.</p>
<p>My own superhero has influenced my entire life. Though we share a bloodline, I have never met her. My great-great-grandmother, Anna O’Keefe, came to the US as a teenage girl, leaving Ireland, her family, and her home to travel to a country she knew little about to get married to a man she had never met. It was not an uncommon story in the mid 1800s. Many families had to make the same choice Anna’s family did. The great <a href="https://www.discoveringireland.com/the-great-famine/">Potato Famine</a> brought brutal living conditions and caused many families to send children off into the world in hopes they would have a better life.</p>
<p>I cannot image having to make such a heartbreaking decision in life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
