<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Wordy One &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-wordy-one/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 03:58:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Dark Seduction: Why Vampires Haunt Us Still</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dark-seduction-why-vampires-haunt-us-still/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rose Strickman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Wordy One]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As summer dies away and the leaves turn, blowing away on chilly winds into a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28691 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/dlevzwzktom-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/dlevzwzktom-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/dlevzwzktom-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/dlevzwzktom-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/dlevzwzktom.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />As summer dies away and the leaves turn, blowing away on chilly winds into a darkening sky, we know one thing: we are entering spooky season, that magical time of year when Halloween is approaching and it is not only permissible but required that we indulge our passion for all things dark, Gothic and creepy. This is a time for reading horror stories, eating too much candy and pondering those questions essential to the human mind and spirit. One question in particular:</p>
<p>What <em>is </em>it about vampires?</p>
<p>Really, what <em>is </em>it? Why, out of all monsters in folklore, does the vampire exercise such a pull over our imaginations? The vampire, as a fictional monster, has survived centuries of social and economic change, remaining as relevant today as it was hundreds of years ago. Vampires appear in novels, short stories, movies, TV shows, and in representational art of all kinds. People dress up as vampires, have vampire fetishes, collect vampire memorabilia. The vampire is one well-loved monster.</p>
<p>But what makes vampires so compelling? Why have so many authors, from Bram Stoker to Stephenie Meyer, written so many books about them? Why so many movies, so much artwork? Why, exactly, do we like those bloodsuckers so much?</p>
<p>Of course, the heyday of the vampire craze is behind us, and thank Dracula for that. For a while there it seemed there weren’t any books <em>but </em>vampire novels. I love a good vampire novel, but even I thought it was too much. Thankfully, vampires have now retreated back into the shadows where they belong. But still, they remain popular, and I have to wonder why that is. The concept of the vampire is, objectively, an extremely disgusting one. A walking corpse that drinks human blood, yuck. So why are they figures of such romance and fascination?</p>
<p>One reason for their popularity is, I think, their versatility. An artist, director ,or writer can do a lot with vampires, from teenage biker gangs to melancholy romantics to bestial ravaging monsters. They operate equally well in Gothic country houses and modern inner cities; you can use them in historical mysteries or young adult melodramas to equally good effect. Vampires are adaptable, and make great characters in everything from manga to movies. Vampires are at home in any human setting: they are, after all, very human monsters.</p>
<p>This brings me to another important point: vampires, unlike most other monsters from folklore, are very human. In most traditions, they are literally former humans who have made the choice to become undead. Vampires, unlike most other monsters, are self-aware: the vampire is often portrayed as an individual struggling with doubt and guilt, who knows they have made a selfish choice. Some who know they have done evil, and know they will do it again. This is something we can all relate to, and so vampires provide a means of examining and interrogating the dark side of our nature as human beings. What is the nature of human evil? Why are we selfish and cruel, when we know it will not solve our problems or bring us true happiness? Why do we delight in hurting others, when doing so just hurts ourselves? Can this selfishness and cruelty be overcome? And, most of all: why do humans do evil when they know it is evil, and doing it will only destroy them? Vampires reflect this fear of ourselves, and our fear of each other: it is a rare human being, after all, who has never felt frightened of other humans. In this day and age, when human activity threatens potentially all life on the planet, this is a particularly poignant question.</p>
<p>Vampires, of course, are also closely intertwined with sex, and humans as a species are completely obsessed with sex. Here I believe vampires reflect another fear: the human fear and fascination with sex. Sex has never been without risks, especially for women, homosexuals, genderqueer and other non-cis-gender people. From rape to STDs to social disgrace to religious strictures to death in childbirth, human sex has always had its menacing side. Vampires, especially vampire erotica, address this issue. I also believe that vampires are especially popular among women because they address heterosexual women’s ambivalence and anxiety toward their own sexuality: being attracted to someone who has the physical power, and sometimes even social and legal power, to kill you. Social custom encourages women to be attracted to men—but at the same time, this attraction can ruin or even end a woman’s life. (Oddly, whenever I mention this theory to men, even educated and supposedly enlightened men, they never take it seriously. They always laugh and make it out to be some kind of joke. I’m not sure what they find so ridiculous: that women’s fears might influence literature or that women might be afraid of men. They should try being women walking home alone at night sometime. When I share my theory with women, they always seem to understand immediately.)</p>
<p>Vampires are also closely associated with other ancient human obsessions: social status and<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28690 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/vv13d2ozcy4-300x216.jpg" alt="brown bat flying" width="300" height="216" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/vv13d2ozcy4-300x216.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/vv13d2ozcy4-1024x737.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/vv13d2ozcy4-768x553.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/vv13d2ozcy4-1536x1106.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/vv13d2ozcy4.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> political power. Vampires are traditionally portrayed as powerful, high-ranked individuals, whether they are European aristocrats or billionaire businesspeople. Vampires ask this question: why do we go to such lengths to gain and keep social power, whether form that takes? Is having power really worth the pain it causes? And why do people with power so often seem immune to the rules of society, just as vampires exist outside human norms of decency and good behavior? Vampires examine the corrupting and addictive nature of power: we all want it, even though it’s bad for us, and vampires provide a means of interrogating this conundrum from a safe distance.</p>
<p>The vampire’s immortality addresses yet another eternal human longing: the desire never to die. Most of us long to live forever, and the idea of remaining young and beautiful while doing so is just so tempting. What <em>wouldn’t </em>people do for such a prize? But is such a prize worth it, in the end? Would earthly immortality ensure our eternal preservation or would it just destroy something essential in ourselves, whether it’s our eternal soul or our connection to other people? In literature, vampires generally tell us that it’s not worth it—but still they choose immortality and continued existence, even at the price of devouring humans, and it’s not only possible but likely that most of us, the readers, would do the same.</p>
<p>In the end, vampires fascinate us because they are <em>us</em>: all our greed, lust, veniality, ambition, and violence, along with our self-awareness and continual striving to rise above our baser natures. Vampires may not have reflections, but they do reflect their creators—that is, human beings—with sometimes disturbing accuracy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back Off, Trolls</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/back-off-trolls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rose Strickman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Wordy One]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28074</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In September of this year, Amazon plans to release a TV show based off the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28162 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thandy-yung-zeW9BQbWmJs-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thandy-yung-zeW9BQbWmJs-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thandy-yung-zeW9BQbWmJs-unsplash-1024x680.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thandy-yung-zeW9BQbWmJs-unsplash-768x510.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thandy-yung-zeW9BQbWmJs-unsplash-1536x1020.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/thandy-yung-zeW9BQbWmJs-unsplash-2048x1360.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />In September of this year, Amazon plans to release a TV show based off the <em>Lord of the Rings </em>books: <em>The Rings of Power. </em>Personally, I can’t wait. I love all Tolkien spinoffs, and from what I’ve seen <em>The Rings of Power</em> looks like an excellent example: lavish, sumptuous, with exciting plotlines, heroic quests through epic landscapes, and an elven princess coming of age alongside a hot elven prince. What’s not to like?</p>
<p>But my opinion isn’t the only one. Indeed, if you look on certain sites, you might think I was very much in the minority.</p>
<p>The teaser trailer on YouTube is still beset with angry comments about how this series destroys Tolkien’s legacy and the sanctity of the Peter Jackson movies. There are dozens of videos about how awful this series is even before it airs, filled with profanities and blistering invective. It’s the <em>Star Wars </em>sequels debacle all over again, only this time the toxic fans aren’t even waiting to see the damn movie.</p>
<p>And do these fans object to Amazon’s questionable labor practices? Do they think such an expensive project is a waste of time and money in our age of pandemic and climate change? No! What people object to, apparently, is that <em>The Rings of Power </em>features elves with short hair and dark skin, along with dwarves and proto-Hobbits who aren’t white, and Galadriel as an uncertain teenager as opposed to a sexy, omniscient elf queen.</p>
<p>Oh, the horror! A show set in Middle Earth that not only features characters of color, but gives them agency as well! Elves changing their hairstyles! Galadriel wasn’t always a sex symbol! The show is introducing original characters! Sauron’s Eye is on the move!</p>
<p>I can understand if people think Amazon’s new show looks like a flop and a disappointment. It’s perfectly possible that’s exactly what it will be. I’m also worried it will be guilty of tokenism: one Black dwarf, one Black elf, etc. But what fans say they object to is that <em>The Rings of Power </em>rejects Tolkien’s “legacy”. What exactly is Tolkien’s “legacy”, then? White supremacy? Women as sex symbols? Nothing ever changing, ever? No new art? No new interpretations? Because that’s basically what they’re saying they want: nothing new in Middle Earth, ever.</p>
<p>What confuses me is that all these fans keep referring back to the Peter Jackson movies as the epitome of Tolkien’s universe, rather than Tolkien’s works themselves. They say they hate change, but the Peter Jackson movies made a <em>lot </em>of changes to Middle Earth. Many characters, such a Tom Bombadil and the Barrow Wights, are removed altogether; Frodo is much younger in the movies than he is in the books; and Arwen plays a larger, more active role. The movies also remove a lot of the songs that are found in the book (and thank God for that). Saruman meets a different fate, and so does Samwise Gamgee. Peter Jackson made a lot of changes, in a brilliant and necessary way that resulted in a wonderful work of art. So why shouldn’t Amazon do the<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28163 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ergo-zakki-QjLE11j5FT8-unsplash-300x180.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="180" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ergo-zakki-QjLE11j5FT8-unsplash-300x180.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ergo-zakki-QjLE11j5FT8-unsplash-1024x616.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ergo-zakki-QjLE11j5FT8-unsplash-768x462.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ergo-zakki-QjLE11j5FT8-unsplash-1536x924.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/ergo-zakki-QjLE11j5FT8-unsplash-2048x1232.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> same?</p>
<p>Toxic fandom itself is completely contrary to Tolkien’s legacy. John Ronald Reuel Tolkien was a man who valued courtesy so highly that he refused to comment on Frank Herbert’s <em>Dune </em>in a private letter to a friend because he disliked the book intensely and to give an honest review would be to disrespect a fellow author. He’d be completely horrified by the furious debate swirling around the franchise. (Of course, Tolkien would be completely horrified that there’s a franchise at all. Yes, Amazon is commercializing Middle Earth—but, frankly, that ship sailed a long time ago.)</p>
<p>Perhaps my spleen is being colored by my intense dislike of toxic fandom. I freely admit that rude YouTube videos of people spraying swearwords at a show that hasn’t even aired yet drive me up the wall. Actually, I hate all forms of toxic fandom. I hate that it’s destroyed all chance of honest, thoughtful discussion of popular culture and art online. I hate that it gives nerds a bad name. I hate that it scares authors and artists into silence, that I have to be grateful I’m writing under a pen name in this blog post. Half the blame for the wreckage of <em>The Rise of Skywalker </em>goes to toxic fandom—the other half, of course, going to Disney for being so spineless as to listen to the trolls.</p>
<p>Fortunately, however, Amazon does not seem to be repeating that mistake. I’ve heard they’ve already planned out the entire show, down to the last shot, and are forging ahead. And there are other reviewers out there, who have seen what the new show has to offer, and have given it positive reviews, or at least fair-minded ones. There’s more to fandom than racist trolls.</p>
<p>So let’s give Amazon a chance. Or, at least, let’s all watch the first episode before we start tearing it apart.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let&#8217;s Get This Murder Party Started!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lets-get-this-murder-party-started/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rose Strickman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Wordy One]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27235</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Marie Claire review of Oyinkan Braithwaite’s 2017 novel My Sister, the Serial Killer calls&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27340 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/david-von-diemar-jM6Y2nhsAtk-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/david-von-diemar-jM6Y2nhsAtk-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/david-von-diemar-jM6Y2nhsAtk-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/david-von-diemar-jM6Y2nhsAtk-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/david-von-diemar-jM6Y2nhsAtk-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/david-von-diemar-jM6Y2nhsAtk-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/david-von-diemar-jM6Y2nhsAtk-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />The <em>Marie Claire </em>review of <a href="https://oyinkanbraithwaite.com/">Oyinkan Braithwaite</a>’s 2017 novel <a href="https://oyinkanbraithwaite.com/product-category/my-sister-the-serial-killer/"><em>My Sister, the Serial Killer</em></a> calls it, “The wittiest and most fun murder party you’ve ever been invited to.” <em>Murder party</em> does not yet officially exist as a literary genre. But it really should.</p>
<p>What are murder party novels? Let’s start with what they are not: they are not murder mysteries. In a murder mystery, the focal question is who did it. In a murder party, the question is how to get away with it. Yes, in a murder party novel, we as the readers are asked to sympathize with the murderer.</p>
<p>And it’s surprisingly easy. In the murder party novels I know best, <em>My Sister, the Serial Killer,</em> Helene Tursten’s 2018<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40104741-an-elderly-lady-is-up-to-no-good?ac=1&amp;from_search=true&amp;qid=8yuskwWJyD&amp;rank=1"><em> An Elderly Lady Is Up To No Good</em></a>,and <a href="https://www.jesseqsutanto.com/">Jesse Q. Sutanto</a>’s 2021 <a href="https://www.jesseqsutanto.com/books/dial-a-for-aunties"><em>Dial A for Aunties</em></a>, the murderers are all rather lovable people. Ayoola, the knife-wielding serial killer in <em>My Sister</em>, might be a sociopath, but she’s a friendly one, with a bubbly personality, who designs gowns for her mother and sister, laughs at social media posts on her phone, remembers to bring them gifts from trips abroad (even if she happens to kill her latest boyfriend during that trip) and “is incapable of practical underwear.” (Braithwaite, 2017, p. 19). Maud, the inventive and resourceful killer in <em>An Elderly Lady</em>, is a very refined and ladylike old woman enjoying her peaceful retirement—when she’s not being driven mad by pesky neighbors who really need a good murder or two. And Meddelin Chan, the protagonist and accidental killer of <em>Dial A for Aunties, </em>is one of the most likable and relatable characters I’ve ever encountered, kind and gentle and rather crushed by her loving but overbearing family.</p>
<p>This dissonance—that we <em>like </em>murderers—is part of the humor that characterizes murder party novels. These are comedies, not tragedies, but comedies in a very lopsided and macabre way. In a murder party novel, there is humor in even the grimmest situation. Consider this passage from <em>Dial A for Aunties</em>, when Meddelin happens to glance out of a hotel window and spots her mother and aunts toting a cooler containing the corpse of the man she killed<em>:</em></p>
<blockquote><p>“…[M]ovement outside the window catches my eye.</p>
<p>Ho. Ly. Shit.</p>
<p>It’s Big Aunt, Ma, and Fourth Aunt, and they’re moving the cooler, staggering across the expansive lawn with it and—oh god—the cooler must’ve popped open at some point without them realizing it, because there is a fucking <em>hand </em>sticking out of it.</p>
<p>‘OH MY GOD!’ I scream.</p>
<p>Tom startles awake. ‘Wh-wha?’ he rasps, blinking around him and wincing. ‘My head.’” (Sutanto, 2021, p. 131).</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Dial A for Aunties </em>is a laugh a minute as Meddelin struggles to keep her bickering, batty aunts focused, reconnect with her old boyfriend, and avoid arrest as the corpse of the man she and her aunts accidentally killed circulates through a billionaire Chinese-Indo wedding at an exclusive California resort. Meddelin and her family are not evil or psychotic, even if they did accidentally suffocate a man to death: they are intensely relatable and sympathetic characters, complete with sisterly rivalries, personal fixations on tai chi or traditional Chinese medicine, and intense desires to own Gucci handbags, even as they’re carting a dead body around a hotel in a cooler.</p>
<p>This humorous dissonance extends to <em>An Elderly Lady Is Up To No Good</em>, where the reader sympathizes greatly with Maud’s annoyance with her neighbors. Who hasn’t felt furious with those irritating, noisy, and thoughtless people next door? It’s when Maud takes murderous action—and then feels no guilt whatsoever—that we catch ourselves laughing at death, and sympathizing with a murderer. Our humor at the situation might be wrong, but it is irresistible.</p>
<p><em>My Sister, The Serial Killer </em>explores this in even greater depth. The protagonist, Korede, is the sister of the serial killer, Ayoola. She is also Ayoola’s regular accomplice, repeatedly covering up the murders of Ayoola’s boyfriends. Even as she does so, Korede keeps asking herself whether this is the right thing to do (“I was tempted to pray, to beg that no door be opened as we journeyed from door to lift [carrying the corpse], but I am fairly certain that those are exactly the types of prayers He <em>doesn’t </em>answer.” (Braithwaite, 2017, p. 11). Korede also has to face up to the fact that the person she loves most in the world, her little sister, is a murderous sociopath. Love does not blind Korede to Ayoola’s faults, but even she is sometimes surprised by Ayoola’s blithe indifference to human life:</p>
<blockquote><p>“She [Ayoola] doesn’t sense my presence—she has her back to me and is thrusting her hips from side to side, her bare feet stroking the white fur rug as she steps this way and that. Her movements are in no way rhythmical; they are the movements of someone who has no audience and no self-consciousness to shackle them. Days ago, we gave a man to the sea, but here she is, dancing.</p>
<p>I lean on the door frame and watch her, trying and failing to understand how her mind works.” (Braithwaite, 2017, p. 34).</p></blockquote>
<p>Ayoola continues in her thoughtless but friendly sociopathy throughout the book, buying gifts for her family, designing gowns for her mother and sister, inviting Korede out to lunch, delighting in fashion and male attention, uploading pictures of food to Instagram and generally enjoying life. She is clearly a lot of fun to be around—when she isn’t knifing her lovers. The two sides of Ayoola—her cheerful friendliness versus her murderous insanity—contrast and highlight each other, and both vividly stand out as a result. In murder party novels, the perpetrator is always, emphatically, a human being.</p>
<p>Another theme in murder party novels is their focus on marginalized members of society. Maud is<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-27341 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/florian-olivo-gD3IR2uBjgY-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/florian-olivo-gD3IR2uBjgY-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/florian-olivo-gD3IR2uBjgY-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/florian-olivo-gD3IR2uBjgY-unsplash-768x1151.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/florian-olivo-gD3IR2uBjgY-unsplash-1025x1536.jpg 1025w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/florian-olivo-gD3IR2uBjgY-unsplash-1366x2048.jpg 1366w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/florian-olivo-gD3IR2uBjgY-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1708w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /> a retiree, condescended to and disregarded by younger, stronger people; Meddelin and her aunts are Asian immigrants in America; and Ayoola and Korede are unmarried women in the male-dominated society of modern Nigeria. These are people—significantly, all women—who are already fighting for a foothold in society, to have their voices heard, their ambitions respected. Murder party novels ask an important question: if society does not respect this individual, why should this individual respect society? What does this person owe a society that ignores, belittles or outright abuses them? Why shouldn’t they try to get away with murder if they can? Indeed, the protagonists of murder party novels often turn their marginalization to their own advantage: Maud uses her persona as a harmless, doddery old lady to hide her crimes; Meddelin plays on the white sheriff’s inability to tell Asians apart to impersonate a lawyer and spring her true love from custody; and Korede adopts her patriarchal society’s stereotype of a stupid, uneducated woman to avoid police questioning. These women are not just murderers; they are tricksters, and tricksters are not only appealing, but bring a much-needed subversive commentary on society’s injustices.</p>
<p>Murder party books also advocate a subversive morality. In <em>An Elderly Lady</em>, the needs of the individual are more important than the needs of society; in <em>My Sister </em>and <em>Dial A,</em> the wellbeing of the family is more important than the wellbeing of anyone outside it. These are not clear-cut certainties for our characters, however—except in <em>An Elderly Lady, </em>whose protagonist is a complete sociopath without any conscience. In <em>My Sister </em>and <em>Dial A for Aunties</em>, the protagonists both wrestle with the question of what is right, especially Korede. Should they admit murder, or report it, if doing so will harm themselves and those they love?</p>
<p>In murder party novels, the answer to that question is <em>no.</em> No, the protagonist should not own up to what she did, or she should not turn in her family member. At the murder party, duty to the family or the self is more important than duty to society, and love is more important than justice. Or, to put it into Korede’s words:</p>
<blockquote><p>“There will never be another opportunity to confess my sins or absolve myself of the crimes of the past…or the future…[B]ecause Ayoola needs me; she needs me more than I need untainted hands.” (Braithwaite, 2017, pp. 222-223.)</p></blockquote>
<p>And let’s face it: this is the attitude that most of us would take in real life. If our sister or niece or grandmother called us in the middle of the night asking for help moving a body, chances are good we would not turn her in. We’re more likely to help her move that corpse and then keep our mouths shut about it. Right or wrong, that’s what most of us would do. As Big Aunt says in <em>Dial A</em>: “‘Is what family do.’” (Sutanto, 2021, p. 114.) In the end, love triumphs over justice.</p>
<p>Let’s just hope we aren’t put to the test.</p>
<p>No one wants to get invited to a <em>real </em>murder party.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Braithwaite, O. (2017). <em>My sister, the serial killer. </em>Anchor Books: New York, NY.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sutanto, J. Q. (2021). <em>Dial a for aunties. </em>PT Karya Hippo Makmur: Berkley, NY.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Tursten, H. (2018). <em>An elderly lady is up to no good. </em>Soho Crime: New York, NY.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seeing Thestrals</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/seeing-thestrals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rose Strickman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 11:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Wordy One]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year, in 2021, I tried reading Robert Jackson Bennett’s 2016 City of Blades. It&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last year, in 2021, I tried reading Robert Jackson Bennett’s 2016 <em><a href="https://www.robertjacksonbennett.com/books/city-of-blades-tr">City of Blades</a>.</em> It was the usual <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26702 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/jessica-delp-U_EjAm-APh4-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/jessica-delp-U_EjAm-APh4-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/jessica-delp-U_EjAm-APh4-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/jessica-delp-U_EjAm-APh4-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/jessica-delp-U_EjAm-APh4-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/jessica-delp-U_EjAm-APh4-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/jessica-delp-U_EjAm-APh4-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />grim, dystopian affair, but I enjoyed it right to the point where the antagonist starts explaining her motivations:</p>
<p>“‘Can you imagine being trapped with all the corpses of your family for days and days, the stink of their bodies, the leak of their blood?&#8230;Imagine going to bed every night not knowing if you might reach out in the night and feel a cold, wet face beside you, and feeling its moustache and eyebrows and knowing it was once your <em>father</em>! Just flesh and bone, and nothing more.</p>
<p>“‘…Then imagine realizing that once there was <em>more</em>. Discovering that there was once an afterlife, a heaven! Once my family could have been safe! Once the dead could have been preserved, loved, respected!&#8230;[I]n one stroke all the afterlives that had been lovingly built for us had come crashing down, collapsing, trapping all those souls in the dark…</p>
<p>“‘This world should never have been…It is accidental. The first thing we should have done after the Blink was line up and calmly walk into the ocean, entering the oblivion from which we no longer had refuge. What is the point of living if there is nothing beyond life?’” (Bennett, 2016, pp. 403-404, 407).</p>
<p>When I read this, I began to shake. I did not sleep that night. I was completely horrified, not because the antagonist was trying to destroy an entire world due to her own tragedy, but because I understood her motivations and emotions only too well.</p>
<p>In October 2020, my father passed away after a long, painful battle with cancer. I was there when he died. I was holding one of his hands, my mother holding the other. Together we watched his pulse race, then stop. We heard his final breath, and then I felt his hand grow cold in mine.</p>
<p>In another universe, I would be able to see thestrals now.</p>
<p>So I can tell you that the antagonist’s agony is entirely realistic. It is completely accurate. This is exactly what goes through your head when someone you love literally dies in your arms.</p>
<p>The protagonist has no sympathy whatsoever, telling the antagonist that her tragedy and sorrow have no importance or meaning: “‘Your tragedy is but a candle flame among a forest fire!’” (Bennett, 2016, p. 404). And she does have a point: the antagonist’s personal tragedy does not justify her trying to kill everyone in the world. But these words hit me like a hammer blow:</p>
<p>“‘Do you even hear how foolish you sound?&#8230;I’ve lived my life in the shadow of oblivion…I’ve seen good people go to it and bad. And I’ve always known I’d go there eventually, one way or another.’” (Bennett, 2016, p. 407).</p>
<p>I felt like the protagonist—and the author—had just slapped me across the face.</p>
<p>I have pondered the same questions that plague the antagonist, and with the same agony and uncertainty: what if there is no afterlife? What if my father is simply nonexistent now? And does life have any meaning if there is nothing beyond it? If we are but a collection of calcium and tissue and electrons, what point is there to anything?</p>
<p>Foolish or not, these are the questions that plague you after a death, a death you have personally witnessed. And no amount of sneering rationalists snarling at you to shut up and make the world a better place does anything to help.</p>
<p>Words matter. Stories can heal an injured soul. Or they can hurt it beyond belief.</p>
<p>Seeing a loved one die changes something inside you. It’s a line that, once crossed, can never be stepped back over again. I am not sure whether Bennett understood this when he wrote the book. His accurate depiction of the antagonist’s anguished horror argues that he does, but his response—basically, to shut up and be a good little soldier—is a statement that personal tragedy and sorrow do not matter, that to even consider spiritual questions about death is an act of selfishness and folly. That to even hope for meaning is stupid, and potentially evil. He would not say this if he’d ever been through the same experience himself.</p>
<p>The Harry Potter books take a wiser and more compassionate view of the matter. In that universe, witches and wizards who see someone die gain the ability to see thestrals, magical spectral horses that blur the boundaries between earth and sky, life and death. In the Harry Potter books, personal tragedy always matters, and to contemplate spiritual questions is never foolish. Whatever lies beyond, the experience of death—even if we are not the ones who die—changes us profoundly. The thestrals of Hogwarts have had far more meaning for me since Dad’s death, just as Bennett’s scathing dismissal has been far more painful.</p>
<p>The morning after I read <em>City of Blades,</em> after my sleepless night, I got up, got breakfast together, and began to cry. For the first time ever, I was able to weep for my father’s death. So perhaps Bennett’s metaphorical slap in the face did me some good, even though I don’t agree with his sentiments.</p>
<p>Stories matter. They inflict both injury and healing. And I hear the screams of despair and see the black-winged thestrals far more clearly now than ever before.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Bennett, R. J. (2016). <em>City of blades. </em>Broadway Books: New York, New York.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two Villains, Both Alike in Dignity: Kaz and Kirigan in Netflix&#8217;s Shadow and Bone</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/two-villains-both-alike-in-dignity-kaz-and-kirigan-in-netflixs-shadow-and-bone/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rose Strickman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 11:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Wordy One]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; Kaz: And I saw his [Kirigan’s] face as he boarded. I know that look.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26082 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MV5BNTNhY2JlMmItMGMzZi00ZTM2LTlmNTItZDBkMGVhNGJhYWRhXkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyMTEyMjM2NDc2._V1_-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MV5BNTNhY2JlMmItMGMzZi00ZTM2LTlmNTItZDBkMGVhNGJhYWRhXkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyMTEyMjM2NDc2._V1_-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MV5BNTNhY2JlMmItMGMzZi00ZTM2LTlmNTItZDBkMGVhNGJhYWRhXkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyMTEyMjM2NDc2._V1_-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MV5BNTNhY2JlMmItMGMzZi00ZTM2LTlmNTItZDBkMGVhNGJhYWRhXkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyMTEyMjM2NDc2._V1_-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/MV5BNTNhY2JlMmItMGMzZi00ZTM2LTlmNTItZDBkMGVhNGJhYWRhXkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyMTEyMjM2NDc2._V1_.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Kaz</em>: And I saw his [Kirigan’s] face as he boarded. I know that look. He’s a man consumed with vengeance.</p>
<p><em>Jesper</em>: See it enough in the mirror, do you?</p>
<p>&#8212;<em>Shadow and Bone. </em>(2021, April 23). No mourners. (Season 1, Episode 8).</p>
<p>When watching Episode 6, “The Heart is an Arrow”, of Netflix’s <em>Shadow and Bone </em>TV show, I had a very strange moment. When the Darkling, Kirigan, comes face-to-face with Kaz Brekker, professional thief, in a dark alley, I had to consciously remind myself that no, Kaz is not Kirigan’s long-lost son; no, he is not shadow-summoning Grisha; no, he and Kirigan have no familial or magical relationship whatsoever. And yet I was still surprised when Kaz didn’t summon shadows to combat Kirigan’s magic, but instead used a flash bomb.</p>
<p>Why would I think that Kaz and Kirigan have a close blood relationship? I’ve read the <em>Shadow and Bone </em>trilogy, along with the <em>Six of Crows </em>duology, and I never once thought that Kaz and Kirigan might be secretly related. In fact, I saw few parallels between them in the books except that they were both antiheroes—and even then, they still seemed very different to me.</p>
<p>It wasn’t until I watched the TV show that I saw similarities between them. They are both manipulative creeps who use the people around them to further their own ends. They are both creatures of shadow: Kaz’s shadows are purely psychological, as opposed to Kirigan’s literal shadows, but they are still there. They are both hiding their pasts, and have deep secrets. They both have the same rather humorless approach to life, and both can be viciously vengeful. They are both extremely ruthless and ambitious, with cold personalities. They’re even both using pseudonyms in their daily lives. Clearly, they have much in common.</p>
<p>This twinning effect in the show is very interesting, and made me question both characters more deeply. Why is Kaz so much more sympathetic than Kirigan? Objectively, he is just as much of a villain as Kirigan: ruthless, cold and selfish, a criminal and conman. He spends most of the first season of <em>Shadow and Bone </em>plotting to kidnap the heroine, Alina Starkov, and basically sell her into slavery. So why, when watching the show, am I on Kaz’s side and not Kirigan’s?</p>
<p>One reason is simple cinematic storytelling: the show’s writers and actors want the viewers to be on Kaz’s side, so we are. Similarly, we are positioned to be against Kirigan. Although his portrayal is not entirely unsympathetic: I can definitely empathize with his frustration and contempt at having to submit to a buffoon like the King of Ravka, and the show successfully conveys the many complexities in his personality. Kirigan is, objectively, actually a more admirable character than Kaz. Kaz is concerned with getting rich, and looking out for his Crows, no matter who else gets hurt; Kirigan genuinely believes he is doing what is right for the future of Ravka and the safety of all Grisha everywhere. He genuinely believes he is being selfless.</p>
<p>That, perhaps, is one characteristic that differentiates Kirigan from Kaz: Kirigan lies to <em>himself</em> just as much as he does to everyone else. Kirigan has half-convinced himself that he really is a righteous and heroic martyr, making the hard choices so others don’t have to. Kaz, on the other hand, is completely honest with himself  and those he respects; he does not engage in self-deception. He knows himself for who and what he is, and has the self-respect never to try to deceive himself about it.</p>
<p>This brutal honesty also extends to those he cares about. This is another difference between Kaz and Kirigan: Kaz might use and manipulate other people but, unlike Kirigan, he never loses track of the fact that they <em>are</em> people. Consider the speech he gives Inej in Episode 7, “The Unsea”:</p>
<p>“Crows don’t just remember the faces of people who wronged them. They also remember those who were kind. They tell each other who look after and who to watch out for. No Saint ever watched over me. Not like you have.”</p>
<p>&#8212;<em>Shadow and Bone. </em>(2021, April 23). The unsea. (Season 1, Episode 7).</p>
<p>To Kaz Brekker, Inej Ghafa is greater and more powerful than a Saint, because she is a true friend. He truly trusts and respects her. He sees her and Jesper as human beings, even extending real respect to Alina by the end of the first season. Kaz’s feelings for Inej are so deep and true that he is willing to mortgage his most valuable asset, the Crow Club, to prevent her falling into the brutal hands of brothel madam Tante Heleen. He risks his own life to save Inej from an attacking volcra, and is, in the end, willing to forgo a million <em>kruger </em>because Inej objects to abducting Alina. Kaz’s selfishness is tempered by true love and friendship, however unwilling he is to admit it.</p>
<p>Kirigan, on the other hand, sees other people as either foes or tools, even those he claims to care about: drafting Grisha into his Second Army, prostituting Genya to the King, and putting what he intends to be a magical slave collar on Alina so he can control her power. In stark contrast to Kaz’s respect for Inej’s values and beliefs, Kirigan respects only his own desires, but is unwilling to admit this even to himself: “Everything that I have done, everything that I have ever done, has been to make Ravka safer, to make Grisha safer!” (<em>Shadow and Bone. </em>(2021, April 23). The unsea. (Season 1, Episode 7). Kirigan has been in the darkness so long that he no longer remembers how to see through it; unlike Kaz, he is utterly disconnected from those around him and from the truth of his own actions.</p>
<p>And he is unable to see this. He truly believes he is doing the right thing, that enslaving Alina is the best thing for her and for everyone. He is utterly unable to see Alina as an equal, as Kaz sees his Crows, and so he loses all of Alina’s trust. Or, to put it into Alina and Kirigan’s own words:</p>
<p><em>Alina</em>: We could’ve had this. All of it. You could’ve made me your equal. Instead, you made me this [a slave]. You don’t care who suffers, as long as you win.</p>
<p><em>Kirigan</em>: Fine. Make me your villain.</p>
<p>&#8212;<em>Shadow and Bone. </em>(2021, April 23). The unsea. (Season 1, Episode 7).</p>
<p>Kirigan, unable to perceive Alina as an equal or even a human being, is unable to hear the truth in her words. He can only dismiss Alina’s position as her being selfish and unreasonable, while being totally blind to his own selfishness and unreasonable hypocrisy. He has lost all empathy.</p>
<p>Kaz, however, has not. He may be wrapped in darkness, he may be selfish and greedy and ambitious, but he still knows himself, and knows his Crows, and acknowledges the humanity of those around him. He walks a very thin line between light and dark, and there is every possibility that, like Kirigan, he will eventually fall completely into evil. But, unlike Kirigan, Kaz has not yet made that fall. Also unlike Kirigan, Kaz has true friends, people watching out for him as he watches out for them, and he has enough sense to value and respect them. He is thus far less likely to succumb to the spiritual darkness that has overtaken Kirigan. He may summon psychological shadows, but he has not yet let them blind him.</p>
<p>References</p>
<p>Heisserer, E., Levy, S., Bardugo, L., Shahbazian, P., Levine, D., Cohen, D., Barry, J. (Executive Producers). (2021-present). <em>Shadow and bone </em>[TV series]. Netflix; 21 Laps Entertainment.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Littlest Potterhead, or, Reading Harry Potter With My Nephew</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-littlest-potterhead-or-reading-harry-potter-with-my-nephew/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rose Strickman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 12:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Wordy One]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I live in close proximity with two young nephews. The older is six and has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I live in close proximity with two young nephews. The older is six and has discovered Harry Potter.</p>
<p>I mean, he is a real, true Potterhead. The Harry Potter books are almost the only ones he will actually allow me to read to him (though he has developed a taste for Neil Gaiman’s <em>Norse Mythology</em>, loving the story of how Thor got his hammer). He adores the movies. He will listen to the audiobooks for hours. He and his mother, my sister, have made Harry Potter accessories out of modeling clay. He had my sister dress him up as Harry, using her makeup to draw in the lightning scar. He imitates the goblin in the first Harry Potter movie, saying, “Key please!” When he wants everyone to accompany him somewhere, he says, “Come, Gryffindors!” He plays rather rough Harry-inspired games with his younger brother. My sister and I have had to remonstrate with him for using “Mudblood” as a swearword—the Harry Potter universe is that real to him.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-25335 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Harry_Potter_and_the_Prisoner_of_Azkaban-184x300.jpg" alt="" width="184" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Harry_Potter_and_the_Prisoner_of_Azkaban-184x300.jpg 184w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Harry_Potter_and_the_Prisoner_of_Azkaban.jpg 247w" sizes="(max-width: 184px) 100vw, 184px" />Reading Harry Potter with my nephew is a strange and wonderful experience. It is marvelous to watch him sit, spellbound (almost literally) as I read aloud from his favorite book, <em>Prisoner of Azkaban. </em>He loves Harry and his friends, and hates their enemies. His delight and enchantment, his sheer joy in the wonder of Harry Potter and his world, are palpable and precious.</p>
<p>At the same time, my nephew is facing some rather adult questions in these books. He asks, in real confusion, why the wizards are torturing the Muggles at the Quidditch World Cup; he expresses puzzlement and anger over Aunt Petunia’s behavior toward Harry. We had a rather productive heart-to-heart about that, concerning jealousy and its evil effects on people, as well as discussions on societal violence and oppression. We are having important discussions that we would not otherwise be able to conduct.</p>
<p>It is eye-opening to see the effect that good fantasy fiction can have on children. My nephew is facing questions that he must confront as a human being—questions of justice, violence, abuse, emotion—but in an accessible format. In the Harry Potter context, my nephew can not only face these questions but consider them productively, without the pain and incomprehension that real-life situations would bring. Reading Harry Potter has been educational for him, in a way that other formats would not be. Fantasy provides a framework for his thoughts, and a very good one.</p>
<p>Re-reading the books as an adult, I find <em>my </em>eyes are opened too. Certain practices and behaviors that did not bother me as a child or teenager, such as the wizards erasing Muggles’ memories, now strike me as deeply disturbing. What right do the wizards have to control Muggles’ reality to this extent? The elitism of the books is something I cannot ignore: the wizards are consistently superior to the Muggles in every way. While Rowling keeps saying that you can’t judge a person by their background, you repeatedly <em>can</em> throughout her books: all the Malfoys are bad, all the Weasleys are good, etc. Also, leaving a baby on someone’s doorstep is an appalling thing to do, both to the baby and to the owner of the doorstep. Indeed, I find I have a certain sympathy for Aunt Petunia these days: not for her abusive behavior, but for her feelings. What Dumbledore is basically saying is that she’s not good enough to be a witch, but she’s good enough to do the extremely hard and dirty work of raising this kid she never asked for, who Dumbledore will take away forever the minute he turns eleven. Oh, and he’s not giving her any financial assistance whatsoever. Petunia Dursley does not have the right to abuse Harry, but she does have the right to be angry.</p>
<p>But my nephew, of course, does not understand these concerns, and I cannot share them with <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-25336 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/frida-bredesen-c1fFv08N7qE-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/frida-bredesen-c1fFv08N7qE-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/frida-bredesen-c1fFv08N7qE-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/frida-bredesen-c1fFv08N7qE-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/frida-bredesen-c1fFv08N7qE-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/frida-bredesen-c1fFv08N7qE-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />him yet. The questions he is already facing are serious enough—and his joy in the books is not something I intend to tarnish. This pure delight is valuable and beautiful, and will hopefully lead him to other books in the future. It is important for children to discover magic in books early—and Harry Potter has plenty of that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gender Identity in The Mahabharata</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/gender-identity-in-the-mahabharata/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/gender-identity-in-the-mahabharata/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rose Strickman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 11:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Wordy One]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have recently finished reading Devdutt Pattanaik’s 2010 Jaya: An Illustrated Retelling of The Mahabharata,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24525 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9864913-230x300.jpg" alt="" width="230" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9864913-230x300.jpg 230w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/9864913.jpg 318w" sizes="(max-width: 230px) 100vw, 230px" /></p>
<p>I have recently finished reading Devdutt Pattanaik’s 2010 <em>Jaya: An Illustrated Retelling of The Mahabharata</em>, and let me tell you, it is awesome. Pattanaik is a wonderful writer and storyteller, and India’s great epic is breathtaking. In <em>The Mahabharata, </em>we have gods, demons, and mortals, shattering family dynamics, everlasting hatred, and undying love. We have characters with godlike powers and human flaws, betrayal, redemption and, of course, lots and lots of bloodshed as the Pandavas and Kauravas fight for possession of a kingdom and, even more vital, to determine which will prevail: <em>dharma </em>or chaos.</p>
<p>We also have something I did not expect when I first purchased the book: a whole range of gender-fluid characters.</p>
<p>In <em>The Mahabharata</em> are many characters who take a nonstandard approach to gender, from a person who is cursed by the gods to change their gender according to the phases to the moon to a man who voluntarily chooses a completely celibate lifestyle. Even the sacrificial stallion is turned into a mare when it wanders through a magical grove. Gender transformations, and non-standard gender identities, abound through the epic.</p>
<p>We are introduced to our first gender-fluid character almost immediately: Budh, offspring of the star goddess Tara and the moon god Chandra. Budh is the illegitimate product of an affair between Tara and Chandra, so Tara’s husband, Brihaspati, curses the child to be “‘of neuter gender, neither male nor female,’” (Pattanaik, 2010, p. 12). Though this condition is handed down as a curse, Budh also represents perfect balance between two states of being, and they later marry someone who is also gender-balanced, albeit in a different way. Ila, formerly a male prince named Sudyumna, runs afoul of Shiva and his consort Shakti, accidentally trespassing into their private grove and so turning into a woman. Shakti cannot undo the spell, but she modifies it so that Sudyumna/Ila is a man during the waxing of the moon and a woman during its waning. Budh and Ila, two magical beings who mix genders, become the ancestors of the Chandra-vamsis, the royal dynasty that comprises the main characters of the epic. Thus, gender fluidity and non-standard gender norms are introduced to the family, and the epic, right from the start.</p>
<p>The next family member who takes an unusual approach to his gender and sexual lifestyle is Prince Devavrata, later known as Bhishma, the one who takes a terrible vow. He renounces marriage, sex, and children so that his father, Shantanu, can marry Satyavati. In the Vedic society presented in the epic, this makes Bhishma effectively a non-man: someone living outside society’s gender norms, as much as Budh or Ila. While Bhishma’s vow is portrayed as a great and terrible sacrifice, dooming him to dwell forever in the land of the dead, without children to facilitate his rebirth, Bhishma seems eager to embrace the celibate lifestyle, and never once expresses any regret or unhappiness over his choice. Even though it goes against society and <em>dharma</em>, Bhishma is in charge of his sexual destiny, and he voluntarily chooses a sex-free life.</p>
<p>Bhishma is not the only character who voluntarily takes up a different gender and sexual identity than the one assigned him at birth. Later in the epic, Arjuna, one of the five heroic Pandava brothers, disguises himself as a castrated, female-living eunuch named Brihanalla, working as a dance teacher at King Virata’s court. Though this is presented as a necessity, as the Pandavas must live in disguise for one year, Arjuna seems to be enjoying his feminine role quite a bit, fluttering his eyelashes and acting coy and flirty with Virata’s son, Prince Uttara. One suspects that Arjuna is having a lot of fun expressing his more feminine side. Interestingly, the character is named Brihanalla and identified by feminine pronouns even in the author’s narrative, suggesting that Arjuna has, on some level, truly taken on a female identity. The moment her disguise is pierced, Brihanalla becomes the male Arjuna again. Inner gender identity is determined as much by outward appearance and behavior as it is by body type or personal choice.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most famous gender transformation is that of Krishna, the Pandavas’ spiritual guide, and earthly incarnation of the god. When Arjuna’s son Iravan is chosen as a sacrifice to ensure victory in battle, he requests that he be given a wife who will mourn his death. Krishna takes his female form, Mohini, marries Iravan, and mourns him after his death the next day. Even today, Iravan is worshipped in India as the husband of all Alis, men who live as women, apart from mainstream society. Through Krishna and Iravan, transgender and gender-fluid individuals are acknowledged and validated.</p>
<p>Female-bodied characters also feel gender conflicts, and have gender-fluid identities. The Princess Chitrangada, while she identifies as a woman, has distinctly masculine qualities, being a famous warrior with a “manly gait” (Pattanaik, 2010, p. 117). Having fallen in love with Arjuna (in his male identity), she prays to Shiva to make her more feminine, so she can catch his interest. But when Shiva complies, this strategy, rather amusingly, backfires: Arjuna has seen many feminine women, and is only interested in meeting the famed warrior princess, who he can’t find. Citrangada hurriedly prays to be restored to her original form and identity, whereupon Arjuna falls in love with her, and they are married. The reader is left to assume that Chitrangada learns her lesson and is ever after true to herself and her own soul.</p>
<p>The Princess Shikhandi is another female-bodied character with gender conflicts. A prophecy at her birth predicts that she will one day be transformed into a man. She is thus raised as a male, and even marries a woman. Her wife, however, is so horrified at marrying a female-bodied individual that her father, Hiranyavarna, lays siege to Shikhandi’s kingdom. Shikhandi borrows manhood from a forest demon, becoming a man and remaining that way for the rest of his life, thus averting war. It’s also worth noting that Shikhandi represents a certain cosmic balance to her twin siblings: the entirely masculine Dhrishtadyumna and the entirely feminine Draupadi, who is Goddess-on-Earth.</p>
<p>Later, however, Shikhandi’s gender identity brings an element of confusion to the great Pandava-Kaurava war: women are prohibited from the battlefield, but is Shikhandi a man or a woman? Or, as Pattanaik puts it:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote><p>“All those who knew this tale wondered if Shikhandi was man or woman. Is gender defined by the truth of birth or by the truth of this moment?” (Pattanaik, 2010, p. 250).</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This is a question that is asked over and over throughout the epic: what is gender? What defines it? Is it dictated by society, personal conviction, or both? <em>The Mahabharata </em>takes an astonishingly nuanced view of this issue, examining the question from many angles, and expressing sympathy for gender-fluid characters, even as they go against society’s dictates and against <em>dharma</em>.</p>
<p>So are we to conclude that the Vedic people were more accepting of gender fluidity and gender ambiguity than we are today? Not necessarily: <em>The Mahabharata </em>is three thousand years old, and has undoubtedly had many edits, additions, subtractions and alterations. Besides, any notion of an ancient Utopian society where all gender identities were welcome is nonsense: human societies across the world have <em>always </em>regulated gender, and <em>always </em>used it as a form of social control. Vedic society, as portrayed in the epic, is heteronormative and patriarchal. The gender-fluid individuals in <em>The Mahabharata </em>are portrayed as special and magical, but also as weird, abnormal, and deeply embarrassing to their relatives. Shikhandi’s female body is so unacceptable that it nearly starts a war; the Chandra-vamsis are humiliated and deny that they are descended from the gender-ambiguous Budh and Ila; and even Bhishma, whose renunciation of his gender identity is relatively mild, is repeatedly upbraided for his choice, and deeply pitied. Also, irritatingly, while transformations from male to female are handed down as curses and terrible punishments, Shikhandi is delighted to become male, and happy to remain that way for the rest of his life. In <em>The Mahabharata</em>, being male is definitely superior to being female, and while gender fluidity is omnipresent, society’s rules regarding gender roles are still deeply important. Non cisgender characters go against those rules, and they are never fully accepted by society.</p>
<p>Perhaps the hidden message is that it is not gender that is important: it is transformation. It is metamorphosis. In the universe of <em>The Mahabharata</em>, transformation is key, and it abounds everywhere: gods become mortals, mortals become gods, the living become dead and the dead become living. Characters morph through all variations and degrees of gender. What makes the Pandava brothers good and the Kauravas unworthy is not that the Pandavas are especially virtuous—they aren’t. It’s that, unlike the Kauravas, they are willing to grow, and learn, and change. The Pandavas experience all manner of existences during their journey, moving between palace and forest, assuming different gender and social roles, even spending time with the gods. In other words, they change, and so they grow. In order for the universe to be preserved, balance must be struck between preservation and progress, stability and change. Metamorphosis through all states of being is vital for the evolution of the soul; gender is only one facet of that eternal state of change.</p>
<p>References</p>
<p>Pattanaik, D. (2010).<em> Jaya: An illustrated retelling of The Mahabharata</em>. Penguin Books India: Haryana, India.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/gender-identity-in-the-mahabharata/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thoughts on Little Free Libraries</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/thoughts-on-little-free-libraries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rose Strickman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 11:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Wordy One]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I love Little Free Libraries. Indeed, as COVID continues and I am locked out of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love Little Free Libraries. Indeed, as COVID continues and I am locked out of regulation libraries and bookstores, I find I like them more and more.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22657 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/books-1332428_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/books-1332428_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/books-1332428_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/books-1332428_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/books-1332428_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/books-1332428_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />There’s always a pleasurable jolt of anticipation when I see the distinctive shape of the tiny house on a pole up ahead. I always hurry to see what’s inside. Because, even if it’s a dusty old Christian philosophy book, some ripped-up kids’ books, and an out-of-date <em>Writer’s Market</em>, there’s always something.</p>
<p>Little Free Libraries always surprise you. Just when you’ve given up all hope of finding anything, you discover a gem. I got my copy of <em>The Book Woman of Troublesome Creek</em> from a Little Free Library, along with <em>The Pillow Book of Sei Shonagon</em>, in perfect condition. Recently, I’ve had quite a lot of luck with the local Little Free Libraries: I found the <em>Encyclopedia of Mammals</em> and a picture book version of <em>E.T.</em> for my nephews, both in excellent condition. I also found my best discovery yet: the complete boxed set of the <em>Griffin and Sabine </em>books, looking brand-new, with all the letters still in their envelopes.</p>
<p>Most of the time, of course, Little Free Libraries disappoint you. But there’s always the possibility that you’ll find something. And there’s something nice about them altogether: the idea that people will voluntarily leave their books for other people to find, in an entirely casual and non-obligatory way, and that books may find second homes and second chances. They’re also a lifeline for book addicts in these COVID times, and a much cheaper alternative to Amazon (which, naturally, I am also hitting very hard). There’s a nice absence of obligation about them, too. You can take a book, read it, and put it back, without hurting anyone’s feelings or any social awkwardness.</p>
<p>I have left my share of books in local Little Free Libraries, of course. Sometimes I’ve regretted it<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22659 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/little-free-library-1741367_1920-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/little-free-library-1741367_1920-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/little-free-library-1741367_1920-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/little-free-library-1741367_1920-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/little-free-library-1741367_1920.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /> immediately (why did I give away <em>The Great Husband Hunt</em>?! Nooo!) but mostly I’m glad that the books I leave may go on to find new homes, with owners that love them better. Or, if the book is on its last legs, with pages curling up and cover falling off, it at least gets an honorable death and burial. (Oddly, these are often the books that disappear the fastest. I guess they get worn out so quickly for a reason.)</p>
<p>In these times of isolation, stress and worry, when both the present and the future seem pretty scary, a Little Free Library is a piece of low-key kindness, an expression of community. Book lovers, even in the darkest of times, are finding new homes for old books, and readers are helping readers find good material. This is a small atom of light, in a dark night indeed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When a Bad Book is Good</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/when-a-bad-book-is-good/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rose Strickman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Wordy One]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I do love a bad book. Don’t get me wrong: I love good books too,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I do love a bad book.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong: I love <em>good </em>books too, far more than I like bad ones. I read a much greater proportion of good books than bad, and value them much more highly. But I do read (and own) bad books, and I do enjoy them.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21347 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/book-3983399_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/book-3983399_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/book-3983399_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/book-3983399_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/book-3983399_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/book-3983399_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Why should this be? A bad book is, well, bad. It has shoddy characterization, poor writing quality, appalling worldbuilding, and general, all-around awfulness. I cannot spend hours on end reading a bad book the way I can a good one. But there are times when a bad book is just what you need. How can this be?</p>
<p>For starters, bad books don’t make you think too hard. Part of what makes a good book good is that it’s thought-provoking. It comments on social issues, it poses questions, it delves into the human mind and spirit. It’s wonderful, but can be a bit exhausting. A bad book doesn’t do any of those things, or it does so very poorly. And sometimes, that’s the exact kind of break you need. If you’re oppressed by the news, or exhausted after a long, hard day, it’s kind of nice, sometimes, to curl up with a trashy bodice-ripper or idiotic space opera. They give your brain a break.</p>
<p>My second reason for liking bad books is a bit more selfish: sometimes I’m just jealous of good authors. It’s frustrating, when you’re a writer yourself, to read the gems of other writers’ minds, or be forced to marvel at their commercial or artistic success. Reading a wonderful book, I’m sometimes uncomfortably reminded of all those stories I wrote that didn’t turn out right, or those novels I never finished writing, or the hours I spent surfing the Internet instead of producing work. Reading a good book, in the wrong mood, can give an author the feeling that she will never get anywhere in comparison with this work of genius in her hands. Reading a <em>bad </em>book, on the other hand, can be cheering: after all, <em>someone</em> managed to publish this piece of trash! There’s hope for you too, and you can certainly do better!</p>
<p>Thirdly, in this age of extreme literary passions, when devotion to a franchise can attain the magnitude of a minor or not-so-minor religion, it’s just plain <em>relaxing </em>to read a novel no one’s ever heard of, that will never make the bestseller list. With people coming to online blows over <em>Star Wars</em>, bestselling authors achieving the status of prophets, and the Harry Potter <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">cult</span> fandom still <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21349 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/relaxing-1979674_1920-300x205.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="205" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/relaxing-1979674_1920-300x205.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/relaxing-1979674_1920-1024x701.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/relaxing-1979674_1920-768x526.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/relaxing-1979674_1920-1536x1052.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/relaxing-1979674_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />going strong, even as its <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">prophet</span> author comes under scrutiny and condemnation, it can be very nice to read something without having to take sides about it, or form an opinion, or face half a million reviews or rants every time you log onto your browser. Nice, anonymous trash that will never be noticed, that no one is ever going to tweet about, is sometimes a welcome break in the ongoing cacophony.</p>
<p>So, the next time I am depressed from the news, or tired of listening to people rant about the <em>Star Wars </em>sequels, I know what I am going to do. I am going to brew tea, draw my curtains, curl up in bed, turn on the lamp, and open the pages of my secret stash of terrible books. I am going to let their mediocrity and awfulness soothe me. After all, no one gives a damn about these books, so I don’t have to either.</p>
<p>I do draw the line at sparkly vampires, though.</p>
<p>A bad book is good only up to a certain point.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hate the Sinner, Love the Sin: When Authors are Repulsive</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hate-the-sinner-love-the-sin-when-authors-are-repulsive/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rose Strickman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 17:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Wordy One]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18804</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is a question with no simple answer: what should we as readers do when&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is a question with no simple answer: what should we as readers do when the authors whose work we admire hold or held personal positions on society, race, religion, etc., that we find objectionable? What should we think? How should we feel?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19137 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kelly-sikkema-E8H76nY1v6Q-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kelly-sikkema-E8H76nY1v6Q-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kelly-sikkema-E8H76nY1v6Q-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kelly-sikkema-E8H76nY1v6Q-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kelly-sikkema-E8H76nY1v6Q-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/kelly-sikkema-E8H76nY1v6Q-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />A classic example of this is H. P. Lovecraft. The man was a truly great author, a pioneer of horror and science fiction, who left a wonderful fictional legacy. He was also a hideous racist and anti-Semite who sympathized with Fascists. It is repulsive to read his description of the Black and Jewish communities, and he didn’t hold poor whites in much higher regard. He seems to have had some truly nasty ideas about race and class. But I, along with many other readers, still love his work.</p>
<p>It’s a phenomenon found across literature. William Shakespeare advocated wife-beating and domestic violence in <em>The Taming of the Shrew</em>, and a performance of <em>The Merchant of Venice </em>is horrific to watch. Doris Lessing positively bragged about how abandoning her young children made her such a feminist. Frank Herbert espoused some very Freudian fears of sex and women. And there are many others.</p>
<p>So what should readers do, when we encounter an author whose work we love—but whose views we hate?</p>
<p>Some older authors, such as Shakespeare, can be cut some slack: they were true to the social norms of their times. Even Lovecraft’s racism can be slightly excused, though not to such a great extent. We can’t expect authors from the 16<sup>th</sup> century, or the 19<sup>th</sup>, or even the 20<sup>th</sup>, to hold the same views we do, or embrace the same notions of correctness. But where do we draw the line? <em>Should </em>we draw the line? Should an author’s personal worldview impact how we approach their work?</p>
<p>To a certain extent, I think, an author’s body of work can stand on its own. Lovecraft’s stories will always be works of genius in the horror and science fiction genres, just as Shakespeare’s works will always be astonishingly wonderful. Just because we disagree with these authors’ worldviews does not mean we can’t enjoy their work, or take valuable messages from it. But an author’s worldview <em>does </em>impact their work. Lovecraft’s racism is obvious in his work, just as Frank Herbert’s fear of women is obvious in his <em>Dune </em>series. So when do objectionable prejudices and phobias become intolerable to us as readers?</p>
<p>Ultimately, I think, it must be a personal decision. Readers must decide for themselves—and <em>only </em>for themselves—whether an author’s genius outweighs an author’s personal views, and to what level they are willing to tolerate those views coming out in the work. Indeed, in Lovecraft’s case, love is probably the best punishment: Lovecraft would have been horrified by his current position as a pop culture icon, with Black people, Brown people, Jews, women and the hoi polloi he so despised not only reading his works, but making them into movies, creating art based off them, and even writing their own stories set in his universe. But he would have to tolerate it. When an author publishes a story, it is no longer theirs in a spiritual or intellectual sense: it belongs to the reading public, and we as the readers will decide what we take from it, what we will think, and how we will embrace or reject it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
