<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tisdale Flannery &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/elizabeth-flannery/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:02:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Seven of Wands: Keep Writing Anyway</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-seven-of-wands-keep-writing-anyway/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-seven-of-wands-keep-writing-anyway/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tisdale Flannery]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tea with Strangers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The military jeep bounced over ruts as it approached the town. The walls in front&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-16643 size-full alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Seven-Wands.jpg" alt="" width="579" height="960" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Seven-Wands.jpg 579w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Seven-Wands-181x300.jpg 181w" sizes="(max-width: 579px) 100vw, 579px" /></p>
<p>The military jeep bounced over ruts as it approached the town. The walls in front of us were cratered with bombs; everything was covered in dust, abandoned, destroyed. It was enough to thoroughly distract me from the misery in my own life. I’d all but given up on writing altogether, for all the usual reasons &#8212; endless rejections, seeing my ideas done with more skill by someone else, meeting a writer whose first book is a masterpiece &#8212; plus the numerous additional demands on my life, plus the fact that writing was not making any money, which we needed, and I was getting older and tireder. I really believed I could manage to give up my writing habit, if I focused hard on, for instance, making music whenever I felt like writing. And when that old sorrow came, the sense of loss I felt when memories of my unrealized story worlds &#8211; well, then, I could just accept that life has sorrows, and deal with it. So, here I was, in a war zone, witnessing some of the world&#8217;s very real sorrows.</p>
<p>My assignment was to interview the character of the Seven of Wands, and I was warned, by Headquarters, that I was going into an active zone. All was quiet at the moment, though. My driver stopped at a crossroads, where we all had to get out, to help move rubble from the road. As I worked, I saw something out of the corner of my eye. A sparkling thing, a small bit of bright color in this sad world. I discreetly pocketed it.</p>
<p>When we reached the western wall of the city, some of the soldiers were resting, quiet, but my subject stood atop the wall. It wasn&#8217;t the size or strength of his body but the expression on his face that told me of his power. I clambered up to sit beside him.</p>
<p>&#8220;The enemy grows,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;Why don’t you give up?&#8221;</p>
<p>He looked at me in astonishment. &#8220;Because giving up is the only failure.&#8221; He gazed at me for a long moment. &#8220;Why did you come here? Why accept this dangerous assignment?&#8221;</p>
<p>I don’t know, I tell him. I don’t fully understand it.</p>
<p>He nodded. &#8220;You don&#8217;t always need to have a reason.&#8221;</p>
<p>He looked at my hand, then, and his eyes focused on the shiny item I&#8217;d found on the ground. I didn&#8217;t know what it was, but he did, and he took it from me in wonder. He held it to his lips and blew. The sound of a bird, unfamiliar to me, filled the air. Delight covered his face.</p>
<p>&#8220;Wait, and watch,&#8221; he told me.</p>
<p>When the enemy charged, he lifted the whistle, and blew. Above the hordes, a cloud of something dark rose on the horizon. It grew. He continued to blow the whistle, all the while parrying the growing number of staffs swept at him to knock him down. The cloud covered the sky above us. A host of large raptors descended on his enemies. Their striped wings beat about the ears and eyes of his attackers. The enemy was driven back.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-16644 size-full alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/hawk-kettle-58a6d7a85f9b58a3c912493c.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="640" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/hawk-kettle-58a6d7a85f9b58a3c912493c.jpg 960w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/hawk-kettle-58a6d7a85f9b58a3c912493c-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/hawk-kettle-58a6d7a85f9b58a3c912493c-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></p>
<p>During the celebration on the ground that night, the soldier found me. &#8220;This is how I live my life,&#8221; he said. &#8220;I am compelled to defend my home. It is not rational; I could not win, according to military experts and politicians. But I fight anyway, and because of the beautiful coincidence of your arrival, I have won. Life is like this.</p>
<p>&#8220;So keep writing, no matter what. You don&#8217;t need reasons. Continue to write, though you receive a thousand rejections, and though it seems everyone in the world has more success and more talent than you do, and have written your own ideas better than you ever could have done yourself. You read the beautiful, breathtaking stories of others, and you think you have no business in this art. You write, and it seems pointless. And then, one day, a lonely book of yours is on a stranger&#8217;s coffee table somewhere. A guest picks it up at the right moment. They flip the pages, they see a phrase you&#8217;ve written, an expression of truth, and it changes their life. And then they go on to change the world.</p>
<p>Keep writing, and trust that your words will work magic in the world, even if you never see the magic done. To create because you are compelled to keep creating is to allow yourself to be the vehicle for all that is good in the world.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-seven-of-wands-keep-writing-anyway/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Two of Wands: The Sanctity of Desire</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-two-of-wands-the-sanctity-of-desire/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-two-of-wands-the-sanctity-of-desire/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tisdale Flannery]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 11:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tea with Strangers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Don’t you think that’s a little selfish?” I stare across the table, across the cups&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16436 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Two-Wands.jpg" alt="" width="579" height="960" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Two-Wands.jpg 579w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Two-Wands-181x300.jpg 181w" sizes="(max-width: 579px) 100vw, 579px" /></p>
<p>“Don’t you think that’s a little selfish?”</p>
<p>I stare across the table, across the cups of coffee between me and my sort-of friend. I honestly didn’t feel like seeing her today. I could have used the time to work on the revision of my novel, but I agreed to get together with her because it had been months and, after all, I couldn’t keep hurting her feelings, right? So I was just telling her about the conference I’d planned to go to in January, and my mixed feelings about leaving the kids in the care of my husband for three days while I indulge my Muse.</p>
<p>That’s when she hit me with the selfish comment.</p>
<p>She must have seen my emotional earthquake, because she backtracked. Sort of. “I mean,” she said, “I know you love to write, but three days away from your kids seems a little, I don’t know, excessive. You could always just take an afternoon each of those days. And then be at home at night. I did that, when I was voice-training, for our last performance.” She proceeds to go into detail about the successes and pleasures of her avocation of theater.</p>
<p>I give her my full attention, knowing this is the last time I’ll make myself sit across a table from her. Still, her words rankle in the car on the way home, at home while I bathe the baby, at night, in bed.</p>
<p>“Do you think I’m being selfish?” I ask my husband. “About the conference?”</p>
<p>He sighs. “Why don’t you get your next assignment done, and see how you feel then?” He rolls over.</p>
<p>I stare at the squares of moonlight on the ceiling, mulling this non-answer.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16437" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/moon-through-window.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></p>
<p>Thirty hours later, I sit in a plush velvet chair, a wide mahogany desk separating me from the subject of my interview. He is framed all around by huge floor-to-ceiling windows, overlooking the harbor where busy ships carry out the labor of his life&#8217;s work.</p>
<p>His story impresses me with the strength of will he showed in building a successful shipping empire. I take notes on his humble origin, the setbacks he faced, the yielding of fate to his determination. Finally he wraps up his story.</p>
<p>“And now,” he says, “what do you want?”</p>
<p>“Oh,” I say. “Just the interview. Thank you. I won’t waste any more of your time. There’s nothing I really want.”</p>
<p>“What do you mean, there’s nothing you want?” He stands, takes his scepter in hand, strides around the desk, and brings his face close to mine, black eyes alight with anger. “How can you have no desire? Were you born without a soul?”</p>
<p>After the shock of surprise, my first thought is of the conference. The time to write. The chance to renew my inspiration. “Well, there is, but I just… my life is full, and I’m needed by others. I don’t want to be selfish.”</p>
<p>&#8220;Ah.&#8221; He leans back, a knowing look on his face. &#8220;Self-denial. A martyr.&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;m about to object, but he goes on.</p>
<p>&#8220;Let me tell you another story, one quite different than the story of my success. You see, I was not always so driven. As a child, I was timid and eager to please. It was a challenge for me to go against the current of whatever I thought would make someone happy. If you asked me for a favor, I&#8217;d want to do it before I even knew what it is. If you told me how you wished I would change, I might have said no, but the pull of your desire would continue to act on me without my awareness, until I either moved in your direction or dug my feet into the silt of my subconscious. And so, when a benefactor helped me follow in his footsteps, working in his factory, I chose to ignore the call to travel, and make this man happy by learning his trade instead. I became moderately successful. But I was never happy.</p>
<p>&#8220;Then, one day, I met a beggar. The beggar recognized me, and hailed me as a man of means. I handed him a coin, thinking to be generous and good, but the beggar threw the coin back at my face. &#8216;I want nothing from you,&#8217; he told me. Shocked, I asked why.</p>
<p>&#8216;Because,&#8217; he said, grinning with a mouth full of missing teeth, &#8216;I have pursued what I wanted in life. I followed my heart. I never sold out for the purpose of pleasing anyone else. I am poor, but I have lived the life I wanted to live. I would not trade places with you for all the coins in your vault.&#8217;</p>
<p>&#8220;It was then that I quit the factory work, purchased a small boat, and began my international trading business, step by step. Success was never sure, but my path was always clear, because I knew exactly what I was supposed to be doing.</p>
<p>&#8220;How do we know what it is we’re supposed to be doing? By our desire. What you want, what makes your heart sing — that is your direction, your purpose. To ignore it is to do a disservice not just to yourself, but to the world. When you follow your desire, you heed the call of your soul. The world offers us so many rules and threats about what we must do and what we must be. It is time to shed those, to dig into the silt of our subconscious, to build stone bridges, dams, fortifications against the desires of others.</p>
<p>“It is not selfish for you to do what you want. If you need an altruistic reason, you can say that you must set a good example for your children. Impress your will upon the world around you. Make your mark. Make no apologies. Make people unhappy. Say no. Make demands. Be unreasonable. Do whatever it takes to pursue your passion, for no reason other than pure desire. We have desires for a reason; they are our map to our enlightened selves. Honor your desires. Don’t deny them. Follow them, or pay a heavy toll in sorrow, which is a far more selfish thing than asking others to make sacrifices for your benefit.”</p>
<p>“When you do right by yourself, you are showing the world that you trust in its guidance. When you do good for yourself, you are doing good for the world. Do not be afraid of being selfish. The fulfillment of your dreams is your purpose here on this brief physical journey of life.”</p>
<p>He’s right. As I drive home, late that night after a seafood dinner in the little town, I feel immensely grateful for the resolution in his answer. I’ll take whatever time I need to write. We’re often told as girls that it&#8217;s right and good to give up what we want if it inconveniences others. That is a lie. Just because I am a woman, just because I am a mother, is no reason not to follow my dreams. I’ll write, and take whatever time I need to do it, knowing that I am following the path of all living beings in honoring my call, the call of my desire.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-two-of-wands-the-sanctity-of-desire/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Three of Cups:  The Case for Ambrosia</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-three-of-cups-the-case-for-ambrosia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tisdale Flannery]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 10:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tea with Strangers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15954</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m sitting at my kitchen table, holding the assignment sheet for my next interview. Finally,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-15957 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Three-Cups.jpg" alt="" width="579" height="960" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Three-Cups.jpg 579w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/Three-Cups-181x300.jpg 181w" sizes="(max-width: 579px) 100vw, 579px" /></p>
<p>I’m sitting at my kitchen table, holding the assignment sheet for my next interview. Finally, I suck in a deep breath and dial the number on it.</p>
<p>“Hello, you’ve reached the Three of Cups. How may I help you?” A man’s voice, polished and professional.</p>
<p>“Yes.” I clear my throat. “I’m the journalist for the Tea with Strangers blog.” That was my attempt at sounding professional. It doesn’t last long. “I was actually wondering if maybe it might be possible to move our interview up just a few days. If they’re free.”</p>
<p>Silence.</p>
<p>“Would you like to give them the reason?”</p>
<p>“I have some free time now.” It sounds as lame as it is. The truth is, I have lots of time this week, and absolutely no inspiration to write anything. It’s a sad state for a writer. Neither coffee nor hard exercise nor sleep nor booze nor weed has sparked any ideas that I actually care about. So, I figured I might as well work on my assignment.</p>
<p>The man sounds sympathetic anyway. “Let me see. I’ll talk with them and get back to you.”</p>
<p>I sit back and roll a pencil between my fingers. A little over an hour later, my cell phone rings. <em>Star Wars</em> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_D0ZQPqeJkk">theme</a>, of course, making my life sound exciting. If only I could go to a galaxy far, far away. I force myself to wait until the second ring to answer it.</p>
<p>“It would be possible for you to talk with them today,” he said, “provided you don’t mind the unusual circumstances.”</p>
<p>My focus is total now.</p>
<p>He continues. “You see, the subjects are scheduled to take a hot air balloon ride, and said they would be happy to provide you an interview, if you could ride along.”</p>
<p>Ride along. “In the car on the way there, you mean?”</p>
<p>He clears his throat and says apologetically, “No, they are already there. You would have to ride along in the balloon.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-15959 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/hot-air-balloon-1024x366.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="261" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/hot-air-balloon-1024x366.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/hot-air-balloon-300x107.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/hot-air-balloon-768x274.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/hot-air-balloon.jpg 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /></p>
<p>“I.” Can hardly speak. “That would be just fine,” I manage. “I could totally, absolutely do that.” I wipe a little droplet of spittle off the corner of my mouth. “I could leave now. Where are they?”</p>
<p>He gives me a location. It takes me seven and a half minutes to get my things and get into my car. It takes me three minutes and forty-five seconds to get to the highway. I keep an eye on the speedometer, because it just keeps creeping up. Oh, I will not get pulled over today.</p>
<p>When I was a toddler, my parents took my older brother and sister for a ride in a balloon. I was too young to ride, then, but I was not too young to long for it. I was not too young to remember. And all my life, I have wanted to do this, but could never justify the expense. Stopped at a light on the way out of town, I let myself squeal like a teakettle at full boil.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15960 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/packer-meadow-300x188.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="188" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/packer-meadow-300x188.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/packer-meadow.jpg 638w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>The field itself, where the balloon is being prepared, is beautiful, a sunlit grassy meadow framed by forests in all directions. The three women, my subjects of interview, are beautiful, dressed in their exquisite ancient gowns and piled hair, casually dangling glasses of wine and feathered fans. The balloon — the balloon is so beautiful, in sunset orange and crocus purple, silver and gold threads over cobalt, crimson, cerulean, that I cannot stop myself from walking to it directly, admiring, as the heat lifts it into shape. In a few moments, after I have remembered my manners and introduced myself, we have been lifted up into the sky in this glorious human invention. As we float over the land below, it’s clear I should have done this a long, long time ago.</p>
<p>My subjects agree, pouring more wine for us.</p>
<p>“I’m sure you will find,” says the one I mentally named Mermaid for her blue and green dress, “that your inspiration will return to you after this experience. Artistic inspiration is excitement for an idea, for a project. No more and no less. And how can you feel that excitement in your art when you don’t have it in your life?”</p>
<p>The woman in the peach colored dress leans back, looking up at the sky, letting her hair dangle down over the edge of the basket. “But do remember,” she says, “and this is important: you have to always have something in the future that you are looking forward to. Doing a fun thing and then thinking, that’s all you need and now you should be able to write, is quite the wrong way to go about it; you must have that little thrill toward the future that can resonate with the thrill of an idea.”</p>
<p>“So,” says the third, the gold-and-green gowned woman, fresh as spring, “when was the last time you felt really excited?”</p>
<p>When was the last time <em>you</em> got excited, when the very thought of something made your body float like a bubble and your smile pop like fireworks?</p>
<p>You need to feel this in your life, so that you can feel it for your writing. You need to feel it outside your writing first. You need to have fun. All work and no play not only makes Jack a dull boy, it makes Jack’s writing dull as cold ash.</p>
<p>Make a list of moments in your life when you felt excited. Reach back, if you need to, even all the way to childhood. A visit to an amusement park? A birthday party? Riding your bike down the big hill, flying, knowing you are actually riding your very own Pegasus? Getting together with friends for a concert, or even better, a music festival?</p>
<p>Now make a list of things that might excite you now. They could be large, like a year long sailing voyage, or small, like a dinner party, or a visit to a new museum.They could be common, like a trip to that farmer’s market you saw last year, or obscure, like learning to read an ancient language. Maybe you’d like to get a tattoo, but haven’t yet justified it. Maybe you’d like to spend the day entirely alone, surrounded by books, in a library in a new city. Maybe you’d like to rescue another <a href="https://www.petfinder.com/">cat</a>. You deserve to do something that would thrill you now. You deserve to do these things regularly. You are a writer, and writers change the world by influencing the way readers think, but writers don’t live on bread alone; they must taste ambrosia, so they can describe the taste of divinity to other mortals. When excitement is a part of your life, your writing self will know how to come alive with just the right idea.</p>
<p>The air around me, the misty cloud we pass through, feeds an old story idea I’d long forgotten. The thrill of riding in the balloon resonates with this thrill of the new idea, the new world to explore, the new characters to fall in love with. When I get home, I am once again at my kitchen table, but this time with my laptop, typing long into the night.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Three of Swords: Facing the Darkness</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-three-of-swords-facing-the-darkness/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-three-of-swords-facing-the-darkness/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tisdale Flannery]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tea with Strangers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A letter from your sponsors Dear reader, Today, your host is missing. The interviewer who&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-15820 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Three-Swords.jpg" alt="" width="579" height="960" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Three-Swords.jpg 579w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Three-Swords-181x300.jpg 181w" sizes="(max-width: 579px) 100vw, 579px" /></p>
<p><em>A letter from your sponsors</em></p>
<p>Dear reader,</p>
<p>Today, your host is missing. The interviewer who writes these articles has not showed up for work. We suspect that she has succumbed to the shadows that often plague writers, the inability to escape the spiraling thoughts of futility, impotence, confusion, and darkness that sometimes keep humans from performing their basic duties and fulfilling obligations. We therefore ask your assistance in finding her.</p>
<p>You will need to come with us on a journey into the darkness. You will need to be courageous, yourself; you will see things here that trouble you, and perhaps even threaten your own ability to move forward. We understand that, as a writer, you are likely a sensitive creature. We know that such as you may see the darkness in the world and forget how to distinguish between outside sorrows and inside sorrows. We ask for your assistance anyway.</p>
<p>Take this torch, please. This light is created by what you write. When you write of the ignorance of leaders, the cruelty of children, the pointlessness of man, you hold the torch firmly aloft.</p>
<p>Now we can enter the tunnel. Hold the fire up to the wall. Do you see how, written there, a President shakes hands with a creator of poisonous insecticide, one that has caused cancer in numerous children? The poison spreads; the infant sickens in the womb. Write about it, please.</p>
<p>We continue. Do you see, now, the picture of the religious leader siphoning off funds from his charity, to fuel his jet, justifying it with elaborate rationalizations? Write every detail of his thinking. Allow yourself to get inside his mind, as ugly as it is.</p>
<p>Are you angry? Good. Now your torch is burning bright. We continue.</p>
<p>A little farther, you see a picture of your own mother, sweet and warm. She is baking for you, isn’t she? She’s also talking on the phone to someone. What is she saying? Listen, please. In her words, you hear that everything she’s told you about her marriage is a lie. She can’t wait to leave; she just needs to get you through school and out of the house, first.</p>
<p>It hurts. Write it.</p>
<p>Starving polar bears, singed baby orangutans, children in Thailand enslaved to peel shrimp eighteen hours a day, so that the cats in the United States can have a variety of canned food. Write it.</p>
<p>Friends betraying each other. Forgotten loves. Unassuaged loneliness, worse as the human race becomes more disconnected from community.</p>
<p>Write it. We need your torch.</p>
<p>You see a picture on the wall of a world, a few centuries from now, where the human race has been reduced to a desperate few. In a way, that’s good, you think; they’d been doing such a poor job of being part of an ecosystem, and maybe the few left will learn. But then you see a closeup of what you thought was a star, and instead, it is a beautiful spaceship, containing the wealthy and powerful remainder, who have escaped the planet they helped to incinerate. They go on to spread the disease of human greed to other worlds. Does that make you despair? Write it.</p>
<p>Feel the breath of cold, clammy chill? That means we are approaching the center. Hold fast, please; now is not the time to falter. Oh, you see a picture of yourself? Yes, hold the torch there. See the memory of your own negligence. See the mouse you caged and let die, because you were a child and you were busy with other things. See the hurt you caused a friend when you chose to be with a new love instead of helping her in need. See the opportunities you&#8217;ve missed, the mistakes you&#8217;ve made, over and over. This is all part of the darkness. No, stand back up. Write it. Your torch burns brighter now.</p>
<p>Now you hold your torch aloft, and see around you a great chamber pulsing with red light. The giant human heart in the center of the room, suspended in midair, is pierced by swords, by knowledge of the ugly truths we must face. And there, in a corner of this chamber, is your host. She curls in a fetal position, overwhelmed by what she has seen, the same images and visions you have had, and others that are specific to her fears and shames. But you can help her. Make her tell the ugly truth, as you have done, and create light with your words.</p>
<p>Yes, look at the heart. Do you see the pain of each piercing sword? Do you see the loss of blood, the sorrow? It hurts to look at it, but you must continue, and describe what you see.</p>
<p>Now, look at the words you have written. They are beautiful, in themselves. They create light. Truth is light, even when what it describes is darkness. The truth itself lights up the darkness. Do not succumb, as your host did, do not stop writing what you see; your light is needed, to guide others out of the dark. There are terrible wrongs in the world, and always will be. It is okay to be sad about them; sorrow is one of the trees in the Garden, and must be watered and fed. Persist, keep writing what you see, and eventually, the shadows fade. See? Your narrator stands, awake now. She is weak but aware. She walks back with you, out of the tunnel, grateful for your help. You have done a true and good thing. You have taken darkness and turned it into light. You and your host arrive at the mouth of the tunnel. The sky is still dark, but on the horizon, a line of pale gold tells of what will come again.</p>
<p>Sincerely,</p>
<p>The Tarot</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-three-of-swords-facing-the-darkness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two of Pentacles: On Shifting Ground</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/two-of-pentacles-on-shifting-ground/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/two-of-pentacles-on-shifting-ground/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tisdale Flannery]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tea with Strangers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15630</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Turn left.” The ocean wind blows into the open car window, reminding me of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15632 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Two-Pentacles-181x300.jpg" alt="" width="181" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Two-Pentacles-181x300.jpg 181w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Two-Pentacles.jpg 579w" sizes="(max-width: 181px) 100vw, 181px" /></p>
<p>“Turn left.” The ocean wind blows into the open car window, reminding me of the summers I spent here as a child. Finally, a place I’m familiar with.</p>
<p>My doppelganger looks over at me, pointedly.</p>
<p>I look back down at the map given to me by Headquarters. “I know it’s not the directions they gave us, but this is the quicker way.”</p>
<p>She shrugs and turns.</p>
<p>We quickly reach a roadblock, the wall of a new neighborhood that wasn’t here before. I should have known. Things change. The doppelganger turns around wordlessly and takes the sheet of directions from my hands.</p>
<p>I had a run of good writing recently. Each day gave me a block of two hours, when the babysitter had time between classes, and my other part-time job started later. That lasted until this week. Now, unfortunately, the babysitter has found a summer job, so she’s only available in the evenings when I have no energy to write, and I can’t find anyone else who can work those two hours in the day. Once I do, I can get back into routine. Until then, these interviews are all the writing I can do.</p>
<p>We arrive at the water’s edge, where a single figure stands on the rocks, gracefully juggling two large golden coins. Waves and foam wash up against his pants legs. Behind him, two ships battle the wild surf, which tosses them forward and back; it is impossible to tell if they will succeed or succumb.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15672 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/shipwreck-300x158.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="158" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/shipwreck-300x158.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/shipwreck-768x405.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/shipwreck.jpg 910w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>The man on the rocks doesn’t seem to be bothered by the chaos. He grins and waves when he sees us, juggling both plate-sized coins with one hand, then resuming the two-handed toss.</p>
<p>When the car stops, I jump out, and immediately fall on my face.</p>
<p>“Watch the ground,” calls my subject, cheerfully.</p>
<p>The ground is, indeed, moving. I had thought it was the ocean washing up against the man, but instead, he is moving, the ground is moving, crashing against the ocean. Vertigo overwhelms me and I fall again. “I thought I knew this place!” I call out. “What’s going on? Why can’t I find my footing?”</p>
<p>He just laughs and helps me up. “Don’t try to move forward by looking back,” he says.</p>
<p>“What do you mean?” I ask, breathless.</p>
<p>He calls out. “Find your center!”</p>
<p>I struggle to stand, wondering what that could mean. All I can imagine is the center of my physical body, right above my navel. Somehow, focusing there allows me to balance.</p>
<p>“Ha! You’re right!” I call out. I look back at my doppelganger, waiting in the driver’s seat, and instantly fall again. She just shakes her head.</p>
<p>My subject laughs and walks over to me, still juggling.</p>
<p>“Finding my center,” I say, struggling to stand up. Just then the ground lurches again, and I fall to my hands and knees.</p>
<p>“Now you must find your feet,” he says.</p>
<p>“I thought I had to find my center.”</p>
<p>“Ah, but the ground shifted. Time changes all things. Find your feet.”</p>
<p>I focus on my feet, and now I can balance. For a moment.</p>
<p>“Do you have advice for writers?” I ask, hoping to get this over with. I am beginning to feel seasick and I am not even in the water.</p>
<p>“Indeed!” he says. “But it’s advice for all of us, for all humans. We want to find answers, always. That is human nature. We want stasis, we want surety.”</p>
<p>The ground shifts and I start to fall. “Jump,” he says, and this time, I listen and obey right away. When I land, I land perfectly, and feel secure again.</p>
<p>He continues. “But letting go of the answers we have found is the lifelong challenge to being human. It is always difficult. But it is needed, because if we do not grow, we are not alive. And how can we grow if we don’t change?” The rock tilts toward the water and I reach out to my subject. He balances me.</p>
<p>In return, he leans against me. The golden coins between us are warm to the touch, the only element here that feels secure to me. Then he stands still, and the ground is still, with him. “Have a seat,” he says.</p>
<p>Finally, I can relax. The ships in the water have moved past the surf, and begin to sail away.</p>
<p>My subject puts a hand on my arm. “There is no truth that is always the truth. There is no answer that is always the answer. You will find solutions, and when you do, run with them, make the most of them, but when the ground shifts again, let them go. Nothing lasts forever. When the dark times come, when it’s difficult to write even a word, don’t insist on using ways that worked before. Look for what is needed right now. Do the dance, find your balance. Adapt. Make a habit of change.”</p>
<p>I sigh. <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/notes/2016/11/the-poems-that-help-with-processing-change/507371/">This is not what I wanted to hear.</a></p>
<p>“Don’t worry. The more you do this, the more gracefully you can handle the shifting ground.”</p>
<p>“But how do I know which way to shift?”</p>
<p>“Pay attention,” he says. “Keep your focus outward, on the here, the now. Observe. Try new things. See what works.” He hands me one of the beautiful coins. It rests across my lap like a bowl of sunshine. Its weight and warmth comfort me. “Trust the feeling of pleasure, of joy. Don’t focus on what you want. Focus on what you <a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/53214/winter-stars-56d2324fcb793">love</a>. And don’t give up, for all things are possible, eventually.”</p>
<p>The ground begins to shake again. He laughs, takes the coin from me, and rises, now juggling again. On the way back to the car, I instinctively lurch as the ground lurches. I see a buckle beginning in front of me; I leap over it. Then, everything is still, and I almost fall. Laughing, too, I run, and just make it to the car door handle. My doppelganger, sitting in the driver’s seat, is now the one to look a little seasick, but I feel great. When you don’t expect life, or writing, to be the same it was yesterday, you can have fun with the endless changes and challenges.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/two-of-pentacles-on-shifting-ground/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Three of Pentacles: Discipline and Structure</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-three-of-pentacles-discipline-and-structure/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-three-of-pentacles-discipline-and-structure/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tisdale Flannery]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tea with Strangers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Like most writers, I long for that gift of uninterrupted time. An hour is never&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-15419 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Three-Pentacles.jpg" alt="" width="579" height="960" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Three-Pentacles.jpg 579w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Three-Pentacles-181x300.jpg 181w" sizes="(max-width: 579px) 100vw, 579px" /></p>
<p>Like most writers, I long for that gift of uninterrupted time. An hour is never enough. Two hours is acceptable, but not when it comes infrequently, and when I do have two hours to write on a regular basis, I can only think how much I&#8217;d get done if I had a whole day to myself. I am greedy for time alone the way that a diva is greedy for praise &#8212; any bit that comes my way only feeds my insatiable hunger.</p>
<p>Now, I&#8217;m proud of myself; I asked my employers to sponsor a weekend for me, away in a cabin. I used the excuse that I needed to learn more about the Tarot. I couldn&#8217;t satisfactorily interview the characters if I didn&#8217;t understand the cards, right? But in reality, I already know everything I need to know about Tarot. I&#8217;m going to use my time to work on my novel. For hours. I&#8217;m going to write the first draft in a hot blast of inspiration. I&#8217;m going to immerse myself in my story world.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15420 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/logdenLodge-2-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/logdenLodge-2-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/logdenLodge-2-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/logdenLodge-2-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/logdenLodge-2.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>I pull up a long, rocky path to a cabin, far away from everything, and park right on the side, where another car is parked. This is bad; I need to be alone. I leave my bag in the car and look around to the front door. Just as I reach it, a woman comes out, paintbrush in hand. “Ah! Our guest for the weekend,” she says, winking at me. “Don’t mind us. We’ll stay well out of your way.”</p>
<p>Only slightly mollified, I fetch my things and settle in.</p>
<p>An hour later, I’m still staring at the laptop screen. I have five sentences written. It&#8217;s the banging of a hammer outside my window. Way too distracting.</p>
<p>“How long are you going to be here?” I ask the handyman, who has surrounded himself with tools, lumber, and what looks like a small pyramid of PVC piping.</p>
<p>“As long as it takes,” he says, smiling innocently.</p>
<p>I remember my headphones in the car. With them on, the sound of the workers is muffled enough that I can finally concentrate on my work. I read and re-read my five new sentences. Forty-seven words.</p>
<p>They suck, every one of them.</p>
<p>I delete them all, put on the music I brought to remind myself of the story idea, and start again. Four entirely different sentences, thirty-three words, and the writing of them is as smooth as roller skating on a pile of gravel.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the presence of other people. I know it. This was a nasty trick of my employer. But there was a shed out back. Maybe there&#8217;s a spot to write there. I cart my laptop out to it and open the door. It&#8217;s beautiful inside, finished, with lots of light from windows and a desk.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15421 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/writers-shed-231x300.jpg" alt="" width="231" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/writers-shed-231x300.jpg 231w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/writers-shed.jpg 416w" sizes="(max-width: 231px) 100vw, 231px" /></p>
<p>It&#8217;s also occupied.</p>
<p>An architect has plans laid out on the desk. He beams at me. &#8220;Welcome! We&#8217;re so glad you&#8217;re here. You can give us advice on the best uses of our space for writers and artists. Come see.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Thank you,&#8221; I say through my teeth, &#8220;but I desperately need to finish what I&#8217;m working on.&#8221; I tamp down the anger and try to explain myself. &#8220;I thought that was why I came.&#8221; I sound like a whining child.</p>
<p>The architect, however, is gracious. &#8220;Of course,&#8221; he says, rolling up blueprints. &#8220;Come sit. Just let us know when you&#8217;re free.&#8221; He leaves, closing the door behind him. The space is perfect now, the sounds muffled. I have everything I need. Peace. Quiet. I start with a new document. Three sentences later and forty-five minutes later, I realize I’m hungry. Well, of course I’m hungry; I traveled half a day to get here and ate nothing since I woke up.</p>
<p>“You know,” I tell the painter in the kitchen, my mouth full of a sandwich, “I thought I’d be able to dive right into this work, but I’m blocked! How unfair is that?”</p>
<p>She smiles mysteriously. “Perhaps you could help us, and we’ll get out of your hair much more quickly.”</p>
<p>I balance things in my mind. “Okay.”</p>
<p>They put me to work sanding the porch railing. It isn’t easy, at first, but after a bit, I get into a rhythm, and time flies.</p>
<p>“Take a break,” says the woman. “Go write for an hour.”</p>
<p>“Okay,” I say. One hour. In the shed, I pop open the laptop. I don’t have time to worry about quality, just quantity. I crank it out.</p>
<p>We continue this back and forth, working on the cabin, breaks to write and other breaks to eat and rest, for the rest of the day. The next morning, I look at the work I’ve done.</p>
<p>It’s brilliant. It has the touch of genius.</p>
<p>My artistic ego blows up like a pufferfish.</p>
<p>When I tell the painter about this, she grins at me. “Of course,” she says. “The life of an artist requires balance. Can a child learn to play the piano in one hundred hours straight? No, he must do just a little each day, for many days. Can you make a tree grow faster by watering it twenty-four hours every day? No, you must do your part, and then let Nature and the tree do theirs. It is the same with you. How badly you all want this all-or-nothing, unlimited immersion in your writing. But you are a whole person, an integral part of a community, and it’s that wholeness and cooperation that feed your art. You must balance writing with taking care of all of your needs, and others as well.”</p>
<p>“But how? How can I do that, when others&#8217; needs are always getting top priority?”</p>
<p>“With discipline. You give them time, but limit it, and when it is time to write, they will have to wait for you. They need you to be a writer as much as you need to be a part of them. We are many things to many people, and it’s good that we are, for if we were allowed to focus all of our energy in just one direction, the paucity of inspiration would starve our creations.”</p>
<p>When the workers leave, they leave behind a Tarot card on the table. The resemblance is plain. These workers were the three in the Three of Pentacles — the architect, the builder, the painter. Once again, my employers have shown me that they know exactly what I need, often better than I do. And what I needed to learn this weekend was the message of the Three of Pentacles: real progress happens incrementally, in small steps each day, achieved through structure and discipline, teamwork and balance.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-three-of-pentacles-discipline-and-structure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Ace of Swords: The Nature of Truth</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-ace-of-swords-the-nature-of-truth/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-ace-of-swords-the-nature-of-truth/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tisdale Flannery]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tea with Strangers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In this monumental task I’ve undertaken, of interviewing the characters who populate my deck of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-15102 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Ace-Swords.jpg" alt="" width="579" height="960" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Ace-Swords.jpg 579w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Ace-Swords-181x300.jpg 181w" sizes="(max-width: 579px) 100vw, 579px" /></p>
<p>In this monumental task I’ve undertaken, of interviewing the characters who populate my deck of Tarot, I haven&#8217;t yet had to come to the administration building. I show up at Headquarters. It’s a bright day, with a light breeze; I almost hate to go indoors, into the cool marble lobby of the building.</p>
<p>“Top floor,” says the neatly coifed receptionist, handing me an elevator key and pointing to the restricted-use penthouse elevator.</p>
<p>A thrill of excitement makes my breath catch. From the street outside, you can see the penthouse area &#8212; a two-story expanse of glass and balcony, hiding untold mysteries.</p>
<p>The elevator ride is slow and smooth and uninterrupted. When the doors open, they reveal a glassed-in garden. Soft padded benches and water fountains peek out from between tall potted trees and mounds of layered planters. Long vines hang from ironwork or climb wooden lattices. No other human is there, but the sparrows that have found their way inside fill the space with soft fluttering. Butterflies are ubiquitous. A hive of bees is protected in one corner. After walking the perimeter of the garden, I decide to settle in on one of the padded benches and wait. Far away, far below, the sounds of the street reach the garden only faintly: the call of one friend to another, a hawker of Italian ice, an organ grinder, the wings of pigeons as they roost in the corbels outside.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15103 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/arboretum-193x300.jpg" alt="" width="193" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/arboretum-193x300.jpg 193w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/arboretum.jpg 406w" sizes="(max-width: 193px) 100vw, 193px" /></p>
<p>The sunlight drops through the leaves of ficus and cherry.</p>
<p>Above the glass roof, a shape slowly manifests. The clouds tease the outline, obscuring, then dissipating. The light shines from within it. The shape is as long as the roof itself, overwhelmingly vast and yet as light and insubstantial as the clouds around it. Long, sharp, platinum gray, with a gilded handle, it is a Sword hanging over me. I am dreaming, now, lucidly dreaming. Consciously, I know that this is why I am here — to hear the words of the Ace of Swords.</p>
<p>The words come not audibly but as words in my thoughts:  genderless, deep, and smooth.</p>
<p><em>THEY SAY that words cannot capture the Truth, that the Truth lives, but words are dead, no more than cages for clouds. I say this: the words carry their own clouds of meaning. Words, set free into the world, have life of their own, as they animate the associations and connotations that vary from reader to reader. Commit yourself to finding exactly the right word, every time. The word shapes the truth as others will experience it. Every word carries the weight of history. Every word carves its mark into the future. Words echo with the stories of those who have used them before; if the nebulous idea of a philosopher cannot be fully captured in a word, the idea does not exist; the word matters more than its referent.</em></p>
<p><em>That is why you, writer, must respect the responsibility of your pen. You lay down words that will be read and re-read, repeated, quoted; each word helps to shape human thought. Know this power in your hand. Draft freely, but edit relentlessly; I am the Truth, and I am not a toy, but a sharp and powerful sword with which to cut through ignorance and lies. I am the power of the Word.<br />
</em></p>
<p>When the image fades, I fall into another dream, this one of a whirlpool in the ocean; an ancient Charybdis, a vortex with no bottom. I am spinning, spinning, and above my head I see an oar held out against the sky. I reach up to grab it, but it is sharp and cuts my fingers; it is no longer an oar, but a sharp and bloody sword. Still, I&#8217;ll choose the pain in my hand over being sucked into the black hole of the whirlpool. The sword lifts, hauling me up out of the water and onto dry land. A pirate stands there, grinning, with blackened teeth and smoke in his hair. For one terrified moment, I think he has been waiting to kill me. Instead, he slaps me on the shoulder, congratulatory. &#8220;Good choice,&#8221; he says.</p>
<p>I wake up.</p>
<p>Searching for truth in words is dangerous. Religious texts promise it, self-help books claim to have succeeded, even textbooks work on the assumption that they can deliver, at least, the truth of facts. Still, we pour out more words, questioning, clarifying, correcting. It seems we can never quite reach the truth with these words. And yet, we can appreciate the ephemeral beauty of their meanings, like our own skin, shed and replaced in total every seven years. I am not the same collection of cells that I was when I last saw my childhood friend, and yet she knows me instantly.</p>
<p>These and other thoughts roll through my mind as I rise up out of the dream. Awake now in the rooftop garden, I can see that the sun has crossed the sky. The elevator doors stand open, waiting for me. The birds have quieted. I must go. This was the interview I was supposed to have, and while I don’t fully understand all that happened, I will go back to my office and write it just as I experienced it; the truth of these things come not from my cogitating and analyzing, but from recording, faithfully, every word of the story.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-ace-of-swords-the-nature-of-truth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Five of Pentacles:  The Gift of Rejection</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-five-of-pentacles-the-gift-of-rejection/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-five-of-pentacles-the-gift-of-rejection/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tisdale Flannery]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tea with Strangers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Inspired by the Tarot Illuminati deck, by Erik C. Dunne, and informed by its companion&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-14792 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Five-Pentacles.jpg" alt="" width="579" height="960" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Five-Pentacles.jpg 579w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Five-Pentacles-181x300.jpg 181w" sizes="(max-width: 579px) 100vw, 579px" /></p>
<p><em>Inspired by the <a href="http://www.aeclectic.net/tarot/cards/illuminati/">Tarot Illuminati deck</a>, by Erik C. Dunne, and informed by its companion book, written by <a href="https://www.llewellyn.com/author.php?author_id=4920">Kim Huggens</a>. </em></p>
<p>The bitter cold works its way in through my coat and scarf, and the sharpness in the air hurts my lungs with every breath. Night has fallen, and the frosty air carries the sounds of bells. I&#8217;m on my way to interview the character in the Five of Pentacles, and I&#8217;ve been looking forward to this for months. I needed the affirmation of acceptance. The reviews of my latest novel were dreadful, the novel I&#8217;m trying to sell right now is not getting any interest at all, and I have been feeling like a failure. The Temple in the Woods is one of the most sought-after destinations in the world. Only a lucky few ever get to visit. Now, with my feet wet and my teeth chattering, I can only think about how good it will feel to warm my hands on one of the temple’s famous cups of lamb broth.</p>
<p>A wooden door on the far side of the temple is the only entrance. I knock, and it opens wide, showing a monk in a silver robe, his face hidden by a heavy hood.</p>
<p>“Good evening,” I stammer. “I have an appointment&#8230;” I squint to check the name on the card.</p>
<p>But the monk nods and beckons me inside. Once the door closes, he throws back the hood. He&#8217;s a young man; he must have done things right from the start, to be living here already. &#8220;Welcome,&#8221; he says, and beams. The golden light reflects from mirrors and crystals everywhere. The temple must house thousands of candles. I have to force my mouth to close against the awe.</p>
<p>“I will fetch you a cup of our broth,” he says, “and then we can talk.”</p>
<p>&#8220;Thank you, Brother Long.”</p>
<p>He turns back around. &#8220;Brother Long?&#8221;</p>
<p>That was the name they gave me. &#8220;You&#8217;re not him?&#8221;</p>
<p>The hood goes back up. He jerks open the front door, gesturing for me to leave.</p>
<p>“But the interview,” I begin.</p>
<p>“He is not here.” His voice is now harsh. &#8220;Brother Long was an impostor.” He pushes my shoulder so that I am forced out of the door.</p>
<p>My feet slide on the thin layer of snow over stone. I have to grab the icy rail. The monk slams the door closed. The lock snaps. The bells continue, playing the same melody that drew me here.</p>
<p>Was I supposed to interview this guy, instead? Does the role change? I sit on the steps, and soon the cold and wet seep through my jeans.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14886 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/brith-300x209.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="209" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/brith-300x209.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/brith-768x536.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/brith-1024x714.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/brith.jpg 1815w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>A shadow moves in the woods, through the thickening snowfall. It is him, the picture they showed me. The old man.</p>
<p>“Wait!” I’m out of breath when I catch up to him. &#8220;Brother Long?&#8221;</p>
<p>He turns to smile at me.</p>
<p>“What happened?” I ask.</p>
<p>“Come,” he says, his voice a raspy croak. “Walk with me, and I will tell you.”</p>
<p>So we make our way through the snow, farther and farther away from the warmth and light and holiness of the temple. “Do you know what that temple is?” he asks. “It is the home of Conventional Success. It really is a delightful place, warm and comfortable and all the hot broth you could ever dream of.”</p>
<p>My teeth chatter. “And you were kicked out?”</p>
<p>He nods, and grins.</p>
<p>“But you seem happy about that.”</p>
<p>He takes my arm and guides me forward. “Let me tell you a <a href="http://www.read.gov/aesop/005.html">story</a>. Once, a fox saw a bunch of luscious grapes hanging from a branch, just out of reach. <em>I want them</em>, he thought. <em>I must have them.</em> He leaped. He snapped his jaws. He came down with nothing but a chipped tooth.” The old man shakes his head sadly. “A crow saw this, and came to taunt the fox. <em>Mmm, so tasty</em>, said the wicked crow. <em>Juicy, sweet. I have a book I can sell you that will teach you how to reach the grapes.</em> The fox, eager and hungry, bought the book and read it that very night. The next day, he followed the instructions to the letter. He ran, he closed his eyes, he leaped and snapped — and still, came away with nothing.”</p>
<p>We’re far enough away from the temple that the only light comes from the moon. The old man doesn’t slow down.</p>
<p>“The poor fox! He was depressed. He sat on the ground with his head hung low, like this.&#8221; He shows me the face of a despondent fox. &#8220;A squirrel saw him and scampered down to sit next to the fox. <em>My cousin</em>, said the squirrel,<em> teaches a class on how to reach the grapes. You really must take it. It</em><em>’s the only way to taste them.</em></p>
<p>“So, with great hope, the fox signed up for the class, spending money he didn’t have, because of course he believed in himself and in his ability to reach the grapes. He took the course, he did all the exercises, and when he was ready, he faced that grapevine once again. He leaped, he snapped, and bit his own tongue so hard that the blood filled his mouth. The fox then said some words I won’t repeat. He retreated into the woods and thought a while. Then he called up the crow and the squirrel. <em>I need more help,</em> he said. <em>Come teach me what you know, and you will never have a better pupil than I.</em> Eager for the fox’s money, the crow and the squirrel followed him into the shadows of the woods.”</p>
<p>He stops talking. The trees thin, and the moonlight surrounds us.</p>
<p>“Is that the end?”</p>
<p>“The end of what?”</p>
<p>“What happened to the crow and the squirrel?”</p>
<p>“Well, the fox ate them, of course. Foxes don’t eat grapes. Grapes are toxic to canines.”</p>
<p>He turns a corner in the path, and brightens. “Ah, here we are.”</p>
<p>We have reached a cave with a roaring fire inside. A pot on a hook over the fire has something bubbling in it, and a heavenly smell fills the air. The old man nods to several others who sit around the cave walls, cups of soup steaming in their hands. “This is our temple,” he says to me, handing me a cup. “We built it ourselves, so no one can kick us out. This is our broth. It isn’t lamb, but it’s made with roots and beans that we can always grow more of. And it’s truly satisfying.” I sit back against the cave wall and enjoy myself with this humble company.</p>
<p>“You see,” says the old man, “if you define success as something based entirely on your actions and yours alone, then you will always have the power to succeed.” He pats my arm. “About that novel you are querying, know this: Success is that you have finished it, and done all you can to get it out into the world. Anyone else’s reaction is, whether professional or reviewer, immaterial. Further, there is no way to know this until you have faced failure. This is the gift of failure, whenever it comes: freedom from emotional dependence on the actions of anyone but ourselves.”</p>
<p>An hour later, the monk who was rude to me in the temple shows up. He is shivering and looks worried.</p>
<p>“What happened, friend?” asks the old man. “Did they kick you out?”</p>
<p>The young man nods.</p>
<p>“Popularity rarely lasts forever,” says the old man. “Sooner or later, you’ll fail, you’ll flop, you’ll sell below expectations. Some critic will say things about you that shatter your reputation, and they’ll kick you out of the temple. But this is a good thing! Welcome! Now you can sit with us and define your own success.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-five-of-pentacles-the-gift-of-rejection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Six of Cups:  Art Is Play</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-six-of-cups-art-is-play/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-six-of-cups-art-is-play/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tisdale Flannery]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tea with Strangers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Inspired by the Tarot Illuminati deck, by Erik C. Dunne, and informed by its companion&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Inspired by the <a href="http://www.aeclectic.net/tarot/cards/illuminati/">Tarot Illuminati deck</a>, by Erik C. Dunne, and informed by its companion book, written by <a href="https://www.llewellyn.com/author.php?author_id=4920">Kim Huggens</a>. </em></p>
<p>For this interview, my employers told me the subject would come to me at home. <em>Great</em>, I thought. <em>My house is a disaster.</em> I spent the morning cleaning. I wiped the floor behind the toilet, I used some vinegar on the glass of the front door, I used the extension on the vacuum to suck all the cobwebs out of the corner, causing the little cellar spiders to curse my faithlessness and dash off elsewhere. I put some bread in the machine, mostly for the good smell, and I sat down to wait.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14597 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/nathan-dumlao-505059-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/nathan-dumlao-505059-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/nathan-dumlao-505059-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/nathan-dumlao-505059-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Now, with my tea on the kitchen table in front of me, I study the card. The Six of Cups: two children playing in a lovely bower, a fountain in the foreground, flowers everywhere. An older man, serious, watches them from the door. If my back yard looked like that, instead of bare patches of dirt and a rusted swing set, I’d want to play all day, but we can’t afford it right now. That’s why I’m doing these interviews: to get paid, so I can create beauty at home.</p>
<p>So I work. I make a list of all of the details I see in the card: hummingbird, sunlight, butterfly.</p>
<p>“That looks like our yard.”</p>
<p>I was so deep in concentration that I didn’t hear my daughter enter the kitchen. A familiar riff of parental guilt plays in my mind; I’ve given her exactly zero attention this morning. “It looks like our yard? Really?”</p>
<p>“Yes. Let me show you.” She takes my hand.</p>
<p>The problem is that the subjects for the interview should be here any minute. “Tell you what. I’ll come out and see it as soon as my interview is done. We’ll have all afternoon then. Go on, make sure it stays like that, and I’ll come out as soon as I can.”</p>
<p>I’m looking at my list, going over it, trying to pay attention to the words on my list and picture on the card instead of the sound of my daughter’s voice echoing in my head. How does she see this in our yard? Maybe I would know, if I paid some attention to her. I leave my tea on the table, and leave the back door open so I can hear the doorbell.</p>
<p>“Hey.” I find her sitting in the dirt, out in the sunlight. “How does our yard look like that?”</p>
<p>She dances in a circle around the well. “Here!” Her hand brushes the rough stone-pocked concrete. A tiered fountain appears, with the melodic percussion of falling water. “Here!” She waves her hands at the chain link fence, a vestige of the house’s previous owners. The morning glory vines that I can’t seem to ever get rid of unfurl and climb up and through the interstices, filling them with flowers of every hue. She waves her hand at the swing set. It becomes a bower, with benches for us to sit and play, shaded gently by wisteria, framing a window that seems to open to a magical world beyond instead of the alley behind my house.</p>
<p>My yard has transformed. No matter how much I wipe my eyes and refocus, the gorgeous garden from the Six of Cups is here. The air itself is a sweet elixir in my lungs.</p>
<p>I kneel beside my daughter. “How did you do this?”</p>
<p>“It’s easy, Mommy,” she says. “I just play.”</p>
<p>I finally get it: she is my subject, the one I am to interview. She is the child in the Six of Cups. I am the stern adult, watching from the doorway.</p>
<p>Natalie Babbitt, in the reader’s guide at the end of my copy of <a href="https://www.powells.com/book/tuck-everlasting-9781250059291?partnerid=33241"><em>Tuck Everlasting</em></a>, said: <em>Writing doesn’t matter</em>. Those words have haunted me ever since I read them. There are several ways to <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14598 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/valentina-locatelli-130318-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/valentina-locatelli-130318-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/valentina-locatelli-130318-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/valentina-locatelli-130318-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />read that, and I’m not sure what her intention was; she could have meant that it does not dig wells or heal the sick, which is true. Writing won’t physically clean the environment or stop bullets. Yet someone’s written word can inspire a reader to <a href="https://www.charitywater.org/thirst">spend their life digging wells</a>, or <a href="https://www.brainpickings.org/2014/11/24/anne-lamott-small-victories-grief/">comfort a loved one on their deathbed</a>; it can convince an oil company to <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/christopherhelman/2017/12/04/why-an-oil-company-plans-to-build-californias-biggest-solar-energy-project/#1b0cb2ab6c84">transition toward greener energy</a>, and give a soldier <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/29/books/review/sebastian-jungers-tribe.html">hope and understanding</a>. In this way, writing does change the world. That’s why I choose to believe that <em>Writing doesn’t matter</em>, instead of being dismissive of the product, encourages the paradoxical approach artists must take to the act of creation.</p>
<p>If we think, <em>My writing is important; I have to be an adult, to be serious, to get it done</em>, then the Muse leaves us as quickly as a butterfly we’ve chased. But if we let go and play, the beauty arrives, surprises us, creates magical worlds out of bare dirt and rust. Art is play, and in our need for approval, for perfection, for income, we writers often forget how to play. Need stifles art, as much as the presence of your overbearing adult figure stifles play. Give that inner adult something else to do. Give him something else to pin his all-important self-esteem on. It has to not matter. You have to not need it. Open your document and start typing, or grab your notebook and pen, and start imagining, sailing away from all self-criticism like a stolen cutter with the furious gendarmes waving helplessly ashore.</p>
<p>Let the words play and get it all entirely wrong. They know what they’re doing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-six-of-cups-art-is-play/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Eight of Wands &#8211; Fire in the Belly</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-eight-of-wands-fire-in-the-belly-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tisdale Flannery]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 11:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tea with Strangers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10900</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The roaring wind whips my hair through the open window of the car. We&#8217;re driving&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Eight-Wands.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10902 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/Eight-Wands-181x300.jpg" alt="" width="181" height="300" /></a>The roaring wind whips my hair through the open window of the car. We&#8217;re driving through mountain peaks, somewhere in the land between states, that no-man’s land that defies borders. The people who live here use stilts to prop up ancient porches and mountain stone to rebuild their chimneys. They tend to refuse the authority of a state; tax them and they’re likely to die for the fourth time, arrest them only to find they never had an identity to begin with. Such are mountain people.</p>
<p>A question rolls around in my mind as we jolt up the rutted road. <em>How am I supposed to interview eight wands?</em></p>
<p>“How am I supposed to interview eight wands?” I shout to my doppelganger.</p>
<p>She gives me that beatific smile that means she has absolutely no clue what I just said. I grunt and look out the window to the peaks around us in the clear bright sun.</p>
<p>Suddenly the car stops, and I see eight beautiful golden wands, as tall as myself, topped by elaborate finials twisting around in whorls. But they&#8217;re stuck in the narrow strip of grass beside the road, not flying through the air, the way they&#8217;re supposed to be. Is the image on the card wrong?</p>
<p>My doppelganger gets out of the car, gets something from the trunk, and marches over to the wands. I can&#8217;t quite tell what she&#8217;s holding, but it&#8217;s taller than she is. She pulls a wand out of the ground and lifts it, holds it across the thing in her hand. What she&#8217;s holding is a large bow. She draws back the string. If she lets go, that golden wand is going to go over the cliff and be lost forever. I leap from the car.</p>
<p>I grab her arm. “You can’t do that.”</p>
<p>She looks at me and grins. <em>Twing.</em> The wand soars. Seven left.</p>
<p>“Stop it! We can’t do this. We’re here on business, and those don’t belong to us.”</p>
<p>“<em>We</em><em>’re here on business</em>,” she says, mocking me with a fake-serious voice. She pulls another wand out of the ground.</p>
<p>“You <em>spoke</em>?” I’ve never heard her voice before. “You’re not supposed to speak.”</p>
<p>“<em>You</em><em>’re not supposed to speak.</em>” She is mocking me again. She notches the second wand and draws back the string.</p>
<p>“Stop it!”</p>
<p>She lets the second wand fly.</p>
<p>“What’s wrong with you? Do you want to quit working with me? You can quit. You don’t have to wreck my assignment first.”</p>
<p>She lowers the bow and turns to me. “What happened to the short story you started, about a girl eaten by a bear?”<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/kalen-emsley-98264-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12749 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/kalen-emsley-98264-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>I shook my head. “You know that couldn’t work. It had a juvenile hero, and a very dark and graphic tone. It didn’t have an audience.”</p>
<p>Before I can stop her, she has the third wand in her bow.</p>
<p>“You can’t write heroes younger than your audience!”</p>
<p>She lets the string loose, and the wand whistles upward. Before I can say a word, she faces me again. “How about the chapter in your novel you’re stuck on?”</p>
<p>“The one I wanted to write was unnecessary to the plot. It didn’t move the story forward at all, so it didn’t belong.”</p>
<p>A fourth wand flies.</p>
<p>“What are you trying to do?” I demand.</p>
<p>“You loved that idea. It sang for you. Why leave it out?”</p>
<p>“Because you can’t waste space,” I say.</p>
<p>With the word ‘can’t’, she has the fifth wand drawn. “You’ve been complaining about a lack of inspiration lately,” she muses. “You say you’re stuck, you can’t move forward, everything feels like a slog and a chore. But every time something inspires you, you hold back. You turn away from it. You don’t give it everything.”</p>
<p>She is right, of course. I&#8217;d been stuck, wondering why I even keep writing. Sometimes your well is dry, and the only thing that keeps you going is your commitment to finish the damn thing.</p>
<p>The fifth wand flies. She draws the sixth, and speaks to me over her shoulder.</p>
<p>“When an airplane takes off, that is a miracle. Many tons of metal rise into the air. What happens if the pilot doubts? If, in fear, he gives the takeoff anything less than full speed, if he feels that maybe he shouldn’t do this, and he hits the brakes a little on the runway, does the plane leave the ground?” The sixth wand flies. She lowers the bow to face me. “No, it does not. This is our inner selves. If we doubt, we are hitting those brakes, and the airplane of our creativity cannot take off. It can&#8217;t leave the ground.” She pulls the seventh wand from the dirt.</p>
<p>“Please,” I say, holding on to her hand with the wand. “I understand, but all of these rules are in place to make us better writers.”</p>
<p>“Let go,” she whispers to me now. “Give yourself completely to whatever whim takes you.”</p>
<p>The seventh wand soars.</p>
<p>“There is magic in passion,” she says, handing me the bow. She is back to her lighthearted self. “Rules make better writers, sure. But that’s for after creation. When inspiration comes, throw yourself into its arms. Believe in your dreams. Fly.&#8221;</p>
<p>I pull the last wand from the ground. I notch it, know I&#8217;m doing the right thing, and let go.</p>
<p>I look up to the cloudless sky. The eight wands hang there, exactly as they are pictured in every Eight of Wands in every Tarot deck I have ever seen. Shining gold, with the backdrop of endless mountain peaks beyond them, the crying eagles in their company, the clouds that pass over and through them: eight long wands, powerful, beautiful, irresistible. Eight golden wands, perfectly parallel to each other, soaring. The sunlight is full on them, and full on the trees below and far below and in the distance. The steep slopes around are full of life. The blue, crystal water is full of life. The wands themselves are full of life as well, driven by the pure urge to express the will upon creation. The higher the mountains they must cross, the better. The bigger the challenge, the greater the glory. The beauty is fierce and the power is great and my soul sings for what I have done.</p>
<p>“Things aren’t supposed to stop mid-air,” I whisper.</p>
<p>“No,” says my doppelganger, sighing with a knowing delight. “They’re not.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
