<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Mythic Memoir &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/mythic-memoir/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 23:52:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Safety in Half-Truths</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/safety-in-half-truths/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elisabeth Sharp McKetta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 18:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mythic Memoir]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every memoir writer knows that if and when our story gets read, the reliability of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every memoir writer knows that if and when our story gets read, the reliability of our truths will be called into question—be it by family members who contest our version, or by engaged and disbelieving readers. But the truth of any story is always the truth of the writer. By using fairy tales, this fiction-nature is held up openly, showed without shame, and illustrated to be a simple baseline for what will turn out to be, if nothing else, a good story.</p>
<p>In other words, writing a life story with the constructs of fairy tales is a way to take refuge in the language that comforts us. And if this is the case, then retelling fairy tales is by definition a hopeful practice. In <em>From the Beast to the Blonde</em> (1994), Marina Warner observes, “The genre is characterized by ‘heroic optimism,’ as if to say, ‘one day, we might be happy, even if it won’t last’.”</p>
<p>All traditional fairy tales stories require both the listener and the teller to be part of the story: in written fairy tales this translates into the writer and the reader, and each reader becomes a possible re-writer in this cycle, using the truths of his or her life and circumstances to flavor the adaptation. For example, many cultures have their own version of Little Red Riding Hood, each made up of its own historical, culinary, psychological and linguistic details. In this way, all fairy tales are half-true.</p>
<p>Try this: Rewrite a fairy tale that you love, changing the generic details into your specific life’s details, adapting the stock characters into the characters from your life.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding our own solutions through Fairy Tales</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/finding-our-own-solutions-through-fairy-tales/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elisabeth Sharp McKetta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 18:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mythic Memoir]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Almost all critics of fairy tales observe the ways in which children and adults can&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Almost all critics of fairy tales observe the ways in which children and adults can fit themselves into these tales to better make sense of their lives. Much of this criticism is indebted to Bruno Bettelheim, who in turn is indebted to Carl Jung and Sigmund Freud. Bettelheim’s canonical work, the <em>Uses of Enchantment</em> (1976), takes as its premise the following idea: “The fairy tale is therapeutic because the patient finds his <em>own</em> solutions, through contemplating what the story seems to imply about him and his inner conflicts at this moment in his life … the fairy tales’ concern is not useful information about the external world, but the inner process taking place in an individual.”</p>
<p>But Bettelheim was not the first writer to come to this conclusion. In his 1936 essay “The Storyteller,” Walter Benjamin observed, “The fairy tale, which to this day is the first tutor of children because it was once the first tutor of mankind, secretly lives on in the story. The first true storyteller is, and will continue to be, the teller of fairy tales. Whenever good counsel was at a premium, the fairy tales had it, and where the need was the greatest, its aid was nearest” (102). In other words, fairy tales and myths guide us through natural processes and natural feelings, showing at once how weird and normal they are – and they allow us to solve our own dilemmas through the experience of the heroes and heroines.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Try this: Look back on a point in your life when you were lost in some way. Free-write a fairy tale to serve as a guide to that earlier version of yourself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mythic Memoir &#8211; October 2014</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/mythic-memoir-october-2014/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/mythic-memoir-october-2014/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elisabeth Sharp McKetta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 17:11:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mythic Memoir]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The problem with autobiography is that it is asymptotic: the writer may come as close&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The problem with autobiography is that it is asymptotic: the writer may come as close as possible to telling a complete story, but the truth itself is untouchable simply because the living writer knows neither the end, nor the themes that will become apparent once the end has transpired. One person’s full autobiography may only be finished by somebody else.</p>
<p>All autobiography struggles with the fact that as time moves, the past self constantly slides away from the present self. One way of attempting to close this gap between the actual life and the telling is to write conversion narratives in which the writer tells the complete story of a past self (now “dead”) from which the present self has emerged. Another solution is to write a memoir of a highly specific time in one’s life, a possibly therapeutic exercise. Veiled autobiographies take many forms, but one of the most extreme involves the employment of fairy tales—an ultimate form of “unreal” fiction.</p>
<p>Fairy tales, in contrast to autobiography, always have an ending. Whether that ending is happy or merely didactic varies with the tale, but the ending allows an illusion of rest after the tale has finished, in contrast to the personal narrative which can never be complete until the “I” dies. Therefore fairy tales offer microcosms of completion, tidy endings for unfinished lives. Every one of us lives a life that takes place in cycles of myth and fairy tale, with heroes and heroines setting forth into danger and returning home with triumph or wisdom.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Try this:</strong> Free-write the final chapter in the autobiography of your life so far. Then take it one step further by adding a made-up ending from a myth or fairy tale that interests you. In other words, tell your story as it <em>should</em> end.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/mythic-memoir-october-2014/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Myth as Container</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/myth-as-container/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elisabeth Sharp McKetta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 15:27:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mythic Memoir]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For so many writers of life stories, the container is the hardest part. Where to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For so many writers of life stories, the container is the hardest part. Where to start? Where to end? Our lives are too big, if they are any good, to be contained in a box of a story. Furthermore, if we are alive to tell it, we can assume that the lives are still going – and how to you solve a problem like that? How do you catch a cloud and pin it down?</p>
<p>There is a safety in form, a reason why stores like The Container Store exist and flourish, even while more useful stores quickly fail. Our lives are big and getting bigger. Seeking containers for our experiences and the fragments of our lives is a way to make sense of our days and our stories—to make them small enough to understand, share, and process. Brenda Miller observed, “For some writers, especially beginning writers, the conscious use of form can sometimes be the only way certain kinds of truths can be approached at all.”</p>
<p>Myth is a container. Using the backbone of myth and fairy tales is an intuitive way to contain a story. Theme is one way. Decade is another. Place, too: chapter by chapter, each one a different city or country. Hemingway planned to write a book about each thing he knew a lot about. But we are not Hemingway. We are our own people writing about our own lives. And memoir writing is like personhood: for each memoir, there can be only one memoirist who could have written it.</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Try this</strong>: Return to an earlier piece of free-writing and underline the parts that pop out or interest you. Then look at your list of myths (from last month). Choose a myth as a writing prompt to continue the story you have begun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Freewriting</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/august-mythic-memoir-freewriting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elisabeth Sharp McKetta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 16:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mythic Memoir]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[But, you might ask: how to begin? Sure, these ideas on wiring blocks of writing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>But, you might ask: how to begin? Sure, these ideas on wiring blocks of writing into mythic structures is nice and all, but how to get those blocks of writing out on the chopping table in the first place?</p>
<p>My best answer is the free-write. Use it as the building block for all stories, real or imagined. All you need is a timer and a way to write: computer, pen and paper, or old-school typewriter. Find a writing prompt (if you wish, visit <a href="elisabethsharpmcketta.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">elisabethsharpmcketta.com</a> for a year’s worth of daily prompts!) Set the timer for ten minutes. Then write like mad.</p>
<p>Write freely without thinking about final drafts, genres, or editing. Write a lot before going back to read what you’ve written, for it will feel raw. It is raw. You just began writing it ten minutes ago and finished it now. People sometimes talk about writing and birth as related practices, and indeed I often feel myself in what feels like a midwife’s role when working with an author on a book.</p>
<p>The way a baby looks when it is born requires clean up: clamping the cord, wiping away blood, perhaps giving it some oxygen, before it becomes a good looking kid. Writing is the same way. There are many stages of clean-up, and our job as writers is to write first, and then step back and sort through the raw mess and find parts that can be grown, cultivated, polished. Our job is not to look at it and say, “Yuck! It’s all pink and it can’t open its eyes yet.” Our job is to say, “Look. It’s perfect. It’s alive. It has legs. It will grow.”</p>
<p>Once you have a file full of compost—five pages, ten, twenty—it is time to begin shaping it into myth.</p>
<p>Try this: Using your birth-love-death free-write from last month (or any life story you choose), mark the beginning, middle, and end. Step back and ask: what myth or fairy tale shares its themes? Note similarities; list creative links.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beginning with the Mythic Cycle</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/beginning-with-the-mythic-cycle/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elisabeth Sharp McKetta]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 16:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mythic Memoir]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2098</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Writers come to my studio, my workshops, my website, with the same question: How do&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Writers come to my studio, my workshops, my website, with the same question: <i>How do I do it? How to I write my life to make it matter</i>? What I endeavor in this monthly blog is to give my version of an answer.</p>
<p>I am a writer of fiction, nonfiction, and poetry, and what I know best is structure. My doctorate and my teaching have focused on memoir and personal writing and essay, and what I <i>love</i> most is voice. This blog combines what I know of structure and voice, lighting a path for memoir writers to combine mythic structures with their own true voice—instructions to write their life and make it matter. The reason myth applies to memoir is because both are hero’s or heroine’s journeys, made up of the only three stories that truly matter: birth, love, and death. These are the three turning points when we open ourselves most vulnerably to growth and change. We all experience all three in some form. In essence, this triangle makes a human life.<i> </i></p>
<p><i>Birth</i>: we set out, new, young, raw, uncertain. We enter a woods, maybe of our own choosing, maybe not. We meet allies, enemies, challenges. We fall in love.</p>
<p><i>Love</i>: love can be anything we move toward, a person, a passion, a metaphor for freedom. Whatever our love is, we grasp toward it—we try to catch it—we seek it, lose it, seek again. Once we have it (if we are so lucky!), we are secure from all things except death.</p>
<p><i>Death</i>: the end of things. We suffer many deaths in our life, each time something or someone we love vanishes, each time an era ends.</p>
<p>Between our own physical birth and death, this cycle will repeat itself over and over. This is the mythic cycle, too. A hero or heroine sets out after something beloved and, if he or she is lucky, holds onto it until the end.</p>
<p>In this way, every life contains many myths, many fairy tales.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Try this</span>: Write about a birth-love-death cycle in your own life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
