<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Foggy Mornings &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/foggy-mornings/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 02:21:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Gifts for the New Year</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/gifts-for-the-new-year/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 11:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foggy Mornings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just a few things I will carry into the new year: 1. A cozy sweater&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><i>Just a few things I will carry into the new year:</i></p>
<p class="p1">1. A cozy sweater or two.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The nights will be long in the new year, and the snows will come. I need a good sweater for the nights when the heat just isn’t enough.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">2. Cozy socks.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">See above.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">3. A good bottle of port.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">For the nights when I have just finished a story, or have something to celebrate. I anticipate there being a few of these nights along the way.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">4. My personal collection of houseplants.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">I have been nurturing them for years. They live on the windowsills of my apartment, and though sometimes I forget to water them for a week or two, I have not killed one in months. They live happily on, my silent green companions. They make me feel less alone in my apartment, like a touch of nature has made its way in.</p>
<p class="p1">4a. My lemon tree.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26570 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/artur-aldyrkhanov-DgMqz4UdaDo-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="218" height="327" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/artur-aldyrkhanov-DgMqz4UdaDo-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/artur-aldyrkhanov-DgMqz4UdaDo-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/artur-aldyrkhanov-DgMqz4UdaDo-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/artur-aldyrkhanov-DgMqz4UdaDo-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/artur-aldyrkhanov-DgMqz4UdaDo-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/artur-aldyrkhanov-DgMqz4UdaDo-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 218px) 100vw, 218px" /></span></p>
<p class="p1">Six years ago I bought a little potted lemon tree from a garden center. It was a charming thing, with green leaves and no fruit. Over the years, I have kept it in windows and on balconies. It has shed its leaves and grown new ones. I has been repotted twice. Its flowers smell of the sweetest perfume in the world, far too saccharine to wear. I have been tending to my lemon tree for six years. One day I will have a house of my own, and I will plant the lemon tree there, where it can send roots deep and grow tall, and give me lots and lots of lemons to eat.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">5. New pillows for the writing chair.</p>
<p class="p1">To get cozy with.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">6. Too many notebooks.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">I always thought that one day, maybe, I would become the kind of person who writes my drafts in longhand. I imagined my writing unspooling across the page, languid and lovely. But I have not yet become that kind of person. I am beginning to suspect that I never will.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> I may have to donate the notebooks.</span></p>
<p class="p1">7. A license to write in any way I please.</p>
<p class="p1">Last year, I nearly stopped writing altogether. This year, I have started the writing habit again, and I wrote more than I have in years. Next year, I will write again, and I will write more. I will write beautifully, and poorly, and generally any damn way I please.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">8. Permission to take a break.</p>
<p class="p1">I will take off. From writing and from work. I will rest, and pause, and sleep, and care for myself. I will not push myself to my limits again.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">9. The view of the sunset.</p>
<p class="p1">I live on the third floor of an old house, the tallest building in town. An old beech tree grows beside the house and I look out through its branches toward the sunset. The sky glows saffron and fuchsia. There are no words to capture the luminous light that flares before everything begins to darken again, turn to grey and then to black. That is my cue to sit down and start writing.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26571 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tim-mossholder-MckU2A7uz0I-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="446" height="297" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tim-mossholder-MckU2A7uz0I-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tim-mossholder-MckU2A7uz0I-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tim-mossholder-MckU2A7uz0I-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tim-mossholder-MckU2A7uz0I-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/tim-mossholder-MckU2A7uz0I-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 446px) 100vw, 446px" /></p>
<p class="p1">10. A few new dreams.</p>
<p class="p1">I dream of romance, and adventure, and interesting villains. I dream of the kinds of stories that I have not yet seen written. I dream of my own words on the page, on your page, published and shared so that everyone can read.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In the morning, I whisper my dreams aloud to myself, to make them become real.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>winter book project</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/winter-book-project/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foggy Mornings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[November is a notoriously hungry month, isn’t it?  Perhaps it is because this is the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">November is a notoriously hungry month, isn’t it?<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Perhaps it is because this is the month when it feels like the greater part of the world is being swallowed by the darkness. A great mouth opens up, Fenrir devouring the sun, and swallows the world piece by piece. Each day we lose a little bit more of the light, until the darkness is deep and cold. This is the dark season coming, the long winter.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">But the coming of darkness is not always a bad thing.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">As the world is being swallowed, we celebrate by swallowing the world in turn. Festivals of feasting and consumption mark this time of year. We may gather with family and friends, give lavish gifts chosen from gift lists, and cook meals large enough to crack dining room tables in two. We tell stories about days that have passed, and tales of gods old and new. We remember, and we looked forward, toward the promise of spring.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">We mark the darker days with bright celebrations, and this is a wonderful thing.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This year, I have decided upon a new kind of celebration. I think that books should be on the dinner table as well.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Not as food for the body, but for the mind. For me, this past year has been a year of upheaval and imbalance. I have been working hard, and constantly, to get my feet back under me. I have written more this year than I have in some time, and my work life has rebounded from last year’s slump with alacrity. It has been a trying year, and I am looking forward to this winter as a time of rest and recovery. I plan to feed the mind like I would feed the body, and rejoice in excess.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">You see, so many of us fear the darkness. The winter months can feel cold and long. The darkness in the world around us may feel absolute. But that is not the truth.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26294 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/henry-be-lc7xcWebECc-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/henry-be-lc7xcWebECc-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/henry-be-lc7xcWebECc-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/henry-be-lc7xcWebECc-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/henry-be-lc7xcWebECc-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/henry-be-lc7xcWebECc-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/henry-be-lc7xcWebECc-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Darkness is a time for rest. It is a time for us to turn inward and reflect. We are given the opportunity to forget the outside would and care for ourselves. We cultivate the inner spirit, when the world is dark and cold.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In the spring and summer, when the world is bright, it is easy to fill our days with work and play. We might write for hours upon hours, pushing ourselves to produce. We take on new projects and try new things. We go out with friends and colleagues. We work hard, so hard that sometimes we need to take a vacation to recover.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">It has become the norm to try to follow this pattern throughout the rest of the year. With artificial lights to turn on and friends just a call away, the winter is no longer a time for fasting and staying in with family. In this modern world, we work through the winter, pushing ourselves just as hard as we would any other day of the year. We do not give ourselves time to rest in stillness; we just keep going, until we cannot go any more.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This November, I am thinking of ways to rest, and feed the spirit. My first thought is to read.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">So I am gathering books to feast upon. My goal is to collect twenty-five books to read over the next few months. I am looking for books of all types—fiction, nonfiction, poetry, art. Some I already own, and some I will buy new. They might be short or long. I do not have any type of goal for these books—I might read all of them, or only a few. Their purpose is to feed the spirit.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">I will take my book list, and I will read it. Not to work, but to feed the spirit. I want to read books that bring me joy, that delight the senses and excite me. I want to learn new things, and imagine new worlds. I will take this winter as a time of rest. I will read and relax to my heart’s content. I will write with lassitude, and will not commit to new projects. I will fill my heart with stories, and let myself recover from this year. I will curl up in the sea<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26293 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/lasse-moller-4y0N8xUBsQs-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/lasse-moller-4y0N8xUBsQs-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/lasse-moller-4y0N8xUBsQs-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/lasse-moller-4y0N8xUBsQs-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/lasse-moller-4y0N8xUBsQs-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/lasse-moller-4y0N8xUBsQs-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/lasse-moller-4y0N8xUBsQs-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />son’s darkness like a shawl, wrap it around my shoulders and tuck in the corners.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">But I will keep a single light. I will hang it over my shoulder like the moon, and let it light the books I read. I will stoke the fires of my curiosity, and keep them burning bright.</p>
<p class="p1">Because I know that next year, when the light returns and the world is bright and vibrant again, I will need that curiosity. I will have new stories to write, and ideas to explore—inspired by this winter’s reading—and I am already excited to see where they will take me.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>the stories that save us</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-stories-that-save-us/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 11:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foggy Mornings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I write this from the edge of breakdown.  The past month has been a difficult&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">I write this from the edge of breakdown.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The past month has been a difficult one, draining in ways I did not realize were possible. I have pushed through, and done my best each day, but it has been hard. I have read articles about burnout and fatigue, contemplated retiring to the countryside like a maiden from an Austen novel, but none of the solutions on offer seem to be enough.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Would that I could escape into the pages of my favorite book and live there for a season. I would not mind suffering all the troubles of my favorite main character, in exchange for the privilege of knowing the ending of this tale. In times like this, when the nights begin to lengthen and the days grow shorter, when ghosts gather in the corners and the neighbors lawns are festooned with gravestones, it is important to gather all the things we love around us. For me—for so many of us—these things are stories.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26135 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="551" height="367" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 551px) 100vw, 551px" /></p>
<p class="p1">A good story enlightens us and leaves us breathless. It pulls the heart out from under our skin and exposes it to the air. It bleeds out the poisons just like some medieval surgeon. It leaves us enlivened.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In my exhaustion lately, I have been gathering my favorite stories closer than ever.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">There is the novel about lesbian necromancers<i>, </i>which manages to be a romance, space adventure, and an ode to the country house murder mystery. It is gorgeously written, fantastically brutal, and absolutely heartwrenching. The sequel manages to be all that and more, with a splash of the literary thrown into its labyrinthine plotting.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">There is the new age fairy tale, in which a star falls to earth and eventually in love. But along the way timelines are stretched and turned inside and out, the past comes into the present, and myths of true love and eternal life are deconstructed.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">There is the pastiche, a novel of the stories that hide within footnotes. It is the tale of two mismatched magicians in a land that is losing its magic, who manage to unravel centuries-old secrets and uncover new mysteries at the same time.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">There is the story of the son of a god who does not know he is divine, but who believes he is cursed until he gets caught in the machinations of a god as old as the land itself. Filled with dark tales, it is a portrait of how a land can contain both beauty and horror, lurking right beneath the surface.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">And there is the epic tale, the ode to romance that divides the heavens, which is the story of a pair of destined souls, brought closer through life and death. They must fight for each other and win out in the end, though the entire establishment fights against them and believes them to be forsaken. And they get their happy ending at last.</p>
<p class="p1">These are the stories that I love. They rest on my bookshelf in good times, and come out in the challenging ones. I have been returning to these stories time and again recently, in order to find myself and find a place where I can rest.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">And in these stories, though they challenge the characters in new and terrible ways with every chapter, I find salvation. Because their stories have ends. They find love, or destiny, or home. When I read them, I am no longer so tired. With these characters, I find those things, too. My story does not yet have an ending. I cannot see the future through the hazy mists of time—most days, I cannot even predict it. But I can read to the end of the novel, and turn the last page.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">I find a good ending in stories.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">So here I am, on the edge of breakdown. I have been here before—exhausted, drained, unable to process. These days come more often than I would like. But I will not stop. I will keep going, day by day and word by word. In the end, I know I will be saved by the stories that I love. They give me hope for easier, more restful days.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">And when they come, I know that I will have the strength to write again. Because these stories live inside me. They give me strength. They teach me how to keep going.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">All the way to the end of the road.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26136 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/katie-moum-5FHv5nS7yGg-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="388" height="582" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/katie-moum-5FHv5nS7yGg-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/katie-moum-5FHv5nS7yGg-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/katie-moum-5FHv5nS7yGg-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/katie-moum-5FHv5nS7yGg-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/katie-moum-5FHv5nS7yGg-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/katie-moum-5FHv5nS7yGg-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 388px) 100vw, 388px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Stories We Tell</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-stories-we-tell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 10:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foggy Mornings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25805</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago I was privileged enough to attend a seminar about converting fanfiction&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A few weeks ago I was privileged enough to attend a seminar about converting fanfiction to original fiction. I was very excited for the opportunity—as a prolific writer of both fanfiction and original fiction, I was eager to learn more about ways to utilize the m</span>any (nearly half a million) words of fanfiction I had written in new and creative ways.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25806 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/shelby-miller-hL0xl0qmxYM-unsplash-300x219.jpg" alt="" width="386" height="282" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/shelby-miller-hL0xl0qmxYM-unsplash-300x219.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/shelby-miller-hL0xl0qmxYM-unsplash-1024x749.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/shelby-miller-hL0xl0qmxYM-unsplash-768x562.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/shelby-miller-hL0xl0qmxYM-unsplash-1536x1123.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/shelby-miller-hL0xl0qmxYM-unsplash-2048x1498.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 386px) 100vw, 386px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have spent many years of my life writing fanfiction, and for many reason</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">s</span>. I began when I was young, and the only path available to me to be a writer was through fanfiction. No one else would have me at the time, and with good reason—I was not yet very good at telling stories. I knew I <i>wanted</i> to tell them, but not how it was done. In school, my language arts classes had focused primarily on reading, or on the craft of essays. And I wanted to write <i>fiction</i>. So when I found fanfiction, it was a revelation. A way to write whatever I wanted to, publish it myself, and grow as a writer. It helped that fanfiction is based on familiar stories and characters, because this allowed me a way to practice craft and plot and style without getting caught up in all the other parts of storytelling. I didn’t fall down any research holes; I didn’t get distracted writing the biography of a character; I didn’t have to submit my writing to a publishing house and hope desperately that it would be accepted. I just wrote, and the act of writing brought me pleasure.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the seminar I attended, the moderator spent a good amount of time explaining </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">what </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">fanfiction was, and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">why</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> people wrote it. It soon became apparent that of those attending, writers like me (experienced in the world of fanfiction) were a minority, and the majority had never written fanfiction before. And if they had heard of it, all they knew was that it was Porn. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I say Porn with a capital P because that was how they said it—as if it was something dirty and illicit, something to be ashamed of. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I admit I have spent a good deal of my life ashamed of writing fanfiction. I was aware from a young age that fanfiction was considered to be second class, not “real” writing. There are many reasons for this. Fanfiction is based on another creator’s characters and worldbuilding, and so people assume that writing fanfiction lacks creativity, or that fanfiction writers are just lazy. Fanfiction is self-published, and while there are often brilliant works of fanfiction on the internet, there are also works that lack editing and skill. And yes, quite a lot of fanfiction is Porn. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For years I hid my pastime from the world. I was personally interested in fanfiction as a way to write without barriers, as a thing of joy and revelation. But I was terrified that someone would find out that I read and wrote fanfiction, that they might think I was a “freak” for enjoying stories about characters I loved. For enjoying stories about sex. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As I sat in this seminar and listened to people ask thinly veiled questions about fanfiction and its provenance, I began to realize that all those years of shame and anxiety were foolish. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My writing—my </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">fanfiction</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">—is not second class writing. Sure, it may have lacked skill at first, but the world of fanfiction allowed me a venue through which to write and continue writing, and so my skill has improved. I may have based my fanfiction upon stories that others had created, but this meant that I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">studied</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> those original stories and learned them inside out, so I could begin to build original stories of my own. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And yes, I wrote Porn. Not exclusively, but a healthy dose of it! And from writing that Porn, I learned some wonderful things: how to write action with a balance of description and clarity; how to reveal a character’s feelings through subtle details; how to use bias and point of view to shift the narrative. I talked to other writers of fanfiction about the craft, and I learned that sex is a normal, physical thing. Desire is a part of life, and there are many shades to it—from asexual love without physicality, to the passion that can be found in a pure friendship, to wild sexual desire that takes all forms. I learned about consent, and power dynamics in relationships, and the tropes of both romance and suspense (because romance without a hint of tension tends to be boring, I have found). I learned how to subvert traditional narratives and upend convention. I learned that love is valid, and a worthwhile thing to desire in life. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These were not topics discussed in school, or among my friends, or in my home. The media portrays love and desire in a very singular form, as if there is only one way that one person can possibly love another. Fanfiction, and the wonderful people I met through the world of fandom, taught me that love comes in many shapes and colors. It is more diverse and beautiful than we can imagine, and just because your love doesn’t look like the kind projected on the movie screen, does not mean it is invalid. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All those years of anxiety were misguided. I had spent my time worrying about being judged by what I wrote, when I should not have worried at all. Fanfiction is not something to be ashamed of; it has been a blessing in my life. I am proud of all the stories that I have written and the ways in which I have improved as as writer. I love the friends I have made through the writing of fanfiction, and the diverse worlds I have been privileged to explore. Fanfiction shaped the way I view the world, and I know now that the greatest thing in the world is not what you </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">achieve</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but how you </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">love</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Did I learn much from this seminar about “converting your fanfiction” into original stories? Not really. Nothing new. Just the things that I had known all along, and forgotten along the way:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That your story is valid, no matter how or where you choose to tell it. You just have to keep writing, and never let them tell you you aren’t enough. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25808 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jason-leung-AxKqisRPQSA-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="399" height="599" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jason-leung-AxKqisRPQSA-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jason-leung-AxKqisRPQSA-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jason-leung-AxKqisRPQSA-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jason-leung-AxKqisRPQSA-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jason-leung-AxKqisRPQSA-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/jason-leung-AxKqisRPQSA-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 399px) 100vw, 399px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>tornado warning</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/tornado-warning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 11:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foggy Mornings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The tornado touched down last Thursday.  We don’t often get tornadoes in this part of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">The tornado touched down last Thursday.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">We don’t often get tornadoes in this part of the country. The storm that brought it rolled through from west to east, a sinuous creature making its way toward the ocean. It brought heavy rains and lightning, cracks of thunder so loud they shook the walls, and the tornado warning blaring across the screens of our phones.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">It was frightening, and then terrifying, as the rains came down heavier and heavier. The sky was a strange kind of grey and the wind stopped blowing. It seemed that any moment, the tornado would come down upon us, tear off the roof and rip apart the walls, leaving our lives wet and tattered.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">It was a near miss, luckily. After an hour of sitting in a stairwell and trying to keep ourselves distracted, we emerged safe and sound. The storm had continued its steady progress and moved on, leaving us with just a river of water pouring down the street. There was not even a branch down from the trees out front.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Two miles to the west, they were not so lucky. The tornado touched down and ripped apart the forest, stranding thousands of people without power.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25574 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/max-larochelle-uu-Jw5SunYI-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="351" height="439" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/max-larochelle-uu-Jw5SunYI-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/max-larochelle-uu-Jw5SunYI-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/max-larochelle-uu-Jw5SunYI-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/max-larochelle-uu-Jw5SunYI-unsplash-1229x1536.jpg 1229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/max-larochelle-uu-Jw5SunYI-unsplash-1638x2048.jpg 1638w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/max-larochelle-uu-Jw5SunYI-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 351px) 100vw, 351px" /></p>
<p class="p1">This is the power of a storm, to tear apart our lives with gleeful abandon. There are many storms in our lives, some of which bring rain and thunder, others which feed on our anxieties and rage within us, others that tear us apart from those we love.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Some storms are so terrible, we do not know how we will survive.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">I drove out of town and down the hill a few days ago, distracted enough that I forgot about the tornado completely. We had had no damage, after all, and I had been busy with work that day. The sky was bright and blue, and the world had calmed.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Down one winding road and then another, I drove. The forest closed in around me and the road thinned; I began to hope that I would not encounter another car, because surely that would force one of us off the road. I reached a detour and followed the twists and turns of the road toward the river’s edge.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">It was not until I reached the damage that I remembered what had happened. I slowed my car as chills raced through me.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">As the road wound down one hill and prepared to ascend the next, I saw the marks the tornado had left. A trail of devastation about a hundred feet wide, no more, that had stripped bare the thin trees on the eastern side of the road and toppled behemoths on the west—some of which had fallen across driveways and through the roof of the house that sat perched on the hill.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">I drove slowly through the area, gaping to the left and the right. Then I drove on.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The devastation vanished as I rounded the curve. Within half a mile, it was as if the storm had never been.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">What is it about the world that allows utter devastation to descend upon some of us, while allowing the rest to be spared? How is it that storms can sweep through, upend our lives, and toss everything we love out into the wind and rain to be ruined? As one person experiences the worst day of their life, so many others have the very best. The storms of life have no rhyme or reason.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Lately, this is how I have been thinking about my writing.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Words have been difficult these days, pulled out of me more by force and determination than by any kind of inspiration. Anxieties slow me, and summer distractions; too much ice cream one day and exhaustion the next. I don’t want to write, and yet I <i>do</i>, because I know that to write is to seek meaning within the abstract, and that if I just keep going and lay down the words beneath my feet, eventually I might build a bridge to the stars.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This is harder when the storms of life come.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Little things and big, they pull me away from writing. The little storms of anxieties, or of jealousy, or of self doubt plague me. I cannot make them go away, just as I could not wish away the storm that came through the other day, bringing fear and possible devastation.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">But I am learning to trust, as I commit myself to words each day. It is a slow process, for sure, but as I grow older, the ability to trust comes easier.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">I have to trust that my readers will understand me, and that it is okay if they don’t. I trust that I have done my best with the words I have chosen, and that my words are enough. I trust that this anxiety is only momentary, and that this storm will pass, and the time will come when writing is easy again.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">I trust that if I keep going, if I keep writing and using my words to guide me, the path will become clear. And that one day the road will straighten out, and the skies above shine blue, and the storms will have left me behind.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Wet and tousled, for sure, but whole.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25575 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/magnezis-magnestic-KUQEo74BgPs-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="438" height="292" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/magnezis-magnestic-KUQEo74BgPs-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/magnezis-magnestic-KUQEo74BgPs-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/magnezis-magnestic-KUQEo74BgPs-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/magnezis-magnestic-KUQEo74BgPs-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/magnezis-magnestic-KUQEo74BgPs-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 438px) 100vw, 438px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>summer heat</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/summer-heat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foggy Mornings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the midst of the hot summer days, there are only two options—write, or don’t&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">In the midst of the hot summer days, there are only two options—write, or don’t write.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">It is the heat that does this to me; it presses down on my skin and my thoughts, making everything stickier. Summer heat reshapes the way I think, and move, and exist, so that I cannot live as usual. The world narrows and becomes simpler. I can only sustain my focus for a limited period of time. <span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25348 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/alfred-kenneally-FE0-9ttSAOc-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/alfred-kenneally-FE0-9ttSAOc-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/alfred-kenneally-FE0-9ttSAOc-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/alfred-kenneally-FE0-9ttSAOc-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/alfred-kenneally-FE0-9ttSAOc-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/alfred-kenneally-FE0-9ttSAOc-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/alfred-kenneally-FE0-9ttSAOc-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<p class="p1">On the Writing Days, I wake with my mind afire. I roll out of bed and brew my coffee, then head to the computer and begin to write. The words dance within me. They are alive, and flow straight from my mind to the tips of my fingers. Or perhaps I do not start right away, but later in the day. I wake and drink coffee and run errands. But in the midst of something—washing the dishes, or taking a walk through the forest—something catches my mind and sparks the feeling. I feel the words beneath my skin, roiling with the need to get out. There is a story there, if only I can find the right words to share it.</p>
<p class="p1">When I have my Writing Days, it doesn’t matter where I am; I can write anywhere. In my car while I wait for my coffee order. On the side of the trail in the woods. In my kitchen while the water boils. (For coffee: yes, I do drink a lot of coffee, don’t you?) In a notebook. On my phone. On my computer. On the old typewriter I salvaged from a yard sale two years ago. I can, and do, write anywhere. There are the days when writing brings me to life, and I feel that it saves me.</p>
<p class="p1">But there are other days: the <i>Wordless</i> Days.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Those days are more common, I have found. These are the days when I wake with nothing in my mind—nothing but the light of the sun on my sheets and the cool air from the fan on my skin. There are no words on those days, just the unspeakable feeling of the universe surrounding me.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">On Wordless Days—and though I do not have words on those days, they are still beautiful—I live the world more fully. Stories are just stories, and the shape of existence is beyond the scope of a single tale. I go for long walks and relish the shape of the clouds. I watch a new television show and laugh with delight at the plot twists. I look out my window and across the rooftops of the nearest houses and wonder at the shapes of the lives inside.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The Wordless Days are not wasted days. They are days when I am me, more than anyone else. I do not wear the shape of a character or speak with the voice of the spirits. I am myself, and only myself. It is a nourishing feeling.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">But life does not always allow me to be myself, with or without the words.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Sometimes I do not have that freedom. Some days my brain is full of words and the urgency to write. This could be a Writing Day! And yet I cannot sit and write—I have to work, and send emails, and coordinate my schedule—so that I cannot find the time or space to put pen to paper. Sadly, this means that I do not have a chance to write until the very end of the day. And often, by that time, the words have vanished from my mind.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">And sometimes I <i>do</i> have the time to write! I have whole days, here and there, when I have the time and space to craft a story. I plan these days out, make sure that my schedule is free and clear. I look forward to them for weeks on end. And then, when they arrive, the words are not there. I sit down in front of my computer, ready to crafted and create, and yet…there are no words. They have vanished from me, and no matter how hard I try, I cannot make them come.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25349 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jorik-blom-HP4VFH70LMc-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jorik-blom-HP4VFH70LMc-unsplash-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jorik-blom-HP4VFH70LMc-unsplash-681x1024.jpg 681w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jorik-blom-HP4VFH70LMc-unsplash-768x1155.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jorik-blom-HP4VFH70LMc-unsplash-1021x1536.jpg 1021w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jorik-blom-HP4VFH70LMc-unsplash-1362x2048.jpg 1362w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/jorik-blom-HP4VFH70LMc-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1702w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" />Yet, for the most part, the summer is easier. Time moves slower. The Writing Days come to me more frequently. Stories brew in my mind like stormclouds, like a bitter cup of coffee, and I cannot wait to take them up.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The days of midsummer are hot and sticky. They cling to my skin. And beneath the weight of the summer air, I either sink into the sea of words, or I sail across it, untouched and triumphant.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>susurrant songs</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/susurrant-songs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 15:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foggy Mornings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Step outside in New Jersey these days, and you will hear the song of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Step outside in New Jersey these days, and you will hear the song of the cicadas.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">They are louder in some towns than others. I have found that they gather in profusion in communities that are closer to the mountains and forests. Each day, I drive down a long country road that sweeps over hills and between wide-open farm fields. It also passes through the remains of the old forests, the ones that have hardly been touched in two centuries, which crowd close to the road and whose branches scrabble to take down the powerlines. It is here that I hear the cicadas singing in the heat of the afternoon, as I drive home from work and begin to unwind.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25112 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/bill-nino-yy-rT8aJp64-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="390" height="520" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/bill-nino-yy-rT8aJp64-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/bill-nino-yy-rT8aJp64-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/bill-nino-yy-rT8aJp64-unsplash-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/bill-nino-yy-rT8aJp64-unsplash-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/bill-nino-yy-rT8aJp64-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 390px) 100vw, 390px" /></p>
<p class="p1">If you have not heard the song of the cicadas, it is an impossible thing. They gather in trees—which ones, I am not sure, but they definitely have a particular taste for a certain kind—and sometimes on the walls of houses. They creep along and flex their wings, and when they move in the millions they fill the air with sound. Their song is a high-pitched scree, an unceasing whine. Driving along, the song rises in volume as you pass the cicada trees, and then falls away to a mere whisper. Stepping out of the car at work, the song fills the air like the sound of a distant scream, like something great and terrible is coming to life just beyond the screen of the trees. It presses down on you, that song, and makes you think that the world might just be ending.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">When I hear the song of the cicadas, I think of one of the haikus of Matsuo Bashō, who wrote of the unceasing song of the cicada:<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">      閑かさや | </span><i>stillness—</i></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">      岩にしみ入る | </span><i>sinking deep into the rocks</i></p>
<p class="p3"><span class="s1">      蝉の声 | </span><i>cries of the cicada</i></p>
<p class="p4" style="text-align: right;"><span class="s2">—Matsuo </span><span class="s3">Bashō</span><span class="s2"> (1644-1694)</span></p>
<p class="p1">This is the year of the cicada. After seventeen years of rest, a particular brood of them has awakened and crept into the world. Their song began with a few, and now swells into the millions. They fill the forest. For the next six weeks or so, their song will be the soundtrack to the early summer. In this heat, the cicada thrives.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">As summer approaches and I begin a new story—one that is long and convoluted—I have been thinking a lot about the cicada’s song. It is an eerie sound, for sure. When it fills the air around me, it lends reality the vibe of an oncoming storm. And yet it is also beautiful. This is the sound of millions, perhaps billions, of inhuman voices raised in wild and raucous celebration. These cicadas have been waiting seventeen years for this moment. They are finally free to fly, to live and to thrive. This is their moment.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">The song of the cicadas lingers with me for two main reasons. For one, it is ever-present, and it has the kind of strangeness that turns the real world into a novel, wherein the apocalypse comes slow and steady over the horizon. The second reason is that the cicada’s song makes me me think of the shape of stories, and how they fill space in our lives.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">What I mean is this: there are billions of cicadas out there, just like there are billions of people. The cicadas sing altogether, their voices a strange chorus. They crowd together on the bark of trees, and flit through the air lazily. They shed their exoskeletons when they grow out of them, leaving them scattered upon the ground and clinging to the bark of trees. The cicada shell is a startling thing, both luminous and ugly at the same time. Split straight down the back, it catches the summer sun and throws it back, gleaming the color of amber.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">And as humans, we sing our own kinds of songs, celebrating life in an infinite variety of ways. We create art, writings, architecture. We dance and we shout and we lift our faces up to the bright dome of the sky. The things that we humans create are our own songs of celebration, and like the cicada’s song, they fill the air and break through the stillness. Our songs and our stories reshape the world, cutting through the rock of reality and weaving a new and brighter tapestry.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">To some being on another planet, perhaps our stories are as strange and eerie as the song of the cicada sounds to us.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This song may vanish in a few weeks, swallowed by the summer storms and the thick curtain of leaves along with the insects themselves. But our stories will not. The tales we craft, the songs we sing, the art we create, will remain.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25113 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/alin-andersen-KBYtszGvC8s-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="524" height="349" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/alin-andersen-KBYtszGvC8s-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/alin-andersen-KBYtszGvC8s-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/alin-andersen-KBYtszGvC8s-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/alin-andersen-KBYtszGvC8s-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/alin-andersen-KBYtszGvC8s-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 524px) 100vw, 524px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moving Up</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/moving-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 10:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foggy Mornings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24852</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Why is it that our characters always have to move? I have rarely read a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Why is it that our characters always have to <i>move</i>? I have rarely read a story about a character sitting still—even imagining it evokes boredom, the weight of it hovering in the distance like a cloud.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Of course, there are authors who have written about characters caught in stillness, because when we sit still we find ourselves going on inner journeys, journeys of the mind. And stories are always about one kind of journey or another.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-24853 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brett-patzke-pYeO_rIZ1EM-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="308" height="462" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brett-patzke-pYeO_rIZ1EM-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brett-patzke-pYeO_rIZ1EM-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brett-patzke-pYeO_rIZ1EM-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brett-patzke-pYeO_rIZ1EM-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brett-patzke-pYeO_rIZ1EM-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/brett-patzke-pYeO_rIZ1EM-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 308px) 100vw, 308px" /></p>
<p class="p1">The main character leaves home to fight a war. She is captured by ogres and taken away, and has to fight her way back. The princess must marry to bring about peace between kingdoms, and she leaves behind everything and everyone she knows. The main character travels to a new planet, or a new universe, or through time. She leaves one place after another, often unwillingly, and always encounters difficulties along the way.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This is the kind of story we like, isn’t it? I know that I enjoy a good adventure, and the further the character goes from home, the better.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">But my life—and I suspect the lives of many of us readers—has not been that kind of story. In fact, from an author’s perspective, it has hardly been a story at all. My life has been with stillness and a lack of movement. I have gone on no grand adventures. No screenwriters will ever want to write a film about my life (despite the fact that it is full of beauty), and no authors will write a biography of my name (though my life has, I hope, been an important one).<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span>I was born five miles from the place where I live. I did not leave my home to go to college. I have only rarely travelled. I have not married or had children. My circle of friends is close, and quiet. We do not throw raucous parties or talk every day. I work a steady job, I eat mostly vegetarian food, and I masturbate only occasionally, when the whim takes me. My life is quiet and still, filled with steady rhythms and routines.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">While Western media likes to portray the ideal life as one full of travel and adventure, I think that most of us live our lives in a kind of stillness. We move in a kind of rhythm, the kind that is so steady and regular that it takes on the appearance of stillness; we move between work, home, school, church (or some variation thereof) and back again. This kind of rhythmic existence becomes background noise to us, so regular and soothing that we tune it out. After all, we do not think of the movement of the waves as utter stillness, but as a constant of the world, something so eternal that it will never cease.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Right now, I am in the midst of moving. I am picking up, packing up, and soon I will be living in a new home. I have thrown myself out of the rhythm of my life, and I’m taking myself on a new adventure. I’m all shaken up about it.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">This is the kind of life change that stories are made of, where I go on a journey from one kind of life to another. It may not be a big, dramatic story with magic and dragons, but my little move—the act of packing up my things and carting them down the winding roads—could be a story all the same, as long as I tune into it.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">I have spent the last month sorting through my things and deciding what to carry with me. What books will I keep? What art will I hang on the walls? I have been packing clothes and kitchen tools into boxes, losing some things along the way and finding others. I found a pair of ceramic shishi statuettes (little, snarling guardian lions) that I had packed away years ago and thought had been broken, whole and in one piece. I even packed away my computer for a time, and couldn’t remember which box I had put it in for nearly a week. I am throwing out old things and broken gadgets. I am trying to take with me only the things that I love.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In a week, I will be done. The worst will be over, and the movers will be gone. I will be in my new home, and I will settle into stillness again.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">In this moment, in the midst of movement, what I long for is stillness. I do not relish the journey, though I know it is necessary. I am excited to set up my new office and get ready to write. I am imagining the reading corner I will set up, between two bookcases stacked high with books, where I can curl up and enjoy a new story. I keep thinking about the rugs I will lay down, layers of them so thick that when I step onto them my toes sink deep into the steady, luxurious pile. I am ready to cultivate a routine again, the steady rhythm of life. I want to fall into the swaying stillness of the waves.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p1">Let my characters go on grand journeys and get carried away by life. Me, I plan to meditate on the rhythm of stillness, and breathe in the color of the setting sun. My journeys are ones of the mind.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-24854 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ryan-loughlin-SQpD3hwXwM0-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="375" height="563" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ryan-loughlin-SQpD3hwXwM0-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ryan-loughlin-SQpD3hwXwM0-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ryan-loughlin-SQpD3hwXwM0-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ryan-loughlin-SQpD3hwXwM0-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ryan-loughlin-SQpD3hwXwM0-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/ryan-loughlin-SQpD3hwXwM0-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 375px) 100vw, 375px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Moon Clouds</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-moon-clouds/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 12:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foggy Mornings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you ever seen a moon cloud?  They are strange, ephemeral things, lasting only for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-24542 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/aron-visuals-4zxSWESyZio-unsplash-300x277.jpg" alt="" width="454" height="419" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/aron-visuals-4zxSWESyZio-unsplash-300x277.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/aron-visuals-4zxSWESyZio-unsplash-1024x947.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/aron-visuals-4zxSWESyZio-unsplash-768x710.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/aron-visuals-4zxSWESyZio-unsplash-1536x1421.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/aron-visuals-4zxSWESyZio-unsplash-2048x1894.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 454px) 100vw, 454px" /></p>
<p class="p2">Have you ever seen a moon cloud?<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">They are strange, ephemeral things, lasting only for a few weeks in spring. You can see them at dawn and at dusk, during those liminal times when the world is dark and grey, but a bit of light clings to the world. The sky is deep blue, and silver at the edges, like a finely wrought piece of jewelry.</p>
<p class="p3">It is at this time that the moon clouds are visible between the trees—lacy and amorphous, floating between one thing and the next: both dead and blooming with life, both magical creation and hard reality.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Perhaps you have not seen a moon cloud. I wouldn’t be surprised. They are something I made up, an idea that has lived in my head since I was a child. I have found that whenever I point out moon clouds to anyone else, they have struggled to see them, shaking their heads and saying, “Yes, that’s very pretty. But isn’t it just a tree?”</p>
<p class="p3">As a writer, I have so often found that there are things in the world that exist only in my head. Which is impossible, for sure. How can something be in the world, and also <i>only </i>in my my head? It is a paradox of contradictions, and I am not enough of a physicist or a philosopher to know for sure, and so I cannot explain it. But the moon cloud is one of these things—a dream and a reality all at once.</p>
<p class="p3">Sometimes, there are things in the world that only artists and writers can see. These things are special to us, pieces of our heart that exist in the world. When we try to explain them to others, they look at us blankly and shake their heads. This is one of the curses of being an artist (and writers are definitely artists of a kind), because it means that we will always be a step out of touch with others, always sensing things that others cannot.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">But this is also a blessing. These ephemeral inspirations, the touches of things that we sense that others cannot, are our fuel. Yes, we need more concrete fuels like coffee and hugs and music and quiet time as well, but without these little things—our own personal moon clouds—we cannot write. They are waking hallucinations, the mind slipping from waking to dreams between one step and the next. Moments like this often make me want to pull my car over to the side of the road, pull out something to write with, and jot down the strange, churning ideas in my mind.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">It is the desire to share these parts of our lives that drives us forward. We write in order to share the intangible with others. We write to share a feeling, a wish, a piece of our hearts. Whether we write conceptual literary fiction or space opera or romantic saga, there is a place in each one of these stories for our souls. We write to share that, and to find those things that our souls have in common with others.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Let me tell you about the moon clouds again. I think that, just maybe, you have seen them.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">In the spring, for a few weeks when the world begins to warm, the fruiting trees begin to bloom. Cherry and pear and apple, their craggy branches sprouting with luminous life. They have small flowers of palest pink and white, and until the spring rains come to beat them down, these flowers bloom in profusion. The trees bloom everywhere—in yards and in forests, mixed in with the oaks and larches and swamp maples.</p>
<p class="p3">When the world is somewhere between night and day, and the sky is the muddled color of a bruise, the light catches on these flowers and makes them gleam. Their true color is stripped from them, and they shine a pale silver. The little bunches of flowers gathered along the branches seem to shift together, to become a thick, wandering cloud of light that hangs between the darker, more solemn trees. It gleams like the widening moon. It is a trick of the eye, that turns a blooming tree into a shining cloud of light. In a few more minutes, the light will have shifted, and the moon cloud will be gone.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-24541 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/david-brooke-martin-5RLPc7cue2o-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="401" height="267" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/david-brooke-martin-5RLPc7cue2o-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/david-brooke-martin-5RLPc7cue2o-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/david-brooke-martin-5RLPc7cue2o-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/david-brooke-martin-5RLPc7cue2o-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/david-brooke-martin-5RLPc7cue2o-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 401px) 100vw, 401px" /></p>
<p class="p3">As I drive, and the moon clouds light up the forest that races by my car, I want to stop and breathe them in. I want to write down the shape of this moment, because I know that it is special to me; only I can see it and feel it, and if I do not write it down it will vanish from the world forever.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Of course, I do not often stop. Life is fast, and will race on without me if I constantly pull over to the side of the road. But every once in a while I do. I slow the car and pull onto the grass. As the radio natters on, I jot down my strange, messy poems about the moon clouds. I close my notebook. And I dream of a reader who will see what I do.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p3">Then I drive on.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Artist in Me</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-artist-in-me/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ann Langley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Foggy Mornings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you ask me, I am an artist. Not exactly the kind of artist who&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-24354 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="449" height="299" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/khara-woods-KR84RpMCb0w-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 449px) 100vw, 449px" /></p>
<p class="p2">If you ask me, I am an artist. Not exactly the kind of artist who paints or sculpts (though I did try both in college and found that, although I love the visual arts very much, I have very little talent), but the kind of artist who writes.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p2">My visual arts training has very much carried over into my writing. It is embedded in the way that I think about my personal writing process, and I often wonder whether other authors have the same kind of mental schematics to guide them in their process. Perhaps you have a process that is wildly different from mine, but similar in the way that it guides you through your work. Perhaps you do not have a process at all, though I would wonder a bit if you told me that. For what it is worth, here is mine:</p>
<p class="p2">First comes the lightning bolt—the hot strike of magic that is inspiration. I imagine it is much the same for any kind of artist—you are moving through your day normally, thinking of something bland like the grocery list or the color of the sky, when all of sudden you notice something. The shape of the moon, or the smell of fire in the wind. Inside you, something clicks and brings together a thousand stories you have heard and the particulates of half-formed ideas. And you are inspired.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24355 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/egor-vikhrev-cV7cOur4sAM-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/egor-vikhrev-cV7cOur4sAM-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/egor-vikhrev-cV7cOur4sAM-unsplash-684x1024.jpg 684w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/egor-vikhrev-cV7cOur4sAM-unsplash-768x1150.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/egor-vikhrev-cV7cOur4sAM-unsplash-1026x1536.jpg 1026w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/egor-vikhrev-cV7cOur4sAM-unsplash-1368x2048.jpg 1368w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/egor-vikhrev-cV7cOur4sAM-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1710w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<p class="p2">It is exciting to feel this kind of inspiration. It is sudden and bright. It illuminates the mind; when before you had been just an ordinary person, nothing special at all, you are now aflame. I tend to feel ideas in the space beneath my ribs, taking up space between my lungs. But I have to be careful or these ideas will burn themselves out, fading away just as swiftly as they come.</p>
<p class="p2">The second step of the process is the sculpting. I imagine the shape of my inspiration as a rough, amorphous stone. It is weighty and powerful, but does not yet have a firm shape. I have to sculpt it. So I take out my tools and get to work. Sometimes this means that I pour myself into a Draft 0, writing fast and chipping away at my idea until it begins to take form on the page. Sometimes I plan, using lists and notecards and plot structures to pattern the idea and find the proper shape of it. This is the part of the process where things tend to be rough and difficult. I might (and have) give up in the middle of this process, because I find that the stone of inspiration has a fatal flaw, or the shape of the story will not reveal itself to me, or I am just not up to the work of shaping it. But sometimes the story takes shape, and I move on to the next step.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p2">I like to think of the third step as the act of collage. Collage is a flexible medium, adaptable to lots of manipulation, and this is what I do in this stage. I go back to what I have shaped, and I look at my sculpture. I find the flaws and cut them out. I slice one piece of the story free and move it to another place. Then I cut out another, and another. I shuffle things around, glue them down, and move them again. For me, this is the act of big edits and changes, I rewrite entire scenes and character arcs, and other times just make small changes. I try to bring harmony to the pieces, though this is the messiest of all the stages of my process. I check plotlines and character arcs, and the tone of each scene. I start to figure out how it is all meant to fit together.</p>
<p class="p2">And when all that is done, and the story feels almost complete, I take out the embroiery thread. For me, this is the act of going back and tidying up the details. I change small things, like dialogue and phrasing. I tweak the style of a scene or I plant a clue that the reader will need later. This is all the little work, when I reread the story again and again to make sure that everything reads and sounds right. I embroider by making small changes, little stitches in the fabric of the story that will finish it up.<span class="Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="p2"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-24356 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/nicole-keller-rADiYLlMeNY-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="252" height="380" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/nicole-keller-rADiYLlMeNY-unsplash-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/nicole-keller-rADiYLlMeNY-unsplash-681x1024.jpg 681w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/nicole-keller-rADiYLlMeNY-unsplash-768x1155.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/nicole-keller-rADiYLlMeNY-unsplash-1021x1536.jpg 1021w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/nicole-keller-rADiYLlMeNY-unsplash-1362x2048.jpg 1362w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/nicole-keller-rADiYLlMeNY-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1702w" sizes="(max-width: 252px) 100vw, 252px" />Each part of my writing process is a tactile thing. I shape the story to match my inspiration, building and refining it layer by layer. Until, somehow, with the last stroke of the brush, it is done. It is a process that works for me. I wonder how other writers see their process. What kind of architecture do you build?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
