<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freedom, Books, Flowers, &amp; the Moon &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/freedom-books-flowers-the-moon/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 14:38:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Science fiction, humanity and everything we could be</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/science-fiction-humanity-and-everything-we-could-be/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria V]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 10:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Freedom, Books, Flowers, & the Moon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“The truth is, Rosemary, that you are capable of anything. Good or bad. You always&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: right;"><em>“The truth is, Rosemary, that you are capable of anything. Good or bad. You always have been, and you always will be. Given the right push, you, too, could do horrible things. That darkness exists within all of us. You think every soldier who picked up a cutter gun was a bad person? No. She was just doing what the soldier next to her was doing, who was doing what the soldier next to her was doing, and so on and so on. And I bet most of them — not all, but most — who made it through the war spent a long time after trying to understand what they’d done. Wondering how they ever could have done it in the first place. Wondering when killing became so comfortable.”</em></p>
<p>I have already mentioned one-of-my-all-time-science-fiction-books, <em>The Long Way to a Small Angry Planet</em>, more than a couple of times during the time I’ve been writing for the LSQ Blog. I’ve realised, however, that I still owe a proper review to those who haven’t yet heard me talking (ahem, screaming) about this incredible work. Maybe if I offer you my thoughts about what makes this book so amazing and different from all of the SF/F books I’ve read, the unwary reader will wind up deciding to pick it up and give this heartwarming story a shot.</p>
<p>Without further ado, buckle up: we’re about to take flight.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25720 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>When I first came across this book, a few years ago, what struck me the most (besides the very pretty cover, I won’t deny), was its premise. This April, I have already rambled about how some commonplace clichés in science fiction and fantasy sometimes carry deeper views behind them, especially when it concerns the depiction of the other, the strange one, in opposition to “us”. Even if at the time I hadn’t fully elaborated this thought, this kind of representation already bothered something deep inside my heart that I couldn’t quite pinpoint. So the idea behind Chamber’s book, a multispecies crew going on a long journey in a universe where humankind isn’t the most evolved nor the dominant species was, at least, appealing. And I couldn’t be more right: in fact, my already great expectations were about to be exceeded.</p>
<p><em>The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet</em> is a hard book to summarize. Essentially, it’s a book all about character development as we follow the common people (or not exactly people, but you get it) across the span of the year it takes them to reach their destination. We’re used to action packed science fiction works that make us cling to the edge of our seats, and I won’t deny that I enjoy them once in a while, but the way the book twists the worn-out clichés is what makes it so interesting.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25721 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/guillermo-ferla-kEEl9csCutg-unsplash-300x197.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="197" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/guillermo-ferla-kEEl9csCutg-unsplash-300x197.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/guillermo-ferla-kEEl9csCutg-unsplash-1024x672.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/guillermo-ferla-kEEl9csCutg-unsplash-768x504.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/guillermo-ferla-kEEl9csCutg-unsplash-1536x1009.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/guillermo-ferla-kEEl9csCutg-unsplash-2048x1345.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>It’s easy to fall in love with (most of) the characters, and, as it happens in real life, what really matters and what really changes them is what happens throughout the journey. Chambers makes us look at our own strange humanity from the point of view of the other species: family, love, home, fear and prejudice are all discussed with naturality and sensitivity, and it’s in the little moments that we smile or feel our hearts swell (not rarely, both). From the wise gender-fluid alien doctor, perhaps the kindest character in the book, to the human captain that’s away from home and the newcomer girl who doesn’t exactly know what home is, I assure that they’ll teach you something about ourselves. And that, when the last page turns, they won’t be the only ones who have changed.</p>
<p>Science fiction has always appealed to me because it summarizes everything that we could be, good or bad. And Chamber’s book beautifully argues that, in spite of the messy places and time, there is still something worth fighting for, even if the fighting is not literal, even if the thing is a crew assembled inside a patched-up ship that becomes home. This story is an ode to hope, and to that tiny little spark inside each one of us that, as one of the characters says, &#8220;can make the galaxy outside a little bit kinder&#8221;.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p><strong><em>The long way to a small angry planet (2014)</em></strong></p>
<p><em>Author: Becky Chambers </em></p>
<p><em>Pages: 518</em></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Follow a motley crew on an exciting journey through space &#8211; and one adventurous young explorer who discovers the meaning of family in the far reaches of the universe &#8211; in this light-hearted debut space opera from a rising sci-fi star.</span></i></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignleft" src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/I/51BhQZOH9zL.jpg" alt="The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet: Wayfarers 1 (English Edition) - eBooks em Inglês na Amazon.com.br" /></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rose</span></i><i>mary Harper doesn’t expect much when she joins the crew of the aging Wayfarer. While the patched-up ship has seen better days, it offers her a bed, a chance to explore the far-off corners of the galaxy, and most importantly, some distance from her past. An introspective young woman who learned early to keep to herself, she’s never met anyone remotely like the ship’s diverse crew, including Sissix, the exotic reptilian pilot, chatty engineers Kizz</i><i>y and Jenks who keep the ship running, and Ashby, their noble captain.</i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Life aboard the Wayfarer is chaotic and crazy—exactly what Rosemary wants. It’s also ab</span></i><i>out to get extremely dangerous when the crew is offered the job of a lifetime. Tunneling wormholes through space to a distant planet is definitely lucrative and will keep them comfortable for years. But risking her life wasn’t part of the plan. In the far reaches of deep space, the tiny Wayfarer crew will confront a host of unexpected mishaps and thrilling adventures that force them to depend on each other. To survive, Rosemary’s got to learn how to rely on this assortment of oddballs—an experience that teaches her about love and trust, and that having a family isn’t necessarily the worst thing in the universe. </i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Portals, doorways, and stories that are home</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/portals-doorways-and-stories-that-are-home/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria V]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Freedom, Books, Flowers, & the Moon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of my favorite ways to spend time as a kid was to play pretend.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of my favorite ways to spend time as a kid was to play pretend. Sometimes, I would pretend to fight with lightsabers with my brother — as the oldest sister, I had the natural right to decide who would be who, and, of course, I always got to be the Jedi. On other days, we would invite our two best friends over, and we’d run around the house, which had become Hogwarts Castle in the blink of an eye, casting spells with our wands and hiding in secret tunnels that would open whenever we wanted them to. The door to the kitchen was, in fact, the wardrobe to Narnia, and the garden, to the dogs’ despair, was our own private fantasy land that we could build with the tips of our fingers and the mere power of our imagination.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24930 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/tim-hufner-ud0Kd5vk3mU-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/tim-hufner-ud0Kd5vk3mU-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/tim-hufner-ud0Kd5vk3mU-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/tim-hufner-ud0Kd5vk3mU-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/tim-hufner-ud0Kd5vk3mU-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/tim-hufner-ud0Kd5vk3mU-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/tim-hufner-ud0Kd5vk3mU-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a kid, too, I was quite lonely. I had a couple of imaginary friends with whom I’d spend break. My favorite stuffed toys had their birthdays written down on my school agenda, and I’d take them to class with me when we were allowed to bring things to play with from home — until the other kids started to make fun of me for still liking plushies. When I came home, I’d spread all of my </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Littlest Pet Shop</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> animals — most of them gifts from my dad from when he travelled to work — on my bedroom floor. I filled a notebook with the imaginary town’s rules: there was something about elections, a fair income distribution, and a Supreme Leader (my favorite pet, a brown dog with glittery ears). Sometimes one of the pets would make their way into my school pencil case, where they’d hide during the day, keeping me company and reminding me that, somewhere, there was a magical town where I made the rules, and where I’d always, always be welcome.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24929 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/6934463e4edf171dd1f771664a199253-300x220.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="220" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/6934463e4edf171dd1f771664a199253-300x220.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/6934463e4edf171dd1f771664a199253.jpg 400w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><em>An accurate portrait of 10-year-old me</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I can’t pinpoint when I grew out of it, but there must have been a day when I packed all of the pets and didn’t pick them up again, and there was also a day when my brother and I decided that, this time, we wouldn’t pretend we were Jedi or X-Wing pilots. But I still liked stories; I still made them up in my mind, and sometimes jotted them down on paper. And, most importantly, I still loved to read them. One day, while searching for a fun book in the middle of the craziness of life — the real life, where we can’t run away to fantasy lands when we want to —I came across Seanan McGuire’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every Heart a Doorway</span></i> <b>— </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">and, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">oh, boy. </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The premise is simple, yet it made me wonder </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">how no one thought about this before? </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Speculative literature is filled with stories about kids who find a magic portal into another world, where they live great adventures. But what happens with them when they come back? When they’re too old and have to face real life in the world from where they escaped, a world where they didn’t fit in?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s what Eleanor West&#8217;s School for Wayward Children is all about. It’s a home for all of the kids who had strange experiences their families and friends can’t understand, and who suddenly can’t fit into the real world anymore. Each one of them went to different places, different worlds which suited their personalities — but those worlds grew tired of them, and now they have nowhere else to go.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24928 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/vaibhav-raina-uXTTeya895c-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/vaibhav-raina-uXTTeya895c-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/vaibhav-raina-uXTTeya895c-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/vaibhav-raina-uXTTeya895c-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/vaibhav-raina-uXTTeya895c-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/vaibhav-raina-uXTTeya895c-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I won’t review the plot in depth, but it follows the story of Nancy, who has just been admitted to Eleanor’s school, as she and her newfound friends unravel a dark secret that has begun to terrorize the other students. The mystery was compelling, there was </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">great</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> representation (take that, old white men who say we can’t write diverse fantasy!),  but what I liked most were the characters, and their relationships with each other as they (re)learned what home meant.</span></p>
<p>This book wasn&#8217;t my best read that year, and I didn&#8217;t really like the ending, but the story stuck with me so much, and now I can see why. Deep down, we’re those children, aren’t we? We have stories, fantastic lands which felt like home, but there is a day when we don’t quite fit in anymore, and reality’s pull is stronger. Which doesn’t mean we have to leave it all behind. <i>It does not do well to dwell on dreams and forget to live</i>, but I argue that a little bit of dreaming is key — even if it’s for us to learn how to build our new homes in a world well-known for being hostile towards the smallest difference.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I still like stuffed toys, and when I travelled to other places (<em>oh!</em>), it wasn&#8217;t rare for me to bring one home as a reminder of those experiences. I still treasure my </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Littlest Pet Shop </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">collection. They’re a part of who I am today, a reminder of the magical portals I built for myself. And, sometimes, when I’m reading, writing, or maybe listening to a podcast while I do dishes, or when a crazy idea comes to my mind right before I fall asleep, I get a glimpse at those doorways, my good old friends, and they never fail at making me smile.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25526296-every-heart-a-doorway"><b><i>Every Heart a Doorway — Wayward Children #01</i></b></a></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">No Solicitations. </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">No Visitors. </span></i><i>No Questions.</i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Children have always disappeared under the right c</span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">onditions; </span></i><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">slipping through the shadows under a bed or at the back of a wardrobe, tumbling down rabbit holes and into old wells, and emerging somewhere&#8230; else. </span></i></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24927 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/51w04pZwgGL-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/51w04pZwgGL-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/51w04pZwgGL.jpg 329w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" /></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">But magical lands have little need for used-up miracle children.</span></i></p>
<p><i>Nancy tumbled once, but now she’s back. The things she’s experienced&#8230; </i><i>they change a person. The children under Miss West’s care understand all too well. And each of them is seeking a way back to their own fantasy world.</i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">But Nancy’s arrival marks a change at the Home. There’s a darkness just around each corner, and when tragedy strikes, it’s up to Nancy and her new-found schoolmates to get to the heart of the matter.</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aliens and galaxies far, far away: who are the others?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/aliens-and-galaxies-far-far-away-who-are-the-others/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria V]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 11:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Freedom, Books, Flowers, & the Moon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Can&#8217;t you recognize the human in the inhuman?” Ray Bradbury, The Martian Chronicles No matter&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: right;"><em>“Can&#8217;t you recognize the human in the inhuman?”</em><br />
Ray Bradbury, The Martian Chronicles</p>
<p>No matter if you&#8217;re a science-fiction enthusiast or if you’ve only watched a handful of movies about laser battles in outer space because your friends made you do it — if you’re my friend, then probably I made you do it — I’m sure all of us are already acquainted with stories about aliens. We have all heard stories about mysterious sightings, or have been scared to death at night, hiding under our sheets, only waiting for the moment a flying saucer would come down from the sky and abduct us or the ones that we love. We’ve all watched ET the Extraterrestrial, and we’re all well acquainted with Ancient Aliens. No matter your literary tastes, aliens are part of our imaginary, and even exert a certain fascination on us.<br />
<em>But why?</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24650 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/aliens-300x263.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="263" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/aliens-300x263.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/aliens.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>It could seem an easy answer at first. We humans understand the world through narratives, since the beginning of time, and these stories are the closest we’ll probably get to peeking into the universe of things we don’t understand: death, life, love, magic, mysteries. Looking up at the starry sky at night can be a beautiful, yet frightening experience. What &#8216;s up there? Are we alone? What would be more terrifying: knowing that we are all by ourselves in the middle of the infinitude of the universe, or knowing that, somewhere among all of those stars, someone — someone so different from us that we can’t even begin to imagine — is looking back at us at our little blue dot?</p>
<p>But, as everything in life, I’d say that there’s more to it. Yes, our will to explore and to know makes us look at the sky and wonder, just like it made humans who lived centuries ago look at the ocean and wonder what was on the other side of it. But why haven’t our stories changed? Just like the ancient people, who imagined monsters roaming across unknown lands and pictured foreign people as barbarians, almost inhuman, the main portrait of the beings who would live beyond our Solar System is still surrounded by an aura of strangeness — and, often, of an implicit threat.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24647 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jonathan-mabey-GJRaeuEPJ5Y-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jonathan-mabey-GJRaeuEPJ5Y-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jonathan-mabey-GJRaeuEPJ5Y-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jonathan-mabey-GJRaeuEPJ5Y-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jonathan-mabey-GJRaeuEPJ5Y-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/jonathan-mabey-GJRaeuEPJ5Y-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Think of an alien movie — any movie. Chances are that plot which came to your mind revolves around a mysterious event that later becomes an invasion that threatens the human way of living, and that humankind has to come together and fight against those strange newcomers who don’t look like us, or speak our language, or even think like us.<br />
Now, think about any event in history — big or small, recent or distant — in which two different cultures or civilizations came into touch, and you’ll start to understand what I mean.</p>
<p>Yes, our imagination can take us to wonderful distant places, but there’s always an anchor connecting us to reality. We can’t completely escape the context in which we are immersed, and some of it will always make an appearance in our stories, no matter if it’s the way of telling them, the words we use, a different lesson at the end.</p>
<p>Stories about aliens are no different. The idea of an other has always fascinated us: what would our complete opposite look like? That thought has accompanied us throughout history. If you stop and think, the definitions of who we are are often supported by the idea of who we aren’t. <em>We were born here, we’re not foreigners. We’re civilized, we’re not barbarians.</em> Countries and people have been shaped by these ideas, and it’s not a surprise that they made their way into our fictional imaginary.</p>
<p>The biggest example of it, in my opinion, is (wait for it): Ancient Aliens. I know, it’s funny and all of us, including myself, already had a good laugh with the absurd conspiracy theories. But why are only some civilizations associated with aliens? It’s not a coincidence that these people are seen as strange and different by Western eyes. Why did aliens have to help build Ancient Egypt, but not Ancient Rome? Why “we” could have done it by “ourselves,” but not “them?”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-24648 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tom-podmore-TG1OTMcn5Qk-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tom-podmore-TG1OTMcn5Qk-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tom-podmore-TG1OTMcn5Qk-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tom-podmore-TG1OTMcn5Qk-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tom-podmore-TG1OTMcn5Qk-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/tom-podmore-TG1OTMcn5Qk-unsplash.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>We won’t undo this way of thinking in a few months or years, but I like to think and say that we who enjoy speculative fiction, we have a part of ourselves that insists on believing that another world, filled with other narratives, is possible. A world like the one Becky Chambers has imagined in <em>The Long Way to a Small Angry Planet</em> (yes, I’ll talk about this book every single time I can), in which the only way out is collaboration and genuine understanding between completely different species and individuals. Or stories like <em>Arrival</em> (2016), in which science is more important than war, in which communicating is more important than fighting. Different ways of seeing space and time are possible. Different ways of seeing ourselves and the others are possible. But for that, we first have to know the ground from where we’re standing.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-24649 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/arrival-300x128.jpg" alt="" width="349" height="149" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/arrival-300x128.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/arrival-768x328.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/arrival.jpg 888w" sizes="(max-width: 349px) 100vw, 349px" /></p>
<p>I still continue to enjoy science-fiction movies about humans exploring outer space. I’ll still read about different planets populated by each writer’s unique imagination of different ways of life. But thinking about the stories we tell ourselves can bring us some of the answers we often ask the stars: <em>who are we? Where do we come from? And where are we going?</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SFF beyond borders: an interview with Jana Bianchi</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/sff-beyond-borders-an-interview-with-jana-bianchi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria V]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 12:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Freedom, Books, Flowers, & the Moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22965</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Growing up as a kid in Brazil, I’ve always been passionate about speculative fiction. But,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="g">
<div class="tF2Cxc" data-hveid="CAYQAA" data-ved="2ahUKEwjo3N3x5OHuAhW_GbkGHWuWAw4QFSgAMAJ6BAgGEAA">
<div class="IsZvec">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Growing up as a kid in Brazil, I’ve always been passionate about speculative fiction. But, until some time ago, all of my references and favorite stories came from abroad — and from very specific places in the world. This is why I’m so enthusiastic about discovering new authors and stories from places I don’t often see in “traditional” fiction. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This month, I’ve interviewed Jana Bianchi: she’s a Brazilian writer and translator, who has experience not only roaming between the territories of national and foreign SF&amp;F, but also promoting Brazilian authors and their homemade stories. You can find Jana on Twitter and Instagram (@janapbianchi).</span></p>
<p><b>Q. Which are your thoughts on the duality between the universality of narratives in speculative fiction and the particular experiences of each culture?</b></p>
<p>A. Woah, this is a very good question!</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignright" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1609348445241-5864562c7a4c?ixid=MXwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHw%3D&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1000&amp;q=80" /><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think they are two sides of the same coin. Reading is all about identifying yourself with characters in fictional contexts. However — and fortunately — empathy allows us to still be touched by stories that don’t reflect experiences exactly identical to ours (which happens more often than we think).</span></p>
</div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is true to all genres of literature, but I think it’s much more evident </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">in speculative fiction. If you want to fully enjoy a story about, say, a spaceship pilot or a dragon hunter, you start from a point where you necessarily need to detach yourself from your reality. What happens is that many readers — especially those who focus only on the mainstream SFF anglophone market — search for elements they already know instead of just enjoying different kinds of stories and connecting with them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Don’t get me wrong: structure <i>is </i>important, but there’s not such a thing as a single formula you need to use in order to write a good story. It’s also a well-known fact that different cultures have very different ways of telling them. Sometimes, readers mistake this lack of standardized structures for the impossibility of connecting with a particular cultural experience that doesn’t belong to them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In conclusion, the universality of narratives is the “what;” the particular experiences of each culture is the “how.” If writers and readers are willing to understand that, I believe they’ll produce, enjoy, and learn from stories that approach very universal issues under different points of view. We really need to do it more often, and it’s definitely a win-win situation once you open up your mind.</span></p>
<p><b>Q. Would you tell us about some of your experiences with translation? What are the biggest challenges and the most rewarding moments?</b></p>
<p>A. I’m very passionate about translation, so I hope the answer is not too cheesy.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, translating is not only converting a bunch of words in a language into another bunch of words in a different language — that’s more or less what Google Translator does, and everybody who tried to use it at least once to translate a piece of fiction knows it’s not exactly effective. Translating is all about sensibility: translators need to understand both cultures, and, using all of their knowledge about the different languages, they must try to build a new work which will convey what the original piece does as accurately as possible. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m not talking only about meaning or the plot, but also about form, cadence, musicality, humor, atmosphere… It’s not always possible to be totally accurate, so translating is also understanding when it’s time to let some things go and accept you’re also writing something new.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> <img decoding="async" class="alignleft" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1589742180935-1d2c008bf593?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MXwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHw%3D&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1000&amp;q=80" alt="white printer paper on brown wooden table" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Curiously, the biggest challenges and the most rewarding moments almost always come together: usually, they both happen when there are very specific cultural references in the original which need to be heavily worked out to have the same effect in the language you’re translating to — or even to have an effect at all.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I translate to Brazilian Portuguese, which is my native language and the language I love with my heart. It’s also an extremely rich, beautiful, and complex language, packed with a heavy historical load, regionalisms, and crazy grammatical rules. Every time I’m able to find a precise, elegant construction in Portuguese to express something the original authors said in English or Spanish (the languages from which I translate), I feel like a very competent paleontologist who successfully unburied a whole dinosaur fossil by using all their complex-but-delicate tools.</span></p>
<p><b>Q. You have been involved with many projects related to SFF in Brazil. In your opinion, why is it so important to value national speculative fiction in countries that traditionally “import” the genre? </b></p>
<p>A. I think all cultures are equally valid when it comes to telling stories — whether the aim is their own internal public or a broad international audience. But every culture not only can or should, but <i>deserves </i>to produce good local fiction.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fiction is an extremely important tool to understand ourselves as part of a society, and I think it’s very risky to rely too much on external lenses when doing this — especially if we talk about the lenses of colonizing cultures. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once again, don’t get me wrong: importing stories is totally legit, and it’s also part of understanding our place in the world. I would never suggest anybody to abstain themselves of reading foreign stories — my work as a translator is essentially based on this attempt to make external literature available to a local public.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, as we’ve discussed, it’s not always possible to translate all of the nuances of a certain point of view. Sometimes, you really need to get it from the source. </span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignleft" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1524311583145-d5593bd3502a?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MXwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHw%3D&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1000&amp;q=80" alt="person carrying backpack inside library" /><span style="font-weight: 400;">I believe we need balance between foreign and local SF&amp;F, which means we also need a mature market to allow our own fiction to thrive — here and, why not, even abroad. This is why I keep writing and publishing in Brazil and working so close with local literary projects like magazines, cons, and podcasts/channels — although I also write and publish in English and try to get as acquainted to the anglophone market as I can. </span></p>
<p><b>Q. Last but not least: do you have any tips for writers who don’t have English as a first language, especially the ones coming from backgrounds that are underrepresented in the international scenario, and who want to publish abroad?</b></p>
<p>A. I do—but rather as a peer than as an expert.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I say this because I still struggle when I write in English; I feel like I’m a kid writing a school essay. At some point, I second-guess every word I use, it’s terrible. I’m a kind of later learner compared to other people from my age — I couldn’t even read a simple book in English before I was 16 or 17. I lived abroad for half a year and, later, I worked as an engineer for a multinational company, but it took me 10 years or so to start using the language to write fiction.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, my main tip is exactly what I’m doing now to improve my own prose: go ahead and read a ton of good fiction in English, all kinds of it, preferably written by native speakers (and preferably from diverse points of views). A friend of mine also taught me to “collect” expressions from fiction written by natives — whenever you find a construction you like, and which you probably would never use yourself, register it in a file. You don’t need to translate it, just try to absorb it as it is, and later try to apply it in your own work. It means you get to be very curious too, always searching for expressions you don’t know, even if you can get the general meaning from context.</span></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignright" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1527784281695-866fa715d9d8?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=MXwxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHw%3D&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1000&amp;q=80" alt="black retractable pen on opened book beside red and white go get'em-printed coffee cup" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Another tip is not to be afraid of rejection just because you’re not a native English speaker. I mean, yes, you can have a story rejected because your prose is not that good, and it’s fine. But believe me: lots of native speakers also get rejected, and they don’t feel discouraged at all by </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">this specific issue.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your writing will never, ever be totally ready, so see rejections as a part of growing and improving it. If you decide to submit stories to the market only when your prose is “good enough,” you’ll probably end up not submitting at all. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So do e</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">xactly what you should do if you’re a native writer: try to learn with the criticism you think is valid and keep going!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">***</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Jana Bianchi is a Brazilian writer, translator, editor at Mafagafo magazine, co-hostess of the Curta Ficção writing podcast, and werewolf walker. Besides her novella Lobo de Rua (2016), her fiction has appeared, in Portuguese, in several Brazilian collections and magazines. In English, her work has been published before or is forthcoming at Strange Horizons, Clarkesworld, and Fireside. She lives in the countryside of São Paulo with her parents, a family of<em> mafagafos</em>, two dogs, and her many animated tattoos. Find her online at @janapbianchi on Twitter/Instagram.</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reimagined Realities</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reimagined-realities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria V]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 13:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Freedom, Books, Flowers, & the Moon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22566</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the things I’ve missed (and am missing) the most during confinement was my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the things I’ve missed (and am missing) the most during confinement was my city. Yes, I’m an introvert who likes to spend time hiding in libraries and bookshops. But I guess spending months and months locked inside an apartment changes something, and I often find myself thinking how much I miss people and how much I miss walking around. (Maybe I’ll change my mind in the distant future, when things “go back to normal” and I have to face my worst enemies, hills and heat, to get to any destination, but let’s ignore this for today. Poetic license, right?). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22569 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ostap-senyuk-k1Ic9QFdSF4-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ostap-senyuk-k1Ic9QFdSF4-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ostap-senyuk-k1Ic9QFdSF4-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ostap-senyuk-k1Ic9QFdSF4-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ostap-senyuk-k1Ic9QFdSF4-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ostap-senyuk-k1Ic9QFdSF4-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cities have always fascinated me, but recently I’ve created the theory that this happens because all of them carry something magical. All cities, no matter how big or small, are a confluence of experiences, different stories coming together. Have you already wondered how many lives exist behind a window, or inside the building next to your own home? (I have, and thanks to this I’ve developed a new hobby during quarantine, which is staring at the buildings and houses and making up short stories for the people who live there. I swear it’s not as weird as it sounds). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22568 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/liam-mcgarry-sWOAUA1M8KY-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/liam-mcgarry-sWOAUA1M8KY-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/liam-mcgarry-sWOAUA1M8KY-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/liam-mcgarry-sWOAUA1M8KY-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/liam-mcgarry-sWOAUA1M8KY-unsplash-1229x1536.jpg 1229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/liam-mcgarry-sWOAUA1M8KY-unsplash-1638x2048.jpg 1638w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/liam-mcgarry-sWOAUA1M8KY-unsplash-scaled.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />How many invisible, undiscovered cities are hidden under the route we take every day to work or to school? Maybe the present meets the past (and even the future, who knows?), on a forgotten corner next to a friend’s place, or on a funny monument we’ve never bothered to watch. Or, maybe, at a little alley we always pass by and never enter, lives someone with an extraordinary life story, or that shares an unusual interest with us.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cities draw me so much because they share something with human life that also amazes me: possibility. What are stories if not an exploration of possibilities? Is there something more magical and more fantastic than knowing that a whole new world lies ahead of us, and can be found even in the most familiar of places?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And, in the end, we find out that, no matter how far or close we are from the cities that have changed us, we will always carry some parts of them in our hearts. Because cities, as almost everything, are made of stories, narratives. As writer </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mia_Couto"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mia Couto</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> says: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“My city wasn’t only a physical place; it was also an entity that had told me stories. My city belongs more to words than to earth, and the places we love always belong more to language than to geography”. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perhaps that is the most magical of it all: knowing that the people we love and places we are made of will always be within our reach—no matter if we’re 6 feet apart, or have to temporarily see the street from behind a glass window.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22570 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/per-loov-Bs4BebcmLec-unsplash-300x236.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="236" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/per-loov-Bs4BebcmLec-unsplash-300x236.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/per-loov-Bs4BebcmLec-unsplash-1024x805.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/per-loov-Bs4BebcmLec-unsplash-768x604.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/per-loov-Bs4BebcmLec-unsplash-1536x1208.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/per-loov-Bs4BebcmLec-unsplash-2048x1611.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, magic lies around us, and nowhere better to find it than in the tales we listen and tell. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/world/year-in-pictures.html">2020 has not been easy</a>. I’ve taken refuge in stories, as I believe other people also have: they have distracted me, made me think, and even comforted me when I needed it. But they also have helped me see that the most important stories are here, around us, happening as I write. That history is made by people, and that each one of them carries their own endless universes within. This is what makes not only cities, but also life, so fantastic. And there is nothing more important or precious than that. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I hope that the brand new year brings us new stories and possibilities—to read, to write, but mostly to live. Happy holidays!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s it all for?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/whats-it-all-for/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria V]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 11:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Freedom, Books, Flowers, & the Moon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=21920</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I don’t know about you, but I’ve been doomscrolling a lot: my addiction to information&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don’t know about you, but I’ve been doomscrolling </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">a lot</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">: my addiction to information and the fact that I’ve been stuck at home for seven months (and counting) don’t help me fight this habit. Every time I promise myself I’ll check Twitter for five minutes or just read the headlines, I come out of the Internet feeling tired just from knowing what is going on. And it isn’t just me: I’ve been noticing, more and more, people around me succumb to a feeling of generalized tiredness, which, I dare to say, isn’t limited only to my internet bubble of progressive Brazilians. It was perfectly summarized by a cartoon by one of my favorite artists, cartoonist and screenwriter </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laerte"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Laerte</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">:</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-21922 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/laerte-acabaram-se-os-cartuns-1-300x86.jpg" alt="" width="359" height="103" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/laerte-acabaram-se-os-cartuns-1-300x86.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/laerte-acabaram-se-os-cartuns-1-768x220.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/laerte-acabaram-se-os-cartuns-1.jpg 972w" sizes="(max-width: 359px) 100vw, 359px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re in the middle of the battle and we ran out of cartoons!</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I sometimes joke that my best writing happens when I’m angry. But, if the impending sense of doom once made me want to sit down and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">do something</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, now all I can feel is a paralyzing sense of uselessness and of tiredness. I turn on the news: climate change is knocking on our door, authoritarianism is on the rise, fundamental human rights are being violated right under our noses, a pandemic with no signs of stopping is taking a gigantic toll out there. No one can know what will happen tomorrow, but for sure our perspectives aren’t looking good.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Then what’s the point?” I, and I believe many other people out there, find myself asking, consciously or unconsciously, over and over again. What’s the point of trying to make your voice heard, of showing what you see from where you stand, of making a change, little by little?  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The answer — or at least the key for an answer — might be in one of my favorite (if not my very favorite) science fiction subgenre: hopepunk. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21926 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/51BhQZOH9zL-195x300.jpg" alt="" width="195" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/51BhQZOH9zL-195x300.jpg 195w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/51BhQZOH9zL.jpg 325w" sizes="(max-width: 195px) 100vw, 195px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Alexandra Rowland, the person who coined the term: “the opposite of grimdark is hopepunk. The essence of grimdark is that everyone’s inherently sort of a bad person and does bad things (&#8230;), it’s looking at human nature and going ‘The glass is half empty’. Hopepunk says, ‘No, I don’t accept that. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yeah</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, we are a messy mix of good and bad, flaws and virtues. We’ve all been mean and petty and cruel, but we’ve also been forgiving and kind.” It’s understanding, as Becky Chambers puts it on her book (also one of my all time favorites) <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22733729-the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet">The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet</a>, that “you are capable of anything. Good or bad. That darkness exists within all of us (&#8230;) and all any of us can do is work to be something positive instead, to decide what part we’ll play.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sounds naïve? I know. But what if that’s all we’ve got? What if, in this moment when we all feel we’re spreading ourselves too thin and that, no matter what or how much we do, it won’t be worth anything, the key is to insist on seeing the glass half full? Fighting and hoping and believing might seem pointless, and some days, or more days, it seems like we’re swimming against the tide and struggling to reach something that never arrives. But, what if the fighting and hoping and believing is a reason itself? “Utopia is on the horizon,” says Uruguayan writer <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eduardo_Galeano">Eduardo Galeano</a>. “I move two steps closer; it moves two steps further away. I walk another ten steps and the horizon runs ten steps further away. As much as I may walk, I’ll never reach it. So what’s the point of utopia? The point is: to keep walking.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21924 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jens-johnsson-36a3U4_UUHY-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jens-johnsson-36a3U4_UUHY-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jens-johnsson-36a3U4_UUHY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jens-johnsson-36a3U4_UUHY-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jens-johnsson-36a3U4_UUHY-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/jens-johnsson-36a3U4_UUHY-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Galeano has nothing to do with hopepunk, but he captures the spirit of hope — something Latin Americans and many other people around the world have relied on across the decades and centuries of injustice. Hope: the only alternative for many of the ones who came before you and I, and who decided to keep moving towards the unachievable, who decided to believe in an utopia because there is still something worth fighting for.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The point is not to change the world. The point is not to be the Chosen One who will wipe evil away while brandishing a sword. The point is to understand that, sometimes, to keep moving is enough. To be stubborn and to insist on seeing the molecules of goodness and kindness and beauty amid the chaos is an act of bravery itself. And, in times like ours, it’s more than enough. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So what’s the point? There might not be an answer, and if all we have is each other, we cannot let each other go, no matter how messy and hopeless humankind may seem. No matter how we make a stand, with art, with kindness, with refusing to give up now, we all have moments when we ask ourselves if it’s really worth it. No matter how we make a stand, not losing hope is an act of bravery.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are where we are thanks to the ones who came before us and didn’t give up. Then, why not us? Why not now? </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21928 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ross-findon-mG28olYFgHI-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ross-findon-mG28olYFgHI-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ross-findon-mG28olYFgHI-unsplash-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ross-findon-mG28olYFgHI-unsplash-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ross-findon-mG28olYFgHI-unsplash-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/ross-findon-mG28olYFgHI-unsplash-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">***</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A last note: take some time to read </span><a href="https://festive.ninja/one-atom-of-justice-one-molecule-of-mercy-and-the-empire-of-unsheathed-knives-alexandra-rowland/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alexandra Rowland’s excellent article on hopepunk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Trust me, it’ll be better than doomscrolling.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notes on a Tomorrow That Might Not Come</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/notes-on-a-tomorrow-that-might-not-come/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria V]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Freedom, Books, Flowers, & the Moon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Everyone who is a stationary enthusiast, like myself, knows that organizing drawers is at the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everyone who is a stationary enthusiast, like myself, knows that organizing drawers is at the same time a nightmare and a delight. You suddenly find yourself overwhelmed by piles and piles of notebooks and notepads you never knew that existed — maybe you don’t need another pretty journal, after all… but </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">why not? </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">— but it pays off when you find something precious among your old notes. The last time I dared to deal with what I call my “chaos cabinet”, my hard work was rewarded with finding a quote that I had scribbled a few years ago on the first piece of paper at the reach of my hand, while reading Ray Bradbury’s </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Something_Wicked_This_Way_Comes_(novel)"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Something wicked this way comes</span></i></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">: “our hour is short, eternity is long.” These words have a special place inside me since then, but they have been particularly resonating in my thoughts during the last days.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the past weeks, Brazilians have been watching yet another tragedy take place in our country: the </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/gallery/2020/sep/17/brazil-pantanal-wetlands-on-fire-in-pictures"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pantanal</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> biome, the world’s largest flooded wetland, which encompasses a unique biodiversity as well as a rich </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">traditional culture, is burning</span> — fires have been set in order to clean the terrain for agriculture, and they’re nowhere close to being controlled. <span style="font-weight: 400;">Pictures of raging flames and wounded animals have taken over my social media, as well as pleas for help from environmentalists and from the inhabitants of the Pantanal. </span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19733 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/roi-dimor-AEQ-166CWY8-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/roi-dimor-AEQ-166CWY8-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/roi-dimor-AEQ-166CWY8-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/roi-dimor-AEQ-166CWY8-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/roi-dimor-AEQ-166CWY8-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/roi-dimor-AEQ-166CWY8-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once more, our patrimony succumbs to flames </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> under the negligent watch of the national government — it’s not my intent to dive into this situation, and all I have to say is that it makes it even harder to swallow. I</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">t is, without doubt, heartbreaking and despairing to witness all of this with hands tied behind our backs, but at this point you may be asking yourself what does that have to do with time and Ray Bradbury. Well, I’m mo</span>re and more convinced that what’s at stake isn’t ““only”” the diversity of the Brazilian Pantanal. This is, also, a tragedy involving time — one could say it’s a tragedy that trespasses time, and to know that it’s happening so close to home, instead of in an apocalyptic science-fiction movie, is what scares me the most.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What is a legacy?” Lin-Manuel Miranda’s Hamilton asks himself (on a lighter note, I know I’m late to the party, but now that I finally put my hands on the movie, I, a history nerd and musical theater fan, won’t stop talking about it anytime soon). “It’s planting seeds in a garden you’ll never get </span>to see.” Because our hour is short, but eternity isn’t limited to it — and, no matter how cruel and brief our time may be, it allows us to all leave something behind. No matter how big or small, I find the idea of leaving something behind, something that will outlive us, beautiful. Maybe it’s someone’s words that reach new readers across space and time, who’ll give them new meanings. Maybe it’s someone’s ideas that’ll only make sense a long time after their own time is up. Maybe it’s what we call art, what we call science, what we call history. Maybe it’s even finding traces of a version of yourself which no longer exist on the pages of a long lost notebook. Yes, we are bound to time, but to be in the present means to be in a constant dialogue with the past, with the legacy that was left to us, and, why not, to be confronted, once in a while, that there will be a tomorrow. This scares us, sometimes, such as all the things we don’t quite understand, but it’s also something that we rely on. And, above everything, something that we always take for granted.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19732 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aron-visuals-BXOXnQ26B7o-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><span style="font-weight: 400;">What happens when the idea of a future itself becomes uncertain? We often compare the current state of our world with dystopias, but what if we’re closer to living inside a story about time? We all have read books or watched movies about time-travelers who mess with time: in the end, they learn not only that they shouldn’t change the past, but that fiddling with the future comes at a price, too. And what is sacrificing complex ecosystems in the name of profit but to do it? With the major Brazilian biomes at risk — unfortunately, it’s not only the Pantanal that’s at stake, but the </span><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-53893161"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amazon rainforest</span> </a><span style="font-weight: 400;">and the </span><a href="https://flixable.com/title/old-lord-savanna/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cerrado savanna</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> too — I can’t help but feel that I’</span>m living the part of a story when humans decide to play chess with what we can’t grasp or understand. All of us who have read a little bit of speculative fiction know how this ends.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ll never be sure of the consequences of destruction. We can’t know wh</span>at losing at least 15% of a biome means. 85% of the biggest reserve of <i>onças-pintadas</i>, the famous Brazilian jaguars, has succumbed to the flames — will this play a role in where we are in ten, twenty, fifty years from now on? How about the traditional communities who are losing the lands from which countless generations have made a living throughout history? We always talk about how the end of the world seems to be approaching, sometimes jokingly, sometimes with genuine worry, but we can’t forget that, for some people, it has already begun — and a long time ago.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19734 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/birger-strahl-0bvFdV4KDnA-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/birger-strahl-0bvFdV4KDnA-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/birger-strahl-0bvFdV4KDnA-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/birger-strahl-0bvFdV4KDnA-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/birger-strahl-0bvFdV4KDnA-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/birger-strahl-0bvFdV4KDnA-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We can never know what sacrificing our possibilities of a future means. A</span>round the world, the concerns about sustainability and our relationship with the environment are growing as we realize that our predatory attitude towards what sustains and nurtures life as we know it is a threat that challenges more than we sometimes first think.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I hope that it’s not too late to understand something that the indigenous leader </span><a href="http://ethicalfashionbrazil.com/book-ideas-to-postpone-the-end-of-the-world-by-ailton-krenak/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ailton Krenak</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has already anticipated: “tomorrow is not for sale”. However, as I write this, the garden where we should be sowing the seeds of what&#8217;s yet to come is disappearing under a trail of fire.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Life, Death, and Our Shared Humanity</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/life-death-and-our-shared-humanity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria V]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 20:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Freedom, Books, Flowers, & the Moon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Any man’s death diminishes me, because I am involved in mankind, and therefore never send&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>&#8220;Any man’s death diminishes me, because I am involved in mankind, and therefore never send to know for whom the bells tolls; it tolls for thee.&#8221;<br />
(John Donne)</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-latin-america-53712087">Brazil</a>, the country where I live, hit the sad mark of 100,000 coronavirus deaths in the weekend when I’m writing this column. It’s the 9th of August. I know this information will be out of date when I send this text to the editors, and even more when it’s published, but, still sometimes I<br />
wonder if it actually matters: my country and so many others have reached a point where the death count doesn’t change the size of the tragedies anymore, and this, perhaps, is the biggest of them all. What to do when human lives, what we have of most precious, dissolve into faceless<br />
numbers?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-19547 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/blog.jpg" alt="" width="180" height="271" />We might not have an answer, but, as always, literature may offer us some clues. This time, like many others, I found it in <a href="https://www.nobelprize.org/prizes/literature/2015/alexievich/facts/">Svetlana Aleksiévitch</a>’s books: she’s the 2015 Nobel Prize winner, and writes about the stories of common people who experienced key events of the Soviet history. In The unwomanly face of war, where she registers the memories of the women who lived and fought during World War II, she reflects: “I try to reduce the big history to a human scale to try to understand something. But it seems that, in this small territory that’s comfortable to look at — the space of a human soul — everything is yet more incomprehensible, less previsible than in history. I have in front of me tears and feelings that are alive. A face that is alive, that is human, crossed by shadows of pain and fear as we talk” (free translation). This excerpt always touches me: as a history enthusiast, the events I find myself studying once in a while take a whole new dimension when I stop to think that real people, with real lifes, hopes, fears and dreams were involved. And now, during this pandemic, when it’s so easy to be swallowed by data and news, I go back to Aleksiévitch’s words and try to never forget what those numbers really mean.</p>
<p>And, in the middle of all of this, literature (and arts, in general), have been a real life-saver for me. Not only because they provide some great moments going from distraction to reflection, but because they help me to better understand our shared humanity. What are stories but an exercise of empathy? We put ourselves in someone else’s shoes for four hundred pages or two hours and a half, and we laugh, cry, worry and sigh in relief for those people we will never know and often don’t even exist. We do this because we are human, and see a little of our humanity reflected in those works — we do this because humans have always been storytellers before anything else, and because narratives are the best way we have of understanding the world<br />
around us. And when we lose sight of the stories that happen around us, of all of the pain and tragedies that a pandemic brings, and of the colossal loss any number of deaths represent, we lose a little of our shared humanity. I hear discussions about what the “ideal” number of obits would be, and the answer is none: and this applies to everything, not only to covid-19. Every life <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-19548 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/blog2.jpg" alt="" width="277" height="183" />is of an incalculable worth, and their loss means a tragedy of its own. Take a moment of your day and read the stories of the frontline workers and of the victim’s families and friends, and you’ll understand.</p>
<p>I wished I could write about books, movies or even some event of my personal life that would be an interesting topic to this column. But when I sit down in front of the keyboard, or with pen and paper in my hands, I can’t think of anything else. Which, here between us, is not that bad. It’s important to take a time off to breathe and rest, but it’s also crucial to never lose sight of the reality around us. As fiction readers and writers, we are used to wandering among worlds that could be, but we should never forget the world that is: not only to imagine different futures and possibilities, but mostly because, before being readers, writers and anything else, we are human. I hope this column will work as a little reminder of it in such turbulent times.</p>
<p>May those who lost loved ones find peace and comfort, and may all of us who stay keep moving with courage and love. As Aleksiévitch reminds us: “there is only one way: to love the human being. Understand it through love.” May we never lose sight of that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Towards a Utopia of Life</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/towards-a-utopia-of-life/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wordpress]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 10:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Freedom, Books, Flowers, & the Moon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Humans are storytellers. We understand the world through symbols and, even before societies developed complex&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Humans are storytellers. We understand the world through symbols and, even before societies developed complex forms of organization and thought, such as science and politics, they had already built narratives that would explain the world around them: stories that we now call “mythology.” Myths are, essentially, stories that reflect the meaning and importance of<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19233 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1024px-Prometheus_by_Gustave_Moreau-178x300.jpg" alt="" width="178" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1024px-Prometheus_by_Gustave_Moreau-178x300.jpg 178w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1024px-Prometheus_by_Gustave_Moreau-609x1024.jpg 609w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1024px-Prometheus_by_Gustave_Moreau-768x1292.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1024px-Prometheus_by_Gustave_Moreau-913x1536.jpg 913w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1024px-Prometheus_by_Gustave_Moreau.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 178px) 100vw, 178px" /> the things around us, that set the stones for the reality we live in and prepare us to face the complexity of life and human relationships. This goes for everything from Greek tragedies, to the Bible, to even the narrative of the French Revolution &#8212; and it’s important to add here that I’m not questioning whether these stories are real or not. What matters is that, at some degree, they teach us how to deal with ourselves and with each other. They are tales of kindness and tales of horror, that show us how far human beings can go, that make us face situations of almost impossible choices, that help us understand where our world has come from and, in the end, in which direction our world should go.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-19234" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/bloodchild-196x300.jpg" alt="" width="168" height="257" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/bloodchild-196x300.jpg 196w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/bloodchild.jpg 310w" sizes="(max-width: 168px) 100vw, 168px" />Very few stories we have today allow us to understand the reality that surrounds us, which grows only more and more complex, and the ones that do so end up forgotten or ignored. Our civilization, then, is adrift, despite its immense technological and scientific knowledge, because it doesn’t know how to deal with what is human. When progress detaches itself from humanity, it’s easy to lose sight of what really matters. It’s not rare to see people commenting on how it feels like we’re living in a dystopian world. Manipulation and surveillance remind us of George Orwell’s 1984; the rising anti-intellectualism takes us back to the world Ray Bradbury imagined in Fahrenheit 451; and exploration, oppression, and the dynamics of power make Octavia Butler’s <em>Bloodchild</em> feel strangely close to home, for example. What all of these have in common is the denial of the inherent characteristics of life: diversity, community, complexity, love. And this allows all kinds of tragedies to happen &#8212; in fiction as much as in reality.</p>
<p>In what is one of the most beautiful texts I’ve ever read, Gabriel García Márquez’s Nobel Prize lecture, he says &#8220;On a day like today, my master William Faulkner said, &#8216;I decline to accept the end of man&#8217;. I would fall unworthy of standing in this place that was his, if I were not fully aware that the colossal tragedy he refused to recognize thirty-two years ago is now, for the first time since the beginning of humanity, nothing more than a simple scientific possibility. Faced with this awesome reality that must have seemed a mere utopia through all of human time, we, the inventors of tales, who will believe anything, feel entitled to believe that it is not yet too late to engage in the creation of the opposite utopia. A new and sweeping utopia of life, where no one will be able to decide for others how they die, where love will prove true and happiness be possible, and where the races condemned to one hundred years of solitude will have, at last and forever, a second opportunity on earth.&#8221;</p>
<p>We’re in a delicate moment of change: we’re standing at the threshold of a differ<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19235 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-of-person-standing-on-temple-2659475-223x300.jpg" alt="" width="223" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-of-person-standing-on-temple-2659475-223x300.jpg 223w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-of-person-standing-on-temple-2659475-762x1024.jpg 762w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-of-person-standing-on-temple-2659475-768x1032.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-of-person-standing-on-temple-2659475-1143x1536.jpg 1143w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-of-person-standing-on-temple-2659475-1524x2048.jpg 1524w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/photo-of-person-standing-on-temple-2659475.jpg 1860w" sizes="(max-width: 223px) 100vw, 223px" />ent<br />
world, be it better or worse than the one we have right now. As readers and writers who believe in all kinds of fantastic situations, we should begin to realize that the reality we live in<br />
is, itself, more fantastic than fiction. I still insist in believing in a possible future in which all voices are heard and in which no one gets left behind, in which life and justice will, at last, prevail. We should, as Márquez and many before and after him did, decline to accept the end of man, and through our stories and narratives, analyze where we’re standing at the same time that we allow ourselves to imagine what kind of reality we’d like to move toward. Creating the founding myths and ideals of this new and sweeping utopia of life is up to us.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
