<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Female Frontier &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-female-frontier/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 02:13:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>A Psalm for the Wild Built by Becky Chambers review</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-psalm-for-the-wild-built-by-becky-chambers-review/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanne Askew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 10:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Female Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26978</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A Psalm for the Wild Built by Becky Chambers If a novella could be prescribed,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>A Psalm for the Wild Built by Becky Chambers</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1600783497l/55077657.jpg" alt="A Psalm for the Wild-Built (Monk &amp;amp; Robot, #1) by Becky Chambers" /></p>
<p>If a novella could be prescribed, it would be this one. Chambers takes every layer of humanity and questions it through the eyes of &#8220;the other,&#8221; whether that be love, life, death, or the way we interact with our natural world.</p>
<p>We enter Chambers&#8217; new world, a world that exists on a moon that suffered a similar fate to where we are heading with our climate crisis; but in this world, on this beautiful moon of Panga (clever reference to our former landmass, Pangaea), humankind have teetered on the edge of extinction and gained enough insight to create a Utopia in which our main characters reside.</p>
<p>Sibling Dex, they/them, is a monk without a purpose. Nothing can satiate the unsettling feeling of being emotionally lost&#8211;that is, until they leave the parts of the moon allocated to human life and venture into the wilds, untouched for a thousand years. But they are not alone, and are soon joined by a wild-built robot named Mosscap with its own agenda.</p>
<p>Chambers creates a kaleidoscope in which we are asked, as readers, to imagine seeing things through the eyes of something else, the other, something created by our own kind who sees the world differently. I struggle with processing my own emotions, and working out what is real and what might be an illusion or a single emotional craving. Being a witness to the monk-and-robot relationship forced me to address my purpose, my role in my own happiness, and my role on this planet.</p>
<p>Respect for nature needs to be embedded into our society as Chambers embeds into her societies. If only Becky Chambers was leading our world, she would lead it into the utopia  science can only dream of.</p>
<p>We can expect more from the Monk and Robot series, with Chambers releasing the next installment in July. &#8220;A Prayer for the Crown Shy&#8221; will follow our beloved Mosscap and Sibling Dex as they seek to answer life&#8217;s greatest questions together.</p>
<p>Grab a cuppa and settle down with this world, it&#8217;s as warm as the tea in your mug.</p>
<p>Find out more about Becky Chambers and the Monk and Robot series <a href="https://www.otherscribbles.com/">here. </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anthologies for the Holiday wish-list</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/anthologies-for-the-holiday-wish-list/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanne Askew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Female Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There will be a permanent indent of my body in one corner of the room&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There will be a permanent indent of my body in one corner of the room when I get my hands on these anthologies.</p>
<p>Anthologies have always been my binge read. Like a good Netflix show, short stories keep me wanting more. The pages turn like rapid gunfire as I lust for each story, one after another like the next one could be one of those stories that stay with you forever and ever.</p>
<p>Here are my most anticipated speculative anthologies that are coming soon, or just out.</p>
<p><strong>Chlorophobia: An Eco-Horror Anthology</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1635420399l/59470847._SY475_.jpg" alt="Chlorophobia: An Eco-Horror Anthology by A.R. Ward" /></p>
<p>This collection of poems and flash fiction is graced by a beautiful cover that communicates everything within. Edited by A. R. Ward, this collection brings together plants, animals, weather phenomena and terror, to shine a light on the horrors of the natural world. With a rise in popularity of eco fiction, this collection is on my must-list to see me into the new year. Authors include the talented Jasmine Arch and Sonora Taylor.</p>
<p>You can get <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B09HHN57NM/ref=x_gr_w_bb_sin?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=x_gr_w_bb_sin_uk-21&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1634&amp;creative=6738">Chlorophobia now.</a></p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>Were Tales: A Shapeshifter Anthology</strong></p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.thisishorror.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/E87xlTCXIAgYVL7-scaled.jpg?fit=1200%2C833&amp;ssl=1" alt="News Round-up Week Ending 24 September 2021 – This Is Horror" width="451" height="313" /></p>
<p>This anthology has been on my kindle waiting for me to dive in. I’m not gonna lie, I wanted to be an Animorph when I was a kid &#8211; who didn’t? The idea of sprouting wings and taking to the sky and being free of everything is surely the draw of this niche area of spec. Delving into these stories of animalistic transformations is worth saving for a stormy day.</p>
<p>Animal transformations rest in many of our societies’ folklore and has always been human’s way of bridging that gap between the unknown creatures of our world, and the safe haven of civilisation.</p>
<p>Buy <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Were-Tales-Shapeshifter-Jonathan-Maberry/dp/B09KF2JSPH/ref=asc_df_B09KF2JSPH/?tag=googshopuk-21&amp;linkCode=df0&amp;hvadid=534907312509&amp;hvpos=&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvrand=4365070189390233138&amp;hvpone=&amp;hvptwo=&amp;hvqmt=&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvdvcmdl=&amp;hvlocint=&amp;hvlocphy=9045316&amp;hvtargid=pla-1462200784028&amp;psc=1&amp;th=1&amp;psc=1#detailBullets_feature_div">Weretales here.</a></p>
<p><strong>Hex-periments: </strong><strong><em>A Dark Biotech Anthology </em></strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1637958999l/59705737._SX318_.jpg" alt="HEX-PERIMENTS by C. J. Tudor" /></p>
<p>Hex-periments is the pun we all needed in anthology form, and it’s a feel-good read. All proceeds go to UK homeless charities who are facing their toughest season yet with UK government cuts to public spending and social care. These authors come together to bite back combining dark science and malice with the otherworldly and occult. This is the perfect anthology for those who love sci-fi and magic, and the kaleidoscope it makes when it twists together inseparably.</p>
<p>These fourteen tales explore the consequences of human intervention when propelled by a dark agenda. With an introduction by C J Tudor, this charity anthology will help the homeless with every penny going towards that cause.</p>
<p>Hex-periments is <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/HEX-PERIMENTS-Anthology-Keith-Anthony-Baird-ebook/dp/B09NF5MKDJ/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=9798767393411&amp;linkCode=qs&amp;qid=1639393794&amp;s=books&amp;sr=1-1">out now.</a></p>
<p><strong>Skulls and Spells</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-26546" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Skulls_and_Spells_Cover_PR-227x300.jpg" alt="Skulls and Spells cover" width="263" height="348" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Skulls_and_Spells_Cover_PR-227x300.jpg 227w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Skulls_and_Spells_Cover_PR.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 263px) 100vw, 263px" /></p>
<p>Skulls and Spells, set for release in early Spring 2022, reached its funding goal in record time (plus stretch goals), as do most of the projects created by Jinx Peregrine (they/them) and Jonas Holt (they/them) from Scottish Indie press, Artemisia&#8217;s Axe. A lot of diverse spec and horror is coming out of Scotland currently, with the likes of Gingernuts of Horror reviewing diverse speculative view points, Luna Press, Dead Ink and 404 Ink publishing underrepresented stories, along with opening submission calls to only underrepresented groups. It’s these publishers that will be thanked for a more diverse future.</p>
<p>Skulls and Spells will be more than just stories. It will bring together 22 creators, including artists, writers and poets from the queer community for a colourful exploration of the theme, “Queer Horror Magic”.</p>
<p>Find out more about <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/skullsandspells/skulls-and-spells-a-queer-horror-anthology">“Skulls and Spells” here.</a></p>
<p><strong>A Women Built by Man </strong></p>
<p>Releasing in early 2022 from Cemetery Gates Media and edited by Elle Turpitt and S.H. Cooper, the anthology, A Woman Built by Man, brings together femme-aligned authors for an exploration into a difficult theme. The stories are based around how a feminine figure is shaped by male hands, what this means for a woman’s narrative, and what ways horror presents this. Horror has always been a genre that explores the far reaches of our societal issues, and this anthology will be no exception.</p>
<p>With the likes of Hailey Piper, Gemma Amor, and Laurel Hightower gracing the contents page, this will be an excellent exploration into what this theme means to some of our favourite women horror authors.</p>
<p>I also have a story in there as well, so pat on the back for me, but really I am just excited to get tucked into this anthology from the heart and souls of the women in the horror industry.</p>
<p>Proceeds from the anthology are heading straight to a women’s aid charity to be announced closer to release.</p>
<p>Watch out for updates from publisher <a href="https://cemeterygatesmedia.com/">Cemetery Gates here.</a></p>
<p><strong>Generation Xed</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="" src="https://img1.wsimg.com/isteam/ip/b565d051-1a01-49d9-972b-ba2cbab4f63b/Gen%20Xed%20eBook%20cover%20WEB.jpg/:/cr=t:0%25,l:0%25,w:100%25,h:100%25/rs=w:400,cg:true" width="222" height="355" /></p>
<p>This anthology, edited by Rebecca Rowland and coming out 26th Jan from Dark Ink pulls together tales from the latchkey generation, AKA Generation X. An interesting perspective in speculative fiction, the unique anthology of monster, folk, paranormal, and psychological horror. Twenty-two authors reveal the cultural demons that lurked in the background while they came of age in the heyday of Satanic panic and slasher flicks, milk carton missing and music television, video rentals and, of course, the feminist punk ideals of riot grrrls.</p>
<p>Horror has always led us down a path to understanding our own society, so with the tagline “Horror written by the authors it created”, it’s no wonder this antho is on my holiday list.</p>
<p>Find out more about it on the <a href="https://rowlandbooks.com/generation-xed#f5bed466-d8ae-4abf-a6cb-8b7d887bb01c">editor’s website here.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>To Be Taught, If Fortunate by Becky Chambers (review)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/to-be-taught-if-fortunate-by-becky-chambers-review/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanne Askew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 11:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Female Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25813</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To Be Taught, If Fortunate, the first novella from award-winning Sci-Fi author Becky Chambers, follows&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>To Be Taught, If Fortunate</em>, the first novella from award-winning Sci-Fi author Becky Chambers, follows Ariadne, an explorer at the turn of the twenty-second century as humans venture into the cosmos studying life and all its forms. The diverse cast work together between bouts of decade-long stasis to catalog life forms on brand new planets.</p>
<p>Chambers is one of the goddesses of sci-fi, inspiring many authors around the globe, such as  myself. She weaves worlds with ease, like the magical fingertips of an all-knowing being. She creates these worlds that invite the wallflowers to a party for the first time in their life. Sci-fi itself can be so heteronormative, despite it being one of the most cutting edge genres, but Chambers has staked her place as THE diversity writer in sci-fi, and for all those readers that found a home in her writing or a family, we won’t forget.</p>
<p>In <em>To Be Taught, If Fortunate </em>Chambers creates a world free of prejudice and allows us to glimpse into the exploration of one of life&#8217;s biggest questions, all the while showing us that love, companionship, and diversity are the things that make the human race so unique, even when faced with an array of strange and slimy creatures. <em>The Guardian</em> described this novella as &#8220;a quietly profound tour de force&#8221;, and they couldn&#8217;t have been more accurate.</p>
<p>For the exploration of the universe, our scientists respect other planets, don’t try to change them, and try to leave no evidence of their visit behind. Cleverly, Chambers has imagined a world where to visit these dangerous planets, we must first change our own bodies. The characters undergo physiological transformation with each planet they visit, so every time they wake, they must re-adapt to their own bodies.</p>
<p>The description of the creatures, big or small or slimy, are so vivid in the novella, that they come back to haunt me in sleepless nights. The sense of isolation is communicated magnificently. I read this mainly in my car on lunch breaks, so it was a deep dive into the abyss every day that held me. We become one of the crew members sent out into the universe of the search for life. We’re not reading a book, we’re reading the notes from the expeditions we join the characters on, and most of all, we share their highs, their lows, and their sheer panic.</p>
<p>The book closes with General Kurt Waldheim’s words from 1977: “As the Secretary General of the United Nations, an organization of the 147 member states who represent almost all of the human inhabitants of the planet earth, I send greetings on behalf of the people of our planet. We step out of our solar system into the universe seeking only peace and friendship, to teach if we are called upon, to be taught if we are fortunate. We know full well that our planet and all its inhabitants are but a small part of the immense universe that surrounds us and it is with humility and hope that we take this step.”</p>
<p><em>To Be Taught, If Fortunate</em> is a one-off contained in its own universes, for now. Becky Chambers’ second novella, <em>A Psalm for the Wild-Built</em>, has recently been released, in what we can expect to be a multi-book series on artificial life.</p>
<p>Both US and UK covers are fantastic, and I have both. You can order your copy of <em>To Be Taught, If Fortunate</em> by Becky Chambers from her website here: <a href="https://www.otherscribbles.com/#/tobetaught/">https://www.otherscribbles.com/#/tobetaught/</a></p>
<figure id="attachment_25814" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25814" style="width: 243px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25814" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9780062936011_700e9cfe-a181-4097-8f6e-10e08e44f6dd-199x300.jpeg" alt="To be Taught, if Fortunate by Becky Chambers" width="243" height="366" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9780062936011_700e9cfe-a181-4097-8f6e-10e08e44f6dd-199x300.jpeg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/9780062936011_700e9cfe-a181-4097-8f6e-10e08e44f6dd.jpeg 430w" sizes="(max-width: 243px) 100vw, 243px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25814" class="wp-caption-text">To be Taught, if Fortunate by Becky Chambers, US EDITION</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_25815" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25815" style="width: 238px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-25815" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/D4brvSFXkAERjhY.jpglarge-194x300.jpg" alt="To be Taught, if Fortunate by Becky Chambers" width="238" height="369" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/D4brvSFXkAERjhY.jpglarge-194x300.jpg 194w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/D4brvSFXkAERjhY.jpglarge-662x1024.jpg 662w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/D4brvSFXkAERjhY.jpglarge-768x1188.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/D4brvSFXkAERjhY.jpglarge-993x1536.jpg 993w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/D4brvSFXkAERjhY.jpglarge.jpg 1324w" sizes="(max-width: 238px) 100vw, 238px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25815" class="wp-caption-text">To be Taught, if Fortunate by Becky Chambers, UK EDITION</figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review of Unburied: A Collection of Queer Dark Fiction</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-of-unburied-a-collection-of-queer-dark-fiction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanne Askew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Female Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pride Month saw the release of horror collection, Unburied, which aimed to showcase LGBTQIA+ talent&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_25173" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25173" style="width: 185px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25173" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FINAL_Unburied-Front-Cover-copy-185x300.png" alt="" width="185" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FINAL_Unburied-Front-Cover-copy-185x300.png 185w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FINAL_Unburied-Front-Cover-copy-632x1024.png 632w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/FINAL_Unburied-Front-Cover-copy.png 707w" sizes="(max-width: 185px) 100vw, 185px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25173" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Unburied</em></figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>Pride Month saw the release of horror collection, <em>Unburied</em>, which aimed to showcase LGBTQIA+ talent in dark fiction and all its glorious subgenres. Disclaimer – my own story appears in the collection but there is plenty to shout about without tooting my own horn.</strong></p>
<p>I found that the women writers in the collection really shone and displayed such an outstanding range across many subjects and tropes. I also found that the stories put queer characters in the spotlight as heroes and protagonists as they should have always been. There is such a varied range of genres and subjects covered in this dark fiction anthology, all dark, all spine-tingling. Editor <a href="https://rowlandbooks.com/">Rebecca Rowland’s</a> proceeds from Pride Month have gone to <a href="https://www.rainbowrailroad.org/">Rainbow Railroad</a>, and the anthology is available <a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Unburied-Collection-Queer-Dark-Fiction/dp/1943201501">here.</a></p>
<p>Firstly, <a href="http://sarahlyn-eaton.blogspot.com/">Sarah Lyn Eaton’s</a> &#8220;When the Dust Settles&#8221; throws us into the recovery of a miner who has lost limbs and we journey with her through recovery. This one tugged at my heartstrings as someone who has experienced a similar thing, along with all the phantom pain, your brain fighting against the physical limitations of your body, feeling that sense of being broken and incomplete, the last thing you want is your recovery to turn into sci-fi terror. Not only was &#8220;When the Dust Settles&#8221; an empowering queer read, I felt like it was an empowering disability read, and something I never knew I craved.</p>
<p><a href="https://iaminyoureyebrain.com/">Laura DeHaan’s</a> &#8220;Open Up and Let Me In&#8221; gave me a continual flow of goosebumps on the back of my neck. We follow an unreliable narrator as we are thrust into the mind of a grieving woman and uncover the events that led up to her trauma, gently guided by the strange image of her wife coaxing us to the truth. DeHaan’s mastery of psychological storytelling leaves us reeling as we reach the climax.</p>
<p>&#8220;Razor, Knife&#8221; by<a href="https://elinolausson.com/"> Elin Olausson</a> is the creepy twins story we all deserve. Elin’s story, &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-moor/">The Moor&#8221;,</a> featured in issue 045 of <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em>, but her <em>Unburied</em> story truly holds a candle to the creepy kids trope we all love. In it, we follow Twiggy and Bell and all their wildness and unpredictability when a new family moves into the local church. The rest involves dark nights, creepy graveyards, and a lusting for something you cannot have.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/christinadeliawriting/">Christina Delia’s</a> &#8220;Moi Aussie&#8221; takes down the Golden Age of Hollywood, specifically the men in it. We hear stories of how women were treated in Hollywood then, and even now, but in this story we see two lesbian ghosts as they implement punishment on Hollywood’s worst offenders. This story sang with ambiance and music, bringing the reader into the dark and devilish world of Hollywood.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/tzrhtjmliem-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25219 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/tzrhtjmliem-300x200.jpg" alt="Marshmello selective color photography" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/tzrhtjmliem-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/tzrhtjmliem-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/tzrhtjmliem-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/tzrhtjmliem-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/tzrhtjmliem-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://theinkblotters.com/">Azzurra Nox’s</a> story, &#8220;Some Kind of Monster&#8221;, takes us into the belly of the beast… literally. Nox’s ability to keep us guessing was showcased in this story. Although one of the shorter tales from the selection, we’re led on a path that keeps us wondering what is real, and what the nightmares bring.</p>
<p>Finally, the outstanding &#8220;1,000 Tiny Cuts&#8221; by <a href="https://veronicakirin.com/books/">Veronica Zora Kirin</a> is a standout of the collection. The story slowly creeps up on you and before you know it, you’re living the nightmare, too. Detailed glimpses into a relationship as it descends into terror shape this tale, and draws on the all-too-familiar anxieties we have about our loved ones and how much love can blind us to red flags. Kirin is a master of pace, tension, and action. We might be seeing this one winning some awards in the future!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Look What You Made Me Do</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/look-what-you-made-me-do/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanne Askew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 14:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Female Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m taking a look at some awesome women characters whose trauma gave birth to their&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>I&#8217;m taking a look at some awesome women characters whose trauma gave birth to their unrivaled power.</strong></p>
<figure style="width: 4096px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/EP4T-PfUYAEkBa5?format=jpg&amp;name=4096x4096" alt="MCU WANDA WANDAVISION" width="4096" height="2304" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The many faces of Wanda</figcaption></figure>
<p>My favorite thing is when a woman enacts her revenge. Whether that be on a small level, or a super-powered disastrous level, it&#8217;s good to see our kick-ass ladies rule.</p>
<p>In <em>Game of Thrones</em>, <em>WandaVision</em>, and <em>Van Helsing</em>, we see women who have come through a lot of trauma and rise as powerful beings. When grief overcomes Queen Daenerys Targaryen over the execution of her beloved translator, Missandei, she destroys the capital of the land with fire, killing thousands. Prior to this, Cersei Lannister had pushed our dragon queen so close to the edge, it was only a matter of time before Daenerys showed her true, unabridged power. Despite the complaints of many on the ending of GOT, it was liberating to see a woman who had been through so much over the course of eight seasons finally let her rage flow, with echoes of &#8220;look what you made me do&#8221; resonating round King&#8217;s Landing.</p>
<figure style="width: 1908px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i.dailymail.co.uk/1s/2019/05/13/04/13423910-0-image-a-36_1557718706336.jpg" alt="Game Of Thrones final episode " width="1908" height="1146" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Our Queen takes down the city at the source of her trauma</figcaption></figure>
<p>Equally, the death of Vision causes grief to consume Wanda, and in that wake, she becomes the villain of Westview. A woman who had spent so much time moving to the beat of others finally has some form of control. I wouldn&#8217;t recommend taking over an entire town, and their minds, as part of the grieving process, but the sense of calm Wanda creates in the mayhem of her grief is beautiful. We see her perfect life, her homely quirks and her desires, it gives her character a chance to slow, to let the audience know her a little more, let you in. The entire hit series is created by Wanda&#8217;s response to her hurt and how she champions that and grows bigger than it. It truly is a show that evolves with each episode and Wanda allows us into her grief process.</p>
<p>On a more serious note, it is common for us to see women persecuted necessarily when reacting to trauma. Far too often we see women incarcerated after finally defending themselves against real-life abusers. There are examples of women being pushed to the very edge, retaliating, and then becoming a villain in the narrative eyes of society. Season Two of <em>The Confession Tapes</em> on Netflix deals with many of these cases, where women needed support from trauma, not a prison sentence. I ask you to listen in to some of these stories, see what domestic violence trauma can do to a person, and discover how much further we need to come in the criminal justice system in understanding trauma and its effect on every person.</p>
<p>As a woman, I love to see woman characters grow and evolve. Sometimes that trauma has a giant impact on their lives, but we know that these women grow much bigger than their trauma. We see them express themselves in powerful ways, beautiful, enchanting in the way their trauma doesn&#8217;t define them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2020 – My Year with Women Creators</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/2020-my-year-with-women-creators/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 14:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Female Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22422</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the start of this year I made a vow that 2020 would be the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the start of this year I made a vow that 2020 would be the year I only read female authors. I took that one step further and only listened to female songwriters also.</p>
<p>In two industries that are well-known to be a man’s world, I needed to consume in a way that addressed the issues within these industries, so I didn’t feel I was adding to the problem.</p>
<p>It wasn’t hard – the talent is out there. I’ll go through some of the gems that my 2020 has been blessed with.</p>
<h3><strong>Poetry</strong></h3>
<p><strong><a href="https://lanadelrey.com/violet-bent-backwards-over-the-grass/"><em>Violet Bent Backwards over the Grass</em></a> by Lana Del Rey</strong></p>
<p>For a songwriter who regularly references the great poets of our time, I knew it wouldn’t be long till we had Lana Del Rey’s own poetry collection underneath our pillows, pressed against our faces as the blue-sky blinds us and the summer breeze makes us want to ride. These poems are open wounds. They seep and pulsate with damage, regret, lust, and hope. Del Rey’s collection is for the woman who has been polished and now lies tarnished, with that tiny illusion of hope keeping her going in a world that has always been against her.</p>
<p>Lana Del Rey has been criticized in the past about her lyrics and how some people consider them to be glorifying domestic violence. I can tell you as a woman who has been beaten and bruised by a man, Del Rey’s words only empower me, give me the strength to admit I am fallible but ferocious, and allow me the space to heal.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22424" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22424" style="width: 1200px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://lanadelrey.com/violet-bent-backwards-over-the-grass/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22424 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/violet-bent-backwards-over-the-grass-lana-del-rey.jpg" alt="Violet Bent Backwards Over The Grass, Lana Del Rey " width="1200" height="900" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/violet-bent-backwards-over-the-grass-lana-del-rey.jpg 1200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/violet-bent-backwards-over-the-grass-lana-del-rey-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/violet-bent-backwards-over-the-grass-lana-del-rey-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/violet-bent-backwards-over-the-grass-lana-del-rey-768x576.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22424" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Violet Bent Backwards over The Grass</em>, Lana Del Rey</figcaption></figure>
<h3><strong>Music </strong></h3>
<p><strong><em>Folklore</em> by Taylor Swift</strong></p>
<p>There are so many amazing female artists that have graced 2020 and have been the soundtrack to my writing including Brandi Carlile, Lana Del Rey, Holly Williams, Cat Power, Caitlin Canty; but I’d be out of line for not mentioning <em>Folklore</em>. In July, Taylor Swift dropped a surprise album comprising of “stories” from other viewpoints. The album was an experimental piece of story-telling for the artist and she succeeded. The album broke all records, broke a few hearts, and is responsible for the amount of white wine consumed over the summer.</p>
<p>Why is Taylor such an important woman to support? She’s fighting the man – and you can too. Swift is in the process of rerecording her entire back catalogue which belongs to a dumb investment company purely for profit making. She has no power over songs she’s written herself. Re-recording them gives her all the power back whilst diverting profits from the corporation who think they can own words written by someone else.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22423" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22423" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://www.taylorswift.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22423 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Taylor-Swift-Folklore.jpg" alt="Image by Beth Garrabrant (Taylor Swift/Republic Records)" width="1024" height="649" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Taylor-Swift-Folklore.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Taylor-Swift-Folklore-300x190.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Taylor-Swift-Folklore-768x487.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22423" class="wp-caption-text">Image by Beth Garrabrant (Taylor Swift/Republic Records)</figcaption></figure>
<h3><strong>Novella</strong></h3>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.otherscribbles.com/#/tobetaught/"><em>To Be Taught, if Fortunate</em></a> by Becky Chambers</strong></p>
<p>Typing this title gives me goosebumps, as did the novella, which I read in one sitting. Released at the back end of 2019, this novella is what we needed in 2020. It reaches out to the stars and shows us what truly matters to humanity, much like this pandemic has. The cast of this novella make us feel at home. It’s like Chambers took every single one of my teenaged anxieties and personified them into this diverse cast that represents the true us. Nothing is as profoundly quiet and loud at the same time than this novella. Read it.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22425" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22425" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://www.otherscribbles.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22425 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/To-be-taught-if-forntunate-becky-chambers-.jpeg" alt="To Be Taught if Fortunate, Becky Chambers, Hodderscape " width="1024" height="512" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/To-be-taught-if-forntunate-becky-chambers-.jpeg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/To-be-taught-if-forntunate-becky-chambers--300x150.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/To-be-taught-if-forntunate-becky-chambers--768x384.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22425" class="wp-caption-text"><em>To Be Taught, if Fortunate</em>, Becky Chambers, Hodderscape</figcaption></figure>
<h3><strong>Novel </strong></h3>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/607293/seven-devils-by-laura-lam-and-elizabeth-may/"><em>Seven Devils</em></a> by Laura Lam and Elizabeth May</strong></p>
<p>A world you feel immediately at home with if you’re one of the under-represented groups this book includes, <em>Seven Devils</em> is military sci-fi with a cast of amazing women bringing an evil empire to their knees. It’s <em>Star Trek</em> on crack and estrogen, but it’s also a big hug to those of us who dream of the stars as a way of coping with a world that struggles to accept us. On a literary level, the world-building in this romp is infallible, thought-out, and reflective of where society will head when we progress to the stars.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22426" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22426" style="width: 970px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://www.lauralam.co.uk/book/seven-devils/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22426 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Seven-Devils-by-Laura-Lam-and-Elizabeth-May.png" alt="Seven Devils by Laura Lam and Elizabeth May" width="970" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Seven-Devils-by-Laura-Lam-and-Elizabeth-May.png 970w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Seven-Devils-by-Laura-Lam-and-Elizabeth-May-300x93.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Seven-Devils-by-Laura-Lam-and-Elizabeth-May-768x238.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 970px) 100vw, 970px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22426" class="wp-caption-text">Seven Devils by Laura Lam and Elizabeth May</figcaption></figure>
<h3><strong>Short Stories</strong></h3>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.apexbookcompany.com/products/best-of-apex-magazine-volume-1?variant=10324516737"><em>Best of Apex Magazine</em></a>, featuring Ursula Vernon, Lettie Prell, Sarah Pinsker, and Chikodili Emelumadu</strong></p>
<p>Armed with <em>Best of Apex Magazine</em> edited by the fabulous Jason Sizemore and Lesley Conner, I cherry-picked stories from the collection that were written by women. Over half of the stories that are considered the best of sci-fi magazine, <em>Apex</em>, were written by female-identifying authors. I found I read most of the collection just by reading the female authors. Other sci-fi mags – take heed. My favorite, and a story that comes back to haunt me, was &#8220;Jackalope Wives&#8221; by Ursula Vernon. Although merely a glimpse into a whimsical world, it made me want more. I want a video game of &#8220;Jackalope Wives&#8221; where you must save them from losing their coats to the flames. It’ll all be very <em>Zelda</em>.</p>
<p>&#8220;If You Were a Dinosaur, My Love&#8221; tore at my heart. It was writing that put me straight back in positions of requited love &#8211; the kind of love that could never be because your best friend just isn&#8217;t into girls like you &#8211; sound familiar? That&#8217;s what the story meant to me.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22428" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22428" style="width: 613px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://apex-magazine.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-22428 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-10-at-10.55.44.png" alt="The Best of Apex Magazine" width="613" height="332" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-10-at-10.55.44.png 613w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Screenshot-2020-12-10-at-10.55.44-300x162.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 613px) 100vw, 613px" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22428" class="wp-caption-text"><em>Best of Apex Magazine</em></figcaption></figure>
<p>If you, too, want to make a difference using the most valuable tool you have – your worth as a consumer – then I implore you to spend 2021 only consuming work from creators who are under-represented. Pick up that sci-fi thriller from a BAME author, check out that spooky horror novella that finally sheds a spotlight on queer characters, listen to those re-recorded records and not the master tracks that “The Man” owns (you know who you are), and most of all, shout about it. And remember – as consumers, we have far more power than the industry.</p>
<p><em>Please note – an alternative title for this article was indeed, “ConsumHER Culture” but it received many groans from pun haters. </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goodbi-erasure: We Need to Get Better at the Portrayal of Bisexuality</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/goodbi-erasure-we-need-to-get-better-at-the-portrayal-of-bisexuality/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanne Askew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 11:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Female Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Freddie Mercury – idol, hero, LGBTQIA+ icon. In the 2018 biopic, Mercury looks to Mary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Freddie Mercury – idol, hero, LGBTQIA+ icon. In the 2018 biopic, Mercury looks to Mary Austin with fear in his eyes and says, “I think I’m bisexual.” Mary looks down to him. “No, Freddie. You’re gay.”</p>
<p>Bi-erasure or bisexual invisibility is the predisposition to ignore, remove, falsify, or reexplain evidence of bisexuality in history, academia, the news media, and other sources. Bisexual erasure can even include the belief that bisexuality does not exist.</p>
<p>I’ll start with an example of this in my personal life. After announcing my engagement to a man, my boss asked me if I was straight again. What followed was the awkward politeness that comes when you’re deeply offended but also don’t want to throw the F word in your boss’s face. I have faced this discrimination all my life. If I’m not just a lesbian lying to myself, then I’m called promiscuous for loving both genders.</p>
<p>I have also been told “give it a few years and you’ll realise you’re actually a lesbian and will run away with a woman from the gym like Carol and Susan in Friends.” No, actually, I am Bi.</p>
<p>Our media shows a distinct misunderstanding of bisexuality. The most damaging thing about this is the pressure and guilt this puts on both young and older people who haven’t yet come out. Bisexuality is seen as a step to being gay – why can’t we just love both genders and not have other people tell us who we are?</p>
<p>Remember that awesome show, <em>Buffy the Vampire Slayer</em>? Willow, iconically portrayed by Alyson Hannigan, was straight for the first three seasons with romantic relationships only with <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19831" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Willow-rosenberg-sexuality-300x245.jpg" alt="" width="238" height="194" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Willow-rosenberg-sexuality-300x245.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Willow-rosenberg-sexuality.jpg 349w" sizes="(max-width: 238px) 100vw, 238px" />men. She then falls for the witch, Tara, and proclaims she is gay. Later, when meeting her vampire self, she states she is “kinda-gay”. Not a mention of the word “bisexual” from the writers. This is a perfect example of bi-erasure.</p>
<p>Shall we talk about the cure to bisexuality? Yes, it’s Ben Affleck. In both <em>Chasing Amy</em> and <em>Gigli</em>, Ben Affleck turns a lesbian straight. No mention of bisexuality ever crosses the scripts of these movies which flaunts the message that you are either gay or straight and there is no in-between.</p>
<p>Finally, begrudgingly, I have to bring up season one of the Netflix original <em>Van Helsing</em>, a show dear to my heart, filled with feminism and diversity. But you got the bisexual stuff wrong. In season one, our protagonist gets a little rosy on a few apocalypse beers and kisses her long-time friend, Susan. Thinking this would be the start of a great representation of bisexuality in a sci-fi, I rejoiced. But by the next episode both Susan and Vanessa are back to hooking up with men again and the queer kiss is never explored. So what was the point? Well, who knows – I personally think it was a ploy by writers to hook men in by making the main character have a girl-on-girl moment, or maybe it was an attempt at making Vanessa seem more interesting to the viewer? Either way – introducing a queer kiss then never explaining it is a form of bi-erasure. Vanessa Van Helsing had a make-out session with another woman but now she’s back to men and saving the world…just like that. Oh – and Susan was killed off shortly after.</p>
<figure id="attachment_19819" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19819" style="width: 362px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-19819" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/van-helsin-vanessa-susan-300x200.jpg" alt="Van Helsing - Vanessa and Susan - Syfy, Netflix" width="362" height="241" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/van-helsin-vanessa-susan-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/van-helsin-vanessa-susan.jpg 685w" sizes="(max-width: 362px) 100vw, 362px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19819" class="wp-caption-text">Van Helsing &#8211; Vanessa and Susan &#8211; Syfy, Netflix (Photo by: Dan Power/Nomadic Pictures Inc./SYFY)</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://www.glaad.org/bisexual/bierasure">As defined by GLAAD</a>, “Bisexual erasure or bisexual invisibility is a pervasive problem in which the existence or legitimacy of bisexuality (either in general or in regard to an individual) is questioned or denied outright.”</p>
<p>I, too, am guilty of my own bi-erasure. When asked about my sexuality, I used to say “I’m a little bit gay, a little bit straight.” Well no – I am bisexual and bisexual voices need to be louder.</p>
<p>As a bisexual woman, I do not want to be disregarded. I do not want the world to think it’s a phase, or that I’m just a lesbian in waiting. Bisexuality needs to be legitimized in the media. A dear friend of mine came out as bi recently in her 30s. She cited her main worry as she didn’t want to be seen as jumping on an LGBTQIA+ bandwagon or to be seen as it just being a phase. The media is making it harder for people to be themselves and embrace their sexuality. We need strong bisexual role models.</p>
<figure id="attachment_19816" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19816" style="width: 451px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-19816" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Van-helsing-kiss-300x169.gif" alt="Van Helsing - Vanessa and Susan kiss - Syfy, Netflix" width="451" height="254" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19816" class="wp-caption-text">Van Helsing &#8211; Vanessa and Susan kiss &#8211; Syfy, Netflix</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ladies, We’re Apocalypse Ready</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ladies-were-apocalypse-ready/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanne Askew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 11:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Female Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ladies, We’re Apocalypse Ready When I chat to my brothers about the good old days&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ladies, We’re Apocalypse Ready</strong></p>
<p>When I chat to my brothers about the good old days of bar-hopping and pub-crawling, my stories have a very different tune than theirs. Theirs are adventurous tales of freedom and mischief which make my experiences pale in comparison. Mine were of being wary, never walking alone at night, and tiptoeing around in order to protect myself, because I am a woman. But these moments, the relentless ways in which women have different experiences to men, only mean one thing in my book – we’re already apocalypse ready.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone wp-image-18913" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/LSQ-woman-in-storm-300x169.jpeg" alt="women in the apocalypse " width="417" height="235" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/LSQ-woman-in-storm-300x169.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/LSQ-woman-in-storm-1024x577.jpeg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/LSQ-woman-in-storm-768x433.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/LSQ-woman-in-storm.jpeg 1187w" sizes="(max-width: 417px) 100vw, 417px" /></p>
<p>There are many things women have already mastered that will help us rule in an apocalyptic world. Below I look at a few of the skills I’ve picked up in our world that will supercharge my survival chances if we ever go full apocalypse on Planet Earth.</p>
<p><strong>1. The Weaponry</strong></p>
<p>My mother taught me as a teenager to use my house keys as a weapon. The message back then that most teenage girls heard was that men were dangerous and we must arm ourselves when going out after dark, along with keeping our wits about us. Women are also routinely encouraged to partake in self-defense classes to defend against potential attackers – I did this too.</p>
<p>In the apocalypse of my imagining, this can only arm us with the know-how we need to escape tricky situations and come out on top. Imagine you’ve collected a large amount of life-saving supplies. Others will want that, others will fight for that. Our experiences of the world as a woman not only give us the strength and cunning to ward off potential attacks, but will make us naturally more cautious of others.</p>
<p>In the comic book series and now popular TV show &#8220;The Walking Dead,&#8221; it is revealed that Michonne Hawthorne, katana-wielding woman and most kick-ass of all the characters, studied fencing in college, hence her spectacular talent with a sword, or any object she can wield. It’s these seemingly simple life lessons that women have that make us formidable and adaptable in a tight squeeze. Michonne would certainly be able to kill the bad guy with a set of house keys.</p>
<figure id="attachment_18915" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18915" style="width: 269px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-18915" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Michone-198x300.jpg" alt="Michonne The Walking Dead comic issue 19" width="269" height="407" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Michone-198x300.jpg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Michone.jpg 396w" sizes="(max-width: 269px) 100vw, 269px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-18915" class="wp-caption-text">CREDIT &#8211; TONY MOORE – ISSUE 19 THE WALKING DEAD</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>2. The Code Word</strong></p>
<p>When having a night out or on a date, it was custom in my college days to assign a code word in case someone was bothering me. This use of coded words gifts us gals with the foresight to have an escape route if things got tricky, and a way to communicate without further antagonizing the situation.</p>
<p>This use of language would prove invaluable in an apocalyptic world. In a stand-off, what better way to communicate the fight or flight response than with a coded message? We are used to using messages and codes to initiate a rescue or communicate that things are fine, from letting our friends know we got home safe, to texting for a phone call to get out of a bad date. It’s something we’ve done all our lives and will utilize in the apocalypse.</p>
<p><strong>3. The Poison</strong></p>
<p>As is common on a night out, the first rule for women is to never leave their drinks unattended. Unfortunately in England and Wales, <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-50508559">reports</a> of drink spiking have risen, with an overwhelming 72% of victims being women.</p>
<p>But how will this make us kick-ass in an apocalypse? Well, natural poisons are common. In the UK, you can find deadly nightshade, hemlock and natural sources of cyanide in your backyard (I’m talking that beautiful hydrangea that was already in your garden when you moved in). Poisoning will continue beyond our manufactured drugs running out, and our experiences guarding drinks at bars will give us the cautiousness we need to be wary of deceitful poisoning from a foe.</p>
<p><strong>4. The Others</strong></p>
<p>We don’t know what will cause the downfall of humankind. Coronavirus has come pretty close to giving us a taste of a society broken, but in the apocalypse of my imagining, it’s more likely that humans will revert to a dog-eat-dog world, and it won’t be for twenty packs of toilet roll.</p>
<p>Many women can&#8217;t walk down the street without unwanted attention. We have to keep our heads down, pretend we don&#8217;t hear wolf whistles or goading from men, much like avoiding other dangerous survivors on the road in an apocalyptic world.</p>
<p>The relentless caterwauling from men for some women has instilled a natural cautiousness in us when simply navigating our world. I, for one, cross the road to avoid groups of men – not because I’m making assumptions about their nature, but because of my experiences as a woman. These moments will be very familiar to some women, but how will this benefit us in the case of a total worldwide meltdown?</p>
<p>Experiences feed our perceptions, and perception of others is a very keen skill to have when dealing with rival groups of survivors. We will have more awareness of keeping our heads down in dangerous areas, and around dangerous people. The character of the Widow in &#8220;Into the Badlands&#8221; shows us this. In a dystopian world where seven barons rule the land, and with a particular type of supply chain, your fighting skill determines your rank. The Widow is the most formidable amongst them all. The baron of oil, she uses her past experiences of abuse to rise stronger than any of the other barons and rule her corner of the apocalypse with her perception.</p>
<figure id="attachment_18912" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-18912" style="width: 445px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-18912" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-widow-credit-AMC-300x168.png" alt="" width="445" height="249" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-widow-credit-AMC-300x168.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-widow-credit-AMC-1024x575.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-widow-credit-AMC-768x431.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-widow-credit-AMC-1536x862.png 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-widow-credit-AMC.png 1650w" sizes="(max-width: 445px) 100vw, 445px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-18912" class="wp-caption-text">CREDIT &#8211; AMC</figcaption></figure>
<p><strong>5. The Commodity</strong></p>
<p>A popular trope in apocalyptic fiction is the use of commodity and value. We see this in the fantastic portrayal of Gilead in <em>The Handmaid’s Tale</em> and <em>Testaments</em>. In this world of Atwood’s creation, women are literally commodities packaged in the right colors for their use. Handmaids wear red, Marthas wear a dull beige, and Wives wear teal. These colors are designed to tell the patriarchal society what purpose the woman has. Handmaids in red represent fertility, with their white head garments symbolizing purity. Marthas in their beige represent domesticity, and the teal of Wives represent subservience.</p>
<p>Women’s fashion has always been far more diverse than men’s fashion, and yet the most popular designers are men. I see it as a metaphor for packaging women up as objects or commodities, but in an apocalyptic world, we will know our value, and we know how to use that to our advantage. Damsel in dis-dress – more like danger in disguise.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This awareness of how the world saw us before the end will give us the cunning to use our femininity and lessons learned to position us powerfully. No longer will we be seen as the weaker sex; instead we will use the various intelligence we’ve learned over the course of living in this world to boss it in the apocalypse.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Love Letter to Sci-Fi’s Leading Women</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-love-letter-to-sci-fis-leading-women/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanne Askew]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Female Frontier]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17441</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a young girl fascinated by science fiction, it was rare in the late 1990s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a young girl fascinated by science fiction, it was rare in the late 1990s to find some kick-ass females to look up to. Sure, we had Leia in <em>Star Wars</em>, Ripley in <em>Alien</em>, but this wasn’t representative of the gender balance. I needed more. Now, we’ve hit the zeitgeist on the head and our sci-fi television is brimming with female protagonists. We’ve got kick-ass heroines, fierce mothers, and scientists making the galaxy a better place.</p>
<p>Here’s my rundown of sci-fi’s most inspirational leading women on our screens currently:</p>
<p><b>Michael Burnham, <em>Star Trek: Discovery</em></b></p>
<figure id="attachment_17451" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17451" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17451" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Michael-Star-Trek-Credit-Netflix-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Michael-Star-Trek-Credit-Netflix-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Michael-Star-Trek-Credit-Netflix-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Michael-Star-Trek-Credit-Netflix-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Michael-Star-Trek-Credit-Netflix-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Michael-Star-Trek-Credit-Netflix.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17451" class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Choose Your Pain&#8221; &#8212; Episode 105 &#8212; Pictured: Sonequa Martin-Green as First Officer Michael Burnham of the CBS All Access series STAR TREK: DISCOVERY. Photo Cr: Jan Thijs/CBS ÃÂ© 2017 CBS Interactive. All Rights Reserved.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Firstly, where are you and are you OK? We’re all eagerly awaiting the next installment of Netflix’s <em>Star Trek: Discovery</em> after we were left on that hell of a cliff-hanger in Season 2. Somewhere, in another dimension, Michael is still kicking ass. As a <em>Star Trek</em> protagonist, Michael, portrayed by Sonequa Martin-Green, breaks all the rules. For instance, she is not the captain, and she does not have a squeaky clean past. Her arc has its own issues to deal with, including the mistakes in her career, and falling for a Klingon inside a human’s body (you can’t choose who you love). What’s special about this woman is that she was raised in a Vulcan environment and took on Vulcan social characteristics. Her journey on the Discovery is about her reconnecting with the emotional side of human nature; this is an exciting trip where things like love and hate are torn apart and remade in Michael’s image. Read <a href="https://metro.co.uk/2019/10/10/star-trek-discoverys-sonequa-martin-green-teases-come-season-3-10892228/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Metro&#8217;s article</a> on Martin-Green&#8217;s teasers for Season 3. </span></p>
<p><b>Nicole Reese, <em>Raising Dion</em></b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nicole, portrayed by Alisha Wainwright, is raising an eight-year-old super-powered kid; it’s no</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_17452" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17452" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17452" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Nicole-Raising-Dion-Credit-Netflix-300x169.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Nicole-Raising-Dion-Credit-Netflix-300x169.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Nicole-Raising-Dion-Credit-Netflix.jpeg 696w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17452" class="wp-caption-text">Credit: Netflix</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">mean feat. But what Nicole teaches us, along with being a great mother, is that consent is power. She is widowed, and her deceased husband’s best friend helps her out with her son, takes him for dinner, plays with him, babysits, but he is constantly drooling over Nicole. His actions become less of a helping hand, and more of a way to get the girl. Nicole, in a very memorable scene towards the end, tells him that just because he helps out with her son, doesn’t mean she owes him anything (romantic). She shows women that you do not owe any man anything. If he opens a door for you, takes you for dinner, picks your kid up from school, it doesn&#8217;t qualify him to expect anything romantic or sexual, which is an excellent message for the youth of today.</span></p>
<p><b>Quinn Ergon/ Nightfall, <em>Final Space</em></b></p>
<figure id="attachment_17455" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17455" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17455" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Quinn-Final-Space-credit-Netflix-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Quinn-Final-Space-credit-Netflix-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Quinn-Final-Space-credit-Netflix-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Quinn-Final-Space-credit-Netflix-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Quinn-Final-Space-credit-Netflix-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Quinn-Final-Space-credit-Netflix.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17455" class="wp-caption-text">Photo Credit: Netflix</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you haven’t streamed <em>Final Space</em> yet, you need to. It has all the typical sci-fi comedy tropes, but inside that lies a deep and passionate heart. Voiced by Tika Sumpter, Quinn (and her future self, Nightfall), is a space officer who is pulled into the antics of protagonist Gary. But Gary is a bit of a fool. Quinn takes the role of heroic leader in <em>Final Space</em>, making sure Gary is on the right path, setting him straight, knocking him out if needed. She reflects all of his advances, despite him being the protagonist, and teaches us that it doesn’t matter if we’re in your show, we make our own way, our own arcs, our own journeys through &#8220;Final Space&#8221;.</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Speaking of problems, maybe you should leave before you become one.&#8221; —Quinn, <em>Final Space</em></span></p></blockquote>
<p><b>Penny Robinson, <em>Lost in Space</em></b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You are sass. You are grace. You are the best thing about <em>Lost in Space</em>. In Netflix’s recent</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_17453" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17453" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17453" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Penny-Lost-in-Space-Credit-Netflix-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Penny-Lost-in-Space-Credit-Netflix-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Penny-Lost-in-Space-Credit-Netflix.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17453" class="wp-caption-text">Photo Credit: Netflix</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">reboot of <em>Lost in Space</em>, we see Mina Sundwall taking on the role of Penny Robinson with such spunk, it leaves us wondering where the hell her spin-off is. Her sharp tongue and ability to manipulate Vijay into doing her bidding leaves us in awe. More than anything, her willingness to throw herself into any situation makes her the teenage heroine of sci-fi we all wish we were in our awkward emo stages. From dumpster diving to connecting with dangerous Dr. Smith, Penny Robinson is a bold, strong woman with a future that will surely see her rule the galaxies.  </span></p>
<p><b>Prairie Johnson/Nina Azarova, <em>The OA</em></b></p>
<figure id="attachment_17454" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17454" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17454" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Prairie-OA-Credit-Netflix-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Prairie-OA-Credit-Netflix-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Prairie-OA-Credit-Netflix-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Prairie-OA-Credit-Netflix.jpg 780w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17454" class="wp-caption-text">Photo Credit: Netflix</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The show, although not renewed for a third season, is likely to come back with the current fan pressure</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">being exerted across the globe. What is great about protagonist Prairie, portrayed by Brit Marling, is that she is a messiah of sorts. She recruits followers to help her understand the many-dimensional world she has discovered. She is a matriarch who rules with a kind and gentle word, not a toughened exterior. Her journey, from missing child with blindness, to the Original Angel, is breathtaking, and if you haven’t watched it, do so. Prairie’s arc will teach you about identity, love, and the meaning of being human. Also how to defeat Jason Isaacs. </span></p>
<p>Read more on the future of <em>The OA</em> here in the<a href="https://www.radiotimes.com/news/on-demand/2020-01-02/the-oa-3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> Radiotimes.</a></p>
<p><b>Angela Abar/Sister Night, <em>Watchmen</em></b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With <em>Watchmen</em>’s Season 2 future looming unsure ahead of us, it has made history, specifically</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_17457" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17457" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17457" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Sister-Night-Watchmen-Credit-HBO-300x166.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="166" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Sister-Night-Watchmen-Credit-HBO-300x166.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Sister-Night-Watchmen-Credit-HBO.jpg 644w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17457" class="wp-caption-text">Photo Credit: HBO</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">black history, with its eye-opening exploration of the Tulsa Race Massacre in 1921 and provocative portrayal of race in America. Sister Night, portrayed by Regina King, is a descendant of a 1921 survivor. She leads us through the world of <em>Watchmen</em> as a mother, wife, and kick-ass vigilante. There aren’t enough black female superheroes, even less who lead their own show. Angela Abar’s character gives us someone to immediately get behind, to support, to question the world with. She’s learning on the job, learning about the changing world, but if you made it to the end of the season, you’ll realize that she had us, the audience, duped as well. That kind of clever writing and character progression only makes you love her character even more. Do read <a href="https://variety.com/2019/tv/news/watchmen-damon-lindelof-behind-the-scenes-1203436108/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Variety&#8217;s interview</a> with writer and producer Damon Lindelof on the themes in <em>Watchmen</em>. </span></p>
<p><b>Vanessa and Scarlett, <em>Van Helsing</em> </b></p>
<figure id="attachment_17456" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17456" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17456" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Scarlett-and-Vanessa-Van-Helsing-Credit-Netflix-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Scarlett-and-Vanessa-Van-Helsing-Credit-Netflix-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Scarlett-and-Vanessa-Van-Helsing-Credit-Netflix-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Scarlett-and-Vanessa-Van-Helsing-Credit-Netflix-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Scarlett-and-Vanessa-Van-Helsing-Credit-Netflix.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17456" class="wp-caption-text">Photo Credit: Netflix</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Anna and Elsa we wished we had, these two sisters reinvent the tale of vampire hunter, Van Helsing, with their relentless beating of bad guys. Vanessa and Scarlett, portrayed by Kelly Overton and Missy Peregrym, respectively, prove that sisterhood runs deeper than a world overrun with blood-sucking monsters and strange prophecies. Both are inspirational badasses, but it&#8217;s their relationship that inspires me as a woman. The sisters, equally matched, unravel mysteries together, break bones together, and ultimately, rule the roost as the Van Helsing descendants tasked with the lineage’s biggest challenge: what to do when vampires take over the world. What’s so special about them is that there is no romance for Vanessa. Just because she’s a beautiful and powerful protagonist, doesn’t mean she needs a romance in her arc. Her strength lies in her ability to treat everyone as equals and not do the kissy-kissy smoochy thing that most female action protagonists inevitably have to face. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
