<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 044 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-044/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 12:53:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 044 Author Interview: Emma Schmid and &#8220;Paths of Life and Death&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-044-author-interview-emma-schmid-and-paths-of-life-and-death/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 13:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 044]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[And so our Issue 044 author interviews come to an end, and the circus must&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>And so our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-044/">Issue 044</a> author interviews come to an end, and the circus must ship out of town. But don&#8217;t despair! You can come back to these stories any time you please, and we saved one final act for you all. Allow Emma Schmid&#8217;s thoughts on her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/paths-of-life-and-death/">Paths of Life and Death</a>&#8221; wrap up our show, and be sure to keep the wonder of the circus in your hearts.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22476 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Dec-2020-website-homepage-300x158.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="158" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Dec-2020-website-homepage-300x158.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Dec-2020-website-homepage-768x405.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Dec-2020-website-homepage.jpg 910w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Stolen as a child and trapped into a service she does not want, what solace does Rhiannon have to find she plays a part in the ringmaster’s death?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: Even though Rhiannon doesn&#8217;t take pleasure in her powers, I think finding out that the ringmaster is going to die gives her comfort. Like you said, he stole her childhood, which makes me wonder how many other children has he done this to? Are there others at the circus that he&#8217;s exploited? While she doesn&#8217;t actually do the deed, I think Rhiannon would both feel responsible and freed by the ringmaster&#8217;s death. Now that he&#8217;s dead, he can&#8217;t hurt anyone the way he hurt her, and that brings her a little bit of peace as she moves forward.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Knowing she can’t change her visions, does Rhiannon feel regret for telling the boy his ill-fated future? But at the same time, how could she not tell him?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emma: I think Rhiannon would be so conflicted about telling her victims their futures. In my mind, she doesn&#8217;t tell anyone what she sees because of her fear of the way people will react, like the townspeople in Luthor do. In Thomas&#8217; case, though, his death may have been prevented, which makes it even more important for Rhiannon to try to help him. Even if he doesn&#8217;t listen to her, at least she&#8217;s given him the opportunity to change his fate. It must be hard for her to do this though, since she can never be sure if people will follow her advice or not.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Shown two paths, she has never before been given the chance to truly alter fate. Is it ironic that the fate she is able to change actually be her own?</em></strong></p>
<p>Emma: I would say it&#8217;s a little ironic, yes. However, I think it also shows the importance of free will and courage. It&#8217;s imperative that Rhiannon fights for the future that the gods have offered her. Without that conscious choice she makes between the two fates, and her determination in putting the plan into action, I don&#8217;t think she would have been able to carry out her escape from the circus. The only person who ends up being able to really change Rhiannon&#8217;s destiny is Rhiannon herself, after she takes matters into her own hands. Without the little nudge from the gods, she likely would have died in the circus, at the ringmaster&#8217;s hands.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Given the complexities of Rhiannon’s character, what is your favorite part about her? Was there anything about your story that was challenging to write?</em></strong></p>
<p>Emma: I did have some trouble with creating the circus atmosphere. Actually, when I was writing the story, I was a little worried that it didn&#8217;t follow the circus theme of the issue enough to be qualified as a circus story. I had to work hard to incorporate more imagery and description relating to the circus later, since I was so focused on creating Rhiannon and her relationship to her powers.</p>
<p>My favorite part about writing Rhiannon was creating her quiet strength. She&#8217;s lived and survived in the circus for most of her life, without being able to really make friends or be close to people. Part of this is because of her powers, and because she&#8217;s afraid to hurt others. Still, she&#8217;s able to use her powers to her advantage in the end, and try to move forward from the life that she didn&#8217;t choose. I think it&#8217;s really important that, in the end as she&#8217;s rushing away from the circus, she leaves her veil off &#8211; almost as if she&#8217;s finally accepted that her sight can sometimes be a blessing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 044 Author Interview: Jennifer Lyn Parsons and &#8220;Silks&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-044-author-interview-jennifer-lyn-parsons-and-silks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 20:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 044]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=23030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s Issue 044 author interview is special, dear readers, because we&#8217;re featuring the ringmaster herself,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-044/">Issue 044</a> author interview is special, dear readers, because we&#8217;re featuring the ringmaster herself, Jennifer Lyn Parsons! Go read her fabulous story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/silks/">Silks</a>&#8220;, then come back and find out what about our circus theme inspires her so much.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: &#8220;Silks&#8221; is partially a story about having confidence in one&#8217;s own abilities. What about Thalia&#8217;s character motivated her transformation?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: Thalia is a self-starter and excellent at teaching herself things. She doesn&#8217;t realize this,<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23157 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/silhouette-712399_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/silhouette-712399_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/silhouette-712399_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/silhouette-712399_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/silhouette-712399_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/silhouette-712399_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> though, and allows what she thinks a formal education provides (that she&#8217;s lacking) to hold her back. As she sees the circus she&#8217;s working for about to close down, she understands that it would be better to move on to something new if she wants to continue practicing her art. In looking for a new place to perform, she has to take an honest look at her skills and she slowly finds confidence in herself and her hard-won abilities.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There are just a few tantalizing hints that this circus is set in another time and place, primarily the anti-gravs Thalia uses with her silks and ships the circus travels in. How do these touches affect Thalia&#8217;s world in the circus? Would it have been different for her if set in the past?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: I think, in a lot of ways, if the setting were different Thalia would have figured out how good she is sooner. The anti-gravs in this world provide a subtle crutch to the performances, making them more of a spectacle that can hide a lack of talent. Their cost also puts a distinct barrier of privilege in place, because the schools where performers learn to use them price out most people. Thalia manages to get a foot in the door because Anton, the ringmaster, sees her talent and is also running the circus on a tight budget. It&#8217;s a lucky break, but if the world were different, Thalia would have been a shining star from the start.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Thalia gets what she wants in the end, but not as she expects it. What was Madame Velena&#8217;s role in helping her recognize this? Regine&#8217;s role?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: Working backwards through the story, Madame Velena comes along at a convenient time and is a fulcrum for Thalia&#8217;s shifting view of herself and her craft. The near-disaster Thalia has with her audition for another circus shows her who she is without the anti-gravs. That event continues her shift in perspective that begins when she meets Regine, who falls for her in part because she can see Thalia&#8217;s true talent. Regine is a catalyst that sparks Thalia&#8217;s reassessment of herself and starts her replacing the negative messages she&#8217;s been telling herself for some time.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Thalia inspires us all by having to show her true self, unafraid to perform without the anti-gravs. What about this story inspires you? What about your inspiration as an author?</strong></em></p>
<p>Jennifer: A lot of Thalia&#8217;s story is my story as well. Though the setting is completely different (I&#8217;m no circus performer) I pulled many facets of this piece out of my own experiences. Having gone through a similar situation, in this story I am sharing the most important piece of wisdom I gained through that experience: be honest with yourself about your hard-earned abilities.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: As founder and editor-in-chief of </strong></em><strong>LSQ<em>, what about the circus drew you to write a story for the issue?</em></strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23158 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/circus-5219365_1920-252x300.jpg" alt="" width="252" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/circus-5219365_1920-252x300.jpg 252w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/circus-5219365_1920-861x1024.jpg 861w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/circus-5219365_1920-768x914.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/circus-5219365_1920-1291x1536.jpg 1291w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/circus-5219365_1920.jpg 1614w" sizes="(max-width: 252px) 100vw, 252px" />Jennifer: The circus is very special in our family, so of course I needed to contribute something. In non-COVID times, we go to the circus a couple times a year. While Cirque du Soleil is amazing and Ringling Bros. (RIP) was a gorgeous spectacle, I admit I have a soft spot for the smaller circuses. There&#8217;s magic to be found there, a rare and special thing in our cynical world. The creativity and daring and beauty are transportive. I&#8217;ve been fortunate enough to sit in the front row for many performances and it&#8217;s a miracle that something so transportive can exist in our modern, disrupted world.</p>
<p>And yes, the aerialists are my favorite. I enjoy them so much that I worked a little puzzle related to them into the story <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f600.png" alt="😀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 044 Author Interview: Aun-Juli Riddle and &#8220;The Infinite Circus&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-044-author-interview-aun-juli-riddle-and-the-infinite-circus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 18:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 044]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to the circus, dear readers! Our popcorn is still fresh and our performers&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back to the circus, dear readers! Our popcorn is still fresh and our performers are still going strong. How is this possible? Well, much like <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-044/">Issue 044</a> author Aun-Juli Riddle&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-infinite-circus/">story</a>, our circus is infinite!</p>
<div><b><em>LSQ: “The Infinite Circus” is separated into sections and titles in an unusual format. What about this format helped to tell Lyra’s and Flora’s tale?</em><br />
</b></div>
<div>
<p>Aun-Juli: Even though I love reading stories with different structures, I haven’t always been one<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23018 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dark-2572874_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dark-2572874_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dark-2572874_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dark-2572874_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dark-2572874_1920-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/dark-2572874_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> to experiment with them. &#8220;The Infinite Circus&#8221; felt different to me—a story that spanned complicated lifetimes—something couldn’t be contained in a simple format.It mostly boiled down to one idea: we are the authors of our own stories. Each moment is a chapter, a story, and if we thought of our lives that way, what would we name them?</p>
<p>If Lyra were to pen her own, what would her novel be called? “The Ringmaster Time Forgot” felt compelling, and I imagine she would find it both cheeky and honest.</p>
<p>Every section is its own story, its own moment in time. I adore stories within stories, and giving each section its own, perfect title felt respectful of these characters I am grateful to have written.</p>
<p><b><em>LSQ: Your story brings in an exciting mix of magic, history, and science fiction to the circus world. How did this combination enhance the mood and ethereal setting? The storytelling theme?</em><br />
</b><br />
Aun-Juli: Magic and sci-fi are a delectable combination, and there’s nothing sweeter than when they’re cozied up together. Science fiction was the tea, and the magic was a sugar cube.</p>
<p>Giving magic to Lyra, and to the circus by extension, was a small way to make the circus truly infinite, and the folks of the Atmos 5 Station deserved every inch of possibility, imagination, and excitement.</p>
<p><b><em>LSQ: Long periods of lapsed time are referenced, as well as how the ringmaster escapes death. How much does the magic of the circus depend on these concepts? Is there an origin you would like to share?</em></b></p>
<p>Aun-Juli: For the people of Atmos 5, the seven-year span between the circus appearances absolutely lends to the magic. I don’t think it’s a stretch to envision a world like Atmos 5, a solid but melancholy community, needing something to look forward to. I imagined there were plenty of stations just like it, and each one of them wanting to inject their normal life with something far beyond anything they’d ever seen or known.  And think of what the seven-year stretch could also achieve, past the anticipation, beyond something to look forward to—think of all of the stories the people created amongst themselves. Lore and legacy! Folktales of the incredible, everlasting Ringmaster!</p>
<p>Stories are life, and that’s what the circus gave them.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: </b><strong>What else about your story did you enjoy writing? Is there something else you are working on now?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-23019 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/aerial-acrobatics-4807229_1920-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/aerial-acrobatics-4807229_1920-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/aerial-acrobatics-4807229_1920-684x1024.jpg 684w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/aerial-acrobatics-4807229_1920-768x1150.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/aerial-acrobatics-4807229_1920-1026x1536.jpg 1026w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/aerial-acrobatics-4807229_1920.jpg 1282w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Aun-Juli: Launching a circus into space and creating an immortal ringmaster was a lot of fun, but the layer underneath, about loss and moving forward—about how it’s okay to move forward—is something incredibly comforting to me.</p>
<p>When we lose someone, time stands still, and we can’t see the days in front of us. This story says, hey, losing someone is hard, but you can bring them with you. It’s not a betrayal of their love to move forward, it’s not forgetting them. It’s living on for them.</p>
<p>As for what I’m working on, there’s so much to say, but I’ll close the interview with some cryptic word combos and hope that we can look back on it and say, hey, she mentioned that x years ago: Enchanted lighthouses, wild labyrinths, and ghost boxes!</p>
<p>Fingers-crossed we&#8217;ll see them published one day!</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 044 Author Interview: Piper and &#8220;The Dog and Pony Show&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-044-author-interview-piper-and-the-dog-and-pony-show/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 044]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Issue 044 circus is still going strong, dear readers! Today we bring you up-close&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-044">Issue 044</a> circus is still going strong, dear readers! Today we bring you up-close and personal with &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-dog-and-pony-show/">The Dog and Pony Show</a>&#8221; by Piper!</p>
<p><em><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22970 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cade-WwWuC2zT028-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cade-WwWuC2zT028-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cade-WwWuC2zT028-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cade-WwWuC2zT028-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cade-WwWuC2zT028-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cade-WwWuC2zT028-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cade-WwWuC2zT028-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />LSQ: There is a lot happening in this tale to transition from our “normal” world to one of circus sideshows and magic. When writing “The Dog and Pony Show”, how did you come by the idea of this new setting?</strong></em></p>
<p>Piper: Circus is a part of my ordinary daily life &#8212; not sideshows, but I am an amateur aerialist. The magic of circus feels real and true to life to me, and not at all abnormal. The loss of the &#8220;regular&#8221; world came from my feelings about the collapse of normalcy during my COVID-19 isolation. They&#8217;re different &#8212; I was separate from my community in real life, and supported by a great deal of technology; in the story I swapped these, so the loss of technology is redeemed by camaraderie and mutual support.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: How would you place your MC’s role in the circus? It seems that she is a little bit wild animal trainer and a little bit ringmaster.</em></strong></p>
<p>Piper: Since my own circus experience is amateur, it&#8217;s a far cry from the regimented roles one might see in a corporate circus like the old Ringling Brothers. My story-circus is a small group, and everyone does what they can. I looked up some circus glossary online to find relevant terms, and here&#8217;s some I picked for her: baggage wagon driver, advance talker, animal tamer, props artist, aerialist, and founder. But mostly she is simply a part of the community.</p>
<p>Of course the animal in question is not quite a wild animal, nor a tame one, so the usual words seem misleading to me. And there&#8217;s no tradition of escorting one&#8217;s audience away after the show &#8212; I made that up first to suit my setting, and then my plot.</p>
<p>I also discovered the delightful phrase &#8220;Boss Hostler — The man who traveled ahead of the mud shows to mark the way for the caravan; sometimes used to denote the one in charge of all horses in a show.&#8221; Aside from not being a man, that covers a bunch of my POV character&#8217;s important roles.</p>
<p>I wouldn&#8217;t call her a ringmaster, who stands up and announces the various acts. If she does that in the story I&#8217;ve forgotten it!</p>
<p>Incidentally, &#8220;Dog and Pony Show&#8221; is a (typically dismissive) term for a very small circus. I like to think my character would embrace it.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: As you noted in the first line, magic came out of the old shattered world and now<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22971 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/keiron-castellanos-7mBzoqrVHSs-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/keiron-castellanos-7mBzoqrVHSs-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/keiron-castellanos-7mBzoqrVHSs-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/keiron-castellanos-7mBzoqrVHSs-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/keiron-castellanos-7mBzoqrVHSs-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/keiron-castellanos-7mBzoqrVHSs-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> seems to be seeping into the new one. When writing this, did you project what might happen next with magic and the traveling circus? Is it just the circus in particular, or other parts of the world as well?</em></strong></p>
<p>Piper: The changes in magic and mundanity are for the entire world. The old and existing magic (and, honestly, mundanity) of circus provides a bridge for those who were involved with it already.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: What were your favorite parts to write in this story? Was anything easier or harder to pen?</em></strong></p>
<p>Piper: The first sentence was easy and I liked it; the rest of the story came naturally from that. The ponies and the performers are more or less straight from life, and writing them as characters was a delight.</p>
<p>The fight scene was hard. I abhor violence, and I suspect it could have been written better than I managed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 044 Author Interview: Elizabeth Hinckley and &#8220;Margins&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-044-author-interview-elizabeth-hinckley-and-margins/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 11:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 044]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy Tuesday, dear readers! Welcome back to our round of Issue 044 author interviews. Elizabeth&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Tuesday, dear readers! Welcome back to our round of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-044/">Issue 044</a> author interviews. Elizabeth Hinckley sat down with us today and gave us some truly thoughtful answers to our questions about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/margins/">Margins</a>&#8220;. Please read on!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There are so many images in this story that stand out, which left me wondering: </strong></em><em><strong>which was the spark of inspiration that led you to write “Margins&#8221;?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: When I heard that <em>LSQ</em> was doing a circus issue, I knew I had to write a circus story.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22909 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/young-girl-1149701_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/young-girl-1149701_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/young-girl-1149701_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/young-girl-1149701_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/young-girl-1149701_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/young-girl-1149701_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> It’s an old-fashioned art form that’s endangered, I think, because of cynicism and an undervaluing of beauty and wonder. In a non-pandemic year, I make sure to see a circus two or three times a year. It’s sometimes hard to explain why such things are not a luxury, especially when people get focused on practical matters during difficult times, but I see it as almost a responsibility to support performers who create amazing things, or they’ll go away. I hope that Adrian’s journey shows how beauty and wonder are some of the things that give us purpose and meaning.</p>
<p>As I wrote, however, this other theme of margins popped up and unified the story &#8211; it was a delightful surprise, and became rather the point of it. As the story took shape, I followed along, discovering the words for some powerful truths. I think I was way too practical when I was younger, but as I got older I remembered to follow wonder. I hope others remember to do so &#8211; life is too short, and you can leave it until you no longer remember.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: The circus and faeries: a rare combination! Was it difficult to blend these two themes? In what ways do you think they complement each other?</em></strong></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I’m glad you liked the combination of the circus and faeries! I did not at all find them difficult to blend, but rather that they are naturally complimentary. Neither world is entirely safe, and that’s an important thing to remember when you want to live a magical life. The risk may be a thrill, which is exciting, but it is also a test that keeps out the unworthy, and challenges those who want to grow and touch the sublime. In both worlds, you seek the amazing, the beautiful, that special liminal something. Some would call such things escapism, and I would call those  people the ones who don’t understand anything about life.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Adrian&#8217;s feelings towards the margins reminds me of how I&#8217;ve also felt while</em> looking at the woods pass by on the side of the highway, for example. Why do you think these spaces hold such a pull?</strong></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I think that so often the worthwhile things we seek, whether beauty, magic, or honesty, are off to the side. It’s not that the wonderful things in life can’t also be the really obvious ones, <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22911 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/acrobat-4171996_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/acrobat-4171996_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/acrobat-4171996_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/acrobat-4171996_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/acrobat-4171996_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/acrobat-4171996_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />but obvious things can be overhandled, exploited, and monetized, while the hidden things might better retain their true nature and value by virtue of being marginalized. Perhaps it goes back to nature itself: unless you have some superlative power, like being the fiercest or fastest animal, many organisms camouflage themselves to survive. If you take just a brief look at a field, you might conclude that you don’t see any animals and move on, but if you look in the margins &#8211; where habitats meet, where colors and patterns overlap and hide things within themselves &#8211; you’ll likely be rewarded by seeing something you didn’t expect.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Who and what inspires your writing?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: When I get a bug to write something, it often comes from some idea that smacks me that I have to somehow express. And it usually comes as a cross-platform inspiration rather than reading fiction &#8211; like a song or movie, a science lecture or some experience I had that made me imagine the world in a certain way. It’s not that there aren’t writers I would love to emulate, but if I get inspired by reading a work of fiction and then sit down to write, I think I’ll just write like that author. My literary influences probably just trickle down into how I think, and that probably comes out on the page without me knowing it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 044 Author Interview: Lisa Gregoire and &#8220;To the Pole!™&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-044-author-interview-lisa-gregoire-and-to-the-pole/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 11:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 044]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22676</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Issue 044 circus is still going strong, and today we&#8217;re highlighting another act! Join&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-044/">Issue 044</a> circus is still going strong, and today we&#8217;re highlighting another act! Join us as we chat with Lisa Gregoire about her cli-fi story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/to-the-pole/">To the Pole!<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></a>&#8221;</p>
<p><span class="im"><em><strong>LSQ: The unusual setting points to a time when our world looks different, but is recognizable and logical due to current environmental circumstances/trajectories. What were the motivations for this particular setting?</strong></em></span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22857 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/polar-bear-2199534_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/polar-bear-2199534_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/polar-bear-2199534_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/polar-bear-2199534_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/polar-bear-2199534_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/polar-bear-2199534_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Lisa: One of my first jobs out of journalism school in the 1990s was reporter for <em>Nunatsiaq News</em> in Iqaluit, Nunavut. In subsequent years, I returned north to write magazine articles about Nunavut society, politics, and climate change, and in 2014, I returned to <em>Nunatsiaq News</em> as managing editor, a job I left a few years ago to write fiction.</p>
<p>All this to say, my love for the Arctic and the people who live there—both Inuit and newcomers—is deep and wide. With this story, I wanted to take some of what I’d learned from Indigenous and non-Indigenous experts about the changing northern landscape and build a story around that. I’ve had the singular privilege of traveling widely throughout Canada’s territories and have seen first-hand how warming oceans, slumping permafrost, and melting glaciers are impacting northern communities. I feel compelled to share that privilege.<span class="im"><br />
</span></p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: </strong></em><span class="im"><em><strong>A different world that still retains its marketing, fanfare, and good old capitalism. What made you combine the concepts of eco-tourism, a family business, and circus presentation?</strong></em></span></p>
<p>Lisa: As Stephen King says, the act of writing is akin to archaeology. You don’t write a story so much as “uncover” it by digging down and putting pieces together. I feel like this happened with &#8220;To The Pole!<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />&#8221;.</p>
<p>I wanted to set a story in a near-future Arctic when the North Pole becomes navigable, but then what? I started brainstorming ideas and concepts with pencil on paper. I like the rasping sound. It makes me feeling like I’m accomplishing something. Once I settled on a floating theme park, I had to answer some questions. What would it look like and how would it function? How would people get there? Who will own the North Pole in the future? And above all, how do I avoid sounding didactic and earnest? The family business gave it the narrative element I needed and the circus—aside from allowing me to feature northern animals, it just seemed to bolster the absurd nature of the story. Once I had Faisal in top hat and jodhpurs, the story came alive. I could see and hear the action unfolding.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: <span class="im">Svetlana seems to be a counterpoint character to the whole operation. How would you define her role as opposed to the MC’s?</span></strong></em></p>
<p>Lisa: Yes, she’s definitely the counterpoint. Originally that role was taken by the protagonist’s twin sister June but I wanted a Russian character and I wanted her to be quite separate and different from the narrator, so I went back and reworked it. Svetlana became the scientist, the biologist.</p>
<p>Once I created this world, I sat back and imagined the narrator, Svetlana and Faisal—the aspiring actor—as average young folks from different backgrounds, trying to make a buck over the summer. Maybe in the end, they all go their separate ways, having shared this very intense, exotic and unforgettable experience, not unlike, I guess, some of the people I met when I was a young reporter in Iqaluit. Svetlana comes from a place of authority and reason. Through her, I can deliver these little facts about northern animals, without it sounding forced. And Faisal, he’s the joker, my comic relief.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: </strong></em><span class="im"><em><strong>“To the Pole!<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />” is partially an eco-cautionary and animal rights tale, with a dash of satire. How important was the farcical when writing your story to bring out the more serious elements?</strong></em></span></p>
<p>Lisa: It was top of mind. I read a lot of fiction—short, long, Canadian, international—and here’s<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22858 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/nature-2408651_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/nature-2408651_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/nature-2408651_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/nature-2408651_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/nature-2408651_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/nature-2408651_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> something I’ve discovered. Humor and satire are ridiculously hard to pull off. I’ve been reading Kurt Vonnegut Jr., George Saunders, Anton Checkov, and Etgar Keret of late. Their stories are about heavy stuff—war, poverty, addiction, consumerism, religion, racism—and yet, they make me laugh out loud. How is that possible? Because their stories are so creative, and wonderfully told, you don’t notice right away the messages they tuck inside. This is what I aspire to in my own work.</p>
<p>The Arctic is changing more dramatically, and rapidly, than anywhere else on the planet. Northerners are understandably concerned. The future is scary and unpredictable, and not just because of environmental changes, but potential changes to lifestyle, traditions and the economy. Enormous cruise ships are already plying the Northwest Passage and docking near remote Inuit communities. Multi-nationals are scouring for natural resources and minerals. As the Arctic gets warmer, more people will come, bringing unforeseen outcomes. These things are heavy, complex, and challenging to write about, especially in an era of climate change fatigue. People want to be delighted by fiction, not preached to. Ultimately, my goal—and probably the goal of many writers—is two-fold: to write entertaining stories about things that matter to me. Striking the right balance, well, that&#8217;s the hard part.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 044 Author Interview: Melodie Corrigall and &#8220;The Circus and the Library&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-044-author-interview-melodie-corrigall-and-the-circus-and-the-library/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 12:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 044]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22556</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s Issue 044 author interview takes us to two of our favorite places. The title&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-044/">Issue 044</a> author interview takes us to two of our favorite places. The title of Melodie Corrigall&#8217;s story tells us what these places are: &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-circus-and-the-library/">The Circus and the Library</a>&#8220;!</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: This is so short but so powerful. I could read it over and over again and get something new from it each time. What inspired this novel take on a circus? Additionally,</strong></em><em><strong> I love the contrast between the library and the circus, the one self-satisfied and unmoved, the other constantly at the edge of ruined. How did you settle on these takes for the characters? Did you consider making the library its own type of unsettled and desperate as well, or were you set on the characterization early on?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Melodie: These two personalities—the Circus and the Library—came to me almost fully formed. As the characters developed I found that the more I described them, the more they supported my original choice. The library: learned, respected, self-confident, and supported financially and philosophically by his world and the circus, enjoyed but considered frivolous, needing to find and keep a paid audience, and therefore frantic for support and attention.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><em>LSQ: The marriage between the library and the circus ends the way so many marriages do—with misunderstandings, with assumptions, and finally with a firm exit. I assume the library will continue doing what it’s been doing without pause, but do you have any idea what might be next for the circus-turned-ship?</em></strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>Melodie: I hope that the future for the circus will be happier and allow her to be appreciated for what she has contributed to our scommunity. I imagine that the library will keep on with the same behavior and find a way—amongst the tomes—to justify it.  But as the story ends I cannot be sure of the future for either of them. Circus’s from the first days have not had as much appreciation as libraries.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 044 Author Interview: Natasha Grodzinski and &#8220;The Harvest-Bringers&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-044-author-interview-natasha-grodzinski-and-the-harvest-bringers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 14:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 044]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy Tuesday, dear readers, and welcome back to the Luna Station Circus! Our Issue 044 authors have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Tuesday, dear readers, and welcome back to the <em>Luna Station </em>Circus! Our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-044/">Issue 044</a> authors have been gracious enough to answer our burning questions about their fabulous stories. Today we&#8217;re featuring Natasha Grodzinski&#8217;s &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-harvest-bringers/">The Harvest-Bringers</a>&#8220;.</p>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: This is a beautifully crafted setting and a fascinating interpretation of “circus.” What inspired you to write about the theme in this way?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22822 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/fox-1883658_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/fox-1883658_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/fox-1883658_1920-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/fox-1883658_1920-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/fox-1883658_1920-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/fox-1883658_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Natasha: I know the historical idea of the “circus” is not without its issues, but there’s something about the glamour and mystique of it that has always appealed to me, particularly where it can overlap with speculative fiction. So when I saw the category for this issue, I knew I wanted to send something in. I initially was going to submit another story I had already written, but it was late summer when I saw the open call, and I was inspired to write something a little warmer, a little more optimistic than what I already had. The concept for this story then came from an amalgamation of a few conversations I’ve had with my mother about Germany, about forests and fairytales. It came in a rather roundabout way, but the story was more or less created from the question: why don’t I create my own fairytale that centers around some kind of circus?</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: I love how Thea begins the story bright and bold and full of adventure, and then once her adventure is underway, she pulls back. It’s so perfectly childlike. Is Thea’s character based on anyone in particular?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Natasha: The entire story is heavily influenced by my mother. It was through her that I was first introduced to the concept of the <i>Weldmeister</i>, as that was the occupation her father was headed toward when he was a boy. She’s also the one who first introduced me to the simple wonder of walking through the woods &#8211; something that I’ve adored since I was very, very young. In that way, I think Thea is based off of both of us. I still go wandering in the woods all the time, even now, and I still hope to stumble across something inexplicable. I’ve never let go of that.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><em>LSQ: The ending feels like the perfect opportunity for a second chance at adventure for Thea. I like to imagine her running away with the “performers” this time around. The richness of the world and descriptions are so lovely—do you have any plans to revisit this story, or these characters?</em></strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>Natasha: As of right now, this story will only continue to live on in my head. But Thea is not the<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22823 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/forest-931706_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/forest-931706_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/forest-931706_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/forest-931706_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/forest-931706_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/forest-931706_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> type of person to miss the same opportunity twice. I’m sure, that if Thea were to come off of the page and tell me what she’s been up to since I finished writing her, she would tell me all about dancing across forest floors and watching the seasons change from the center of it all.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 044 Author Interview: Priscilla Kint and &#8220;The Legend of Emma Sondheim&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-044-author-interview-priscilla-kint-and-the-legend-of-emma-sondheim/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 044]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22506</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every Tuesday on our blog, we share an interview with an author from our most&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every Tuesday on our blog, we share an interview with an author from our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-044/">most recent issue</a>, and we have plenty more to share! Today&#8217;s spotlight is on Priscilla Kint and her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-legend-of-emma-sondheim/">The Legend of Emma Sondheim</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What an unexpected twist! I love the idea of a time-traveling circus inside a house. How did you come up with that concept?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22748 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/luggage-2017588_1920-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/luggage-2017588_1920-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/luggage-2017588_1920-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/luggage-2017588_1920-768x510.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/luggage-2017588_1920-1536x1021.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/luggage-2017588_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Priscilla: Thank you! Honestly, it was never my intention to include any time travel in this story. I wrote a manuscript that deals with the topic not too long ago, and that gave me such headaches that I swore I’d never dive into it again – but that didn’t last very long! I knew I wanted location to play a major part in this world, so I knew very early on the Circus would be one building, a place that would be a character in itself. Then, as I was writing down some notes and setting up the world, I wrote the words “traveling circus”, which, of course, wouldn’t make much sense if the circus was in the same building every time – unless, that is, the circus travelled in some other way. And that’s how I found myself writing about time travel yet again. Luckily, this time definitely didn’t give me as much of a headache. It was actually great fun!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Oh my goodness, Emma and Jeremiah’s ending—I saw it coming, and yet I still couldn’t quite believe it when it hit. Did you know you were going to end things that way from the beginning? What scene in the story came first to you? </strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Priscilla: Yes, I always knew their story was going to be a tragedy. Emma and Jeremiah’s story actually started as a cautionary tale in my mind, something children living in the Circus years and years later would hear and grow afraid of. As I was building up the world of the Circus, I quickly realized I wanted petrification to play a part. When you’re able to travel through time, it might feel like nothing is set in stone. That’s true for the Circus as well – until you try to leave. That’s the first image that came to me: a statue in the middle of a square that looks just out of place. No engravings, standing in an odd location, looking just a little bit too real. From there on, Emma’s and Jeremiah’s characters quickly came to me, immediately followed by Lumen and the mirror room.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This feels so high concept to me. Would you ever consider writing another story about the Circus, perhaps from the perspective of a visitor who gets swept along to a new time, or someone who gets the better of the Circus some day?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22749 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mini-theatre-591423_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mini-theatre-591423_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mini-theatre-591423_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mini-theatre-591423_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mini-theatre-591423_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mini-theatre-591423_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Priscilla: Funny you should ask! The setting of this story is actually the center stage of a novel-length manuscript I’m working on. The story of that manuscript came to me long before Emma did, even though it takes place long after she and Jeremiah have left. The Circus has changed a lot in the time between the two stories, which was so nice to explore, and it has many more secrets to reveal. Emma and Jeremiah took the risk of leaving the Circus and paid the price for it, but in this new story even its obedient inhabitants find themselves in danger. And the real trouble starts when a young boy decides to join the Circus as their new fire artist. The manuscript is titled WHEN THE DARK DANCES and I’m currently querying it. Fun fact: if you’ve read “The Legend of Emma Sondheim”, you’ve already met the main character of DARK!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 044 Author Interview: Amanda Baldeneaux and &#8220;Crab Pots&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-044-author-interview-amanda-baldeneaux-and-crab-pots/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 14:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 044]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What makes the Luna Station circus the best circus? We&#8217;ve got a touch of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What makes the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-044/"><em>Luna Station</em> circus</a> the best circus? We&#8217;ve got a touch of the otherworldly in our acts, of course! Today we&#8217;re spotlighting Amanda Baldeneaux and her fantastical story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/crab-pots/">Crab Pots</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: This story is such a smooth blend of everyday world issues and subtle otherworldly</em></strong><br />
<strong><em>influences like mermaids and empaths. How did you decide on such subtle worldbuilding?</em></strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22705 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/vintage-1721918_1920-190x300.jpg" alt="" width="190" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/vintage-1721918_1920-190x300.jpg 190w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/vintage-1721918_1920-649x1024.jpg 649w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/vintage-1721918_1920-768x1212.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/vintage-1721918_1920-974x1536.jpg 974w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/vintage-1721918_1920.jpg 1217w" sizes="(max-width: 190px) 100vw, 190px" />Amanda: I love stories that add surreal elements to everyday scenarios that might otherwise be classified as literary fiction. Writers I’ve been reading lately/love all the time who do this in some of their stories include Kelly Link, Sarah Shun-lien Bynum, and Julia Elliot. Reading and re-reading their stories in recent months has influenced my own writing, including this story. I love the art and symbolism of tarot cards and wanted to utilize that in a circus story, which is how the<br />
empath came about: thinking about the water element of the queen of cups, which naturally led<br />
itself to wanting to include mermaids. I love writing mermaid stories (I’ve got quite a few in<br />
various states of drafting), and before starting the first draft of this one I made a list of all the<br />
reasons I find mermaids fascinating and tried to incorporate those reasons into the story.</p>
<p>I love how mermaids exist in between two different states, an existence I think many people,<br />
perhaps especially women, navigate regularly but even more so since pandemic lockdowns began last spring. It’s been almost impossible to do multiple things well since losing regular<br />
childcare. I can either be a half present mom and a half present writer which means I’m not<br />
particularly good at either, or I can be a decent, all-focused mom who doesn’t have time to write,<br />
or a writer who only has time to write by ignoring kids. The in-between isn’t a place I can really exist, and I envy those who can. I can’t focus that many places and go smoothly back and forth–the guilt is killer either way. That’s one reason mermaids hold so much allure to me–they<br />
successfully navigate the in-between; they literally have it all. They are of water and of air and do both well. I think this story is a manifestation of my envy, and the dark turn envy can take when it leads to sabotage of others and self.</p>
<p>I’ve been really enjoying the podcast <a href="https://writerwifemothermonster.com/"><em>Writer Mother Monster</em></a> for this reason, it addresses head-on<br />
the myth that we can have it all, be it all, do it all. It’s impossible to be writer, parent, cleaning service, cook, errand runner, assistant teacher, tech support, household manager, and any other hats a person can try to squeeze on all at once. I read news articles about students going to high<br />
school during the day and working in factories all night. When do they sleep? Our systems ask so much – too much – of people, and eventually either the people or the fabric of the system will tear. I get at least 6-7 hours of sleep at night with a one-year-old and a five-year-old at home, and I still feel the seams ripping.</p>
<p>I try to remind myself that my children are little and it won’t always be this busy at home, but there is still the weight of stories I want to write piling up in my head that tear at me in their own<br />
way, and I think all writers kept apart from their work feel this way. I’m not always positive the stories will be patient enough to wait for me, and that anxiety is heaped on top of all the other<br />
anxieties circulating communally now. I began typing this interview with ten minutes I had in between my daughter’s remote preschool sessions (she uses my laptop, so that’s been gone for<br />
half the day since they went remote). I’m sitting down at it again, over a week later, on a Sunday<br />
when my husband is home and I’ve barricaded myself in our bedroom with my laptop. There are<br />
screams occasionally, but I’m sure everyone is fine.</p>
<p>When I feel frustrated by all the lost spare time in these safer-at-home months, I am reminded of the articles that have come out since the pandemic began about how this period will set women back in the professional sphere by years or decades. I had to leave my full-time job in April to care for my children. I had a part-time editing job I fell so far behind on that I was let go in July. I’m lucky we can rearrange our household budget to be ok on just my husband’s salary, but I still<br />
worry what options I will have when we have full time childcare again. Will the gap in my resume hurt me? Will I have forgotten how to write stories? There are no shortage of essays about mothers losing themselves in the deluge of motherhood. Am I already lost in that sea? If I was a mermaid, I’d probably be a better swimmer, and not so bothered by storms. I made my mermaids wild animals in my story, which may be because I wanted them to not care what others think of them or project on them, a facet I also envy.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Skyla’s life feels so relatable, to me at least, and you do such a good job of fleshing her </strong></em><em><strong>out with actions as well as thoughts. Who was your inspiration for this character?</strong></em></p>
<p>Amanda: This story was in part inspired by Amanda Rea’s story “<a href="https://americanshortfiction.org/issue-68/">Crab Theory</a>,” a story about a couple holding each other back with devastating consequences when everything comes to a boil, so to speak. Crab theory the concept, is based on the observation that crabs will prevent an individual from successfully escaping a dire situation–like a fisherman’s bucket. When I first read that story, I thought a lot about American subcultures that still think a woman’s only place in the home with her children–and while I say subculture, I think it’s so pervasive that every mother-figure feels the pressure of “failing” if time is spent out of the home or away from the children, even if it’s absolutely critical to afford housing and food. The idea that women are just mother-figures holds women back from achieving other things or being recognized for the achievements they are reaching, which I connect to crab theory. But it gets convoluted, as <em>Writer Mother Monster</em> dives into, when you go the opposite end and say women can have it all. Not unless we never sleep, which isn’t a long-term solution. The pandemic, in my own life, has compounded these pressures, and I know I’m not alone in that. I’m privileged I am able to stay home and become my girls’ full time carer, but it’s at the expense of my other aspirations and desire to contribute to the household budget. Skyla isn’t living in a pandemic world, but she’s still a character constrained by outside forces and invisible cages, and when she’s confronted with that reality, she makes a choice in line with crab theory.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This feels like a story that could easily become bigger than it is right now if you wanted it to. Do you think you’ll ever write more of Skyla, Zania, and mermaid catching?</strong></em></p>
<p>Amanda: I hadn’t considered it, but I like the idea. I’m a novelist in denial right now; I don’t have <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22703 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mermaid-4761358_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mermaid-4761358_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mermaid-4761358_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mermaid-4761358_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mermaid-4761358_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/mermaid-4761358_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />the time to regularly devote to a novel, but I can draft a short story in one to three sittings if I forego sleep a few nights, so I’m very anti-novel solely so I can have short term gratification when drafting something. In-person preschool resumes in January – hopefully – and I’m planning to coordinate my baby’s nap time with the five-year-old’s half-day school schedule so I can try to get back into the novel I’m working on. In terms of this story’s world, a circus has so many potential stories and a Tarot deck has so many potential stories, and I only zeroed in on one of those potentials here. I like the idea of a series of stories connected to the Tarot deck through a circus that embodies each of the suit’s elements. Of course, my favorite suit is cups, so it’d be hard to turn towards another. I already have at least three other mermaid short stories on my hard drive and a shelved mermaid novel which I’ll (one day) revisit and revise, and I’m sure that mermaids will demand I keep writing about them in new stories, too. They just won’t leave me alone; even completely landlocked at 5280 feet above sea level, I hear them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
