<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Girls &amp; Games &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/girls-games/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 17:13:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Final Fantasy VIII &#8211; Love interest and independent woman: can the balance be struck?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/final-fantasy-viii-love-interest-and-independent-woman-can-the-balance-be-struck/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 17:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girls & Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22299#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=22299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year was 1998. Final Fantasy VII was a cultural reset. Squaresoft had unlimited resources&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The year was 1998. Final Fantasy VII was a cultural reset. Squaresoft had unlimited resources <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-22320 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/viii-248x300.jpg" alt="" width="248" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/viii-248x300.jpg 248w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/viii.jpg 414w" sizes="(max-width: 248px) 100vw, 248px" />and the unadulterated goodwill of the gaming community. They had one job. What was it? Create a game better than the biggest roleplaying game of the late 90s, a game so iconic that it helped usher in a new era of heights to reach for in game development. And what did they do? They broke everything. Final Fantasy VIII tore apart everything fans thought they knew about the series in a way that reflected the jump between Final Fantasy I and Final Fantasy II in the late 80s. Final Fantasy VIII is the most polarizing title in the history of the franchise, second only to Final Fantasy XIII. It has it’s ardent supporters, but it also has it’s equally ardent naysayers.<br /><br />Final Fantasy VIII is an odd game. The gameplay has a steep learning curve, the visuals lean harder into the steampunk, sci-fi aesthetic than ever, and the overall feeling is much more realistic compared to the stylized counterparts of the previous installments. The game’s narrative also introduces some firsts to the franchise from a story standpoint, most notably being the presence of a love story between main characters Squall Leonhart and Rinoa Heartilly driving the plot in a major way. <br /><br />Romance is no stranger to Final Fantasy; with a couple of exceptions, there have been romance subplots woven into every game since Final Fantasy IV. However, no game commits to its romantic storyline the way Final Fantasy VIII does. In all aspects of the game save for the mechanics, the romance is prioritized. The love story drives the plot forward. Longtime series composer Nobuo Uematsu wrote a romantic pop ballad called &#8220;Eyes On Me&#8221; as a romantic theme for Squall and Rinoa. The song covers the themes and characters of the story very well. Sung beautifully by Faye Wong, &#8220;Eyes On Me&#8221; was a hit amongst gamers upon release. Even the game’s logo, which always depicts a theme of major importance to the story, is of Squall and Rinoa in an embrace. <br /><br />Rinoa, the main female character, is caught in the middle of this whirlwind romance with the broody, introverted Squall. Despite that, she has moments throughout the narrative where she exists independently of him. Rinoa does not attend Balamb Garden, the mercenary school where <img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-22321 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/RinoaDissidiaNT-224x300.png" alt="" width="224" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/RinoaDissidiaNT-224x300.png 224w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/RinoaDissidiaNT.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 224px) 100vw, 224px" />Squall and the rest of the characters attend. Instead, they meet her on a mission to free Rinoa’s hometown from the oppressive Galbadian empire. Rinoa is a member of the Forest Owls, a resistance group working towards that goal. She hires Squall and his friends as mercenaries, and together they work to defeat one of the game’s main antagonists, Sorceress Edea. When the mission fails, Rinoa joins Squall’s crew permanently. As the story progresses, she falls in love with Squall. However, Rinoa also finds herself in situations where she has to be rescued by Squall, and she does not have the same amount of agency in the back half of the game as she did in the front half. She is either in a coma, possessed by an evil sorceress, or both at the same time. This helps propel the romance along, as it gives Squall the opportunity to fall in love with her back, but it is ultimately at the expense of Rinoa’s agency. At the end of Final Fantasy VIII, the two share a kiss, confirming their relationship.</p>
<p>Like Final Fantasy VIII itself, Rinoa is a polarizing character. Some love her, and find her arc from pacifist to mercenary inspiring and realistic, while others find her rife with cliché damsel in distress stereotypes. In an attempt to give Rinoa some further depth, a popular fan theory arose that posited that the time traveling sorceress Ultimecia, the final boss of Final Fantasy VIII, was actually Rinoa from the future. This version of Rinoa is one who fully succumbed to the darkness of the sorceress magic. However, the theory was debunked by game director Yoshinori Kitase.<br /><br />The hyperfocus on romance in Final Fantasy VIII was new territory for the franchise. Never before has a character been so fully defined by a romance as Rinoa Heartilly was in the history of Final Fantasy. While it allowed for the writers to explore a different angle in their story, it came at the expense of Rinoa’s individual character arc, and resulted in a very divisive experience among fans. The Final Fantasy franchise does not have a romance drive the A-plot in any of its other games going forward.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Final Fantasy VII &#8211; Fridging? Iconic?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/final-fantasy-vii-fridging-iconic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hayley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 11:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girls & Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=20268</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spoilers for Final Fantasy 7! The late 1990s were a major turning point in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spoilers for Final Fantasy 7!</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The late 1990s were a major turning point in the history of video games. 3D animation was thriving, and major advances in the technology were being made at a rapid pace. Video game developers were exploring this, and a new generation of consoles that could run 3D games were on the horizon. Naturally, considering they have already spent a decade being on the forefront of game development, Hironobu Sakaguchi and his team at Squaresoft jumped on this golden opportunity. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> took the franchise into 3D and as a result, helped pull the JRPG (Japanese roleplaying game) genre out of being niche and into a global phenomenon. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">games have always been groundbreaking in their own ways, but </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VII </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">was <img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-21861 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/FFVIIRemake-209x300.png" alt="" width="209" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/FFVIIRemake-209x300.png 209w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/FFVIIRemake.png 263w" sizes="(max-width: 209px) 100vw, 209px" />on another level. The visuals, while dated by today’s standards, were nothing short of revolutionary at the time. The game was so dense, both graphically and narratively, that Squaresoft had to switch from Nintendo cartridges to Sony Playstation discs, a hardware shift that persists to this day. The impact </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> had on the gaming community was truly unparalleled. It was, unquestionably, </span><b>THE</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> biggest roleplaying game of the era.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the most legendary moments in gaming history, one that casual and hardcore gamers alike are aware of, is the death of Aerith Gainsborough by main antagonist Sephiroth, at the end of Disc 1 of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Aerith is one of nine playable characters in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, three of whom are female, one of whom is optional. If Yuffie is not recruited, there is one female character left in the party, to six male characters (five if Vincent is not recruited) after Aerith’s untimely demise. Yet, her legacy far eclipses the skewed gender makeup of the party in the back half of the game. How does fridging a female character contribute to a legacy like that? Killing off one of your main playable party members was simply unheard of in video games up until this point, and the way </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VII</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> executed her death scene was honestly excellent. The unexpectedness of it all is heartbreaking, and the emotions still hit today. It was a turning point in gaming, and it emboldened other game developers to take narrative risks, despite the consequences. Whether or not the game’s desire to take a risk that large boded well for female characters in JRPGs moving forward, the narrative decision at the time cemented Aerith (and her music theme) as one of the most memorable characters in the history of video games.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In life, Aerith Gainsborough is quirky and fun. Her personality is not what you would expect a character like her to have, but that contributes to her charm. It also makes her a great foil to the <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-21863 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Aerith_Gainsborough.png" alt="" width="199" height="297" />game’s sulky and broody protagonist, Cloud Strife. Aerith is upbeat, carefree, and joyful, and has no reservations about flirting with Cloud. She is stubborn and adventurous, but will do anything to protect her friends. Early in the game, the player learns of Aerith’s true identity as a Cetra, an ancient race of people who were said to have spiritual powers and were capable of communicating with the Planet. The Shinra corporation, who serve along with Sephiroth as the antagonists, spend most of Aerith’s life trying to capture her and experiment on her. Aerith’s consistent ability to evade capture by Shinra is what makes her demise at the hands of Sephiroth that much more devastating.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aerith’s death is sad. It is unexpected, even if the player goes into the game knowing it’s coming. Most importantly, it is a transcendent moment in video game history.  </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Final Fantasy VI &#8211; The First Female Protagonist</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/final-fantasy-vi-the-first-female-protagonist/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hayley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 12:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girls & Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[CW: Suicide mention &#160; Both Final Fantasy V and Final Fantasy VI were in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CW: Suicide mention</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19609 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/kamil-s-NPP4Z-3dJe8-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/kamil-s-NPP4Z-3dJe8-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/kamil-s-NPP4Z-3dJe8-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/kamil-s-NPP4Z-3dJe8-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/kamil-s-NPP4Z-3dJe8-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/kamil-s-NPP4Z-3dJe8-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Both </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> were in the development stages at the time the SNES (Super Nintendo Entertainment System) era drew to a close. While </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was critically overlooked upon its release, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">garnered a much different reaction from fans. Released in 1994 (under the title </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy III</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> overseas), </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was met with universal critical acclaim from franchise enthusiasts both domestic and international. Despite being the first title to be helmed by someone other than series creator Hironobu Sakaguchi, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is still lauded by many fans as the best game in the series, with good reason.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">touts itself as an ensemble piece, weaving a complex and nuanced good-versus-evil tale about a war between magic and technology. The game boasts fourteen playable characters (the most ever seen in a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> game), each with rich character backstories that are subtly peppered throughout the game. However, for the first time in franchise history, the protagonists of the story are women: Terra and Celes. Despite fronting as an ensemble, players of the game can clearly see how Terra and Celes’s characters drive the narrative and emotional arcs of the story forward.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is divided into two parts: the World of Balance and the World of Ruin. The first part focuses on Terra Branford and her character growth. When players first meet her, Terra is being mind-controlled with the power of a magic crown and laying waste to the small town of Narshe. When she awakens, Terra admits that she is an amnesiac, and has no memory of her life prior to the crown being placed on her head. It turns out that the reason the empire was so intent on robbing Terra of her agency is because she can use magic, an art that was previously thought extinct. The first part of the story sees Terra coming into her own, learning about her true identity as a half god (or Esper, as the game calls it), and becoming more proactive in helping out the rebellion against the evil Empire as she reclaims her agency. While Terra’s presence in the second part of the story is not as strong, her character arc is nevertheless compelling. After the main antagonist of the game (an evil Joker-lite clown named Kefka) successfully becomes a God and destroys the world, Terra finds herself adopting a bunch of children in a small town in the aftermath. Through becoming their adoptive mother, Terra grapples with the concept of love, an emotion she had been previously incapable of comprehending. With the help of her friends and her children, Terra comes to understand love in all of its forms, and helps save the world.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second part of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the World of Ruin, picks up right after Kefka destroys the world. This part of the game opens with Celes Chere, the other main female protagonist, on a deserted island, desperately trying to keep her adoptive father alive. In the World of Balance, Celes was a former Imperial general who defected from the empire as her disillusion with them grew. She joins the rebellion and works through the complicated emotions of abandoning <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19610 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/gabriel-varaljay-TwP4GjKC_3w-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/gabriel-varaljay-TwP4GjKC_3w-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/gabriel-varaljay-TwP4GjKC_3w-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/gabriel-varaljay-TwP4GjKC_3w-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/gabriel-varaljay-TwP4GjKC_3w-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/gabriel-varaljay-TwP4GjKC_3w-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />everything she&#8217;s have ever known for a cause that feels just. One of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy’s</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> most </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nEuf9ZSJrdg"><span style="font-weight: 400;">iconic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> moments features players getting to control Celes as she sings her way through an opera scene. (Fun fact &#8211; this scene was </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lpj0wJeS3hg"><span style="font-weight: 400;">parodied</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the indie darling <em>Undertale</em>!) Despite her efforts, Celes’s father passes away, and what follows is the first ever depiction of suicide ideation in a video game. Celes’s suicide attempt is raw and powerful, and it is a groundbreaking theme for a video game to explore in 1994. After Celes finds the drive to carry on in the wake of her prior hopelessness and despair, she proceeds to track down and gather up her old friends. Together, they team up to defeat Kefka and bring peace and balance to the world once more. All of those party retrieval quests are optional, and the player can attempt to fight Kefka with just Celes if they really want to. It is absolutely not recommended, as the Kefka boss fight is tough, but Celes being the only mandatory party member in the second half of the game cements her role as a protagonist.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a master class in showcasing the potential of video games as an art form. Video games are capable of nuanced storytelling, with rich depths that the player has to seek out. They are also capable of striking visuals and cinematic cutscenes despite graphical limitations. They are capable of slick, timeless gameplay that causes players to think and strategize. And finally, they are capable of telling stories about (though the game tries to hide it behind an “ensemble cast”) women. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is high art, and one of the greatest video games ever made. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Final Fantasy V &#8211; Platonic Love is Important Too</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/final-fantasy-v-platonic-love-is-important-too/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/final-fantasy-v-platonic-love-is-important-too/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hayley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 11:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girls & Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Final Fantasy IV was an incredible triumph for Square Enix. The game succeeded on multiple&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy IV </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">was an incredible triumph for Square Enix. The game</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">succeeded on multiple levels: it told a fully realized story and had compelling characters, whose relationships with each other drove the narrative forward. On the heels of this great success, Square Enix began development on both </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the final two games that would be released on the Super Nintendo Entertainment System. However, while </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy VI </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was met with critical acclaim from fans around the world, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was not so lucky.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-19290 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Final_Fantasy_V_Box_JAP-300x166.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="166" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Final_Fantasy_V_Box_JAP-300x166.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Final_Fantasy_V_Box_JAP.jpg 425w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Final Fantasy V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which initially came out in Japan on the SNES in 1992, is often ignored when compared to the other two games in its generation. With a brighter tone and a tighter focus on game mechanics as opposed to story, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> nevertheless didn’t see a worldwide release until 1998. The game was described as “just not accessible to the average gamer” by Ted Woolsey, the lead translator for the SNES-era </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> titles. The game was considered too difficult. Boasting an intricate job system with the return of the active time battle combat system from the previous installment, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy V </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">allowed players plenty of freedom to customize their playing experience, but that also led to intimidating, difficult gameplay. The story took a bit of a backseat so the developers could focus on building the job system, but it’s still a fun, lighthearted tale with plenty of humor and heart.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like all </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">games, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has its share of interesting and complex female characters. They are very different from the characters in its predecessor, but still compelling in their own way. The game has five main playable characters. Three of them are female. What makes </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> stand out is that it is the only </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> game with named characters that does not reduce its female characters to being the blatant subjects of a romance storyline.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lenna Charlotte Tycoon is the game’s princess character. She is the daughter of King Tycoon and heir to the throne of Tycoon. In the average JRPG, Lenna would be the main character’s love interest. However, the game does not explicitly have her falling in love with the game’s main hero, Bartz. Instead, Lenna thrives on her own and has compelling platonic relationships with the rest of the cast. If each player character in </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> represents an element, Lenna’s is water &#8211; devotion. She initially fights for her father, determined to rescue him when he goes missing. She accepts the duty the crystal gives her. When the Chancellor of Tycoon begs her to stay at the castle, she refuses his requests, feeling that her duty to save the world is more important than her life. Lenna is altruistic and kind, constantly risking her life for her loved ones. At one point in the game, Lenna willingly exposes herself to poison to save a wind drake from death. Her most compelling character relationship is with Faris. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Faris Scherwiz is a cross-dressing pirate captain who initially presents herself as male to the cast. She is one of the first characters in video games to play with gender presentation, though unfortunately, the game does not explore this too deeply. The game does not have Faris fall in <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-19291 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Amano_Faris_III-218x300.jpg" alt="" width="218" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Amano_Faris_III-218x300.jpg 218w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Amano_Faris_III.jpg 269w" sizes="(max-width: 218px) 100vw, 218px" />love with Bartz either, instead choosing to focus more on her relationship with Lenna. Faris is courageous and sometimes reckless, and often does not care about what other people think of her. While Lenna is kind and altruistic, Faris is selfish. If Lenna’s element is water, the element of devotion, Faris’s is fire, the element of courage. The two of them clash on the surface, but ultimately share similar character traits in their impulsive natures, courageous acts, and thirst for adventure. Faris joins the team for superficial reasons, not because she feels she has a duty to save the world. Late in the game, the player learns that Faris is actually Sarisa Scherwil Tycoon, Lenna’s sister and a princess of Tycoon. She was lost at sea and found by pirates. As Sarisa was unable to pronounce her name, the pirates dubbed her Faris. Learning about her sisterly connection to Lenna is what drives Faris’s character development. She becomes protective and fond of her fellow Warriors of Light, and slowly shifts her priorities.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Krile is the third and final playable female character. She is the granddaughter of another playable character, Galuf, and permanently replaces him in the party after Galuf sacrifices himself in the fight against Exdeath, the game’s antagonist. Krile is a bright and optimistic girl, who uses her hope to keep her spirits up and allow her to be the moodmaker of the group. Her hopeful attitude keeps the group’s spirits up as well, despite the grave situation they find themselves in. However, the story allows Krile moments of sadness and introspection, as well. She is allowed to grieve her grandfather and feel lonely. Krile also loves animals, and has the ability to communicate with them telepathically. The game does not explain why she has the abilities, but it makes for a very useful character. Krile, like Faris and Lenna, does not have any romantic inclinations towards Bartz, and she enjoys a platonic big brother/little sister relationship with him.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was always overlooked. However, it finds ways to stand out and continue the franchise’s streak of revolutionary gaming choices. It is the only </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> game where the number of female playable characters is higher than the number of male characters. It is the only </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> game to not include any romance storylines. There is a focus on sisterhood, and it is the only </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> game to have that kind of relationship between its playable characters. For a long time, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy V</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was series creator Hironobu Sakaeguchi’s favorite, an opinion he held until the release of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy IX</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2000.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/final-fantasy-v-platonic-love-is-important-too/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Final Fantasy IV &#8211; Pushing Boundaries with Female Characters</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/final-fantasy-iv-pushing-boundaries-with-female-characters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hayley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 10:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Girls & Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The year was 1991. A small company nestled in the heart of Japan called Square&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The year was 1991. A small company nestled in the heart of Japan called Square was reaping the critical and financial benefits of their budding game franchise, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The first game, released in 1987, was a last-ditch effort to save the company from bankruptcy. As the turn of the decade approached, the company had released three installments of Final Fantasy games, each building on the groundwork the previous game had laid.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy I</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was a dungeons and dragons campaign reimagined as a video game. It sounds absurd, but it was a major success for series creator Hironobu Sakaguchi and his team. However, there were no named characters, and the story was thin. The first sequel, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy II</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, was a valiant attempt to tell a harrowing story of war and sacrifice on an 8-bit console in 1989, but it fell a bit short due to unremarkable characters and troubling gameplay mechanics. And </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy III</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the last installment released on the Nintendo Entertainment System, introduced many </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> gameplay and world building staples that are still seen in <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19048 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/controller-5048166_1920-300x150.png" alt="" width="300" height="150" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/controller-5048166_1920-300x150.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/controller-5048166_1920-1024x512.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/controller-5048166_1920-768x384.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/controller-5048166_1920-1536x768.png 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/controller-5048166_1920-1110x555.png 1110w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/controller-5048166_1920.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />releases today. However, the story and characters in the game</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">were still lacking.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Square released </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy IV </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">on the heels of the invention of the 16-bit Super Nintendo Entertainment System, and what a game changer it was.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy IV</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is one of the first video games to have a complex story, similar to one that you would see in a movie. The tale draws inspiration from cinematic epics like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Star Wars, </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">about a dark knight named Cecil Harvey who comes to grips with the atrocities he commits in service to his empire, and his journey of atonement and redemption over the course of the story. The game has a rich cast of supporting characters, and it is one of the first games ever made where there are named female characters with their own character arcs. While the characters themselves feel like stock JRPG characters by today’s standards, the fact that they were conceptualized and programmed into a video game in the early 90s is nothing short of revolutionary. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The game</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">allows the player to control five characters in their party, and each one offers unique abilities from a tactical perspective. Rosa Farrel and Rydia are the two female characters in the game.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rosa is Cecil’s childhood friend and lover. She is also the team’s white mage and archer, and a crucial member of the squad from both a gameplay and story perspective. When approaching female characters in stories from a modern viewpoint, Rosa’s presence in the story definitely feels a bit backwards. She is introduced as Cecil’s love interest, and is often placed in situations where Cecil needs to rescue her. The player’s first major introduction to her is framed as a need to rescue her from a disease. She gets kidnapped by Golbez and is sort of in the center of a love triangle between Cecil and Kain (the narrative establishes the Cecil/Rosa relationship fairly early on and sticks to it). At the end of the game, Cecil insists that Rosa (and Rydia) stay behind in the wake of the final dungeon so he can “protect” them, which was admittedly frustrating to see as a player. Society has truly surpassed the need for outdated story moments like this, especially from a gameplay perspective: Rosa and Rydia are the most essential members of the squad due to their magical abilities. However, both Rosa and Rydia insist that Cecil is full of it and convince him to let them come defeat Golbez once and for all. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite some of these outdated storytelling beats plaguing her story, Rosa is a great character. She serves as a nice foil for Cecil, a source of light in his journey through the darkness. She is also one of the first female characters in gaming to get a character theme, and the piece of music that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> composer Nobuo Uematsu writes for Rosa is nothing short of </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GffeBZOqZGU"><span style="font-weight: 400;">genius</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The track is tender, romantic, and a touch bittersweet. The player really gets a sense of Rosa’s endless devotion and love for Cecil, and how she will stand by him through it all, when the track plays during their most emotionally charged scenes together. The song adds another dimension to their relationship, filling in all of the gaps of their history left unsaid by the text. There are even hints of Cecil’s feelings in the music, both for Rosa and for himself. That is where the bittersweetness comes in. You can sense Cecil’s hatred of who he used to be, how he is desperately trying to atone, and how Rosa will stand with him through his journey. The song feels like a conversation between two lovers, and it’s probably my favorite piece of </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> music ever written. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19051 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/potion-3539394_1920-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/potion-3539394_1920-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/potion-3539394_1920-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/potion-3539394_1920-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/potion-3539394_1920-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/potion-3539394_1920.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />Rydia, meanwhile, is more of an independent character and undergoes one of the most meaningful character transformations in the game, second only to the protagonist. Rydia is the game’s primary black mage and summoner, making her a powerhouse and truly essential member of the squad from a gameplay perspective. When we are introduced to Rydia early in the story, she is a small child whose village had just been destroyed by Cecil and Kain. It turns out that she is the daughter of a summoner, and has potential for great power. In the beginning, Rydia is angry and resentful towards Cecil. It’s understandable though, the guy did destroy her home and kill her mother. However, over the course of the story, Rydia learns to overcome that rage and anger. She bonds with Cecil after he saves her life, and together they overcome their demons. Rydia’s character arc also openly addresses the concept of childhood trauma and how to overcome it. Early on, there is a scene in the game where she is afraid to use fire magic due to how her home was destroyed. With help from her friends, Rydia learns to overcome her trauma and uses fire magic to save the lives of her friends who are fighting off monsters.  </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">as a franchise is all about setting precedents and taking risks, both within the franchise and for gaming as a whole. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy IV </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is no exception &#8211; this game shows that there is opportunity to tell compelling stories in video games. And more importantly, there is room for rich, interesting, fleshed-out female characters in this art medium. All future </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Final Fantasy</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> installments follow this trend, creating even more interesting and iconic characters than the last.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
