<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 041 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-041/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 12:14:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 041 Author Interview: Tiffany Meuret and &#8220;Mouse, Crow, Cockroach, Valkyrie&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-tiffany-meuret-and-mouse-crow-cockroach-valkyrie/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 10:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 041]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here at Luna Station, we like to pick our most recent issue authors&#8217; brains about their&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Here at <em>Luna Station</em>, we like to pick our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">most recent issue </a>authors&#8217; brains about their masterful stories. Today on the table we have Tiffany Meuret and her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/mouse-crow-cockroach-valkyrie/">Mouse, Crow, Cockroach, Valkyrie</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Writing from the point of a view of a non-human character can be difficult, but youdo it extremely well. What advice would you give to writers trying to do the same? </strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Tiffany: I struggled with this quite a bit. There is a fine line between the story being believable and being readable. A mouse wouldn&#8217;t know the name for a streetlight or a prison, but I found when I leaned too hard into (my best guess of) a mouse&#8217;s perspective that the prose was too <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18763 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mouse-1708347_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mouse-1708347_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mouse-1708347_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mouse-1708347_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mouse-1708347_1920-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/mouse-1708347_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> confusing to be enjoyable. So I guess my advice to other writers would be to be deliberate and precise in your word choice. Yes, your character is a mouse, but sometimes you have to call a streetlight a streetlight so the flow of the story isn&#8217;t impeded by abstractions. That said, try not to lose the whimsy. You are pretending to be a mouse, after all.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Why did you choose not to use human perspective for this story? </strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Tiffany: I tried writing scenes with human perspectives and I found that those lent themselves to something far more visceral and dark than the rest of the story. The tone was off, and I just didn&#8217;t like it, so I cut it.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Which was your favorite part to write—mouse, crow, cockroach, or Valkyrie—and why?</strong> </em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18764 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/raven-1347374_1280-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/raven-1347374_1280-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/raven-1347374_1280-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/raven-1347374_1280-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/raven-1347374_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Tiffany: Crow was my favorite. Maybe that&#8217;s just because I love crows? It was the easiest section to visualize, likely because there is so much material to work with&#8211;crows are well known for being clever and curious and mischievous, which lessened to load on me as writer. Readers can fill in the blanks. But while crow was my favorite, the Valkyrie section was the easiest to write. They served as inspiration for a novel too, which I completed last summer. Hopefully it becomes a real book one day.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects? </strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Tiffany: What am I not working on? I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever been busier in my writing career. I just finished up recording a part for a science fiction podcast written by one of my author friends, and am in the beginning stages of co-writing a book with another author. On top of that I&#8217;m working on another solo novel that is scaring the crap out of me simply because the idea is so big (it involves multiple selves and the multiverse and revenge and talking mirrors). I&#8217;ve also been working on edits for my debut novel, A Flood of Posies, releasing this fall. And it only took 14 years to get here (lol).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 041 Author Interview: Lindsey Duncan and &#8220;Sweet Little Lies&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-lindsey-duncan-and-sweet-little-lies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 10:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 041]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s time again, dear readers, for another Issue 041 author interview! Today we&#8217;re joined by&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s time again, dear readers, for another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">Issue 041</a> author interview! Today we&#8217;re joined by Lindsey Duncan as we chat about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/sweet-little-lies/">Sweet Little Lies</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Illusions baked into cake. Genius! Where did the inspiration for this story come from?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Lindsey: I don’t remember precisely how the idea came about, but I wanted to write a story about an illusionist who lost his talent and had to recruit an unwilling apprentice.  I picked a baker almost at random.  I had a general shape for the plot, but I wasn’t sure of all the pieces and details.  I knew that <em><strong><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-18109 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/david-holifield-kPxsqUGneXQ-unsplash-300x221.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="221" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/david-holifield-kPxsqUGneXQ-unsplash-300x221.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/david-holifield-kPxsqUGneXQ-unsplash-1024x753.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/david-holifield-kPxsqUGneXQ-unsplash-768x565.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/david-holifield-kPxsqUGneXQ-unsplash-1536x1130.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/david-holifield-kPxsqUGneXQ-unsplash-2048x1506.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></strong></em>I wanted Ilanor’s specific talents to help Tanniv when he was imprisoned, but until I got up to that point in writing the story, I really wasn’t sure how.  As so often seems to happen for me, a detail that I had put in earlier with no specific emphasis gave me the solution:  the flute and the technique of folding up an illusion.  If one wanted to send an illusion in secret, what better way than to bake it into a cake?</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The original draft of this story is an older one.   I wrote it before I started culinary school–before I had any plans to do so.  When I came back to edit it for submissions, I was a classically trained pastry chef.  That informed a lot of small changes…and a sneaking suspicion that maybe life really does imitate art.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story reads like an epic fantasy novel. Do you have any plans on writing more with these characters?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Lindsey: Oh, no, not that comment!  As much as I’ve written and sold short fiction, I’m a novelist at heart, and it always peeks through, sometimes at the most inconvenient times.  It is probably one of the rejections I receive most often on stories:  that it reads like part of a novel.  To some extent, that’s by design.  No tale, whether it be the briefest piece of flash fiction or a rambling ten book saga, simply comes into being in the first sentence and ends with the last.  Life goes on, before and after.  I love the “Yes, but…” ending to a story: the main problem is solved (or not), but it creates all new ones.  I like to leave readers picturing where the characters might go next.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Which is also a roundabout way of saying that I don’t have any plans to write more about Ilanor and Tanniv, but the door is never fully closed.  If an idea drifts into my mind, you just might see them again.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any writers who have influenced your work?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I grew up on a steady diet of fantasy novels, starting with books like Lloyd Alexander’s Prydain Chronicles–which planted the seed for a later fascination with all things Welsh–and Tamora <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-18110 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/The_Chronicles_of_Prydain_set-222x300.jpg" alt="" width="222" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/The_Chronicles_of_Prydain_set-222x300.jpg 222w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/The_Chronicles_of_Prydain_set.jpg 272w" sizes="(max-width: 222px) 100vw, 222px" />Pierce’s Song of the Lioness quartet.  For me, adventures rarely occurred in the real world, and I inhaled fantastic realms.  Early on, I developed a distinct intolerance for works where the women were just decorative.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Later, I found inspiration in the immersive detail of Elizabeth Moon.  Her <em>Remnant Population </em>may be my favorite “first contact” novel.  I learned a lot about characters and their interplay in the works of Lois McMaster Bujold and Jane Lindskold.  For me, the Children of Dodec books by Dave Duncan–no relation–were a perfect illustration of Teresa Nielsen Hayden’s saying, “Plot is a literary convention.  Story is a force of nature.”  That reading experience solidified the concept as a goal for me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 041 Author Interview: Genevieve Gornichec and &#8220;What the Gods Left Behind&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-genevieve-gornichec-and-what-the-gods-left-behind/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 041]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another Tuesday, another interview with one of our current authors. Meet Genevieve Gornichec as we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Another Tuesday, another interview with one of our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">current</a> authors. Meet Genevieve Gornichec as we get up-close and personal with her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/what-the-gods-left-behind/">What the Gods Left Behind</a>.&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">LSQ: Your story reflects situations that are a bit uncomfortably familiar. What do you think we can learn from stories like this?</span></strong></em></div>
<div>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Genevieve: Well, I didn’t expect certain aspects of this story to be so…uh, relevant. Things have really been put into perspective lately for a lot of us, as far as how much we take for granted in our everyday lives, and I think that’s part of the takeaway I was going for: could we even imagine a world like this, where so much has been lost? I really tried to put myself in Katla’s shoes. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18142 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/viking-5157647_1280-229x300.png" alt="" width="229" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/viking-5157647_1280-229x300.png 229w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/viking-5157647_1280-780x1024.png 780w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/viking-5157647_1280-768x1008.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/viking-5157647_1280.png 975w" sizes="(max-width: 229px) 100vw, 229px" />Imean, she has one pair of glasses and if she loses or breaks them, she won’t be able to see for the rest of her life. I couldn’t even imagine.</span></p>
<p><em><strong><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">LSQ: As soon as I realized who the dog was, I got really excited. Why do you think stories about gods taking form in the real world are so appealing?</span></strong></em></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Genevieve: </span><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">That’s awesome!! My sister texted me as she was reading it and was like, “So is the dog Odin or…?” And I was like, “If there is a one-eyed being in a story, and I wrote the story, there’s a really good chance it’s Odin.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">But all in all, I think it’s because we crave a little magic to counteract the mundane, you know? We like to imagine there’s something more out there than what we can see, and incorporating gods and goddesses people already know about into the real world makes them into something we recognize, something we can connect with. I love reading modern mythology stories because it’s just so interesting the different ways it can be done. <i>The Goddess Wars </i>series by Kendare Blake and <i>The Sixth World </i>series by Rebecca Roanhorse are some of my favorite reads for these exact reasons.</span></p>
<p><em><strong><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect of writing this story and why? What do you like best about this story and why?</span></strong></em></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Genevieve: </span><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">The most challenging aspect of this story was its gentle lean towards sci-fi. I enjoy reading and watching sci-fi, but personally I’ve only ever written urban/historical fantasy. Gods? Sure. Ghosts? Absolutely. Talking animals? Sign me up. Trying to plan out what happened to the world to make it into a plausible dystopia? Not so much.</span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18138 alignright" style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/apocalyptic-158627_1280-300x219.png" alt="" width="300" height="219" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/apocalyptic-158627_1280-300x219.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/apocalyptic-158627_1280-1024x749.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/apocalyptic-158627_1280-768x562.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/apocalyptic-158627_1280.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">My favorite heroines are the unlikely, reluctant ones, so Katla herself is what I like best about this story. She’s so stubborn that she tries to avoid using the magic within herself, just because she’s convinced that it shouldn’t exist and it makes her doubt her own mind. She’s sort of a psychopomp, sure, but she’s also a mom in her thirties, an accountant who has the misfortune to be nearsighted after the end of the world, a regular person trying to navigate a dystopia. And she wouldn’t leave me alone until I wrote her story down.</span></p>
<p><em><strong><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</span></strong></em></p>
<p><span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif;">Genevieve: Absolutely! In addition to chugging along on my sophomore novel, my debut novel,<i> The Witch’s Heart</i>, releases in early 2021. The entire thing takes place behind the scenes of Norse mythology and centers on Loki’s wife, Angrboda. She’s a background character in most retellings you pick up—and usually a rather vilified one at that—but if you combine her with a couple other female figures lurking in the Norse myths, with whom she shares common attributes? Suddenly you’ve got this rather formidable woman with a whole story to tell. It’s the book of my heart, honestly.</span></p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 041 Author Interview: Nicole Crucial and &#8220;The Anatomy of Spines&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-nicole-crucial-and-the-anatomy-of-spines/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 13:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 041]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17825</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s Tuesday, which means another Issue 041 author interview! Meet Nicole Crucial as she chats&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s Tuesday, which means another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">Issue 041</a> author interview! Meet Nicole Crucial as she chats with us about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-anatomy-of-spines/">The Anatomy of Spines</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Werewolf stories aren’t seen too often, at least in my experience. What do you like best about them?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Nicole: I think werewolf stories call to the angsty little part of my heart that lives on from my preteen and teenage years—the years where I began writing. (It probably helps that the <em>Twilight</em> werewolves were among my first fictional exposures to werewolves—plenty of angst there. Most of the literary werewolves I’ve encountered have been in<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18043 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/moon-2933976_1280-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/moon-2933976_1280-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/moon-2933976_1280-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/moon-2933976_1280-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/moon-2933976_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> YA fiction/coming-of-age stories overall, although that’s probably because I read a lot of it.) Werewolves represent the darker, animal side in all of us. In my story and in many other stories, werewolves’ transformations are triggered by anger, upset, or other intense negative emotions, mirroring the way we sometimes unleash the worst parts of ourselves when we experience those emotions. Especially as a teenager, it can feel like that side of you is a separate species, something you don’t recognize. You’re not yourself: you’re some creature consumed by an emotion. I don’t miss much about being a teenager, but one thing I sometimes wax nostalgic about is how intensely you seem to feel things so deeply in that time of life.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Werewolves also have an interesting power dynamic at play. In most stories, and in mine, werewolves gain a lot of physical power, strength, and sometimes other abilities when they transform. But it comes at a cost—your humanity, your sense of reason, your self-control. Werewolf stories so often cast the condition as a disease or a curse. The <em>Harry Potter</em> series, for one—it’s literally a curse. In the show <em>The Magicians</em>, lycanthropy is an STI. But I like stories where lycanthropy is a negotiation of power, and what the characters have to give up to access that power. Stories about monsters are never really about monsters, after all.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story has a strong will-she-won’t-she vibe that played out very well. What advice do you have for writers who want to effectively build tension?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Nicole: Tension builds when two or more forces exert opposite wills. In the case of “The Anatomy of Spines,” it’s Rosco’s will against the wills of his mother, girlfriend, and Pack. But force can come from non-person entities: institutions, cultural norms, etc. I think what made the tension so strong in my story is that I knew the characters well and knew that both sides truly believed they were right, and each character wanted what they wanted intensely. Every piece of fiction is driven by character desire. These characters desired exact opposite things, whereas in some stories, characters/entities just want <em>different</em> things.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">If you have a story about a couple and one wants to travel a lot and the other wants to start a business, there’s certain to be some tension because what comes along with each of those goals will cause conflict. (It’s hard to travel when someone is consumed 24/7 by building a business, and it’s hard to build a business if you’re spending money and time traveling and not staying in one spot.) Still, with an issue like that, characters can still get creative in their problem-solving and try to find alternate solutions. When character desires are dead opposite each other, though, that’s a really easy way to ramp up tension. And when the issue is literally life-or-death, it’s hard for characters to think about anything else.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect of writing this story and why? What do you like best about this story and why?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Nicole: This story was actually a novel. I wrote 80,000 words of this story, with a much more complex plot and more characters and a big external conflict taking up the space, and a much different outcome for certain characters. I decided to try to condense it and interpret it as a short story, focusing on the development of tension and the crafting of language, as an exercise for myself. (In a short story, you can get really into the weeds with poetic language—you can’t do that easily in a novel because it will be exhausting to read.)</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">In some senses, having written Rosco and Lorelei’s story at length before made it easier to write briefly—I knew who they were, much more intimately than I usually know a character in a short story. However, it was really challenging to distill a whole novel’s worth of plot and world and character into 3,500 words that still captured the atmosphere, conflict, and story I was going for. Honestly, I think I failed—this story is much different than the novel, as it had to be. But the <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18047 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/wolf-3022813_1280-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/wolf-3022813_1280-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/wolf-3022813_1280-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/wolf-3022813_1280-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/wolf-3022813_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />failure isn’t a bad thing because I’m also really happy with how this separate iteration turned out.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">My favorite thing about the story is how it feels a little haunted from the beginning. I think you know how it ends from the first scene, although perhaps the means is a little different. I’m also very proud of a lot of the dialogue, as well as how I was able to portray the many complicated relationships succinctly. There’s a certain beauty in using subtext for storytelling, using what isn’t said—I don’t think I was always subtle in this piece, but it’s something I’m always working on, and I think there are some great moments of subtext in “The Anatomy of Spines.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 041 Author Interview: Kel Purcill and &#8220;Luminous&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-kel-purcill-and-luminous/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-kel-purcill-and-luminous/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 10:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 041]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17711</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What do Tuesdays have in common with Issue 041? Both feature our amazing authors! Today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">What do Tuesdays have in common with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">Issue 041</a>? Both feature our amazing authors! Today we chat with Kel Purcill about her sensuous story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/luminous/">Luminous</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Starting a story off with a “failed” happily-ever-after isn’t seen much in popular culture. Do you feel it’s important to have more stories that show the positives that can come from divorce?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kel: Absolutely! I believe the female experience of divorce in particular &#8211; in all its complicated, gutting, joyous, maddening, elusive, incandescent rawness &#8211; hasn’t been even close to adequately explored. There are more outcomes from divorce as there are reasons behind them, or the people experiencing them. So sharing the positives that come from divorce are a vital addition to the conversation and communal library of potential “what-next” scenarios.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-17958 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/evening-sky-700279_1280-300x200.png" alt="" width="444" height="296" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/evening-sky-700279_1280-300x200.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/evening-sky-700279_1280-1024x682.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/evening-sky-700279_1280-768x512.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/evening-sky-700279_1280.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 444px) 100vw, 444px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">There are established tropes and stereotypes about the female divorcee in media which is understandable and born from reality. But the experience of divorce doesn’t stop once someone stops crying at the mention of an ex, or throws clothes out a window, or gets revenge or&#8230;or&#8230;or&#8230; insert montage of choice, really. I’m fascinated in the “now what?” question: this has happened, now what? I’ve crash-landed on Planet Now-Divorced&#8230;now what? And why can’t the now what be amazing?</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The moon coming down from the sky and falling in love—you must tell us how you came up with this!</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><span style="color: #222222;">Kel: Take a scoop of the sky late one night when, in your undies, on your way to rescue the clothes from the clothesline, you’re stunned by the moonlight pouring down the sky like an invitation. Store, carefully wrapped, for a few years. Finely grind the eye-rolls and sighs collected when you’re introduced as divorced before anything else. Season well with snark, hilarious innuendo, and puns from everyday life. Mix in generously the laughter, lessons, terror, and delight of chasing dreams. Sauté a handful of ponderings on what a future relationship might look like. Leave to cool, maybe get frostbite. Boil in a university course where one week’s focus is on magic realism and fabulism, leave to marinate and ferment into deliciousness&#8230;</span></p>
<p dir="ltr">The idea of the moon coming down to woo a woman was all of that, then lead to considering how the moon would date someone, who they would find attractive, the logistics and little moments that would connect them&#8230; and the consequences for the rest of the world.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: There’s quite the repertoire of baked goods in this story. Are you a baker yourself? Why do you think baked goods add such richness to prose?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Kel: I am a baker! Adding baking to Luminous wasn’t deliberate, but baked goods certainly adds the richness to prose. I think that’s because we all eat, and we all have some food-related memories which punch us directly in the tastebuds and vice versa. Using baked goods in particular adds a level of intimacy or emotional messaging, particularly if hand-made. Cardamom cookies may be untasted to the reader, but the connection is there to cookies, all the senses used, and that connection (hopefully positive) ties the reader into the story through memory, emotion, taste-memory, and curiosity.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17959 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/blue-3778955_1280-231x300.jpg" alt="" width="231" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/blue-3778955_1280-231x300.jpg 231w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/blue-3778955_1280-788x1024.jpg 788w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/blue-3778955_1280-768x998.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/blue-3778955_1280.jpg 985w" sizes="(max-width: 231px) 100vw, 231px" />An interesting question to ask people is what their favorite food-related memory is. I’ve found everyone has one &#8211; and you can even drill down into emotion related specifics. My favorite regret-related food memory is a cherry tart I tasted when I was maybe twelve. It was baked by the “Siberia! No other!” mother of Sabine, the woman I babysat for of a Friday night. It was Sabine’s birthday, the mother had flown to Australia for the occasion and baked all week in preparation. She made this incredible dark cherry tart among other things, which remains the best thing I’ve ever tasted and eaten. The food at the party was way too rich and I ended up throwing up&#8230; And no more tart was left or made. I think the word ‘regret’, and I can taste that tart. It makes sense that food plays a huge part in our relationships, in our tokens of affection, our personal histories. Baking something is often time-dependent, just like creating. Taking the time to create is self-nurturing, whether it’s baking or writing or bagpipes or concreting, no matter how many others share it at the end.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong><span style="color: #222222;">LSQ: </span></strong></em><em><strong>What was the most challenging aspect of writing this story and why? What do you like best about this story and why?</strong></em></p>
<div><span style="font-family: Arial;">Kel: The most challenging part was not thinking about what people would say about it, or say about me because of it, and writing it anyway. Maybe because of that fear, writing was both a love letter to myself and declaration to the universe. I think it’s joyful, optimistic and celebratory. There’s magic in that. What I like most is it’s the story that wanted to be told, on the page in all its lush, sensual honesty. </span></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-kel-purcill-and-luminous/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 041 Author Interview: C.L. Holland and &#8220;On the Cusp of Darkness&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-c-l-holland-and-on-the-cusp-of-darkness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 041]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back to our Tuesday interviews, where authors from Issue 041 tell us what&#8217;s on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Welcome back to our Tuesday interviews, where authors from <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">Issue 041</a> tell us what&#8217;s on their minds. Today we&#8217;re featuring C.L. Holland and her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/on-the-cusp-of-darkness/">On the Cusp of Darkness</a>.&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><i>LSQ: Although it’s never explicitly stated what the Darkness is, it’s clear that women have an important role to play here. What drew you to writing about a women-centric secret society?</i></strong></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17910 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stairs-2799299_1280-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stairs-2799299_1280-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stairs-2799299_1280-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stairs-2799299_1280-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stairs-2799299_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div>C.L.: The Darkness itself isn&#8217;t woman-centric, but it made sense to me that the choice the child makes &#8211; to embrace their power or to be &#8220;cured&#8221; &#8211; would be treated differently depending on gender roles. Women and girls are often encouraged to give up their own opportunities to support others, to reject power, and demonized if they make another choice. For that reason</div>
<div> it made sense for the adept collecting Sirsa to be female too, having made the same choice herself. She understands in a way a male narrator wouldn&#8217;t.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><i>LSQ: There’s a lot left unsaid in this story, and lots of room for expansion! Do you have plans to revisit Sirsa, or this world you&#8217;ve created?</i></strong></div>
<div>C.L.: I actually don&#8217;t, there are so many other ideas I want to work on! Sometimes the best stories are the ones that leave questions.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><i>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story?</i></strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>C.L.: The moment I realized why Sirsa was in the cellar in the first place.</div>
<div><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17911 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/candles-burning-4663345_1280-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/candles-burning-4663345_1280-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/candles-burning-4663345_1280-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/candles-burning-4663345_1280-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/candles-burning-4663345_1280.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></em></div>
<div><strong><i>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</i></strong></div>
<p>C.L.: I have several short stories in various stages of editing, but my main project at the moment is a fantasy novel. Kind of <em>The Raven</em> meets the <em>A-Team.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 041 Author Interview: Victoria Feistner and &#8220;Ganymede Days&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-victoria-feistner-and-ganymede-days/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 10:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 041]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17478</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to Tuesday, where we routinely sit and chat with an author of our current&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Tuesday, where we routinely sit and chat with an author of our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">current <em>Quarterly</em></a>. Today, meet Victoria Feistner, author of &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/ganymede-days/">Ganymede Days</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What drew you to set this story on Ganymede, our solar system&#8217;s largest moon? </strong></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17869 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nasa-jlV2k_Fx0fc-unsplash-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nasa-jlV2k_Fx0fc-unsplash-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nasa-jlV2k_Fx0fc-unsplash-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nasa-jlV2k_Fx0fc-unsplash-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nasa-jlV2k_Fx0fc-unsplash-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nasa-jlV2k_Fx0fc-unsplash-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nasa-jlV2k_Fx0fc-unsplash-2048x2048.jpg 2048w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nasa-jlV2k_Fx0fc-unsplash-550x550.jpg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Victoria: The Ganymede series (currently a tryptich comprised of <i>Ganymede Riots, Ganymede Nights</i> and <i>Ganymede Days)</i>, is based in part on a dream that I had about standing on the moon&#8217;s surface, staring up at the bulk of Jupiter. Staring eye-to-eye, so speak. As for being the system&#8217;s largest moon&#8230; I think that once humanity expands into the solar system that Ganymede will be a likely choice for a future colony, thanks to its location (close to the resources of the asteroid belt), and the fact that Ganymede has its own magnetic field, which should help to shield colonists and make their lives easier. So the setting decision was a combination of imagery and science.</div>
<div></div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The narrator makes frequent reference to God. What is the significance of this, and also is this in contrast to how an Earthling may think of the same being? Why or why not? </strong></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>Victoria: Balancing against the science aspect of the story is the fact that the protagonist (left unnamed in the tryptich) refers to Jupiter as their &#8220;god&#8217;—despite, or perhaps because of, the view out the window. Even in the future I don&#8217;t think that humanity will ever shed its need to believe in something larger than itself, the supernatural in some form or another, even if atheism spreads to become the majority view. But perhaps new religions will pop up as humanity spreads, growing and changing. The main difference in belief in an earthly religion and Ganymede&#8217;s version is that the protagonist can <i>see</i> their god, can see that god looking down on them. And, after all, Jupiter the planet replies to prayers the same way that Jupiter the god did.</div>
<div></div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Class systems, colonization, and the politics of a health care system—</strong><strong>all huge issues that are deftly featured in this relatively short piece. What was the biggest challenge in writing this story and why? </strong></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>Victoria: Class systems, colonization, the politics of health care—these are all huge issues in the news of any given moment of any day (as I write this, COVID-19 spreads worldwide and the RCMP interferes with the Wet&#8217;suwet&#8217;e Nation on unconceded territory). It&#8217;s natural for those issues to come out in a story, even if I didn&#8217;t intend them when I sat down to write it. The greatest challenge in any short story but particularly SF is fitting the world-building into the narrative without breaking the line of the story, and if that happened with &#8220;Ganymede Days&#8221; then I am proud to have accomplished it.</div>
<div></div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Unintended sacrifice is the narrator&#8217;s conclusion, but they seem to be accepting of their fate, as if nothing else is to be expected of their life on Ganymede. Can you speak to this? What does this say about the narrator?</strong></em></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>Victoria: There are always people marked by society to give, whether they want to or not. After <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17870 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jupiter-2208206_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jupiter-2208206_1920-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jupiter-2208206_1920-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jupiter-2208206_1920-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jupiter-2208206_1920-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jupiter-2208206_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />all, if society has a class structure, then someone has to be, by definition, on the bottom, and sacrifice and exploitation always flow upwards from the lower rungs. Struggle—whether class struggle or along any other axis that holds up patriarchy—is exhausting. And sometimes resignation is the result. It isn&#8217;t fair, and I wish I had more hope that humanity would outgrow this mode of thinking, but perhaps the hope comes from the fact that there are still people alive to be resigned, and living among the stars. In the meantime, we need to keep doing what we can here and now so that such a pessimistic view is, in the future, as unrealistic and dated as the Jetsons are to us.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 041 Author Interview: Jenny Wong and Sylvia Santiago and &#8220;Stealing Through the Stars&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-jenny-wong-and-sylvia-santiago-and-stealing-through-the-stars/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 10:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 041]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17476</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to our weekly chat with authors of the current LSQ issue. Today we sit&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to our weekly chat with authors of the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">current LSQ issue</a>. Today we sit down with Jenny Wong and Sylvia Santiago, authors of &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/stealing-through-the-stars/">Stealing Through the Stars</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Firstly, can you describe the experience of writing a short story between two people, both creativity and logistically?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17777 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/greg-rakozy-oMpAz-DN-9I-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Jenny and Sylvia: It’s not as complicated a process as people may think. For us, it’s pretty organic. Each of us comes up with a line, scene, or a character, and hands it over to the other.  We work out of Google docs on a shared document. Often, we’re not working on the same scene or even with the same character. Sylvia came up with Nova, Jenny came up with Bis, and both had joint custody of the cat. We’ll finish a scene, then one of us will say, “I know what happens next&#8230;or at the end..or four scenes from now.” We’ll go away, write, then come back and surprise each other.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The setting of the starship is described vividly; what was the inspiration for the Veronica Speedwell?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Jenny and Sylvia: We thought the idea of a cruise ship (a starliner) set in space would be fun.  Then a bunch of little things came together and snowballed&#8230;</p>
<p dir="ltr">The following is a dramatization of real life events. Creative liberties have been taken.</p>
<p dir="ltr">J: What if the starliner had an atrium area where people could walk in a garden and feel like they’re on a planet with a night sky?</p>
<p dir="ltr">S: Let’s make that the theme of the whole ship&#8211;the Earth Experience. We can have a labyrinth, maybe a menagerie or two. And we can name the ship after one of the favorite plants in the garden.</p>
<p dir="ltr">J: And there can be some sort of crime caper.</p>
<p dir="ltr">S: With a cat burglar…</p>
<p dir="ltr">J&amp;S: YES!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The characters and locale seem built for more adventures and mysteries &#8212; do you have plans to continue this story?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Jenny and Sylvia: Yes. Probably. Even while we were writing the story, we had to contain ourselves to the main story line of the “cat caper”. There was a more in depth back story between the Queen and the Captain that we’d discussed. Bis still has some stories to tell, and <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17778 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nathan-duck-KnLj3o9A66E-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nathan-duck-KnLj3o9A66E-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nathan-duck-KnLj3o9A66E-unsplash-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nathan-duck-KnLj3o9A66E-unsplash-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nathan-duck-KnLj3o9A66E-unsplash-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/nathan-duck-KnLj3o9A66E-unsplash-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />there’s a whole other planet where Chuy is running his family restaurant.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Ironically, there is a crossover between this story and another published in an earlier issue of <em>LSQ</em>. The homeland of the Ujimi pines shows up in the “<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-volcano-keeper/">The Volcano Keeper</a>” (written by Jenny), then in “Stealing Though the Stars” a character is presented with a gift of Ujimi pine oil.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on other writing projects at the moment, together or individually? If so, can you tell us about them? </strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Jenny and Sylvia: We co-wrote our first story in 2018, and we had such a good time with it that we decided to write something every year. This year, it may or may not be a chapbook about spooky little saints.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 041 Author Interview: Sarah Pauling and &#8220;Cloth Mother&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-sarah-pauling-and-cloth-mother/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 041]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Saddle on up, pardners, and meet Issue 041 author Sarah Pauling as she discusses her&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saddle on up, pardners, and meet <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">Issue 041</a> author Sarah Pauling as she discusses her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/cloth-mother/">Cloth Mother</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div><em><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17739 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/alexander-sinn-KgLtFCgfC28-unsplash-1-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/alexander-sinn-KgLtFCgfC28-unsplash-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/alexander-sinn-KgLtFCgfC28-unsplash-1-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/alexander-sinn-KgLtFCgfC28-unsplash-1-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/alexander-sinn-KgLtFCgfC28-unsplash-1-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/alexander-sinn-KgLtFCgfC28-unsplash-1-2048x1368.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />LSQ: This story first appeared in </strong></em><strong>Strange Horizons</strong><em><strong> in 2015. Given it&#8217;s been five years, have some of your thoughts on the themes of this piece changed over half a decade? Why or why not?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Sarah: Half a decade! Wow.</div>
<div></div>
<div>This was my first serious attempt at writing original fiction. My interest in these themes (child psychology, AI, sacrificial relationships, hope for a barren Earth) has only intensified since then. There are elements of the story I&#8217;d approach differently now, but I also think the words would come more slowly: one of my current goals is to reconnect with the shameless, fearless writing process I had pre-publication. These days I have to beat back the internal editor with a broom.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Child psychological development features heavily in this piece. Do you have a background in this or related sciences? What drew you to explore this concept in the isolation of an orbiting satellite? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Sarah: I have a Master&#8217;s degree in educational sociology. In 2015, I did not. Therefore, this story functions more as a premonition than a thesis. Even then, I was interested in the ways love and social support shape our communities and our brains. I had read up on all of the groundbreaking, unethical experiments from when psychology was a younger field. Harlow and his monkeys fascinated and frightened me. Experiments like that required isolation of the subject, so outer space seemed like a natural fit.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Also: I&#8217;d watched a lot of <em>Star Trek</em> that year and couldn&#8217;t stop thinking about AI characters (this has not changed).</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: As a reader, I felt relief when Mazie finally makes contact with Ian, leading me to realize I was at some level unaware of the tension building in the story. What was it like to build the character of Mazie as she works through her formative years? Was this challenging or did it come naturally? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>Sarah: Mazie&#8217;s character crystallized pretty quickly for me. I wanted her to be headstrong and precocious, but it didn&#8217;t take long to realize that this intelligence and capacity for self-reflection was going to make parts of her isolation even harder for her to bear. She&#8217;s not just lonely&#8211;she&#8217;s <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17740 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stefan-cosma-GVlcXhQejA8-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stefan-cosma-GVlcXhQejA8-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stefan-cosma-GVlcXhQejA8-unsplash-820x1024.jpg 820w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stefan-cosma-GVlcXhQejA8-unsplash-768x959.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stefan-cosma-GVlcXhQejA8-unsplash-1230x1536.jpg 1230w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stefan-cosma-GVlcXhQejA8-unsplash-1639x2048.jpg 1639w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />deeply afraid of what that loneliness is doing to her, and what that means for her ability to carry out the mission she was born for. That was an interesting complex to explore through the eyes of a child.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us about them?  </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Sarah: I&#8217;m writing a surreal post-apocalyptic Michigan regional fantasy involving sentient <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pumpjack">pumpjacks</a>. I&#8217;m also revising a retrofuturist story about a comedienne who accidentally disrupts a galactic antifascist rendezvous. (She mistakes it for a drug deal and heckles it from onstage. She is very sorry.)</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 041 Author Interview: Rachel Delaney Craft and &#8220;Black Crocodile&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-041-author-interview-rachel-delaney-craft-and-black-crocodile/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 041]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17472</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to our chat with Issue 041 author Rachel Delaney Craft about her story &#8220;Black&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to our chat with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">Issue 041</a> author Rachel Delaney Craft about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/black-crocodile/">Black Crocodile</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div>
<div><em><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17695 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/hotchicksing-Dyc95dKuGp4-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/hotchicksing-Dyc95dKuGp4-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/hotchicksing-Dyc95dKuGp4-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/hotchicksing-Dyc95dKuGp4-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/hotchicksing-Dyc95dKuGp4-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/hotchicksing-Dyc95dKuGp4-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />LSQ: The images of the drought, the struggling village, the livestock, the monk, the buffalo calf, and the mangoes are so vivid throughout your story. How did you conjure such strong sensory details? Have you written about Buddhist culture before?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Rachel: They say we read to escape, but I think we often write to escape as well. Part of the joy of writing this story was the research I did on Buddhism and Thailand&#8211;reading personal blogs, perusing photos online, essentially trying to transport myself there so I could portray the setting and characters accurately (though I&#8217;m sure I didn&#8217;t succeed 100%). I always start my research with nature, because that&#8217;s what interests me most: the climate and weather, the plants and animals, the relationship between the people and the land. These ideas were integral to this story in particular, where the people, livestock, crops, and drought are all tightly interconnected.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Do you consider this a coming of age story? What do you see as the narrator&#8217;s purpose when she&#8217;s finished with her transformation at the end?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Rachel: Absolutely. Like most teens, Kanokwan is grappling with the joy and heartbreak of first love, taking on more responsibility at home, and worrying about her future. She is also searching for a purpose in life, which is something many of us (myself included) struggle with long after adolescence. She finds new purpose in caring for the buffalo, and after her transformation, her purpose becomes protecting the buffalo and the village. I love the idea that sometimes what we need most is to be needed by others.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Deep reading of this story could conjure many types of symbolism hidden within. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17696 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stephane-yaich-HEs5KxL0VJ4-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stephane-yaich-HEs5KxL0VJ4-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stephane-yaich-HEs5KxL0VJ4-unsplash-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stephane-yaich-HEs5KxL0VJ4-unsplash-768x509.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stephane-yaich-HEs5KxL0VJ4-unsplash-1536x1017.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/stephane-yaich-HEs5KxL0VJ4-unsplash-2048x1356.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Do you have anything along this line you&#8217;d like the reader to focus on?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Rachel: I never intended to cram in so many symbols&#8211;water, mangoes, snakes, colors, just to name a few. Instead, they emerged naturally as the story progressed. What I love about symbols is how every reader interprets them differently based on their own unique worldview and experience. So I would say go into every story with an open mind, and let yourself discover as you read. Think about which symbols emerge and what they mean to you. If a story resonates with you, read it again&#8211;you&#8217;ll probably discover something new.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect of this story to write and why? What are you most proud of?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>Rachel: I think the greatest challenge, and the thing I&#8217;m most proud of, was patience. I worked on this story for four years before it finally found a home at <em>LSQ</em>. I workshopped it with critique partners, submitted it to magazines, got rejections and feedback from editors, and revised, revised, revised. The process was slow but rewarding, because with each new draft I watched the story bloom a little more. The story&#8217;s various layers, its themes and images and symbols, needed that time and patience to grow.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
