<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lisa Shininger &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/lisa-shininger/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 18:54:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Short story reviews for February 2016</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/short-story-reviews-for-february-2016/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lisa Shininger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 16:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Binary System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early spring has arrived here, though it seems to have skipped a few steps. By&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Early spring has arrived here, though it seems to have skipped a few steps. By late February, we&#8217;re used to seeing the first neon-green shoots of onion grass and crocuses poking through snow. This year, though, we have massive rainstorms and unseasonable heat. It adds an element of the bizarre to picking through the detritus of a Valentine&#8217;s Day candy binge while dressed appropriately for a summer picnic. Spending a few hours a day sifting through, or writing in, science fictional and fantasy worlds, it&#8217;s hard not to see all the reasons why those seasonal norms are shifting. It&#8217;s hard not to fear many of those reasons. It&#8217;s harder still to admit to being exhilarated by any of them.</p>
<hr width="50%" />
<p><strong>&#8220;<a href="http://www.fantasticstoriesoftheimagination.com/flash-fiction-while-i-wait/">While I Wait</a>&#8220;</strong> by Ayla Al-Bedawi (500 words)<br />
<em><a href="http://www.fantasticstoriesoftheimagination.com/">Fantastic Stories of the Imagination</a>, January/February 2016</em></p>
<p><em>Every morning after I set the kettle on the stove, I peek through the blinds to check on the dead who have collected on my stoop overnight.</em></p>
<p>A piece of flash that packs a wallop. The narrator&#8217;s world is one of mundane, familiar horror. In other stories we might explore how it came to be, or how it can be resolved, but here Al-Bedawi uses it as a backdrop for a tiny bit of human kindness. No purpose. No mission.</p>
<hr width="50%" />
<p><strong>&#8220;<a title="" href="https://www.freitag.de/autoren/der-freitag/the-house-of-surrender">The House of Surrender</a>&#8220;</strong> by Laurie Penny (4100 words)<br />
<em><a title="" href="https://www.freitag.de/">Der Freitag</a>, January 2016</em></p>
<p><em>Not far from here and many lifetimes&#8217; journey away, there is a place called Sanctuary where they grow almonds and avocados and the weather is a perpetual late Spring. The town and its hundred thousand happy folk are watered by a wide, grey, treacherous river, and in that river is an island where no trees grow, and on that island is a house unlike any other.</em></p>
<p><em>It has had many names, but the people of Sanctuary have forgotten them. They call it the House of Surrender.</em></p>
<p>Der Freitag is a German site, but don&#8217;t worry: this is the English-language version of the story. Unfortunately I no longer remember how it wound up in one of my open tabs, but it was another refreshing and unexpected surprise. Although it is a science-fiction story set in a future world like ours, like Al-Bedawi&#8217;s piece, it doesn&#8217;t feel like it falls all that far away from a path we&#8217;re currently walking. Horrifying, but with a thread of hope. I thought of James Tiptree throughout. Mind that Rape Culture tag at the beginning; it definitely applies.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short story reviews for December 2015</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/short-story-reviews-december-2015/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lisa Shininger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 17:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Binary System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every time I sat down to read stories for this month&#8217;s column, I thought the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every time I sat down to read stories for this month&#8217;s column, I thought the theme was obvious. At the end of a long year filled with outrage and sadness, focusing on the lighthearted seemed like the way to go. But this winter has been strange. The days are warm and rainy, almost balmy, more like late spring than a midwestern midwinter. Tonight, as I&#8217;m putting this together, the hemisphere creeps closer to the longest night of the year. In the winter I expected, this is the point at which the snow starts to stick. When the days begin to lengthen again, when the sun decides to stick around a minute longer every day&#8230; This winter, I keep thinking that&#8217;s no longer a guarantee. And the stories that keep sticking in my head? They&#8217;re the ones about endings, about new starts deferred, about the hope for something <em>beyond</em>, even if you won&#8217;t live to see it.</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><strong>“<a href="http://www.shimmerzine.com/a-drop-of-ink-preserved-in-amber-by-marina-j-lostetter/">A Drop of Ink Preserved in Amber</a>”</strong> by Marina J. Lostetter (4700 words)<br />
<a href="http://www.shimmerzine.com/">Shimmer</a> #28, November 2015</p>
<p><em>Amber knew normal girls didn’t have drawers in their chests. Or in their stomachs, or backs, or thighs. She knew her parents had had her specially designed by a geneticist in Pakistan, where the international genome-manipulation laws were more difficult to enforce than in the U.S. In the history of the world, there had never been another human like her. And she was human, even if she didn’t look it on an X-ray.</em></p>
<p><em>And her parents had made it quite clear that X-rays were to be avoided at all costs.</em></p>
<p><em>“You are too special,” they told Amber when she was little. “There are some things other people were simply never meant to know.”</em></p>
<p>In this short, Lostetter puts an emotional and resonant twist on what could be called bodypunk: Set in a not-so-future version of America in which extreme body mods have taken a turn for the genetic, Amber is a girl who is aware from an early age that she is entirely the product of her parents&#8217; desires. It&#8217;s not entirely in the same sense with which all of us have to come to terms &#8212; Amber&#8217;s parents&#8217; desires are for wealth and status and the thrill of the illicit. They take a great chance with her safety at a time when society is turning against its own advances. As she grows, and has to hide, Amber learns that secrets can be a form of currency. Hers, her friends, her society&#8217;s. Long after the danger has passed, she lacks the courage to be open but she manages to preserve enough of herself to keep the story alive long after she&#8217;s gone: a gift for others like her, even if their difference isn&#8217;t the same as hers.</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><strong>“S<a href="https://sub-q.com/play-swept-up/">wept Up</a>”</strong> by Hannah Powell-Smith (interactive fiction, &gt;5 minutes)<br />
<a href="https://sub-q.com/">Sub-Q</a>, November 2015</p>
<p><em>and here you are and she&#8217;s driving through the night and the car engine rumbles in your chest and your mouth tastes of bruise and blood and gravel and your tooth feels &#8211;</em></p>
<p><em>and your sleeves are soaked and you&#8217;re pretty sure it&#8217;s your blood but it&#8217;s hard to tell</em></p>
<p><em>she swerves</em></p>
<p>Interactive fiction doesn&#8217;t get a lot of play in more traditional sf/f/horror venues, which is a shame because a well-made IF story can push the envelope in a lot of ways work in those venues can&#8217;t. Powell-Smith&#8217;s sparse tale packs a punch that wouldn&#8217;t be as noticeable among thousands of extra words. It&#8217;s not the choose-your-adventure style you remember; no pits of broken branches or secret agents lie in wait for you here. Instead you put yourself into the persona of a girl in trouble, though you aren&#8217;t exactly sure how large that trouble will prove to be. The girl you are depends on the choices you make, but you can always refresh and try again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short story reviews for November 2015</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/short-story-reviews-november-2015/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lisa Shininger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 16:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Binary System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[October might belong to pumpkin spice, but November is for wood smoke and bare branches.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>October might belong to pumpkin spice, but November is for wood smoke and bare branches. For winds grown biting and sharp, and tender plants withering after a hard frost. Already I&#8217;m burrowing under too many blankets and dreaming of the next hot chocolate. As we near the end of the calendar year, it seems as if every conversation turns to stories of families: found, constructed, inherited, discarded. At work, holiday and vacation plans have shifted from exotic or expensive locales to gathering or avoiding loved ones. Families crowd into the TV listings and movie showtimes in all shapes and forms: functional, dysfunctional, familiar, unrecognizable, loving, deeply disturbed. Whatever you&#8217;re looking for in a family (or the absence of one), here are a few of my recent fictional favorites:</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><strong>“<a href="http://www.strangehorizons.com/2015/20151012/children-f.shtml">Let&#8217;s Tell Stories of the Deaths of Children</a>”</strong> by Margaret Ronald (2800 words)<br />
<a href="http://www.strangehorizons.com/">Strange Horizons</a>, October 2015</p>
<p><em>In the mornings she shakes loose any feathers that have gathered during the night (down comforter, she explained to a coworker who noticed one in her hair; that was years ago), then before she eats or washes or does anything else, she crams her feet into her boots. Stylish boots, though that&#8217;s incidental; only custom-made boots will fit over the scabby talons that twinge and clench even after she&#8217;s shod.</em></p>
<p><em>She takes the bus to work. It goes by three different schools, but she usually misses their morning rush. If anyone notices her gazing out the window, they put it down to the morning sleep-glaze that still clings to most other riders.</em></p>
<p><em>It&#8217;s been decades since she stole any children. Centuries, maybe.</em></p>
<p>Lilly, once known by other names, built herself a new life, or fell into one. It&#8217;s small and nondescript enough to allow her to pass for ordinary. She works in the company of women and idly watches the way entertainment takes stories of tragedy and loss to fuel individual stories. In doing so, Lilly buries her nature and her past &#8212; the family she was denied, the families she destroyed and created. But she&#8217;s grown perhaps too comfortable, and we start to see the cracks in her resolve. Chief among them is the woman in her office who is hugely pregnant and unafraid to give voice to her fears: all the ways in which the world endangers children and safety and complacency. Lilly starts to remember the value of her old life, or at least to convince herself that it meets a need the world has forgotten it has.</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><strong>“<a href="http://clarkesworldmagazine.com/kritzer_11_15/">So Much Cooking</a>”</strong> by Naomi Kritzer (8700 words)<br />
<a href="https://clarkesworldmagazine.com/">Clarkesworld Magazine</a>, Issue 110</p>
<p><em>This is a food blog, not a disease blog, but of course the rumors all over about bird flu are making me nervous. I don’t know about you, but I deal with anxiety by cooking. So much cooking. But, I’m trying to stick to that New Year’s resolution to share four healthy recipes (entrées, salads, sides . . . ) for every dessert recipe I post, and I just wrote about those lemon meringue bars last week. So even though I dealt with my anxiety yesterday by baking another batch of those bars, and possibly by eating half of them in one sitting, I am not going to bake that new recipe I found for pecan bars today. No! Instead, I’m going to make my friend Carole’s amazing roast chicken. Because how better to deal with fears of bird flu than by eating a bird, am I right?</em></p>
<p>A variation on a found family story that unfolds slowly enough to allow dread and hope to build in equal measure. Kritzer&#8217;s using a modified version of the epistolary format to great effect, giving her narrator&#8217;s voice in a succession of blog posts to an unknown and possibly endangered audience. We only know about the world she&#8217;s in through what non-cooking details she feels up to providing. The slow expansion of her family, as danger and privation set in, feels both as natural and unnatural as the progression of the epidemic outside. If you don&#8217;t pause partway through to check out your own home delivery options and the state of your pantry, you&#8217;re made of sterner stuff than I.</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><strong>“<a href="http://www.unlikely-story.com/stories/and-other-definitions-of-family-by-abra-staffin-wiebe/">And Other Definitions of Family</a>”</strong> by Abra Staffin Wiebe (7600 words)<br />
<a href="https://www.unlikely-story.com/">Unlikely Story</a>, Issue 12</p>
<p><em>May’s doorbell pulsed, sending a subsonic wave shivering through her. She rubbed her hands over her arms to banish the goose bumps, and made a mental note to speak to Nueva Nova station maintenance about resetting the doorbell to human standards. The doorbell pulsed again, and May hurried to deactivate it.</em></p>
<p>She didn’t have a client appointment scheduled, but they all knew she welcomed drop-ins. She checked the peep-cam. Optimal lighting, background soundscape, clothing level, hairstyle, and pheromone spray all depended on the client’s species. Her eyebrows lifted involuntarily when she saw the bat-like Bitocktee male at her door.</p>
<p>Another unconventionally constructed family story (my catnip, if you haven&#8217;t caught on) that manages to convey both the sheer alienness of the Bitocktee as well as the ways in which social behaviors overlap with those that we consider to be human nature. The protagonist, May, is a sex worker on some type of space station, with a background in xenology &#8212; an academic discipline that she furthers with the knowledge gleaned from her interactions with clients. When Red2, the Bitocktee male mentioned above, offers May a job well outside the normal definitions of her role, she&#8217;s motivated not just by the money but by the opportunity it offers for her to see inside his society. Staffin Wiebe turns a fairly standard romance trope into something that hardly invokes romance at all, and kept reminding me of the sensibilities of classic <em>Star Trek</em>. One of the stickiest stories I&#8217;ve read so far this year; it stayed with me long after I&#8217;d closed the tab.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short story reviews for September 2015</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/short-story-reviews-september-2015/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lisa Shininger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 16:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Binary System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4706</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I spent a week in California last month, where it was easier than ever before&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I spent a week in California last month, where it was easier than ever before to imagine the end of the world. Well, the end of human civilization, anyway. Driving through the Central Valley–which in my imagination has always been a wonderland of vibrant green crops and thriving livestock–was like driving into the wastelands of your favorite post-apocalyptic nightmare, where the sky was yellow with smoke and the grass the same shade. Only on the coast and in the affluence of San Jose did it seem like we weren’t on the verge of tumbling into the desert.</p>
<p>Home now in the Midwest, the leaves are starting to turn and fall. It’s less startling here. I’ve had decades of experience of watching the slow slide into winter, when the world washes out into shades of grey. Here, it’s just the thing that happens every year. Here, I look forward to the smell of smoke in the evening air, to the chill that settles in even when you’re safe and warm. Here, I don’t spend long drives staring at the horizon and wondering what will be required of me when we’re up against the wall.</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/cs104.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-5270" style="float: right; padding: 0 0 10px 10px;" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/cs104-194x300.jpg" alt="Clarkesworld issue 104" width="194" height="300" /></a><strong>“<a href="http://clarkesworldmagazine.com/pawley_05_15/">For the Love of Sylvia City</a>”</strong> by Andrea M. Pauley (5300 words)<br />
<a href="http://clarkesworldmagazine.com/prior/issue_104/">Clarkesworld</a>, Issue 104</p>
<p><em>I was an infant when my parents fled with me to the ocean floor. Sylvia City had already turned away thousands of Carbon War refugees after the first few hundred tried to spread the dryland conflict to the benthos. But my mild-mannered parents were engineers with the skills to fix Sylvia City’s overburdened environmental systems. My parents were welcomed. I was let in, too. I have no memory of life beyond the ocean floor, but growing up, I was known as the last dryland refugee. Ten thousand cable repairs can’t erase that fact.</em></p>
<p>The Carbon War seems to be an endless conflict, lasting long enough to be a danger during the protagonist’s childhood and now, when it looks like war has erupted on dryland again. As the last refugee, it falls to our protagonist to safeguard the world she knows–the underwater refuge where she has bonded with the ocean dwellers. As a technician in an outpost on the cable that connects the city to the dryland power station, she is the first to discover that danger is on their doorstep again. The cable doesn’t just provide power; it could act as a bridge to invasion forces, as the dryland becomes uninhabitable. I didn’t get the sense that there was ever really a decision point for the protagonist. She has to do what needs to be done, because she is the best suited to it and because she owes a debt to the community who accepted her family. As an apocalypse story, this one is somehow both unsurprising and fresh.</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/fsfsepoct.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-5271" style="float: right; padding: 0 0 10px 10px;" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/fsfsepoct-204x300.jpg" alt="Fantasy &amp; Science Fiction September/October 2015" width="204" height="300" /></a><strong>“<a href="https://www.sfsite.com/fsf/current.htm">Ten Stamps Viewed Under Water</a>”</strong> by Marissa Lingen (4500 words)<br />
<a href="https://www.sfsite.com/fsf/current.htm">Fantasy &amp; Science Fiction</a>, September/October 2015 (requires purchase)</p>
<p><em>The first stamp my sister got when she began collecting was a deep cobalt blue, engraved. It was on a letter from her best friend, which we did not know at the time would be the last letter from her best friend. She had the impulse to cut it off the envelope anyway, all unknowing, and I found her soaking it in a little dish of water.</em></p>
<p>This story unfolds in ten chapters, one each for a stamp in the sister’s collection. A plague has isolated the sisters from the rest of their world. Unknown numbers of people are dead&#8211;or infected&#8211;which means as good as. As their quarantine continues, the protagonist grows more concerned about her sister’s behavior, which culminates in a burst of (necessary?) violence. The plague is understandably obscure; the world slightly less so. We know there is magic, because the sister was an apprentice mage whose training was cut short. The sister chafes at not being able to work with those in power to find a cure for the plague while her own personal supplies dwindle. As a sister myself, I’m always delighted when a sibling relationship is depicted in ways that ring true to my own, as it is here. Though I could have read twice as many words in this setting, the ending was satisfying though some may find it frustrating.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short story reviews for June 2015</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/short-story-reviews-for-june-2015/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lisa Shininger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 15:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Binary System]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the summer, I crave stories about survival, especially about people and places in flux.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the summer, I crave stories about survival, especially about people and places in flux.</p>
<p>Here, though the sun shines hot and bright through the day, thunderstorms roll in quickly to soak the ground and blow down trees, and there&#8217;s a cool, thick smell of wet in the mornings that dissipates by midday. I drive out of my way to follow a small creek that runs alongside a winding, crumbling road. It has no name that I know, whatever it once was called is lost in the anonymous sprawl of suburban living. At odds with the quality of the street, the homes along this stretch of creek are opulent, to say the least. Their driveways are long, the property lines delineated with old-growth trees and shrubs grown so thickly the bright morning light barely reaches the ground.</p>
<p>Within a few weeks of the last frost, between the bridged driveways, the muddy creek banks overrun with small frogs known as spring peepers. Early on, they&#8217;re hard to hear over the sound of tires thundering on the uneven asphalt. By the time the summer starts to turn sticky, the peepers become cacophonous. They sing for their mates at night and early in the morning, before the heat builds, uninterrupted by floods, rain, or the road crews who lurch from one end of the road to the other, dribbling tar to seal insufficient patches. As the woods recede and the McMansions proliferate, the frogs keep breeding and hiding and singing.</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lackingtonsissue6.jpeg"><img decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-4701" style="float: right; padding: 0 0 10px 10px;" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lackingtonsissue6-232x300.jpeg" alt="lackingtonsissue6" width="232" height="300" /></a><strong>“<a href="http://lackingtons.com/2015/04/08/littoral-drift-by-l-s-johnson/">Littoral Drift</a>”</strong> by L. S. Johnson (1100 words)<br />
<a href="http://lackingtons.com/issues/issue-6-spring-2015/">Lackington&#8217;s</a>, Issue 6</p>
<p><em>There is only a thin sunlight this morning, yet the pill glows with promise. It is blue and fat, the kind of gelatinous capsule we used to call a supplement. But those pills were never blue; they were oily colours, browns and yellows, they spoke of healthy colons and balanced chemistry. I used to work in marketing, I know about these things.</em></p>
<p>There is little that&#8217;s new in this story, to us or to the narrator. The world has moved on considerably from our time and hers but the essence remains the same. Ruin and repair in equal measure, and the energy and obsessions of the young do little but exhaust the old. The blue pill promises a new future for our aged narrator, who remembers fondly when children played on the beach instead of with their screens. But for all that her story echoes the too-familiar lament of the modern wannabe Luddite, there are hints that both of her potential choices are the same kind of ending. Either she takes the pill and wakes to a new world where her deteriorating body is renewed, like Neo in <em>The Matrix</em>, a comparison I can never shake when life-changing pills are invoked. Or she chooses to move closer to her lost loved ones, and gives up the promise of a longer life. In her world or yours, which would you choose?</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lightspeed61.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-4702" style="float: right; padding: 0 0 10px 10px;" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lightspeed61-200x300.jpg" alt="lightspeed61" width="200" height="300" /><strong>“</strong></a><strong><a href="http://www.lightspeedmagazine.com/fiction/madeleine">Madeleine</a>”</strong> by Amal El-Mohtar (5900 words)<br />
<a href="http://www.lightspeedmagazine.com/issues/june-2015-issue-61/">Queers Destroy Science Fiction &#8211; Lightspeed Magazine</a><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/lightspeed61.jpg">, June 2015</a></p>
<p><em>Madeleine remembers being a different person.</em></p>
<p><em>It strikes her when she&#8217;s driving, threading her way through farmland, homesteads, facing down the mountains around which the road winds. She remembers being thrilled at the thought of travel, of the self she would discover over the hills and far away. She remembers laughing with friends, looking forward to things, to a future.</em></p>
<p>Another story about memory and loss, and finding ways to come out on the other side of both. Madeleine&#8217;s mother has died of Alzheimer&#8217;s, and Madeleine seems to have participated in a drug trial meant to find a way to combat memory loss. Now, much like Billy Pilgrim, she is bouncing through her own life&#8211;in memories so vivid and present that she can&#8217;t tell whether she&#8217;s moving through time or simply remembering so fiercely everything becomes real again&#8211;until she starts running into a girl in those reminiscences. A girl she&#8217;s never seen before. A girl who couldn&#8217;t have been there in her past, but now figures in all her memories. It&#8217;s unclear whether the girl is a figment of Madeleine&#8217;s imagination or something else. The tactile details that El-Mohtar gives to Madeleine&#8217;s memories/visions makes them seem more real than her interactions with what is ostensibly the only other &#8220;real&#8221; character in the story, Madeleine&#8217;s psychologist, Clarice. But the choice of name and profession together left me with the feeling that we can&#8217;t trust the most obvious conclusion there, as the combination of the two immediately bring to mind the fevered hallucinations and machinations of Hannibal Lecter. Which of the two realities she experiences should Madeleine take to be the truth? I&#8217;ve read the story half a dozen times in the past few weeks and I still wish I knew.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond the Binary System: short story reviews for May 2015</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/beyond-the-binary-system-short-story-reviews-for-may-2015/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lisa Shininger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 16:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Binary System]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4426</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One morning a few weeks ago, I looked out the kitchen window to find that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One morning a few weeks ago, I looked out the kitchen window to find that the maple trees had begun to drop their keys. A thick blanket of bright green whirligigs covered the street and cars. They studded the grass and piled up in the gutter in mounds after a brief downpour swept through them. I&#8217;ve never seen a spring yield like it. Even the pine trees are nearly bursting with tiny cones, every branch bristling with two or three times as many clusters as usual. The winter here was long and cold and wet, but I couldn&#8217;t help but wonder if the trees are readying themselves for something the rest of us haven&#8217;t sensed yet.</p>
<p>Both of this month&#8217;s short stories struck a similar nerve.</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/lakesidecircus.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-4430" style="float: right; padding: 0 0 10px 10px;" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/lakesidecircus-241x300.jpg" alt="Cover of Lakeside Circus Year Two Issue One" width="219" /></a><strong>“<a href="http://lakesidecircus.com/2015/03/janna-layton-presents-the-medici-fountain/">The Medici Fountain</a>”</strong> by Janna Layton (1000 words)<br />
<a href="http://lakesidecircus.com/year-two-issue-one/">Lakeside Circus</a>, Year 2, Issue 1</p>
<p><em>The pet fish tell us the fountain is vast. They tell us it is dirty. The ducks tell us it is not so vast, but agree that it is dirty. Often the pet fish are goldfish like us: red or white and red or red and black. Sometimes they are misshapen goldfish with eyes bulging and heads weighted down. There are others that are not goldfish: tiny and silvery, blue and flowing. The small ones we eat. The others that are not goldfish or not properly shaped goldfish die quickly, sinking and gasping. But they all tell the same story about tiny fountains you can barely swim in where it is always too bright and too warm. The water never moves and is so clear that you are always exposed. Always exposed and cramped in brightness.</em></p>
<p><em>The ones who survive love the Medici Fountain. It is dark and cool and quiet and you can breathe.</em></p>
<p>Janna Layton somehow manages to pack an entire culture inside the confines of the fountain, complete with a history and worldview unique to its inhabitants. It might be tempting to write it off as a goofy little anthropomorphic story, but there&#8217;s a poignancy to the narrator&#8217;s musings about the inevitability of loss, death, and renewal. <em>Lakeside</em> publishes mostly flash, but even for a short short, it felt like this was over too soon. If Layton ever expands this story into a longer one, I&#8217;m in.</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/full_waysofwallsandwords.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-4433" style="float: right; padding: 0 0 10px 10px;" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/full_waysofwallsandwords-219x300.jpg" alt="Cover of Ways of Walls and Words - Tor.com - Art by Tran Nguyen" width="219" height="300" /></a><strong>“<a href="http://www.tor.com/2015/04/15/the-ways-of-walls-and-words-sabrina-vourvoulias/">The Ways of Walls and Words</a>”</strong> by Sabrina Vourvoulias (7000 words)<br />
<a href="http://www.tor.com/">Tor.com</a>, April 2015</p>
<p><em>She and her people are in cells lined along a corridor in the deepest reaches of the convent. On occasion the mentally disturbed have been kept here, tended to and made safe by walls so thick they are more than an arm’s length. These people, however, are all one family: a mother; an adult son; four older daughters; and this one, who has spent nearly half her life in here.</em></p>
<p><em>That was all the information the Dominican Brothers shared with me the day I started. Except that I must not attempt to speak to the girl or her family through their doors. The Brothers made me swear this before I swept even one stone.</em></p>
<p><em>In the language I share with jailer and jailed, my name is Bienvenida, though my Nahuatl name is different. By the Brothers’ reckoning, it has been 1,562 years since the death of God.</em></p>
<p>This is a bruisingly lovely story about transformations, both those undertaken and those refused. The girl in the cell is Anica, a member of a family of Marranas, or converts to Christianity who were held captive, tortured, and executed by the Inquisition in Mexico City. Bienvenida learns to know Anica through the poems she speaks, which are prayers and imbued with a kind of magic that Bienvenida seems to recognize, though it is very different than the Nahua ways she knows.</p>
<p>Though the passage of time in the story is somewhat muddy—is it years or months that it takes the girls to get through to each other?—the weight of place and consequence are palpable throughout. Though Bienvenida never seems to fear for her life the way you (okay, I!!) might want her to, there is a considerable sense of danger hanging over her acts of kindness and rebellion. Knowing some of the particular history of this period of Mexican history will help to fill in the gaps, but the story carries enough of that on its own.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond the Binary System: short story reviews for April 2015</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/beyond-the-binary-system-short-story-reviews-for-april-2015/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lisa Shininger]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 15:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beyond the Binary System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4251</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A lifetime of long dreary winters has me programmed for snuggling up with thick novels. The longer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A lifetime of long dreary winters has me programmed for snuggling up with thick novels. The longer I get to sit wrapped in a fleecy blanket, the better! But as this new and glorious neon-green spring chases away the last vestiges of grey skies and stinging sleet, my attention span grows shorter and my patience thins. Novels sit neglected while my e-reader app fills with short story magazine subscriptions. I can&#8217;t complain, either, because we&#8217;re in a great new golden age for speculative fiction, with a wide field of talented writers and intriguing venues.</p>
<p>In this column, <b><i>Beyond the Binary System</i></b>, I&#8217;ll share with you some of the best&#8211;and my favorite&#8211;speculative fiction short stories from around the web and in print. In keeping with Luna Station Quarterly&#8217;s mission statement, every month we&#8217;ll focus on stories by cis and trans women and non-binary writers. And, I&#8217;ll admit, I&#8217;m going into this with a slightly biased eye for the great new writers getting into the game. Bottom line: what I hope you&#8217;ll get from this column is an introduction to your favorites for many years to come.</p>
<p>Before we jump into this month&#8217;s stories, a little bit about me: I live in Ohio, where we get sunny days only 75 times a year and even those we spend complaining about the weather. My day job is in marketing, and the rest of my time is spent reading everything within reach, writing fiction, recording podcast episodes, watching too much TV, and neglecting my website. My favorite speculative fiction genres are fantasy, hard and soft sci-fi, magical realism, horror, and fabulism, and it&#8217;s a rare romance novel I don&#8217;t love.</p>
<p>All right! Ready to read some great short stories?</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/ApexMag68.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-4252" style="float: right;" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/ApexMag68-210x300.jpg" alt="cover of Apex Magazine issue 68 - January 2015" /></a><strong>&#8220;<a title="Pocosin, by Ursula Vernon" href="http://www.apex-magazine.com/pocosin/">Pocosin</a>&#8220;</strong> by Ursula Vernon (5000 words)<br />
<em style="line-height: 1.5;"><a title="Apex Magazine" href="http://www.apex-magazine.com/">Apex Magazine</a>, </em><span style="line-height: 1.5;">issue 68</span></p>
<p><em>This is the place where the hairstreak butterflies flow sleekly through the air and you can hear insect feet drumming inside the bowl of the pitcher plants.</em></p>
<p><em>This is the place where the old god came to die.</em></p>
<p>Let me tell you a secret about this short story by Ursula Vernon from back in January: I haven&#8217;t gone a single day without thinking about it since I first read it.</p>
<p>The place described above, a clearing by a pond somewhere in the Carolinas, is as familiar to me as if it were my vacation home. Maggie, the main character who lives there, is the style of grudgingly welcoming and not-totally-abrasive you&#8217;d hope a back-country witch would be. Each new revelation in the story was a delight the first time through, and a comfort on each subsequent read. The old god&#8217;s last moments could be painful to read, especially for those with a tender loss of their own, but Vernon captures the delicate balance between pain and relief that comes with the end of someone&#8217;s suffering and the start of a new cycle of life. The story is funny in parts and charming throughout, so you&#8217;re not in for a slog through crumpled tissues and dehydration, either.</p>
<hr style="text-align: center!important;" width="50%" />
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/omenanaissue2.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-4253" style="float: right;" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/omenanaissue2-212x300.jpg" alt="cover of Omenana issue 2 - March 2015" /></a><strong>&#8220;<a title="Story, Story: A Tale of Mothers and Daughters" href="http://omenana.com/2015/03/02/story-story-a-tale-of-mothers-and-daughters/">Story, Story: A Tale of Mothers and Daughters</a>&#8221; </strong>by Chikodili Emelumadu (3700 words)<br />
<em><a title="Omenana" href="http://omenana.com/">Omenana</a>,</em> issue 2</p>
<p><em>In one town like this, not too long ago, lived an enterprising young girl. Ugonwoma, her parents called her, as she was the pride of their lives. She was so rich that she built a house in the village for her retired parents before any of her brothers could say </em>taa!<em> and painted it white so that under the sun it was like staring into the flare from a welder’s torch. People would use the house as a landmark in the village: “Take right until you come to the white house,” which made her parents very happy.</em></p>
<p>First, a few words about <em>Omenana</em>, which is a new bi-monthly magazine that started publishing late last year. <em>Omenana</em> features established and emerging writers in Africa and throughout the African diaspora, with a particular focus on dispelling the myth that there is no interest in science fiction, fantasy, horror, or magical realism in Africa. All of the stories are free to read online and I highly recommend you bookmark the site. It was so difficult to choose which of their pieces to talk about first!</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not familiar enough with Igbo literature to whether this is an update of a traditional folk story or if this is entirely her own creation. Either way, Emelumadu has written a beautiful and heartbreaking modern fable that will resonate with any audience. But my favorite thing about the story is that although it reads like one of the treasured fables of my childhood, there is no moralizing to redeem the painful ending. There is only the continuing cycle of hurt and triumph that characterizes so much of life. The women in the story are frustrating and endearing, and the world of <em>the</em> woman&#8211;whose name is as fluid as her identity in the village&#8211;is rich and vibrant. If I could borrow any extra thumbs, I&#8217;d put them all up for <em>Story, Story</em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
