<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Wendy Van Camp &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/wendy-van-camp/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 03:59:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Elizabeth Crowens</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-elizabeth-crowens-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy Van Camp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 13:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I met author Elizabeth Crowens at World Con in Kansas City.  We are both members&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>I met author Elizabeth Crowens at World Con in Kansas City.  We are both members of Broad Universe.  Her <em>Time Traveler Professor</em> series is an alternate history/spooky steampunk published out of London.</strong></p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-11656" src="http://b60.a63.mwp.accessdomain.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Author-Elizabeth-Crowens-213x300.jpg" alt="" width="213" height="300" />Hi, I’m Elizabeth Crowens. Why do I use a pen name? Because back in the 80s I wrote for <em>Ninja Magazine</em> and a bunch of other unusual publications. This was when Hollywood and Hong Kong were churning out a lot of over the top films on the tail end of the Bruce Lee craze. I actually had a blackbelt in ninjutsu that I received from the top masters in Japan, but I knew the reality behind the façade and felt I needed a bit of anonymity from my professional life working at a publishing company at the time. The last headache I needed was to have someone plan a surprise attack to see if I could really do a triple backflip and throw ninja stars in my defense. I didn’t need the hassle. So I just came up with a pen name.</p>
<p><strong>When and why did you begin writing?</strong></p>
<p>In the 70s when I was in college I thought my career path was going to be screenwriting. Back then I didn’t have a very realistic view of how the film industry worked. My head was in the clouds with wildly creative ideas and my teachers weren’t the best influences because they came from the avant-garde and Andy Warhol schools of artsy indie film making. However, my goals were commercially oriented. New York film schools were like that back then. Unfortunately, I was young, naïve and didn’t know any better and flying by the seat of my pants until I finally moved out to Hollywood in 1990.</p>
<p><strong>When did you first consider yourself a writer?</strong></p>
<p>Back in the 80s when I was writing articles for magazines and working on the first draft of this manuscript. However, I wasn’t making enough money to make a living out of it. My degree was in Photography and Film studies, but I found out the hard way that in journalism people were paid more for writing articles in magazines than they were for the photography that accompanied them. So I thought to myself, “Hey, I was always good at English in school. I’ll write the article, as well, especially since I’d get paid more for it.”</p>
<p><strong>Can you share a little about your current book with us?</strong></p>
<p><em>Silent Meridian</em> is a 19th century <em>X-Files</em> meets H.G. Wells’ <em>The Time Machine</em> featuring Sir Arthur Conan Doyle and his paranormal enthusiast partner, John Patrick Scott, the Time Traveler Professor. It’s a delightful mash-up blending those elements with hints of Doctor Who, Tim Powers, and Nicholas Meyer. Contrary to people’s first impression, it is not a Sherlock Holmes story.</p>
<p><strong>What inspired you to write this book?</strong></p>
<p>That’s a stranger than fiction story. I’ve always had a passion for collecting antiques and antiquarian books. Very similar situations that occur in the book, sometimes finding a strange book or an unusual item, can inspire a whole flood of ideas.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have a specific writing style?</strong></p>
<p>I try to mimic a Victorian first-person point of view although I tone it down for modern readers. Authors such as Henry James and Arthur Machen can get incredibly wordy. Editors today are always hopping on our backs about word count.</p>
<p><strong>How did you come up with the title of this book?</strong></p>
<p>In the book, I refer to two similar metaphors, i.e. the sfumato effect and the Verdaccio technique of underpainting. These are both art terms from the Italian Renaissance referring to the methods used by Leonardo da Vinci as to how he depicts seamless and invisible edges in paintings such as the Mona Lisa. However, it alludes to the often-indistinguishable transition from dreams to reality to jumping back and forth in time.</p>
<p><strong>Is there a message in your novel that you want readers to grasp?</strong></p>
<p>“The key to the future lies in clues from the past.” That’s from a quote in the novel. It’s very much tied into resolving karma and moving forward and any conflicts you experience now most likely can have their roots traced back in history—therefore the justification of traveling through time.</p>
<p><strong>Are experiences in this book based on someone you know or events in your own life?</strong></p>
<p>Shush! That’s a secret.</p>
<p><strong>What authors have most influenced your life? What about them do you find inspiring?</strong></p>
<p>I’d rephrase that by asking the question, “What books or media have been the most influence?” I’ve gone through spurts with reading, but I’ve always been a film buff. My answer? Stanley Kubrick, Harry Potter, and <em>Star Wars</em>. Kubrick and Lucas were the reasons why I got involved in the film industry. I remember being blown away by <em>A Clockwork Orange</em>, especially in its art direction and cinematography when I was in high school, and <em>Star Wars</em> just at the time I was graduating college and about to spring out in the job market working in film production. Harry Potter didn’t come around until many years later.</p>
<p><strong>If you had to choose, is there a writer would you consider a mentor? Why?</strong></p>
<p>If I can resurrect someone from the dead it would be Arthur Conan Doyle, because his Sherlock Holmes stories are so damned clever. One that is living now? Tim Powers. I’m amazed as to how he puts everything together in his plotting.</p>
<p><strong>Who designed the cover of your book? Why did you select this illustrator?</strong></p>
<p>This was an unusual situation where I, as the author, had a significant amount of input in the cover design.</p>
<p>“Do I have any ideas?” I thought to myself. “Boy, am I going to surprise everyone!”</p>
<p>Little did they know that I’ve been professionally trained as both a graphic designer and photographer and have had over 20 years experience with Photoshop. Previously in my career, I used to art direct and shoot movie posters in Hollywood. Since I had full intentions of pitching the Time Traveler Professor series (<em>Silent Meridian</em> is the first of approximately seven books) as either a film series or a cable television series, I had already composited a one-sheet or sell sheet mini-poster as a leave behind. The background photo on the cover is one that I took at the University of Edinburgh Medical School where Conan Doyle received his medical degree.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any advice for other writers?</strong></p>
<p>To quote Buzz Lightyear from <em>Toy Story</em>, “Never give up. Never surrender.”</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16385 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/The-Time-Traveler-Professor-Book-1-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/The-Time-Traveler-Professor-Book-1-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/The-Time-Traveler-Professor-Book-1.jpg 350w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" />Elizabeth Crowens<br />
New York, NY</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/BooksbyElizabethCrowens/?ref=aymt_homepage_panel" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FACEBOOK</a><br />
<a href="https://www.twitter.com/ECrowens" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TWITTER</a><br />
<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29886548-silent-meridian" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GOODREADS</a></p>
<p><strong>Silent Meridian</strong></p>
<p>Art Director: Elizabeth Crowens<br />
Publisher: Atomic Alchemist Productions, LLC.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07Q4LYNYH">AMAZON</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AUTHOR INTERVIEW: LILLIAN NADER</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-lillian-nader/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-lillian-nader/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy Van Camp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11636#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=11636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How would I describe Author Lillian Nader? For one, she is a writer for fun&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>How would I describe Author Lillian Nader? For one, she is a writer for fun and profit. Expect the unexpected!</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11639 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Author-Lillian-Nader-227x300.jpg" alt="" width="227" height="300" />I am Lillian Nader, an author, dreamer, freelance copyeditor, retired special education teacher, and part-time tutor. My name originated with my cousin, Lillian Ann, who asked my pregnant mom to name me after her when the Ouija board said I would be a girl. Weird things have happened to me ever since. My favorite poem is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-moyZ7Rld2w">“Find Your Own Voice” by Jayne Cortez</a>. I prefer outdoor walks for exercise, especially at the beach or in beautiful parks with large shade trees and small squirrels. My favorite people are other writers, metaphysicians, and my family. I have a lot of cousins and two older siblings but no spouse or children of my own. I rely on close friendships of extended family and confidantes. I participate in dream work with a small group called Sacred Dreamers, and I frequent writers’ groups all over Orange County, CA. My professional memberships include SWCA, Southern California Writers Association; PWOC/PWSD, Publishers and Writers of Orange County and San Diego; and IBPA, Independent Book Publishers Association.</p>
<p><strong>When and why did you begin writing?</strong></p>
<p>I grew up in Marshall, a small town in East Texas, and moved to California to pursue a writing career in 1981. While I was taking a script writing class, I met a lyricist, Larry Marino, who was in search of a cowriter for his musical, Pandora. We embarked upon a successful collaboration to the completion of the script with me as the librettist. It was my love for the theater and Larry’s incredible talent that spurred me on.</p>
<p><strong>When did you first consider yourself a writer?</strong></p>
<p>When I became a published author of instructional workbooks with two California publishers of educational materials for the classroom, I considered myself a writer. One workbook, <em>Native Americans: A Proud Heritage</em> became a best seller for the classroom several years in a row.</p>
<p><strong>Can you share a little about your current book with us?</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for asking about my newly released sci-fi book for young readers, <em>Theep and Thorpe: Adventures in Space</em>. Jonathon Curtis is the fourteen-year-old narrator of the story. He has the ability to manifest objects out of nowhere, but he doesn’t know how to control his gift. His emotions take over and get him into trouble, landing him on Planet Staruus. The planet houses troubled kids from an overpopulated Earth and is thought to be uninhabited, but it isn’t. Theep and Thorpe are enlightened space beings who establish telepathic communication with Jonathon, and the fun begins.</p>
<p><strong>What inspired you to write this book?</strong></p>
<p>My artist friend, Angelo Divino, created two colorful and friendly-looking space beings, and I was inspired to write about them. Their names came to me first, based on the concept that each of us has a unique sound frequency as well as fingerprints to distinguish us from one another. It occurred to me that space beings would use their sound frequencies in place of names. The names, Theep and Thorpe, are approximate sounds to the actual frequencies, which cannot be spoken with our voices. Years later, the actual story began to take shape in the form of a novel.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have a specific writing style?</strong></p>
<p>I am a character-driven writer, which means I start with characters that interest me, put them in weird situations, and figure out the plot from there. In <em>Theep and Thorpe: Adventures in Space</em>, I chose the narrative style of a troubled teen and used both internal and external dialogue to advance the story. His encounter with space beings is entirely from his point of view. I like to insert humor using a sprinkle of sarcasm and a bit of irony as part of my show, don’t tell strategy.</p>
<p><strong>How did you come up with the title of this book?</strong></p>
<p>Since the book is about space beings and I am a character-based author, I naturally gave their names, Theep and Thorpe, in the title to go with their images on the cover. I came up with the subtitle to give the reader more information about the story, and to distinguish it from other books in the series.</p>
<p><strong>Is there a message in your novel that you want readers to grasp?</strong></p>
<p>“Thoughts are things” is the overall theme of the story. Jonathon has the power of manifestation, and Theep and Thorpe teach him how to control his gift by choosing positive, productive thoughts.</p>
<p><strong>Are experiences in this book based on someone you know or events in your own life?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, I drew upon my experiences as a teacher in a juvenile court school for part of the setting, although it changed drastically as soon as it became housed on the fictional Planet Staruus.</p>
<p><strong>What authors have most influenced your life? What about them do you find inspiring?</strong></p>
<p>I was influenced by J D Salinger’s <em>Catcher in the Rye</em> for the narrative style of my book and J K Rowling’s Harry Potter for motivation. As a special education teacher working with reluctant readers when the Harry Potter books were released, I noticed my students were choosing those books of their own volition. This made a big impression on me;</p>
<p><strong>If you had to choose, is there a writer would you consider a mentor? Why?</strong></p>
<p>Oh, yes. I have at least two writing mentors. One is Marjorie Miles, author of <em>Healing Haiku: A Poetic Prescription for Surviving Cancer</em>, who teaches a class I’ve been taking for the past four years. Dr. Miles encourages creative expression through free writing activities. The other mentor is Dr. Heather Friedman Rivera, author of the Prism Walker fantasy series for young readers along with nonfiction and fiction for adults. Heather is my weekly writer’s check-in partner. We email each other once a week with our writing goals, successes, and encouragement for one another. She is also a revered beta reader and writing coach.</p>
<p><strong>Who designed the cover of your book? Why did you select this illustrator?</strong></p>
<p>My book cover was designed by Laura Gordon Moyer at The Book Cover Machine. She was referred to me by Heather Rivera, and I loved the design she did for Heather’s books. She worked with the original artist/creator of the space images and me for the design. Laura is responsive, cooperative, extremely talented, and reasonably priced.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any advice for other writers?</strong></p>
<p>Listen to your inner voice. Study the craft of writing, consult experts and peer readers and writers for their opinions, but always stay true to your inner voice. Each of us has a unique voice that only we can express. Dream big and don’t give up on your dreams. Surround yourself with positive people and energy. Participate in professional groups with other writers. Build an author’s platform to express your own voice. Have fun.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have anything specific that you want to say to your readers?</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for choosing <em>Theep and Thorpe: Adventures in Space</em> for your reading pleasure. Always remember, thoughts are things! ***</p>
<p><a href="http://www.lilliannader.com/">Lillian Nader</a><a href="http://www.lilliannader.com/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11640 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Custom-Book-Cover-Lillian-New-Small-File-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a><br />
Yorba Linda, California</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/Lillian.nader">FACEBOOK</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/lnader1910">TWITTER</a><br />
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/lillian-nader-">LINKEDIN</a><br />
<a href="http://www.lilliannader.com/blog">BLOG</a></p>
<p><em><strong>Theep and Thorpe: Adventures in Space</strong></em></p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Theep-Thorpe-Adventures-Lillian-Nader-ebook/dp/B01DTAKL3I">AMAZON</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-lillian-nader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Laurel Anne Hill</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-laurel-anne-hill-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy Van Camp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Author Laurel Anne Hill is an award-winning author of science fiction, fantasy, steampunk, and horror. Many&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Author Laurel Anne Hill is an award-winning author of science fiction, fantasy, steampunk, and horror. Many of her stories inspire readers to choose the way of worthiness. Laurel is a fellow Broad Universe member and costumer with whom I’ve shared many a rapid fire reading with.</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11689 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/Laurel-Anne-Hill-for-EWL-Back-Cover-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" />Hello, I’m Laurel Anne Hill, author, and former underground storage tank operator. Really! My day job for many years included environmental health and safety at a pharmaceutical research and development facility. I grew up in San Francisco with more dreams of adventure than good sense or money. My close brushes with death, love of family, respect for honor, and belief in a higher power continue to influence my writing and my life. I’m blessed to have a loving husband and four wonderful children.</p>
<p><strong>When and why did you begin writing?</strong></p>
<p>I started writing before I could read. Stories created themselves within me and I’d tell them to my older sister and she’d write them down. I’d illustrate my tales with pictures from comic books and magazines. My sister loved to write her own stories, too. I admired her and still do.</p>
<p><strong>When did you first consider yourself a writer?</strong></p>
<p>When I was very young, I don’t think I understood the concept of being a writer. At some point in elementary school, I knew writing was what I wanted to do. I had a story published in the children’s section of a major San Francisco newspaper when I was eleven years old. Then I knew I’d become a real writer. The story, “Nancy Saves the Day,” was horrid, or course. Heck, I didn’t know the conventions for creating quality prose. I still read the piece every once in a while, to laugh and remind myself of how far I’ve progressed.</p>
<p><strong>Can you share a little about your current book, <em>The Engine Woman&#8217;s Light</em>, with us?</strong></p>
<p>A mystical vision of an airship appears to fifteen-year-old Juanita in 1894. The long-dead captain commands her to prevent California’s thrown-away people—including young children—from boarding trains to an asylum. That institution’s director plots murder to reduce the inmate population.</p>
<p>Spirits watch over Juanita. But who is she? A mystic in love who holds life sacred? Or a ghost-possessed railroad-saboteur?</p>
<p>To save innocent lives Juanita must take lives of the corrupt. How can she reconcile her assignment with her belief in the sacredness of all human life? And will she survive to marry her betrothed?</p>
<p>Juanita sets out despite inner trepidation to sabotage the railroad. Her ancestor, Billy, guides her. Then bit by bit, she discovers the gut-wrenching truths all of her dead family neglected to reveal.</p>
<p>Come visit Juanita’s world—an alternate nineteenth-century California—where spirits meet steampunk, where both love and anger emanate from beyond the grave.</p>
<p><strong>What inspired you to write this book?</strong></p>
<p>In the early 1990s, I had a dream about an elderly woman riding a train. The train headed toward a disreputable asylum where inmates died of neglect or even by euthanasia. The attendant placed an abandoned baby in a basket on the adjacent seat. The woman realized the baby was her great-granddaughter and escaped the train. With a broken foot, she carried the infant many miles. This dream became the basis of a short story, never published.</p>
<p><strong>Where had the dream come from?</strong></p>
<p>First of all, when I was a teen in the 1950s, my beloved maternal Swedish grandmother had paid the hospital bill for the birth of one of my sister’s sons. The bill had cost Grandma much of what she’d possessed. Grandma died in 1989. In the early 1990s, my memories of her remained close.</p>
<p>Next, a month before I birthed my daughter in 1979, I’d fallen and broken my foot as I left work in San Francisco. My husband, David, had expected to meet me on the other side of the bay. Cell phones as we now know them didn’t exist. I hadn’t wanted to worry David by not showing up when expected. I’d walked on a broken foot, taken public transportation, and traveled thirty miles to reach the train station near our home.</p>
<p>Third, and quite important, before I’d married David, I’d worked for him in a hospital laboratory. The hospital performed lots of abortions, including many late term. I’d believed in the right to choose, and still do. Yet stacks of plastic specimen containers containing pickled babies left a sour taste in my mouth. After all, I’d hoped to birth a child of my own someday.</p>
<p>That fateful night of dreaming, my pro-choice beliefs had gone head-to-head with a pro-life type visualization. In the story that emerged, a woman who’d married into a Mexican family declared her own opinions. I had no choice but to accept her challenge to tell the tale of the baby she saved. Only years later did I discover the inspiration and tragedy associated with my paternal Mexican great-grandmother’s life. I’d never met her. She’d died over twenty years before I’d been born.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have a specific writing style?</strong></p>
<p>My stories tend to be plot driven, although I try to stay close to my point-of-view characters. I like to “show” rather than “tell” whenever I can.</p>
<p><strong>How did you come up with the title of this book?</strong></p>
<p>I’d gone through a number of potential titles during the writing process. When I sent my manuscript to Sand Hill Review Press, I’d entitled the novel “Woman of the Light.” That title hadn’t worked for the editor, so I chose <em>The Engine Woman’s Light</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Is there a message in your novel that you want readers to grasp?</strong></p>
<p>What we do can make a difference in the world.</p>
<p><strong>Are experiences in this book based on someone you know, or events in your own life?</strong></p>
<p>Some experiences are based on events in my own life, as explained above. Also, I’ve hiked, camped, run rapids, ridden horseback, and operated a steam locomotive.</p>
<p><strong>What authors have most influenced your life? What about them do you find inspiring?</strong></p>
<p>I love the work of many authors, such as Neil Gaiman and Graham Joyce. I think, however, the work of children’s authors have had the biggest impact on my life. For example, Elizabeth Foster, author of <em>Gigi: The Story of a Merry-Go-Round Horse</em>, showed me the magic created when blending imagination with the reality of world conditions and history.</p>
<p><strong>If you had to choose, is there a writer you consider a mentor? Why?</strong></p>
<p>My mentor is Charlotte Cook, a writer, editor, and dear friend. She has the ability to read a story and determine with ease what makes the piece work and what doesn’t.</p>
<p><strong>Who designed the cover of your book? Why did you select this illustrator?</strong></p>
<p>Julie Dillon, winner of the Hugo and Chesley awards, designed the cover of <em>The Engine Woman’s Light</em>. I love the vibrancy of her art and her breathtaking ability to portray diverse women protagonists.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any advice for other writers?</strong></p>
<p>If you love a story that’s not working, don’t give up on it. Put it away for a while then take a fresh look. Read each page, then ask yourself if the text invites a reader to turn the page, and why?</p>
<p><strong>Do you have anything specific that you want to say to your readers?</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for reading my work! All the characters living in my head thank you as well.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Laurel-Anne-Hill/e/B002XK5R5S" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Laurel Anne Hill</a><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Laurel-Anne-Hill/e/B002XK5R5S" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11688 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/EWL-cover-proof-2-RGB-4_001-202x300.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="300" /></a><br />
Orinda, California</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/laurel.hill.7" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FACEBOOK</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/laurelannehill" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TWITTER</a><br />
<a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/134334001365730985/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PINTEREST</a><br />
<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1280430.Laurel_Anne_Hill/blog" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GOODREADS</a></p>
<p><em><strong>The Engine Woman’s Light</strong></em></p>
<p>Cover Artist: <a href="http://www.juliedillonart.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Julie Dillon</a><br />
Publisher: <a href="https://www.sandhillreviewpress.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sand Hill Review Press</a>,</p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss_1?url=search-alias%3Daps&amp;field-keywords=the+engine+woman%27s+light" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AMAZON</a><br />
<a href="http://www.barnesandnoble.com/w/the-engine-womans-light-laurel-anne-hill/1125518593?ean=9781937818470" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BARNES &amp; NOBLE</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Karen Michelle Nutt</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-karen-michelle-nutt-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy Van Camp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No matter the genre her tales fall under, author Karen Michelle Nutt tries to capture&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>No matter the genre her tales fall under, author Karen Michelle Nutt tries to capture the rich array of emotions that accompany the most mysterious and fabulous human phenomena of falling in love.</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11693 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/author-karen-michelle-nutt-249x300.jpg" alt="" width="249" height="300" />My name is Karen Michelle Nutt. As a multi-published author, I spin tales for The Wild Rose Press, Highland Press, Victory Tales Press, and Publishing by Rebecca J. Vickery. I have also ventured into self-publishing.</p>
<p>I reside in California with my husband. We’ve been married for thirty-two years and have three fascinating children, who are grown now and have started their own adventures in life. We still have a houseful of demanding pets. Jack, my Chorkie, is my writing buddy and sits long hours with me at the computer.</p>
<p>When I’m not time traveling, fighting outlaws or otherworldly creatures, I create pre-made book covers with my daughter Katrina Gillian at Gillian’s Book Covers, “Judge Your Book By Its Cover.”</p>
<p><strong>When and why did you begin writing?</strong></p>
<p>I started writing down my stories when I was about nine or ten because I thought it was fun. I wrote plays at first. My fifth-grade teacher let my friends and I perform one of them too. It was very exciting for a ten-year-old.</p>
<p>Later, I jotted down stories in notebooks. I still have those early writings. They were written in ink, not on a computer, so spell check wasn’t available. I couldn’t erase or add words if they were needed. Definitely, a rough draft. My daughters, when they were young, loved those stories and read them over and over again.</p>
<p>However, after I was married and had three children, life seemed to be too busy to pick up a pen and write. It wasn’t until a good friend of mine asked me why I didn’t write anymore that I realized how long it had been. That week I sat down and started my first novel and haven’t stopped writing since.</p>
<p><strong>When did you first consider yourself a writer?</strong></p>
<p>I suppose I’ve always been a writer in my heart, but when I held my first book in print that my publisher had sent me, I truly believed it.</p>
<p><strong>Can you share a little about your current book with us?</strong></p>
<p>Evie Reid on a whim agrees to travel back in time to 1997 to change bad boy/rock star Bellamy Lovel’s path. She’s smart with a college degree, but she is still fan-girl crazy for the rock band Civilized Heathens. Evie knows despite all Bellamy’s smiles and enthusiasm on the stage, he’s destined to end it all on one lonely night in a hotel room unless she can change his path.</p>
<p>Bellamy isn’t keen on having Evie as his personal assistant, hired by his bandmates to watch over him, and keep him on schedule. However, there is something about the woman that sparks his interest, despite his best to ignore her. When darkness threatens to consume him he realizes she may be the only light that will chase the shadows away.</p>
<p><strong>What inspired you to write this book?</strong></p>
<p>My daughter and I watched ‘INXS, Live at Wembley’ on DVD. We were sad to think the lead singer had died so tragically and there would never be another song written or performed by him. The time travel tale about Bellamy Lovel took root, but I wanted a happier ending for my rock star and sent Evie back in time to try and save him.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have a specific writing style?</strong></p>
<p>No matter how dark the story may be, I try to also keep some levity in the tale. Life is about ups and downs and everything in between. I strive to keep the characters real no matter if they&#8217;re human, a vampire, or shape-shifter. I want them to have genuine emotions and flaws because no one is perfect. I want them to fall in love and by the end of the story, I want the characters to find their happily ever after even if it&#8217;s only for now.</p>
<p><strong>How did you come up with the title of this book?</strong></p>
<p>It was inspired by an INXS song. It wasn’t the title or the theme but three words within the song that inspired the title. <em>Two Worlds Collided</em> became the title for two reasons. My heroine is from the future and my hero is from the past, but their worlds collide. Also, my heroine’s essence is what travels back in time to merge with her younger self in 1997. In a sense, her worlds collide so she can be with the hero and hopefully change his tragic past.</p>
<p><strong>Is there a message in your novel that you want readers to grasp?</strong></p>
<p>First and foremost, I hope the story is heartwarming, fun, and simply entertaining.</p>
<p>Though <em>Two Worlds Collided</em> is a time travel romance with plenty of humor and steamy romantic moments, my fictional character, Bellamy, struggles with addiction, depression, and suicide. They are all serious emotions that should never be overlooked.</p>
<p>Of course, thoughts of suicide are not necessarily something people announce to the world and this means loved ones often have no idea that their friend or family member is even contemplating such an act. However, there may be signs and risk factors, and while you might think you can’t make a difference by yourself, you’re wrong. Sometimes all it takes is one person to say something or do something that will change their decision. One smile, one comment, a conversation or even a gesture toward someone who is considering suicide could make all the difference in the world. It could instill hope and with hope they may seek help.</p>
<p><strong>Are experiences in this book based on someone you know or events in your own life?</strong></p>
<p>Though I’ve known people who have suffered from addiction and depression, <em>Two Worlds Collided</em> was inspired by the tragic story of a true-life rock star.</p>
<p><strong>If you had to choose, is there a writer you would consider a mentor? Why?</strong></p>
<p>Not really a mentor, but I do have someone I can bounce ideas off and discuss story plots. This is my daughter Katrina, who is not only a talented cover book artist but also an author as well. We’ll sit down and brainstorm about where I should send my characters next.</p>
<p>I also have a very good friend who edits my work and she’s not shy about telling me if something isn’t working for her in the story. This is vital in penning a good tale. I value her honest opinions. Thanks, Cathy.</p>
<p><strong>What authors have most influenced your life? What about them do you find inspiring?</strong></p>
<p>I’m blessed with knowing many author friends that I’ve met online who have shared their experiences on what works and what doesn’t work in the storytelling world. Both are important in striving to be a successful writer.</p>
<p><strong>Who designed the cover of your book? Why did you select this illustrator?</strong></p>
<p>Gillian’s Book Covers, “Judge Your Book By Its Cover” is the name of my book cover store that I co-own with my daughter, Katrina Gillian. I created the cover for <em>Two Worlds Collided</em>. There were a few covers created before the one you see now was finally chosen.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any advice for other writers?</strong></p>
<p>Be true to yourself. Write every day even if you don’t feel inspired. Sometimes your quick thoughts can blossom into something more.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have anything specific that you want to say to your readers?</strong></p>
<p>Readers are what writers can never live without. The novel doesn’t only belong to the writer; it also belongs to the reader as well. Without the reader, the story is just ink on a paper and nothing more. Opening the book, reading those first words, this is where the true magic begins. I love readers! Thank you so much for loving books.</p>
<p><a href="http://kmnbooks.blogspot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Karen Michelle Nutt</a><a href="http://kmnbooks.blogspot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11692 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/book-cover-two-worlds-collided-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a><br />
Huntington Beach, CA</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/authorkarenmichellenutt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">FACEBOOK</a><br />
<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/190487.Karen_Michelle_Nutt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GOODREADS</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/KMNbooks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TWITTER</a><br />
<a href="https://www.pinterest.com/karenmnutt/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PINTEREST</a><br />
<a href="http://kmnbooks.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">TUMBLER</a><br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/kmnbooks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">YOUTUBE</a></p>
<p><strong>Two Worlds Collided</strong></p>
<p>Cover Artist: <a href="http://judgeyourbookbyitscover.blogspot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gillian’s Book Covers</a><br />
Publisher: <a href="http://twinstarbooks.blogspot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twin Star Books</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Karen-Michelle-Nutt/e/B002BLLBPE/ref=dp_byline_cont_ebooks_1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AMAZON</a><br />
<a href="http://www.barnesandnoble.com/s/%22Karen%20Michelle%20Nutt%22?Ntk=P_key_Contributor_List&amp;Ns=P_Sales_Rank&amp;Ntx=mode+matchall" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BARNES &amp; NOBLE</a><br />
<a href="http://www.smashwords.com/books/search?query=karen+michelle+nutt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SMASHWORDS</a><br />
<a href="https://www.kobo.com/us/en/search?Query=karen+michelle+nutt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KOBO</a><br />
<a href="http://www.booksamillion.com/search?query=karen%20michelle%20nutt;where=All;No=0&amp;id=6784675421138" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">BOOKS A MILLION</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Crystal Singer</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-crystal-singer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy Van Camp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 10:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Book Title: Crystal Singer Author: Anne McCaffrey First Published: 1982 Anne McCaffrey was born in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7857 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Crystal-Singer-Book-Cover-177x300.jpg" alt="" width="177" height="300" /></p>
<p><strong>Book Title: <em>Crystal Singer</em><br />
Author: Anne McCaffrey<br />
First Published: 1982</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/authors/19647/anne-mccaffrey">Anne McCaffrey</a> was born in Cambridge, Massachusetts. The only daughter of three siblings and the middle child, she grew up on the east coast of the United States. Eventually, she graduated cum laude from college where she earned a degree in Slavonic Languages and Literature. In 1950 she married Horace Johnson and they had three children: Alec, Todd, and Gigi. The family lived in Wilmington, Delaware for around a decade and then moved to Sea Cliff on Long Island in 1965 where they remained until 1970. During this time, Anne McCaffrey began to work full time as a writer and served a term as the secretary-treasurer of the <a href="https://www.sfwa.org/">Science Fiction &amp; Fantasy Writers of America</a>. Her duties not only included the publishing of two monthly newsletters for the guild but also handcrafting the <a href="https://nebulas.sfwa.org/">Nebula Award</a> trophies.</p>
<p>In 1970, McCaffrey divorced her husband and took her children to live in Ireland. During the 1970s, Ireland allowed artists to live exempted from income taxes and Anne McCaffrey, being of Irish descent, emigrated to Ireland to take advantage of this opportunity. Anne’s mother soon joined the family where they lived in Dublin. McCaffrey’s books about the dragons that lived in a symbiotic relationship with the human settlers of the planet Pern became bestsellers and classics of science fiction. They paid for her cottage in Ireland that she called “Dragonhold” in honor of the dragons that supported herself and her children. She lived there until her death at the age of 85.</p>
<p>The roots of the <em>Crystal Singer</em> series began while Anne McCaffery was a student studying voice. She performed as a singer, directed a play, and was employed by the record label, Liberty Music Shop. Despite these successes, it was during her later years of study that she learned about a flaw in her voice that would limit her achievements in the field of music. McCaffery was devastated by this experience and used it in the <em>Crystal Singer</em> series to shape her main character Killashandra Ree.</p>
<p>The book first began as a series of shorts that were published in<em> Continuum Magazine</em>:</p>
<p>“Prelude to a Crystal Song,” <em>Continuum</em> 1 (Apr 1974)<br />
“Killashandra – Crystal Singer,” <em>Continuum</em> 2 (Aug 1974)<br />
“Milekey Mountain,” <em>Continuum</em> 3 (Dec 1974)<br />
“Killashandra – Coda and Finale,” <em>Continuum</em> 4 (Aug 1975)</p>
<p>In the short stories, Killashandra Ree dies, but when McCaffery decided to combine all the short stories into a single novel, she revised all the shorts heavily to not only blend them into a single story, but changed the main character’s ultimate fate. The name of the crystal singer was inspired by a small town in north central Ireland called Killeshandra.</p>
<blockquote><p>“There’s nothing wrong in doubting. It sometimes leads to greater faith.”<br />
― Anne McCaffrey</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Crystal Singer</em> begins when a young vocal student named Killashandra Ree is finishing ten years of study in order to become a vocal soloist of a futuristic civilization known as the Federated Sentient Planets. She anticipates becoming a “rock star” of interstellar proportions. During her final exams, it is discovered that she has a fatal flaw in her voice that will forever prevent her from singing lead roles, despite her perfect pitch and performing talents. Killashandra is heartbroken and plans to leave both the school and her home world in private disgrace.</p>
<p>At the spaceport she meets an older man who uses his musical skills to identify an arriving space shuttle that is about to explode, averting the disaster. The two hit it off and he treats her to a whirlwind romance on her home world while he is on vacation. She grows curious about her new lover and his profession of “crystal singer.” It is an occupation of people with perfect musical pitch that use their voices to control devices to mine a very rare crystalline mineral on the planet of Ballybran. These crystals are used in most of the complex systems that power interstellar communications and power much of the machinery of her civilization. It is a dangerous profession, but one that earns high credits and has a select and small membership. Although she is warned away repeatedly, Killashandra is drawn to the mysterious Heptite Guild and becomes determined to become a crystal singer herself.</p>
<p>Travel to Ballybran is forbidden to all but its residents. On the moon of Ballybran, Killashandra learns the reason why. Anyone that ventures onto the planet is infected by a symbiotic life form that invades the human body and causes genetic mutations. Many people simply die. Others only gain a partial adaptation that allows them to live, but with reduced hearing or eyesight. They are forever confined to the planet, unable to leave because if they do the symbiont dies and they along with it. Those few that get a full adaptation to the symbiont become the crystal singers who gain increased vision and hearing, rapid healing, and a long life. It makes them sterile and in the end they suffer memory loss, paranoia, and dementia, but only after hundreds of years of life. They also can depart Ballybran for short periods of time without their symbiont dying.</p>
<p>Headstrong and stubborn, Killashandra journeys to Ballybran along with thirty other inductees. The novel follows her and her classmates during their education while they wait for the invading infection. One by one, they fall to the symbiont until all have been converted. During this time she gains the attention of the head of the guild, a man named Lanzecki. He offers her a job that she can’t refuse, one that not only allows her to use her new skills as a crystal singer, but one that might allow her to present a public performance that would put her back in the spotlight for which she trained all those years.</p>
<p>I have always loved the <em>Crystal Singer</em> series by Anne McCaffery. I first read the book when it was released in the early 80s and felt a strong identification with the main character, Killashandra Ree. She is a complex character, a combination of confidence that borders on arrogance and yet inside she is shy and vulnerable. Many artists have this sort of personality and I liked that she was a strong woman who was willing to take control of her own life in the face of failure. She felt like a real and likable woman to me.</p>
<p>The Federated Sentient Planets that Killashandra lives in is powered not by manufactured technology, such as ours is, but by natural forming crystals that can be sung into service. I love the concept of human art meeting function in this way. It is quite unique and the world of Ballybran and the Heptite Guild society is an interesting concept. The visual of the crystal singer serenading a mountain side and it singing back to her is powerful and one that you will not soon forget. Of all the series set in the universe, I feel that this one is the most clerical in nature. You need a card for everything and the machines monitor all the details. It reminds me of our current way of life.</p>
<p>There are some outdated qualities to the book. During the late 70s and early 80s, sexual freedom was thought to be women sleeping around much as single men of the time period did. Killashandra has several lovers in this fashion. The sex is free and easy, completely consensual, but without long-term attachments. There are no steamy sex scenes in the book, but in my view, the easy going relationships don’t quite mesh with what we might think of feminism now.</p>
<p>The men in the book were also somewhat paternalistic toward the female main character. Again, this was a common attitude during this decade and it has carried over into the culture of this interstellar society. It is not as bad as in some books and for the most part, I felt that Killashandra was treated as an equal by peers, even when they could not stand her for her “perfection.”</p>
<p>While <em>Crystal Singer</em> is not a Nebula or Hugo award winner, it does have staying power and I believe that it would most appeal to high school or college aged readers. It can be a little difficult to find at the local library due to its age, but you should be able to find it on the online outlet of your choice. Go and find the books. If you love classic science fiction and enjoy reading females authors in this genre, <em>Crystal Singer</em> is a great choice.</p>
<p><strong>Crystal Singer Series</strong></p>
<p><em>Crystal Singer</em> 1982<br />
<em>Killashandra</em> 1986<br />
<em>Crystal Line</em> 1992</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Deborah J. Ross</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-deborah-j-ross/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy Van Camp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 10:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Deborah J. Ross writes and edits fantasy and science fiction. Her work has earned Honorable&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Deborah J. Ross writes and edits fantasy and science fiction. Her work has earned Honorable Mention in Year’s Best SF; been a Kirkus notable new release; featured on the Locus Recommended Reading List and James Tiptree, Jr. Award recommended list; was a Finalist for the Lambda Literary Award; and nominated for the National Fantasy Federation Speculative Fiction Award for Best Author, the Nebula Award, and the Gaylactic Spectrum Award. [<em>editor&#8217;s note: whew!</em>] She’s a past Secretary of SFWA and currently on the Board of Directors of Book View Café, an online writers&#8217; co-op.</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7906 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Author-Deborah-J-Ross-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" />I grew up in California and Oregon, coming of age in the 1960s, so of course, I grew my hair long, protested everything, and have the tie-dyed t-shirt to prove it. I accumulated various academic degrees, including a BA in Biology from Reed College and an MS in Psychology from Portland State University, before realizing the true “work of my heart” was storytelling. Now I live in a redwood forest with my family, which includes three cats and a retired “seeing-eye” German Shepherd Dog. In between writing, I’ve lived in France, worked as a medical assistant to a cardiologist, taught parent-child gym classes at the Y, revived an elementary school library, studied Chinese martial arts (tai chi and kung fu san soo), classical piano, and yoga.</p>
<p><strong>When and why did you begin writing?</strong></p>
<p>Well before I learned to scrawl my name, I made up stories, and once I could form proper words and pictures to accompany them, I began putting together whole books. My father was a printer, and our home was amply supplied with paper and ink. In my teens and twenties, I began many novels, even finished a few of them, but never knew what to do with them next, nor did I know any writers beyond a few school friends who were just as clueless as I was. I knew I loved to write, and I occasionally dared to hope that someday, my writing would be more than a secret pleasure.</p>
<p>In my early thirties, just after my first child was born, I hit career burnout and decided to work part-time from home. A friend invited me to join a women’s writing group. Although none of us knew what we were doing, I came home from the first meeting so exhilarated that I drafted the story I’d been playing in my head for the last year. No one told me it was crazy to write a novel in six weeks with a new baby and a part-time career. The real break came in 1991, when I lived in Lyons, France. A couple of months after I returned to the States, I sold my first novel.</p>
<p><strong>How did your writing relationship with Marion Zimmer Bradley develop?</strong></p>
<p>Somewhere around 1980, I wrote Marion a fan letter. To my surprise, she wrote back, three pages of single-spaced typewriting. I’d been studying martial arts and we began a correspondence about women’s empowerment, story-telling, family, and a host of related topics.</p>
<p>At that time, the <a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/Friends_of_Darkover">Friends of Darkover</a> held periodic writing contests and published its own fanzine. I sent her a couple of stories and received encouraging comments (and, as I remember, an award for one of the stories and eventual fanzine publication of the other). When Marion began editing the first <em>Sword &amp; Sorceress</em>, she suggested I submit a story for her. I was as elated by the invitation as if it had been a sale, and threw myself into writing the best story I could. It was a modest little story, a respectable first professional sale, but more than that, Marion showed me that I could take my writing seriously.</p>
<p>When I submitted a story for the second volume, Marion telephoned me. “Now Deborah,” she said, “I’m going to take your story, but I’m sending it back to you for revisions.” With that, I made the leap from all-or-nothing sale-or-rejection to working with an editor. My manuscript came back covered in red ink, with comments like, “All thuds are dull!” and “Overwritten.” Don’t just fall in love with your words, she was saying: make them serve the story.</p>
<p>Marion didn’t buy every story I wrote, but she saw most of them. More editorial notes followed, although not as extensive as that first round. I like to think I was improving, but it may also have been that Marion understood when outside critical feedback is helpful, and when the act of writing itself, story after story, is the key to development. She often said that the first million words are practice, and I was well on my way.</p>
<p>With my first novel sale (<a href="https://www.fantasticfiction.com/r/deborah-j-ross/jaydium.htm"><em>Jaydium</em></a>, a science fiction adventure through time and parallel worlds, complete with gigantic, intelligent silver slugs), and short fiction sales to increasingly prestigious markets (like <em>Asimov’s</em> and <em>F &amp; SF</em>), I came into my own.</p>
<p>Over the years, we became friends as well as colleagues and editor/writer. My natural authorial “voice” was close, although not identical, to hers. Toward the end of her life, hampered by a series of strokes, Marion worked with in collaboration several other writers. I was one of the writers she considered because she had watched me develop from a novice to an established professional. We discussed the basic details by mail and then I drove up to see her for a personal chat. She’d been resting and was on oxygen, but she insisted on sitting up when I came in, and soon we were deep in discussion of plot ideas. One of my best memories of her was watching her “come alive” as we discussed character and hatched plot points. Her eyes “glowed as if lit from within,” to use one of her favorite descriptions, and energy suffused her whole being. I asked question after question and then sat back as she spun out answers. It was as if she had opened a window into her imagination and invited me to peek inside. She died before we started the actual writing (<em>The Fall of Neskaya, Zandru’s Forge, A Flame in Hali</em>). and I went on to write three more (<em>The Alton Gift, Hastur Lord, The Children of Kings</em>), and there are more to come.</p>
<p>Writing Darkover stories is much like writing historical fiction. I do research, using not only Marion’s published work, but <em>The Darkover Concordance</em> and her articles in the old Darkover newsletters. I try to create story lines that are true to Marion’s vision of Darkover and the themes that were meaningful to her. Since I work closely with the MZB Literary Trust, I hammer out a detailed outline before I start. Once that’s approved, I turn the process over to my creative back-brain. Because I’m not trying to distort my own intuitive style, I can then write from my heart.</p>
<p><strong>Can you share a little about your current book with us?</strong></p>
<p>My most recent Darkover novel is <em>The Children of Kings</em>, an action-adventure set in the Dry Towns, featuring Gareth Elhalyn, Regis’s grandson, and some nasty space pirates bent on turning Darkover into a smuggling base. I just turned in the next Darkover novel, <em>Thunderlord</em>, a sequel to Hawkmistress, in which the son of the defeated Lord Scathfell plots revenge by marrying a girl from the Rockraven clan, noted for their ability to control storms and lightning. [Editor&#8217;s note: this was  a August 2016 release from DAW, under the dual byline with Marion Zimmer Bradley.]</p>
<p>Other recent publications include the Lambda Award Finalist Collaborators (under my former name, Deborah Wheeler), and an original epic fantasy trilogy, <em>The</em> <em>Seven-Petaled Shield</em> (in which women get to have heroic adventures), all of these from DAW.</p>
<p>In terms of editing, I’m wrapping up the anthology <em>Realms of Darkover</em>. Once that’s done, I’ll dive into the next novel, <em>The Laran Gambit</em>, which continues the “modern” timeline and brings Darkover and the Terrans back into conflict, er – contact – in a clash between machine-mediated mind control and natural laran Gifts.</p>
<p><strong>What authors have most influenced your writing in addition to Marion Zimmer Bradley? What about them do you find inspiring?</strong></p>
<p>The list is very long! Some of my favorite contemporary authors include Barbara Hambly, Mary Rosenblum, Lois McMaster Bujold, Sherwood Smith, Carol Berg, Freda Warrington, Jennifer Roberson, Chaz Brenchley, Judith Tarr, Vonda N. McIntyre, Ursula K. Le Guin, Charles Stross, Saladin Ahmed, Diana Wynne Jones, and Tanith Lee. I love authors who give me a new way of thinking about story or language. Once it was possible to keep up with who was writing what, but the field is so large now, I’ve given up trying. I rely on the advice of friends whose taste I trust. It’s hilarious when a friend hates what I love and vice-versa, so I go for whatever they pan. When I go to a science fiction convention, I try to buy at least one book by an author I have just met but have not yet read.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any advice for other writers?</strong></p>
<p>Writing is both craft and art. You already have the dream. Now you have to learn the craft. As exciting as the prospect of publication is, if you’re in this for the long haul, be patient. It takes time and work to achieve excellence. There are so many aspects of success you’re powerless over, but the quality of your work is one you do have control over. I wrote a series of essays about nurturing yourself as a writer as you wrestle with the skills, called <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Ink-Dance-Essays-Writing-Life-ebook/dp/B00HX2A20G"><em>Ink Dance: Essays on the Writing Life</em></a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-7907 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Children-of-Kings-Book-Cover-201x300.jpg" alt="" width="201" height="300" /><strong><a href="http://www.sff.net/people/deborahjross/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Deborah J. Ross</a><br />
Boulder Creek CA</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://deborahjross.blogspot.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BLOG</a><br />
<a href="http://deborahjross.livejournal.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LIVEJOURNAL</a><br />
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/deborah.j.ross.9" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FACEBOOK</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/DeborahJRoss" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TWITTER</a></p>
<p><strong>The Children of Kings</strong></p>
<p>Cover artist: <a href="http://www.mattstawicki.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Matt Stawicki</a><br />
Publisher: <a href="http://www.penguin.com/meet/publishers/daw/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DAW Books</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Children-Kings-Darkover-Novel-ebook/dp/B009VMC1FA/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AMAZON</a><br />
<a href="http://www.barnesandnoble.com/s/deborah+j+ross?_requestid=558248" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BARNES &amp; NOBLE</a><br />
<a href="http://bookviewcafe.com/bookstore/bvc-author/deborah-j-ross/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BOOK VIEW CAFE</a><br />
<a href="https://www.kobo.com/us/en/search?Query=deborah+j+ross" target="_blank" rel="noopener">KOBO</a><br />
<a href="https://www.smashwords.com/books/search?query=deborah+j+ross" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SMASHWORDS</a><br />
<a href="http://www.indiebound.org/search/book?searchfor=deborah+j+ross" target="_blank" rel="noopener">INDIEBOUND</a><br />
<a href="http://www.powells.com/SearchResults?kw=title:deborah%20j%20ross" target="_blank" rel="noopener">POWELL’S</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Karen Azinger</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-karen-azinger/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy Van Camp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Author Karen Azinger writes epic fantasy inspired by the style of George R. R. Martin’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Author Karen Azinger writes epic fantasy inspired by the style of George R. R. Martin’s<em> Game of Thrones</em>, but with more women. </strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8082 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Karen-L.-Azinger-232x300.jpg" alt="" width="232" height="300" />My name is Karen Azinger. I guess the best description of myself is a Renaissance woman, someone with wide-ranging interests and skills for both work and play. On the play side, I love the beauty of nature, from hiking in the Columbia River Gorge, to walking on a beach, to snorkeling and scuba diving in warm clear oceans. My favorite hobby is art, from photography, to fused glass, to acrylic painting. Our house is full of art. And of course, I love to read, especially fantasy. In terms of work, I’ve worn many hats, from a chemical engineer, to a business strategist, to a vice-president. I’ve worked around the globe in the resource sector. And now I’m wearing one of my favorite hats, a published author of epic fantasy!</p>
<p><strong>When and why did you begin writing?</strong></p>
<p>About twelve years ago, I finished reading George Martin’s <a href="https://awoiaf.westeros.org/index.php/A_Storm_of_Swords"><em>Storm of Swords</em></a> and I desperately wanted more. But of course, George takes a long time between books. I scavenged bookstores but could not find anything to satisfy my craving for epic fantasy with deep plots and complex characters. Disappointed, I went on a hike in the Columbia River Gorge and imagined what I would do if I wrote an epic fantasy. By the time I finished the hike, I had so many original ideas that I decided to write my own saga. I sat down at the computer, started writing, and never stopped!</p>
<p><strong>When did you first consider yourself a writer?</strong></p>
<p>When I finished the first manuscript of <em>The Steel Queen</em> and was willing to give it to strangers to read.</p>
<p><strong>Can you share a little about your current book with us?</strong></p>
<p>For the last twelve years, I’ve been working on <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Steel-Queen-Silk-Saga-Book-ebook/dp/B0060AMHKU"><em>The Silk &amp; Steel Saga</em></a>, an epic medieval fantasy with swords and knights, castles and monasteries, sorcery and seduction. In many ways, I’ve felt the most pressure writing the last book, because I know how critically important it is to have a great ending. As an author, I want each book to be better than the last. But the last book carries an extra challenge because it has to be written so the reader never forgets.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have a specific writing style?</strong></p>
<p>I write in the style of George R. R. Martin’s <em>Game of Thrones</em>, where each chapter is from a different POV. I love this style of writing because it lets both the reader and the author get deep into the hearts and minds of the different characters.</p>
<p><strong>How did you come up with the title of this book?</strong></p>
<p>Epic fantasies are often referred to by their acronym, LOTR for <em>Lord of the Rings</em>, GoT for <em>Game of Thrones</em>. The acronym for <em>The Silk &amp; Steel Saga</em> is SASS, for all the sassy women!</p>
<p><strong>Is there a message in your novel that you want readers to grasp?</strong></p>
<p>On the surface, this saga is swords and sorcery, but on a deeper level, the saga explores how women gain, keep, and wield power in a medieval world. Filled with strong female characters from a sword-wielding princess, to a brilliant queen who uses beauty to beguile, spies to predict, and gold to control, to a silver-haired grandmother who wields knitting needles and knives, to a priestess who plies poison and seduction in a bid for immortality, this sage will never let you underestimate the ‘weaker’ sex again.</p>
<p><strong>What authors have most influenced your life? What about them do you find inspiring?</strong></p>
<p>I’m most influenced by the three I most love to read, Tolkien, George Martin, and Frank Herbert (might as well learn from the best!). From Tolkien, I take lessons in how to create an amazing and believable world brimming with wonder. From reading George Martin’s <em>Game of Thrones</em> I grew fascinated with the idea of writing deep in the POV of complex characters ensnared in tangled plots. From Frank Herbert’s <em>Dune</em>, I look lessons in how to thread multiple themes through my saga to give my story depth and meaning. To me, theme is the secret weapon of authors. Theme is what elevates a good read to a great read, making us think about the story long after the last page is turned.</p>
<p><strong>Who designed the cover of your book?</strong></p>
<p>Greg Bridges designed my front covers, an award winning artist from Australia.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any advice for other writers?</strong></p>
<p>Write, write some more, and then get as many people as you can to read your work. And never stop reading. All writers start as readers.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have anything specific that you want to say to your readers?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, I love hearing from my readers! The best way is on Facebook or Twitter. <em>The Silk &amp; Steel Saga</em> has the best fans all around the world! Thank you!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8081 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/The-Battle-Immortal-Book-Cover-205x300.jpg" alt="" width="205" height="300" /><a href="http://www.karenlazinger.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Karen Azinger</a><br />
Portland, Oregon</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100000411777461&amp;fref=ts" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FACEBOOK</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11375883-the-steel-queen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOODREADS</a></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/karenazinger" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TWITTER</a></p>
<p><em>The Battle Immortal</em></p>
<p>Cover Artist: <a href="http://www.gregbridges.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Greg Bridges</a><br />
Publisher: Kiralynn Epics</p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Steel-Queen-Silk-Saga-Book-ebook/dp/B0060AMHKU" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AMAZON</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: D.L. Carter</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-d-l-carter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy Van Camp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Author D. L. Carter has been called crazy, restless optimist, pessimist, lazy, a crank with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Author D. L. Carter has been called crazy, restless optimist, pessimist, lazy, a crank with delusional invisible friends who have the greatest, dangerous ideas. She is also an excellent science fiction and fantasy author. Please welcome “D” to No Wasted Ink.</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8086 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Author-DL-Carter-213x300.jpg" alt="" width="213" height="300" />D. L. Carter (Dee Leana, call me ‘D’) was decanted from her incubation pod in the outback of Australia many decades ago. This terrifying event was closely followed by shrieks of “There, there it goes. Hit it with a brick!”</p>
<p>These valiant attempts to correct the existence of D.L. were, unfortunately, unsuccessful, and she now resides in New Jersey, in a box with her toys, two human beings, and a variable number of cats.</p>
<p>From the preceding you can assume that I don’t take bios, or many things, seriously. I am a professionally silly person and weirdo. The late great Sir Terry Prachett, in his Witches series, described some people as lying sideways across the tracks on which the human race was run and that describes me down to the ground.</p>
<p><strong>When and why did you begin writing?</strong></p>
<p>When – very, very young. Mother reports that she would read me a story and when it was over I would demand to know “what happens next?” When she explained that the book was over I would tell her the further adventures of those characters. Later, preschool, I would walk around the back garden talking to myself, telling stories. I think this means I have always been writing.</p>
<p>The why? Mostly because I do want to know what happened next, what happened before and why the heck the chicken crossed the road?</p>
<p><strong>When did you first consider yourself a writer?</strong></p>
<p>Um. Always. One of my English teachers praised my dialogue back in 8th grade (I don’t know what that translates to in US years) and I have always had a little notebook (paper in pre-computer years) in my bag to continue the adventures of whoever had my attention at the time. My published career started in <em>Star Trek</em> fan fic and I regarded myself as a successful writer when I started getting letters from people who had read my short stories in various fanzines. If I could make people think and feel then obviously my writing was working.</p>
<p><strong>Can you share a little about your current book with us?</strong></p>
<p>The second book in the “Changing Magic” series. In the first book I looked at the issues that would arise in a society dependent upon magic when the magic users had a fertility problem. In the second book I look at what happens when the magic goes away because of a severe failure of the weather spells.</p>
<p><strong>What inspired you to write this book?</strong></p>
<p>Having personally lived through a flood where all the usual facilities disappeared – power, clean water, flush toilets, the person who refilled the sweets machine – I could empathize with the suffering of magic users and those dependent upon them.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have a specific writing style?</strong></p>
<p>I’m in it for the laughs.</p>
<p>I am a great admirer of the late great amazing George Carlin and Terry Prachett. From George I learned that you need to use more words to create humor. You have to build a cadence, a rhythm, an avalanche of words to render your audience breathless with admiration and laughter. I have not achieved their brilliance, but it is a personal ambition to be funny.</p>
<p><strong>How did you come up with the title of this book?</strong></p>
<p>In a conversation with my publisher. I gave her the first in this series which had the interesting but unsellable title of “The Use and Complexity of Sex Magic”. It was intended to be a stand-alone book but publisher (Corvallis Press) requested (demanded) a trilogy. I said since I was introducing new forms of magic into this fictional world I would call the series “Changing Magic” and the first became <em>The Use</em>, the second <em>The Complications</em>. The third will be<em> The Consequences</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Is there a message in your novel that you want readers to grasp?</strong></p>
<p>Message? Um. OK.</p>
<p>There are very few personal problems that cannot be solved by a suitable application of high explosives.</p>
<p>Wait! No.</p>
<p>Suitable application of Reasonable Intelligent Heroines.</p>
<p>When reading novels I get really short-tempered when the heroines are twits. I can’t stand it. I do believe in the historical record that tells us that women are self-rescuing princesses. We don’t have to wait for a prince or a soldier or whatever to come solve the problems. In my house, I am the one with the power tools and the screwdriver set. I assemble the furniture. I got the mortgage. Why do we let our fiction tell us that we have to be passive?</p>
<p>The old Germanic fairy tales include the Princess with the Iron Shoes where a woman wears out the soles of seven pairs of iron shoes trying to find her lost husband.</p>
<p>Message – let’s go out and save the universe.</p>
<p><strong>Are experiences in this book based on someone you know, or events in your own life?</strong></p>
<p>Flood, yes. Sex Magic, no.</p>
<p><strong>What authors have most influenced your life? What about them do you find inspiring?</strong></p>
<p>Issac Asimov – wrote about everything and anything, proving that you don’t have to stick to one genre. There are some publishers and agents who say you have to build up a readership that you cannot confuse. Choose one area and stay with it and only with great trepidation do you challenge the readers to go with you into another area. Myself, I like to jump around – a lot.</p>
<p>Agatha Christie – writer and pharmacist. The medical profession is no deterrent to a successful writing career.</p>
<p><strong>If you had to choose, is there a writer would you consider a mentor? Why?</strong></p>
<p>I have mentors. Dr. Charles Pellegrino (<em>DUST</em>, <em>Her Name: Titanic</em>, <em>Flying to Valhalla</em>) is an old friend. From him, I learned how to research and how to stubbornly ignore negative reviews. He does non-fiction and fiction so he encouraged me to play in as many different genres that made me happy.</p>
<p>Leigh Michaels – (<em>The Birthday Scandal</em>) I met through Gotham Writers&#8217; group – classes you can take online. I took a couple of classes with her, and one of the greatest days of my life was the end of a set of classes when she asked to see the rest of the book that I had presented. I said I couldn’t afford her editing fee. She said, &#8220;No, I actually wanted to know what happened next. I want to read the book for my own pleasure.&#8221; Oh, wow! I had caught a reader’s attention! And that reader was a published author. ::Blush::</p>
<p><strong>Who designed the cover of your book? Why did you select this illustrator?</strong></p>
<p>Cover illustrator works for Corvallis. All I said was that I wanted a building that looked like it was drowning.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any advice for other writers?</strong></p>
<p>OK. My brother-in-law who is a professional movie critic (votes on the academy awards, etc., and has a blog with one million hits) directed my attention to <em>9 Indispensable Ingredients That Are Always Present in Every Hit Film</em>, written by Tom Laughlin, the writer of the famous <em>Billy Jack</em> movie series.</p>
<p>Book blurb: After the most exhaustive research and analysis of box office grosses of films through the 1990’s, Tom Laughlin has discovered 9 indispensable ingredients that must be present in every film, book, TV show or play in order for it to be a commercial success. These ingredients are ALWAYS present in the hits, and ALWAYS absent in the failures.</p>
<p>After reading this book I have made a point to go through my book plots and make sure I have these ingredients. There has to be a legitimate villain, a believable Hero and Heroine. A ticking clock, a sword of Damocles, etc., etc. I believe this book has helped me make well-rounded worlds and adventures.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have anything specific that you want to say to your readers?</strong></p>
<p>Write your book.<br />
Finish book.<br />
Submit book for publication and move on to next book.<br />
Don’t stop.<br />
Refine your craft.<br />
Having a pile of books in your computer doesn’t help. You have to put it out there.</p>
<p><a href="http://dlcarterauthor.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DL Carter</a><a href="http://dlcarterauthor.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8166 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Complications-of-Changing-Magic-Book-Cover-201x300.jpg" alt="" width="201" height="300" /></a><br />
New Jersey, USA</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/1618084415085564/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FACEBOOK</a><br />
<a href="https://twitter.com/dlcarter2" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TWITTER</a><br />
<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/9811019.D_L_Carter" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GOODREADS</a></p>
<p><strong>Complications of Changing Magic</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Complications-Changing-Magic-D-Carter-ebook/dp/B0194EZOG2/ref=la_B0064R8COE" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AMAZON</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Forty Thousand in Gehenna</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/book-review-forty-thousand-in-gehenna/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy Van Camp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 10:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Book Name: Forty Thousand in Gehenna Author: C.J. Cherryh First Published: 1983 Nominated for Locus&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7862 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/40K-in-Gehenna-Book-Cover-186x300.jpg" alt="" width="186" height="300" /></p>
<p><strong>Book Name:<em> Forty Thousand in Gehenna</em><br />
Author: C.J. Cherryh<br />
First Published: 1983<br />
Nominated for Locus Award (1984)</strong></p>
<p>Author <a href="http://www.sf-encyclopedia.com/entry/cherryh_c_j">Carolyn Janice Cherry</a> is better known by her pen name C. J. Cherryh. She is a Hugo Award-winning science fiction and fantasy writer with 40 novels under her belt. Cherryh is pronounced “Cherry”. When she first began publishing her stories in the early &#8217;70s, Cherryh was asked to create a pen name by DAW editor Donald Wollheim. He felt that her real name fit a romance writer instead of a science fiction writer. She also switched to using her initials to disguise that she was female. This was a common practice at the time since women authors were not as accepted in the genre as male authors were. Fortunately, that is no longer the norm in the genre.</p>
<p>C.J. Cherryh was born in 1942 and raised in Lawton, Oklahoma. In 1964, she earned a Bachelor of Arts degree in Latin from the University of Oklahoma, and went on to gain a Master of Arts in classics from Johns Hopkins University. After graduation, Cherryh became a high school teacher of Latin, ancient Greek, and the classics and taught secondary school in the Oklahoma City public school district. While her job was teaching Latin, her passion was history. During her summers off, she would conduct student tours of ancient ruins in England, France, Spain, and Italy.</p>
<p>As busy as she was, Cherryh could not shake the writing bug. She had been writing stories since the age of ten and continued to write novels in her spare time. She did not follow the usual path of science fiction writers of the time, starting with publishing short stories in the national magazines of the day, but instead her focus was on writing novels. While Cherryh has written shorter works, she did not begin to do so until after she had published several of her novels first.</p>
<p>Her break came in 1975 when Donald Wollheim bought two manuscripts she submitted to DAW Books. She stated once in an interview in <em>Amazing Stories</em>, “It was the first time a book really found an ending and really worked, because I had made contact with Don Wollheim at DAW, found him interested, and was able to write for a specific editor whose body of work and type of story I knew. It was a good match. It was a set of characters I’d invented when I was, oh, about thirteen. So it was an old favorite of my untold stories, and ended up being the first in print.”</p>
<p>It was the start of a long and fruitful friendship. Cherryh has gone on to publish almost 40 novels, most of them with DAW, but not exclusively, and still continues to write more books today. She has won the Hugo Award for Best Novel twice, first for <a href="https://io9.gizmodo.com/5733980/downbelow-station-heres-how-you-write-a-novel"><em>Downbelow Station</em></a> and then again for <a href="http://www.syfy.com/syfywire/review_regenesis"><em>Cyteen</em></a>, novels that are part of the Alliance-Union Universe series that <em>Forty Thousand in Gehenna</em> is also part of.</p>
<p>Currently, Ms. Cherryh lives in Spokane, Washington, with her partner science fiction/fantasy author and artist Jane Fancher. She enjoys skating, traveling and is a regular guest at many science fiction conventions.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Culture is how biology responds and makes its living conditions better.&#8221; – C. J. Cherryh</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Forty Thousand in Gehenna</em> is not a normal story about the colonization of a planet where an intrepid group of humans sets up a foothold on a world and builds. Instead, it is the story broken into two main sections with a few smaller bridging vignettes. The characters are born and die of old age as the centuries go by. The focus of the novel is about the interaction between humans, from Cherryh’s Alliance-Union universe, and the Caliban, large lizard aliens that are not the unintelligent animals the colonists were led to believe when they first arrive.</p>
<p>Gehenna, which means “hell”, is an experimental colony set up by Union. It is made up of a small faction of “born men” and forty thousand “azi”. The azi live to the age of 40 and then their bodies fail. When they are cloned in the lab, each human azi is programmed psychologically so that he or she is subservient to the born men and happy in their place in society. They are the worker slaves of the Union civilization and outnumber their aristocratic masters a thousand to one. The azi are the key to how Union manages to take over worlds ahead of their competitors, the merchants of the Alliance, giving biological numbers to the leaders of Union to place where they will.</p>
<p>The first part of the novel is about the original colonists and follows a born-man named Gutierrez who comes aboard the colony disguised as an azi, a clone named Jin, and his love interest Pia. Within a few years, it is realized that Union has abandoned Gehenna and no more supplies or the promised azi labs arrive as scheduled. The colony begins to fall apart as the machines break down. The azi begin to have children instead of reproducing via cloning techniques and teach their programming to their children as best they can. In the mix, the alien Caliban intrude as the settlers realize that the giant lizards are far more intelligent than first realized. The azi children imprint on the Caliban as well as their azi parents. This creates an entirely new culture that grows more different as the centuries go forward.</p>
<p>The middle of the book covers when Alliance discovers Gehenna and via a mix of reports and chapters from many different points of view, we see how the outside stellar civilization sees what is happening on the planet in the long view. Alliance meddles in the Gehenna culture with ill effects.</p>
<p>The final part of the novel covers a war between the descendants of Jin and Pia’s two children. The descendants have formed three cultures: one is aggressive and “male” while the other is more passive and “female”. The third group is termed “weirds”. They are people that choose to live with the Caliban in their tunnels. All groups have formed a symbiosis relationship with the alien Calibans. While the Alliance watches and files reports, the cultures clash for domination of Gehenna.</p>
<p>Diving into the Alliance-Union Universe can be confusing. There are a great many novels, some of which follow their own mini-series inside the series. This book can be considered the first of a trilogy, the final installment only being written a few years ago. The original cover of a girl riding a Caliban lizard into battle is what originally drew me to the book. It reminded me a great deal of McCaffery’s dragons of Pern, who also had a symbiotic relationship with their human partners. As it turns out, the Caliban are a more complex komodo dragon with a unique way of communication. You learn about it via submersion just as the colonists do in the story. Cherryh is a master at not only developing sweeping historical world views that explore intricate human cultures of her own devising, but she also is adept at creating stunning alien cultures.</p>
<p>I am fascinated by the concept of the human clones known as azi. Here in Gehenna we get a good look at the Union’s tank-bred, hypnotic-tape-education workforce. The azi make up most of Union’s population and have allowed it to out-breed Sol and the Alliance in these stories, but at what cost? Cloning is a process that is starting in our day and age. The morals and ethics behind the technology have not been fully addressed. What was once science fiction may soon be science fact.</p>
<p>Finally, I enjoy that Cherryh does employ female protagonists in her stories. While in the first section she followed two male Azi, in the last section the protagonist was a girl named Elai who was certainly no wimp and proved to have the wit to fight for her community and people. The 1980s is known for introducing female characters who were independent and functional as full characters in their own right instead of always being the “love interest” for the men.</p>
<p>While <em>Cyteen</em> is the Hugo Award Winner, I feel that you should start with <em>Forty Thousand in Gehenna</em> since it precedes <em>Cyteen</em> chronologically in the series. The two books can be read independently of each other and be fully understandable, but it works better if you read the two together.</p>
<p><strong>Unionside Series of the Alliance-Union Universe</strong></p>
<p><em>Forty Thousand in Gehenna</em> (1983)<br />
<em>Cyteen</em> (1988) – Hugo and Locus SF Award winner, British Science Fiction Award nominee, 1989<br />
<em>Regenesis</em> (2009)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Interview: Elizabeth Gaines Johnston</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-interview-elizabeth-gaines-johnston/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Wendy Van Camp]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 10:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8089</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A huge fan of fantasy and medieval history, Author Elizabeth Gaines Johnston loves weaving complicated&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>A huge fan of fantasy and medieval history, Author Elizabeth Gaines Johnston loves weaving complicated storylines together to create characters who feel like real people. She enjoys using words to paint a picture, so her worlds have a tangible feel to them.</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8091 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Author-Elizabeth-Gaines-Johnston-251x300.jpg" alt="" width="251" height="300" />My name is Elizabeth Gaines Johnston, author of the <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32163981-dragon-s-gift"><em>Gilded Serpents </em>trilogy</a>, as well as the upcoming sequel series, <em>The Realm of Possibilities </em>trilogy. I am a single mother of two sets of identical twin boys (ages 16 and 10) as well as a busy school volunteer, where I direct and teach the theater program for 2nd-8th graders, as well as helping publish the school’s student paper. I have a BA in English Literature with an emphasis on medieval studies, and a History minor. I love to travel. I don’t get to do it as often as I’d like. I’m also a fan of <em>Doctor Who</em>, <em>Firefly</em>, Marvel, some DC (mostly Wonder Woman), <em>The Princess Bride</em>, and many fantasy series.</p>
<p><strong>When and why did you begin writing?</strong></p>
<p>I’ve always loved to write; in my pre-teen and teen years it was mostly short stories and poetry for friends. When I was first married, right out of college, we moved from California to Minnesota, and so while my husband was in med school, I took whatever jobs I could to keep us solvent. To keep my sanity, I used my lunch breaks and after hours writing what I initially thought would be another short story. However, the characters had other ideas, and soon, I found myself writing <em>Dragon’s Gift</em>, the first book of my first trilogy.</p>
<p><strong>When did you first consider yourself a writer?</strong></p>
<p>Good question. I suppose in college I began to think of myself as a writer, but it wasn’t until I had over 1000 pages of my trilogy written that I knew myself to be one. I finally felt like an author when I sold my first book to a total stranger, who later told me how much they enjoyed it.</p>
<p><strong>Can you share a little about your current book with us?</strong></p>
<p>All three books are out simultaneously, so no one has to wait to find out what happens! The first book, <em>Dragon’s Gift</em>, is the most lighthearted, as our heroine is starting out on her journey, meeting new friends and acquiring new skills. The second book, <em>Magic’s Price</em>, is the longest of the three, mainly because that’s where the divisions naturally occurred. It is more complex, as several key players become separated during this time, and they find they must face challenges they never expected. Our heroine, and her friends, also grow more and more to doubt themselves during this portion of the tale. Finally, in the conclusion of the trilogy, <em>War’s Toll</em>, our main characters have to overcome tremendous odds and their own misgivings in order to defeat the great evil threatening their lands.</p>
<p><strong>What inspired you to write this book?</strong></p>
<p>I’ve always loved the fantasy genre, but the majority of the books have a main male character at their core. I wanted my story to revolve around my heroine, but also to show the strength she gets from those beside her. Not just in the sense of romance, though there are romances in my books, but also from family and allies, some of whom she never expected to find rallying to her cause. I also wanted to give young women the sense that if they believe in themselves, they have already won the most important battle.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have a specific writing style?</strong></p>
<p>I try to give the reader a chance to see things through the eyes of different characters. I hate to compare myself to another author since each of us has a distinct voice. I am particularly proud of the images I am able to create with my words. I like the sense of painting a picture that the reader can see.</p>
<p><strong>How did you come up with the title of this book?</strong></p>
<p>For each book, it was what the heroine found herself facing. In <em>Dragon’s Gift</em>, Kwyleeana finds herself in possession of a magical pendant given to her by Baelwyn, a dragon. This gift opens her to an entirely new world around her. In <em>Magic’s Price</em>, she has to come to terms with what the magic she is using costs her. She also must decide if she is willing to pay that price. In <em>War’s Toll</em>, the war has arrived, and all the characters, our heroine included, will be forced to face the devastation and loss that wars bring.</p>
<p><strong>Is there a message in your novel that you want readers to grasp?</strong></p>
<p>Empowerment. I have always felt if you believe in yourself, you are well on your way to success. The worst thing we do is defeat ourselves before we’ve begun. Also, I’m a strong believer in the concept of relying on the strength of those around you…none of us is in this world alone, and the greatest burdens become lighter if we have loyal friends beside us willing to share the load.</p>
<p><strong>Are experiences in this book based on someone you know, or events in your own life?</strong></p>
<p>As this is a fantasy novel, not really. However, I spent many years as a member of the <a href="http://www.sca.org/">Society for Creative Anachronism (SCA)</a>, and several of my characters in this world are amalgams of people I knew from those years. It also helped me add a real authenticity to my dialogue and details of a medieval-esque fantasy world.</p>
<p><strong>What authors have most influenced your life? What about them do you find inspiring?</strong></p>
<p>As an English lit major, I found a lot to inspire me. The strength of Isabel Allende’s women, the rich details of Marion Zimmer Bradley’s Arthurian tales, the fun and excitement of David Eddings, and the way I can lose myself in the worlds of Terry Brooks. I also find hope in the tales of Brooks and J.K. Rowling, who were in other careers and did not find success as authors until later.</p>
<p><strong>If you had to choose, is there a writer you would consider a mentor? Why?</strong></p>
<p>Terry Brooks. The way he incorporated what he knew into his books, and then cast aside his career as a successful lawyer to follow his dream of being a fantasy adventure author.</p>
<p><strong>Who designed the painterly cover of your book? Why did you select this illustrator?</strong></p>
<p>Kimberly Daniel designed all three book covers. The first one she did for me as a friend, because all the covers I was being sent by my first publisher were awful, and didn’t fit my writing style at all. I then contracted her to design the other two to keep my styles consistent. I also knew she would give me what I needed for a design, and would do it on time and professionally.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any advice for other writers?</strong></p>
<p>Don’t try to be anyone else. Be true to your own voice. The biggest mistake you can make is to write for what pleases other people. If you write to please yourself, that’s when you will create brilliance. And like my heroine, Princess Kwyleeana, believe in yourself, for then you have the strength to win all battles.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8090 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/Dragons-Gift-Book-Cover-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /><strong>Do you have anything specific that you want to say to your readers?</strong></p>
<p>All authors need readers to support them. If you like my book, please give me positive reviews on Amazon, Barnes and Noble, and other websites. Ask your local bookstore to stock my books. Recommend my books to friends (or better yet, buy them copies as gifts). And never be afraid to contact me. I’d love to hear from you.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.lulu.com/spotlight/GildedSerpents" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Elizabeth Gaines Johnston</a><br />
Los Angeles, CA</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/The-Gilded-Serpents-Trilogy-183250061693608/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FACEBOOK</a></p>
<p><strong>The Gilded Serpents Trilogy</strong></p>
<p>Cover Artist: <a href="http://www.artbyksd.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kimberly Daniel</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss?url=search-alias%3Daps&amp;field-keywords=elizabeth+gaines+johnston" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AMAZON</a><br />
<a href="http://www.barnesandnoble.com/s/gilded+serpents?_requestid=600981" target="_blank" rel="noopener">BARNES &amp; NOBLE</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
