<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ill Lit &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/ill-lit/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 21:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Illness, Infantilization, and Where Fan Creators Get It Wrong</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/illness-infantilization-and-where-fan-creators-get-it-wrong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Lien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ill Lit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While earning my MFA, and in my 10+ years in fandom spaces as a fanfiction&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_26446" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26446" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26446" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/thought-catalog-mmWqrsjZ4Lw-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/thought-catalog-mmWqrsjZ4Lw-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/thought-catalog-mmWqrsjZ4Lw-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/thought-catalog-mmWqrsjZ4Lw-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/thought-catalog-mmWqrsjZ4Lw-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/thought-catalog-mmWqrsjZ4Lw-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26446" class="wp-caption-text">Thought Catalog / Unsplash</figcaption></figure>
<p>While earning my MFA, and in my 10+ years in fandom spaces as a fanfiction writer, I&#8217;ve seen many writers and creators infantilize chronically ill characters – typically women. It’s a trend that has long bothered me, but that has been difficult to articulate in a way that doesn’t warrant some kind of example. But, luckily for me (and maybe for you), this column is all about spec fic <em>and </em>chronic illness, and so referencing fiction isn’t just expected but encouraged. Hooray for me!</p>
<p>So, in an effort to talk about infantilization, characterization, and where I see storytellers going wrong, I’m choosing to reference a character I know well: Dulcinea Septimus from Tamsyn Muir’s <em>Harrow the Ninth. </em>I did touch on her character a bit <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-if-and-what-next-speculative-fiction-and-the-erasure-of-chronic-illness/">in last month’s column</a> if you’d like to get the backstory.</p>
<p>A brief disclaimer: As you read this breakdown, please do keep in mind that these are just my opinions about Dulcinea’s characterization and that your mileage and read of her may vary – and that’s okay!. It is my responsibility to share my thoughts and perspective in a respectful way, and that is my intention here.</p>
<h2>The Infantilization of Passion</h2>
<p>Dulcinea is intelligent, charming, and personable. She takes open and visible delight in the lives of the people around her, makes a lot of clever jokes, and openly displays affection toward those she loves. She does all of this while managing symptoms probably too familiar to chronically ill people: fatigue, a consistent and annoying cough, and the ever-present need of people around her to baby her when she is fully capable of taking care of herself.</p>
<p>I’ve seen there are some people who feel that Dulcinea’s effusive, passionate personality is unnecessarily childlike – and that’s a conversation for another day. I can’t help but wonder if Muir was making a point with this element of Dulcinea’s character as well; there’s something about female characters and their passions that are typically labeled as “childish” in popular culture, but in a stark departure from how that behavior is typically displayed, that’s how Dulcinea asserts her agency. She is loud and assertive about these elements of her personality because, without that, she would only ever be seen as an ill and dying woman.</p>
<figure id="attachment_26171" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26171" style="width: 192px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26171" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-2.01.47-PM-192x300.png" alt="" width="192" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-2.01.47-PM-192x300.png 192w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-2.01.47-PM.png 594w" sizes="(max-width: 192px) 100vw, 192px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26171" class="wp-caption-text">Harrow the Ninth / Tor.com</figcaption></figure>
<p>This, as I’m sure you can tell, is a great example of solid characterization – Dulcinea is characterized by how she interfaces with her world, and it is made clear to us in the text that is how she prefers to be known, and that the fact that she is known for her illness is thanks to those around her and despite her own objections. This is the first reason why I’m holding her character up as an example of the difference between infantilization and characterization; the second rests within the way fandom engages with her…and what that signals to me about some larger issues.</p>
<h2>Fandom and Illness</h2>
<p>Ironically, fans of Muir’s books often do to Dulcinea the very thing she would hate ­– in fanworks, they reduce her to her physical limitations as a reason for why she “can’t” or “wouldn’t” do anything from engaging with her loved ones to getting a bit spicy in the bedroom. While I’m sure some of this stems from the all-too-familiar ableist mindsets that many people carry with them when it comes to disabled and chronically ill folks, when it comes to fan writers approaching her character, there’s something else that troubles me.</p>
<p>In the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-chronic-illness-rep-in-spec-fic-from-my-own-experience/">first column I wrote for LSQ</a>, I touched on how I was told at a young age that my desire to see chronic illness represented in speculative fiction was “unrealistic” because scientific developments would make such afflictions obsolete. Obviously, that assessment is reductive and incorrect, but it does hint at what I’m trying to get at here: I believe many fan writers use Dulcinea’s illness – and really, I think this could apply to any chronically ill or disabled character – as an excuse or a reason to not explore her character any further.</p>
<p>Throughout my time in fandom, I’ve seen this happen many times; fanfiction writers tend to go to one extreme or another, either failing to acknowledge that a chronically ill or disabled character is chronically ill or disabled or acknowledging it to the extent that it gives them an “excuse” to sideline a character from their narratives entirely. And while there could be an argument for how it’s the author’s right to choose which characters they want in their stories, I ask this: Why include a chronically ill character like Dulcinea at all if you don’t intend to give her the due you give her able-bodied counterparts?</p>
<h2>Inclusion or Infantilization?</h2>
<p>Is a chronically ill character providing representation through their characterization, or are they being reduced to <em>only </em>that illness? And is their personality taking center stage because they are a whole, complete person – same as their able-bodied counterparts – or is their illness being used as a smokescreen that renders the character two-dimensional?</p>
<p>This is a multifaceted conversation, for sure, and one that can hardly begin and end with a single column. My aim, ultimately, is to encourage anyone reading this who engages with fanworks or original content that includes chronically ill characters to think critically about how you are engaging with said representation – and how you choose to work it into your own lexicon as you tell the stories that matter to you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What If and What Next? Speculative Fiction and the Erasure of Chronic Illness</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-if-and-what-next-speculative-fiction-and-the-erasure-of-chronic-illness/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-if-and-what-next-speculative-fiction-and-the-erasure-of-chronic-illness/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Lien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 10:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ill Lit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There’s a quote hanging above my desk by author Tom Clancy: “Two questions form the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There’s a quote hanging above my desk by author Tom Clancy: “Two questions form the foundation of all novels: ‘What if?’ and ‘What next?’.” While Clancy isn’t a speculative fiction writer, per se, I always felt that quote was particularly relevant to my particular brand of speculative fiction writing and reading.</p>
<p>It is also that question that I asked myself this week while working on my master’s thesis, which explores speculative fiction, chronic illness, and where the two intersect – or rather, where they historically don’t. As a part of writing this thesis, I was asked to examine my own relationship to this topic, and a few titles came to mind immediately. The more I thought about it, the more I realized that there had been many books I’d read throughout my childhood and adolescence that would have been – at least to me – so much more interesting if the characters in whom I found a slice of representation had been approached differently.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong, I’m not in the business of nitpicking other writers’ work on the basis of my own preferences. That’s just not cool. But I do want to offer up an alternate perspective because, historically, this particular perspective has been lacking.</p>
<p>So, if you’ll indulge me, what if…</p>
<h3>…FEED’s Violet wasn’t reduced to her demise?</h3>
<p>M.T. Anderson’s <em>Feed</em> is an early-2000s imagining of a far-off future where human beings exist within cyberspace. A huge computer network called the “feednet” is directly connected to the brains of almost three-quarters of American citizens by means of an implant device called a “feed.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_26172" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26172" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-26172 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/feed-300x300.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/feed-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/feed-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/feed.jpeg 450w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26172" class="wp-caption-text">FEED / Penguin Random House</figcaption></figure>
<p>This was a fascinating concept for yours truly, who watched elderly relatives get pacemakers and benefit from other medical technology. But while this tech helped my relatives, the tech in Violet’s world was killing her slowly. The narrative centers around Violet’s slow death at the hands of the technology that kept her from accessing help for her health issues, and on her loved ones’ struggles to understand that.</p>
<p>I wondered this both in my youth and now: Isn&#8217;t there a better, less reductive story centered around Violet’s struggle to fit into a world that has, by virtue of technological advancements, shut her out and barred her from accessing what she needs to survive? That is a struggle to which I relate more than the experience of dying, but alas, Violet’s story centers around the pain her loved ones feel at her loss, reducing her suffering to something that’s more of a plot point than anything else.</p>
<p>Speaking of reducing a character’s terminal illness, what if…</p>
<h3>…HARROW THE NINTH’s Dulcinea Septimus wasn’t infantilized by the fandom?</h3>
<p><em>Harrow the Ninth’s </em>Dulcinea is a necromancer who spent most of her life critically ill and knowing that her society glorifies her eminent demise as a thing of beauty. Despite the fact that her people expect her to die the “perfect death,” she is not known for her impending</p>
<figure id="attachment_26171" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-26171" style="width: 192px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26171" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-2.01.47-PM-192x300.png" alt="" width="192" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-2.01.47-PM-192x300.png 192w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/Screen-Shot-2021-10-25-at-2.01.47-PM.png 594w" sizes="(max-width: 192px) 100vw, 192px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-26171" class="wp-caption-text">Harrow the Ninth / Tor.com</figcaption></figure>
<p>demise among those who know her personally – she is remembered for her clever sense of humor, and a charming and personable demeanor.</p>
<p>It’s those personality traits that many people in the fandom choose to infantilize. While canonically she uses a wheelchair and a cane to get around, she exerts her own agency in a way that fanon tends to forget. Dulcinea’s strength comes from her desire to live on her own terms because she understands she won’t get to have her death to herself – and, because she won’t be alive to control the aftermath, she has accepted it.</p>
<p>Once again, Dulcinea’s approach to the limits her physical health imposes on her is reduced. Fandoms often play an active role in readers’ participation with the text, and while everyone is certainly welcome to interpret works in their own way, it grates against me that the fandom seems to have equated a combination of kindness, vivacity, and physical illness with license to infantilize a character in fanworks.</p>
<p>Which leads me to my last “what if…”</p>
<h3>…authors chose to change their point of view?</h3>
<p>Fiction impacts reality in many ways: perception, investigation, policy, the list goes on. Our world is shaped by the media we engage with, and storytellers are charged with reflecting the diversity of the world in which we live.</p>
<p>To return to the Clancy quote for a moment: We’ve talked about the “what if” plenty, and I’d like to leave you with the “what next.” From the #OwnVoices hashtag to this very column, it’s pretty obvious that chronically ill people want to see their stories represented in speculative fiction and have the ability to tell those stories accurately and fairly.</p>
<p>If speculative fiction is built upon the desire to imagine new, different worlds from our own, it’s time to examine what’s next in terms of representation and inclusion, especially when it comes to the worlds we imagine. If our what ifs and what&#8217;s nexts have nothing to do with chronically ill people, what does that say about who we as human beings plan on becoming?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-if-and-what-next-speculative-fiction-and-the-erasure-of-chronic-illness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On chronic illness rep in spec fic, from my own experience</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-chronic-illness-rep-in-spec-fic-from-my-own-experience/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Amanda Lien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 10:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ill Lit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I was a teenager, someone informed me that I was unjustified in wanting chronic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was a teenager, someone informed me that I was unjustified in wanting chronic illness representation in science fiction. I was told that my desire to see my experiences reflected in my favorite genre was unrealistic because &#8220;science would have advanced enough where chronic illness wouldn&#8217;t exist anymore.”</p>
<p>Which, holy eugenics, Batman! But I digress.</p>
<p>Thanks to them, I’m writing this column, because I’m very stubborn and enjoy proving people wrong – but, more importantly, I feel responsible for standing up for the younger version of me who searched and yearned for chronic illness in speculative fiction and couldn’t find it.</p>
<p>You know the saying: “if you want something done right, you have to do it yourself”? I&#8217;m doing it myself.</p>
<h2>My self-indulgent backstory</h2>
<p>As this is my first column entry for LSQ, I figured I’d offer something by way of introduction. I’m Amanda, I’m reasonably old and also reasonably young (depending on who you ask), and I’m a chronic illness lifer. I was born like this and there’s no sign of my afflictions going anywhere; something I cope with through tongue-in-cheek humor, sarcasm, and some strong language.</p>
<figure id="attachment_25886" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25886" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25886" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IMG_1295-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IMG_1295-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IMG_1295-1024x1024.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IMG_1295-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IMG_1295-768x769.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IMG_1295-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/IMG_1295.png 1279w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25886" class="wp-caption-text">The author, age 16. Clearly not much has changed.</figcaption></figure>
<p>(As a small aside, I know some writers lump chronic illness and disability into the same category. I see those two identities as resting within a Venn diagram – not everyone who is disabled may be chronically ill, and not everyone who is chronically ill is disabled. I’m not one to police how someone chooses to identify, but for the purposes of my column, I prefer to say I am chronically ill, but do not feel I’m disabled.)</p>
<p>When I was a kid, I loved reading. Clearly, that hasn’t left me, but when I was a kid, it was bonkers – I was reading 1-2 chapter books a day when I was in elementary and middle school, and only really slowed down in high school when I started working at Starbucks part-time.</p>
<p>But, while I did try my best to find them, I could never get my hands on fiction that represented my lived experience in a body that is constantly trying to take me out (and succeeds maybe 40% of the time). And when I expressed this desire to others, I was met with indifference, commentaries like the one I brought up at the start of this column, or the proffering of new bestselling books like John Green’s <em>The Fault in Our Stars</em>, which wasn’t what I wanted on multiple levels. (Yes, I was 16 in 2014. I’m a baby.)</p>
<p>Two college degrees, some scholarship, and a manuscript in the query trenches later, I’ve started trying to solve the problem I first identified as a young teen. There isn’t much by way of academic writing about chronic illness in speculative fiction, so I produced some while earning my MFA. I couldn’t find many characters whose chronic illness is present, but not a plot point, so I wrote the story myself.</p>
<h2>The stories that matter</h2>
<p>For a long time, I thought I was the only person who cared about wanting chronic illness representation in my media. I figured there must be valid reasons for why I rarely saw characters with afflictions like mine: maybe it was too hard to depict in writing? Maybe being sick was too ugly for the media to want to betray?</p>
<figure id="attachment_25887" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25887" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25887" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/yannick-pulver-hopX_jpVtRM-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="A notebook flips closed in the foreground as a cup of coffee sits in the sunlight in the background." width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/yannick-pulver-hopX_jpVtRM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/yannick-pulver-hopX_jpVtRM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/yannick-pulver-hopX_jpVtRM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/yannick-pulver-hopX_jpVtRM-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/yannick-pulver-hopX_jpVtRM-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25887" class="wp-caption-text">Yannick Pulver/Unsplash</figcaption></figure>
<p>This was only furthered by the proliferation of narratives that seemed to embrace characters who were ill or dying, so long as they made some kind of beautifully tragic tableau that readers could woobify in fanfiction. (And sure, I may be coming down a bit too hard on those narratives, but when it&#8217;s all I see, it gets a bit old!)</p>
<p>The only thing I will always refuse to believe is that all chronically ill characters and their stories are good for is trauma porn or “hero stories” about how courageous some young person is for living with a chronic illness (which is just condescending, let’s be real). Take it from me – chronic illnesses are just a facet of being a human, no different than anything else. My chronic conditions are things I carry around with me – and sure, they inform my personality and character – but I am whole and human nonetheless, and I want stories that treat me, and everyone like me, that way.</p>
<p>So here I am, spite-writing a column all about chronic illness and queer rep in spec fic and why it matters. Woohoo! I’m not going to sit here and say that I’m the best writer for the job – I’m just one human being trying her best to make the representation she wishes to see in the world – but I’m trying. And I’m glad you’re here and ready to listen to my thoughts on the matter. Because I do belong in speculative fiction. And in every other type of fiction. I intend to do my damndest to prove it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
