<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/uncategorized/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 20:57:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Review: A Starbound Solstice, by Juliet Kemp</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-a-starbound-solstice-by-juliet-kemp/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanna Z. Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 12:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Noteworthy Novellas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28932</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since we’re heading into winter here in the Northern Hemisphere, I decided to check out&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-29016 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/59823183-211x300.jpg" alt="" width="211" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/59823183-211x300.jpg 211w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/59823183.jpg 352w" sizes="(max-width: 211px) 100vw, 211px" />Since we’re heading into winter </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">here in the Northern Hemisphere</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">I decided to check out <a href="https://robotdinosaurpress.com/product/a-starbound-solstice-by-juliet-kemp/"><em>A Starbound Solstice</em></a>, by <a href="https://julietkemp.com/">Juliet Kemp</a>. This queer, cozy holiday story takes place in space, at the mid-point of the journey between Earth and </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">the</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> first </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">planned human/alien shared colony</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">It’s a lovely </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">book</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> about choosing hope and trust over fear.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">The story lingers over the opening, introducing the seven characters – five humans, the ship’s AI (Heron), and their alien liaison (Aliax) – as they plan a solstice celebration, combining the best of all of their respective winter holidays. It’s worth noting that every one of the human characters is queer. Three of them are in a poly relationship, and two use alternate pronouns (as does the alien, Aliax, though that feels less noteworthy). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Their holiday planning is interrupted when Heron begins to malfunction. This is a problem for the obvious reasons, but also because Heron controls their needledrive, the alien technology that will allow them to make this trip in a mere 70 years. Without it, it could take another thousand years to reach their destination. To make matters worse, Aliax – the only alien on the ship, and thus the only who understands how the needledrive works – falls ill shortly after Heron starts to glitch, and so xe can’t do much to help.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Fifty years before the ship left Earth, the Ferolyt – aliens like Aliax – helped humanity step back from the brink of self-destruction, giving humanity hope and a future. When our crew finds the source of Heron’s malfunction, they have to decide if they are going to hold onto that hope, or give in to fear. Will they take a risk in order to live up to their ideals, or will they take the route of self-interest and suspicion? The journey to get there is a bit predictable, but no less delightful for it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">I loved the interactions of the crew. This story </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">feels </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">cozy – even though they’ve only known each </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">for a little over a year, they feel like a family. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">There’s a real twenty-somethings, punk vibe to the group that I found endearing. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">That being said, there are too many characters for such a short book. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">T</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">he plot only needed 3 of the human characters, if that. Fortunately, since most of them </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">seem to be there to add personality, and </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">don’t </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">have much </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">impact the plot, it’s okay if you lose track of them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">And what holiday story would be complete without a romantic subplot? The narrator (Linn) has a huge crush on the ship’s engineer (Taye). The rest of the crew constantly tease xyr about it, and xe spends a lot of time trying to determine whether or not they reciprocate. It’s sweetly done, and I enjoyed seeing two nonbinary people flirting.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Overall, this is a sweet, low-key story. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">It’s enjoyable and wholesome, without demanding much from the reader.</span> <span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">I salute Juliet Kemp. They have </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">written the </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">optimistic,</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> queer holiday story that my </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">frazzled</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> heart needed this season. If you, too, need a break from the chaos, <em>A Starbound Solstice</em> is worth checking out.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SFF Movies &#8216;Based On&#8217; Books I love</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/sff-movies-based-on-books-i-love/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 10:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Movies &#8220;based on&#8221; books. Oh, as a confirmed SFF geek, where do I begin? So&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Movies &#8220;based on&#8221; books. Oh, as a confirmed SFF geek, where do I begin? So many, many bad movies made from good books. Okay, I get it: every movie can’t achieve the utter worshipful perfection of Peter Jackson’s THE LORD OF THE RINGS. But some could definitely try harder is all I’m saying.</p>
<p>Let’s start with the inimitable Andre Norton. In 1959 she published THE BEAST MASTER, book one in the tale of Hosteen Storm, a Navajo who was telepathic with several genetically-modified animals. They all get sent to an alien planet and the usual Norton hijinks ensue. Good, classic Andre Norton, am I right?  <img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28582 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Beast_master-212x300.jpg" alt="" width="170" height="241" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Beast_master-212x300.jpg 212w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Beast_master.jpg 269w" sizes="(max-width: 170px) 100vw, 170px" /></p>
<p>Then why, pray tell me, oh why did the screenwriters for the 1982 THE BEASTMASTER even suggest that they &#8220;based&#8221; their story on Norton’s book? I mean, what the who? Now suddenly we have the barbarian Dar—brilliantly portrayed by Marc Singer’s pecs—who as a fetus gets magically transferred from his mama’s womb into a cow—dazzling special FX here as the cow’s belly swells—and grows up into the aforementioned bundle of pecs. Then there’s a &#8220;story&#8221; about how he meets and bonds with a big cat, a hawk, and a pair of ferrets—the ferrets being clearly the best actors in the entire movie, as I still remember their names: Kodo and Podo. There’s a big bad guy—Rip Torn in his best scenery-chewing mode—a noble black guy and a fur bikini filled with Tanya Roberts. Don’t get me wrong, I loved the movie, but it was obviously made by someone who had: 1. Never read Norton’s book, and 2. Only knew in the very vaguest fashion what constituted a good fantasy movie. Hint: it’s not pecs and a fur bikini.  <img decoding="async" class="wp-image-28584 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/TheBeastmaster-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="149" height="227" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/TheBeastmaster-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/TheBeastmaster.jpg 256w" sizes="(max-width: 149px) 100vw, 149px" /></p>
<p>However, any and all movies would be improved by the addition of a pair of ferrets—fact. TITANIC, for instance, badly needed ferrets.</p>
<p>Oh, yeah, and Andre Norton insisted her name be removed from the credits. Surprising, huh?</p>
<p>Next in this litany of infamy is the pair of movies based on John W. Campbell-writing-as-Don-A.-Stuart’s novella, &#8220;Who Goes There?&#8221; First was 1951’s THE THING FROM ANOTHER WORLD, starring pre-Gunsmoke James Arness as a vegetable alien—no, he’s not a confirmed plant eater, he’s an actual plant. The novella and the movie share a location—a claustrophobic base in the Antarctic—and a basic premise—alien ship frozen in ice inadvertently destroyed but inhabitant saved—but skips over most of the shapeshifting bit. Still, it does have a lovely sense of fear and danger and I adored it as a kid, as I uncritically adored anything faintly SFF.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28585 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who_Goes_There__John_Campbell_book_1st_edition_cover_art-205x300.jpg" alt="" width="185" height="271" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who_Goes_There__John_Campbell_book_1st_edition_cover_art-205x300.jpg 205w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Who_Goes_There__John_Campbell_book_1st_edition_cover_art.jpg 263w" sizes="(max-width: 185px) 100vw, 185px" /></p>
<p>In 1982, John Carpenter directed THE THING, with a bearded Kurt Russell and a team of actors familiar from TV. This one was much, much closer to the original novella and, even though I was no longer in grammar school, I loved it. This time, as in the story, the alien can replicate others, leading to a growing sense of paranoia. Who’d human, and who’s not?</p>
<p>Great Carpenter-esque scenes of decapitated heads sprouting legs to run away from flamethrowers—honestly, does it get any better than that? And my favorite scene of all: a doctor is doing CPR and it goes terribly, terribly wrong, not only for the patient…but for the doctor. Watch it and see.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-28587 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/The_Thing_1982_theatrical_poster-195x300.jpg" alt="" width="171" height="263" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/The_Thing_1982_theatrical_poster-195x300.jpg 195w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/The_Thing_1982_theatrical_poster.jpg 220w" sizes="(max-width: 171px) 100vw, 171px" /></p>
<p>Oh, and there’s a suitably depressing ending that leaves the viewer up in the air about who is still infected and who survives. Or doesn’t.</p>
<p>And finally, THE PUPPET MASTERS. Heinlein’s 1951 book is one of my favorites of his, full of thinly-disguised Commie obsession of that time period, but with some seriously kick-ass characters. And the movie wasn’t bad, don’t get me wrong. I mean, all Donald Sutherland needs to do is stand there and I’m agog. Hey, I even drop what I’m doing to listen—with varying amounts of drool—to that lovely, lovely voice pitch orange juice.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28583 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Thepuppetmastersposter-202x300.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Thepuppetmastersposter-202x300.jpg 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Thepuppetmastersposter.jpg 259w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" /></p>
<p>And Sutherland is not miscast as the head of a secret organization who’s the only one to realize Earth is being invaded and Earthlings being controlled by soul-sucking aliens that look like slugs with rather fetching whip-tails. In the book, though, one of his operators is his son, Sam, and another is a brilliant badass red-haired woman named Mary—who has an interesting backstory that plays into the denouement.</p>
<p>In the movie, Sam and Mary are played by, well, actors that don’t fit my image of the roles is all I’m going to say. Story doesn&#8217;t suck too much either.</p>
<p>Heinlein’s books deserve good movies. The closest I’ve seen is PREDESTINATION, based on his &#8220;All You Zombies.&#8221; It gets the twisty-turny-wibbly-wobbly time travel bits down. Go watch it if you haven’t seen it.</p>
<p>And watch the others too. After all, they are SFF…after a fashion.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Triffids and Krakens and Chrysalids and Cuckoos, Oh My!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/triffids-and-krakens-and-chrysalids-and-cuckoos-oh-my/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K.G. McAbee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 14:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Grey Lenswoman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[John Wyndham Parkes Lucas Beynon Harris was an English science fiction writer who died in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://John/ Wyndham - Wikipedia">John Wyndham Parkes Lucas Beynon Harris</a> was an English science fiction writer who died in 1969. He started off writing for the pulps in the 1930s under a slew of pen names, mostly derived from his impressive and what must have been extremely useful selection of given names: John Beynon Lucas Parkes. He wrote as John B. Harris and Johnson B. Harris before finally publishing novels as John Wyndham.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-28345 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/John_Wyndham_Parkes_Lucas_Beynon_Harris.jpg" alt="" width="264" height="300" /></p>
<p>‘Cozy catastrophe’ was what Brian Aldiss termed a bunch of Wyndham’s books, meaning less Big Picture <em>boom boom Independence Day</em> <em>alien attacks end of the world aaah!</em> and more experiencing a catastrophe on an individual level and the long process of dealing with the aftereffects.</p>
<p>My first introduction to Wyndham’s work was in middle school with THE DAY OF THE TRIFFIDS, about ambulatory poison plants. Think big honkin’ Venus flytraps with an attitude: they have poison-tipped whip-like appendages and three thick roots they can scoot around on. Slow? You betcha. But if you’re trapped and can’t get away? Face it: you’re plant food.</p>
<p>Of course, when the triffids first appear, crafty corporations find out they’re useful sources of animal feed…so naturally, they start farming them, because fields and fields of six-foot tall poisonous walking plants is always a good idea. Sure, they start off removing the poison sacs…until they find out the quality of the feed declines, so they simply teach their factory farms how to ‘be careful.’ Because that always works for corporations. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28346 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/JohnWyndham_TheDayOfTheTriffids-202x300.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/JohnWyndham_TheDayOfTheTriffids-202x300.jpg 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/JohnWyndham_TheDayOfTheTriffids.jpg 259w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" /></p>
<p>But were acres of walking poison plants the catastrophe? Nah. The disaster really kicks in when the Earth enters a ‘meteor field’ that exposes everyone who’s watching to pretty green lights in the night sky. Ooh! Ahhh! Pretty lights!</p>
<p>Oops.</p>
<p>The next morning, everyone who watched the spectacle wakes up blind. The triffids escape. Cue the catastrophe.</p>
<p>THE KRAKEN WAKES is an alien invasion on a muted, very English scale. Balls of light are seen falling into the sea. A short time later, sea levels begin to rise, and heavy little armored tanks trundle onto beaches. It seems the lights were ships containing creatures that can only live under very high pressure, hence their descent into the deep sea. They’re invading to turn good old Terra into something more suitable for their needs. The protagonist is a reporter struggling to survive in a slowly flooding London.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28347 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Thekrakenwakes-202x300.jpg" alt="" width="202" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Thekrakenwakes-202x300.jpg 202w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Thekrakenwakes.jpg 261w" sizes="(max-width: 202px) 100vw, 202px" /></p>
<p>THE CRYSALIDS is less about a catastrophe and more about its aftermath. Centuries after a nuclear holocaust, society has reverted to a medieval level, and anything mutated is considered evil-with-a-capital-E and either killed or banished—even a little girl with six toes on one foot. Pragmatically, huge horses are A-okay, as they’re useful around the farms.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28344 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Chrysalids_first_edition_1955-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Chrysalids_first_edition_1955-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Chrysalids_first_edition_1955.jpg 238w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></p>
<p>A group of children, however, have developed a mutation that isn’t visible—they’re telepaths. Cue the burning torches.</p>
<p>One of Wyndham’s most impactful books is THE MIDWICH CUCKOOS, turned to the movie(s) CHILDREN OF THE DAMNED and VILLAGE OF THE DAMNED…with varying degrees of success. Another alien invasion, but with a clever twist on the aliens’ part.</p>
<p>One day, an invisible dome settles over the small English village of Midwich. The people inside are all sprawled out as if dead, and anyone who steps inside the perimeter of the dome collapses. Twenty-four hours later, the dome dissipates and everyone who looked dead wakes up. Whew! They were just asleep all along.</p>
<p>Then every woman of childbearing age who’d been inside the dome find out she’s pregnant, regardless of her marital status…or even her virginity. Nine months later, they all give birth to eerily similar blonde kids with glowing eyes.</p>
<p>Awww, cute helpless children, right? Uh, not so much. The kids grow up fast, always travel together in a pack, show no emotions, and are able to protect themselves by mind-controlling anyone who messes with them. One guy who’d insulted them runs his car ‘accidentally’ into a tree.<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28348 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheMidwichCuckoos-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="197" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheMidwichCuckoos-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/TheMidwichCuckoos.jpg 258w" sizes="(max-width: 197px) 100vw, 197px" /></p>
<p>Oh, and apparently they can read humans’ minds. And Midwich wasn’t the only town this happened to: a native village in in the far north had stoned the mothers and their offspring as soon as they were born. And reports from Russia—the book takes place in the 1960s during the height of the Cold War—tell of a town nuked to nonexistence.</p>
<p>Neither of these would be typical English reactions to this little problem. But Wyndham’s protagonist manages to confront the issue.</p>
<p>Wyndham wrote other books, most of which I recommend mostly because I love his low-key, intimate and usually first person POV style. I think you might enjoy ‘em too. You can grab a bunch of his public domain work&#8211;Canadian public domain&#8211;at <a href="https://www.fadedpage.com/csearch.php?author=Wyndham%2C%20John">Faded Pages</a>.</p>
<p><strong>  </strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: Uncommon Charm, by Emily Bergslien and Kat Weaver</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-uncommon-charm-by-emily-bergslien-and-kat-weaver/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanna Z. Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 10:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Noteworthy Novellas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Uncommon Charm, by Emily Bergslien and Kat Weaver, lives up to its name. The frothy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"><a href="https://www.neonhemlock.com/books/uncommon-charm"><em><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-28400 size-medium" src="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/charm-188x300.webp" alt="" width="188" height="300" srcset="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/charm-188x300.webp 188w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/charm.webp 640w" sizes="(max-width: 188px) 100vw, 188px" />Uncommon Charm</em></a>, by Emily Bergslien and <a href="https://kathrynmweaver.com/">Kat Weaver</a>, lives up to its name. The frothy period piece, set in a magic-wielding alternate 1920’s London, charmed this reviewer, though it’s a hard story to classify. It’s part alternate history, part comedy of manners, part magical treatise, and part family mystery, all tied together by chatty, vivacious narration.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">The story is told by Julia, the charming and frivolous 16 year old daughter of Lady Aloysia Stirling, one of the most notorious wizards in 1920’s London. Julia has just been expelled from the Marable School for Girls when Simon Wolf arrives, to study magical with Lady Aloysia. Simon is serious, anxious, and also the illegitimate son of a close family friend, Prince Vladimir. The two become fast friends.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Julia and Simon stumble upon a </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">painful </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">secret </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">from</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> her mother’</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">s past</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">, and have to sort through what it all means. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">T</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">he main thrust is not about solving </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">the</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> mystery, so much as understanding it, and integrating </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">the way in which</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> this new knowledge affects their understanding of the people involved. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">This leads to some exceedingly heavy revelations, though, so be prepared.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Julia’s relationships form the backbone of this book. Her growing friendship with Simon starts the story, and also serves as the catalyst for the plot. Their differing personalities – he quiet, shy, and serious, and she talkative, frivolous, and clever – complement each other, and each brings out the best </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">in the other</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Over the course of the story, both Julia and Simon come into themselves. Simon </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">learns</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> to trust his magic, and grow</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">s</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> in confidence, while Julia comes to better understand </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">her mother,</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> the upper-class society she lives in, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">and who she truly wishes to be.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">In contrast, Julia and her mother get on each other’s nerves. Lady Aloysia is neurotic, reclusive, and eccentric as only the wealthy can be (she also read as potentially neuroatypical to me, though I don’t know </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">w</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">hat the authors intended). She </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">is outwardly patient with her flighty daughter, but Julia smarts from the disapproval she senses under the surface. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">M</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">agic </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">forms much of the backdrop of this story. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">There is no </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">firm</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> system, and in fact, most of the conversation between Lady Aloysia and Simon revolve around the fact that magic is undefinable, nearly ineffable. She is constantly prodding her pupil to examine his own experiences, to figure out what is true for him, and then to act on it. It’s a refreshing change from novels that rely on strict formulas for magic, with clearly defined cause and effect, energy and cost, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">and contributes to the intellectual tone.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">A quick shout-out to the deft portrayal of Judaism. Simon is a young man of great faith, and his Jewishness subtly influences everything he does, without ever becoming his entire character. In particular, the way that his faith influences and defines his use of magic is fascinating.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">My only criticism of this book is that it can be </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">so</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> subtle as to cross the line into vagueness. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">I struggled to keep</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> track of what </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">wa</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">s happening, and of what Julia and Simon ha</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">d</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> discovered, because nobody ever talk</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">ed</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> about it directly. This is probably true to </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">life</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">, but it ma</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">de</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> the story hard to follow at times. I couldn’t fully piece it together until I read it the second time. For</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">t</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">unately, Julia’s narration and the charming cast of characters made that a pleasure, rather than a chore.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">All in all, <em>Uncommon Charm </em></span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">delivers a refreshing story with a solid core. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Though the </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">novella</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> does explore some dark past events, I still found this to be a delightful palette cleanser between heavier books. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">This is a strong choice for anybody who enjoys a blending of roaring 20’s high society and magic.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monopsony and the Publishing Industry</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/monopsony-and-the-publishing-industry/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[K C Maguire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 11:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[On the Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a break from my usual focus on contracts and intellectual property law, I’ve decided&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28402 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-768x1151.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-1025x1536.jpg 1025w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-1367x2048.jpg 1367w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/clay-banks-GX8KBbVmC6c-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1709w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />In a break from my usual focus on contracts and intellectual property law, I’ve decided to delve into a little antitrust law for this month’s column. Many authors have been watching with interest the Department of Justice’s (DOJ) attempt to prevent Penguin Random House (PRH) from acquiring Simon &amp; Schuster (S&amp;S) on antitrust grounds. Some helpful background to the case can be found <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/publisher-news/article/87783-doj-sues-to-block-prh-acquisition-of-s-s.html">here</a> and <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/publisher-news/article/89932-doj-vs-prh-and-s-s-book-biz-legal-showdown-of-the-century.html">here</a> as reported in Publishers Weekly.</p>
<p>For those who don’t know, and in extremely over-simplified terms, antitrust law is largely aimed at preventing a corporate entity or group of entities from exerting too much control in a market in a way that may create economic harm. The focus of the harm is usually on consumers—in terms of the aggregation of control of an industry leading to artificially increased prices because of lack of competition in the market.</p>
<p>Claims of monopoly in the publishing industry are not new, and have intensified both as a result of the entry of large digital players (like Amazon and Apple) on the sales and distribution side of publishing around 2010 and as a result of increasing consolidation of the major publishers. If the acquisition goes through, the “Big 5” publishers will become the “Big 4” and it’s not all that long ago that we were talking about a “Big 6” (i.e. before Penguin merged with Random House). Recently HarperCollins also acquired Houghton Mifflin Harcourt which, while not one of the largest houses, certainly boasted significant lists of its own. The HMH logo and corporate identity have been fully retired since the merger.</p>
<p>Obviously monopolies in publishing have the potential to harm the market for books and associated products and services. However, as a bit of a law geek, what is interesting to me (and to many watching the current litigation) is that the case between the DOJ and PRH/S&amp;S is not predominantly framed in monopoly terms, emphasizing costs to the ultimate consumers of books.</p>
<p>Instead, the more significant legal claim seems to be a <strong>monopsony </strong>argument. Unlike a monopoly, a monopsony refers to a situation where there is only one or a limited number of <strong>buyers</strong> in a market, as opposed to sellers. Publishers both buy literary works from authors and sell them to consumers and this case seems to focus on the former part of the equation in large measure. The DOJ is arguing that with increasing consolidation of publishers as <strong>buyers</strong>, less competitive deals will be made to authors who will have less choice in terms of bargains for the sale/licensing of their work. It’s an interesting twist on the usual legal narrative about aggregation of power in publishing. Of course there are also concerns about the consolidation of selling power of what would be the ”Big 4” post-merger, but it is interesting to watch the situation of authors being brought to the fore in this case.</p>
<p>The links to PW coverage (above) go into more detail about the nature of the arguments and how a monopsony differs from a monopoly in terms of market concerns so I won’t go into more detail here, particularly as I’m not an antitrust expert. But it is interesting to see the DOJ put its emphasis on the position of authors at a time when there are increasing concerns about whose voices are represented in the publishing industry, the ability of mid-list creatives to make a living from their work and the cost structures within publishing houses themselves.</p>
<p>When economies of scale are created through acquisitions and mergers, it has been far from<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28404 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-768x509.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-1536x1017.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/debby-hudson-asviIGR3CPE-unsplash-2048x1356.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> clear that those benefits are passed on to the authors who create the works that fuel the business. It’s also not clear the benefits are passed on to workers at the organizations in question. A significant number of editors and other staff members<a href="https://www.themarysue.com/march-2022-leaving-publishing-exodus/"> have been leaving the larger publishers</a> due to concerns over unsustainable conditions in terms of salaries, workloads and living expenses (particularly for those expected to work in expensive locations like NYC). In fact, the unionized HarperCollins staff organized <a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/publisher-news/article/89825-hc-union-sets-july-20-strike-date.html">a strike on July 20</a> to protest their working conditions.</p>
<p>The case is set to be argued in August and the results will be fascinating to follow.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scares of All Shapes and Sizes: Categorizing Fear</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/scares-of-all-shapes-and-sizes-categorizing-fear/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/scares-of-all-shapes-and-sizes-categorizing-fear/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Eve Taft]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 10:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Quaint and Curious Volumes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27345#038;preview=true&#038;preview_id=27345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stephen King classifies scares in three categories: Terror, Horror, and Gross-Out. “The 3 types of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stephen King classifies scares in three categories: Terror, Horror, and Gross-Out.</p>
<p>“The 3 types of terror: The Gross-out: the sight of a severed head tumbling down a flight of stairs, it&#8217;s when the lights go out and something green and slimy splatters against your arm. The Horror: the unnatural, spiders the size of bears, the dead waking up and walking around, it&#8217;s when the lights go out and something with claws grabs you by the arm. And the last and worse one: Terror, when you come home and notice everything you own had been taken away and replaced by an exact substitute. It&#8217;s when the lights go out and you feel something behind you, you hear it, you feel its breath against your ear, but when you turn around, there&#8217;s nothing there&#8230;”</p>
<p>Far be it from me to argue with the master of horror. However, I want to subdivide these three categories a little further.</p>
<p>The reason I started thinking about this was because I watched <em>Apartment 1 Br</em>, and even though it’s a good movie, I really didn’t enjoy it. I ended up watching <em>Howl’s Moving Castle </em>to calm down.</p>
<p>But Eve, you like being scared! That’s your whole thing! *insert montage of me riding rollercoasters alone because my friends have reached their limit, watching horror movies in the dark, and generally spooking myself silly*</p>
<p>Thinking about this seemingly contradictory idea: that I can love being scared sometimes and not others, led me to the idea that “fear” is a catch-all term that can be defined even further. So…</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Types of Terror </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Cosmic Horror</p>
<p>“The universe and the laws thereof are absolutely not what I thought they were.” This is the heart of cosmic horror, and of course I’ve got to nod to Lovecraft for solidifying this genre.</p>
<p>There’s a great line from Stephen King’s <em>IT </em>that explains it pretty well, I think. It’s from Stanley Uris’ POV, and it explains why he’s completely unable to cope with the monster that is It.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27485 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/paaz-pg-Scn5vzk3D2c-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1706w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />“It&#8217;s offense you maybe can&#8217;t live with because it opens up a crack inside your thinking, and if you look down into it you see there are evil things down there, and they have little yellow eyes that don&#8217;t blink, and there&#8217;s a stink down there in that dark and after a while you think maybe there&#8217;s a whole other universe where a square moon rises in the sky, and the stars laugh in cold voices, and some of the triangles have four sides, and some have five, and some have five raised to the fifth power of sides. In this universe there might grow roses which sing. Everything leads to everything, he would have told them if he could. Go to your church and listen to your stories about Jesus walking on the water, but if I saw a guy doing that I&#8217;d scream and scream and scream. Because it wouldn&#8217;t look like a miracle to me. It would look like an offense.”</p>
<p>What’s interesting is that this feeling of tininess in a world you don’t understand manifests much differently in other genres. In sci-fi, it can be a moment of awe and hope, while in religious tradition it can be sacred, proof of forces larger than us.</p>
<p>Paul Tremblay posits (and pushes back against) the idea that horror is a fundamentally conservative genre. New, unknown things that break the rules of the world as we know it are scary and bad. Cosmic horror, anyway, reinforces his theory.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Too Close For Comfort</p>
<p>This one is anything that doesn’t exactly rearrange your concept of reality, but it hits a little too close to home. Babysitters getting mauled while they order pizza and ghosts hover just on the edge of your vision, for example, are scary because “Hey, maybe that could happen, after all, you know that story about my friend’s cousin’s mom who…”</p>
<p>This kind of fear has us checking over our shoulders and doubting the people we see every day.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Types of Horror</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Profanity</p>
<p>I almost wanted to categorize this one as “perversion,” but there’s connotations there I don’t <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-27486 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/erik-mclean-tzzWuCl_onM-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />mean. This kind of horror is what happens when something usually perceived as innocent is twisted into something frightening: possessed children’s toys, evil carnivals, cannibal clowns.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Spooky Stuff</p>
<p>This one is simple: things that creep us out on a cultural or species level like dead bodies that zombify, ghosts, curses, haunted objects or houses. This kind of fear explores things we find disturbing on the best of days (but also sometimes find fascinating).</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Types of Gross-Out</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Phobia</p>
<p>Sometimes, whether there’s a reason for it or not, specific things can put a person into a deep state of fear, even if they aren’t in any danger. Phobias range from “Hey, don’t ever ask so-and-so to hold your pet tarantula” to medical diagnoses that can be debilitating.</p>
<p>An ophidiophobe would rather fight a bear than go into the reptile house and a claustrophobe might find a tanning bed intolerable. Some movies play on these fears and allow viewers a form of DIY exposure therapy that rarely works. And they create their own audiences, because some children form phobias just from seeing something scary on screen.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Adrenaline Rushes</p>
<p>Jump scares! VR horror experiences! Sitting next to me in a theater during a jump-scare-heavy movie because I always grab my companion!</p>
<p>I think this one is so much fun. It’s reasonably easy to do: set a tense atmosphere (a POV short where a character creeps down an empty hallway with plenty of places for the big bad to hide, for example, or a scene where the viewers can spot the danger but the character can’t), draw it out for as long as your sadistic little heart thinks is necessary, and then BAM! Hit ‘em with a shock to the senses like sudden movement or loud noise.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Body Horror</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27487 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-198x300.jpg" alt="" width="198" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-198x300.jpg 198w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-676x1024.jpg 676w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-768x1163.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-1014x1536.jpg 1014w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-1353x2048.jpg 1353w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/sandro-gonzalez-G32RcLD7a_E-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1691w" sizes="(max-width: 198px) 100vw, 198px" />This one is very evolutionary in nature—where Lovecraft terrorizes our frontal cortexes, squeamish body horror goes straight for the hindbrain. Messy kills, buckets of blood, snapping bones—either you love this stuff or you hate it. We’ve got the effects team to thank for the images that stick in your mind and the sympathy pain you experience.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Trauma-Triggers</p>
<p>This one is probably the least fun. Watching <em>The Shining </em>if you grew up with an abusive alcoholic or <em>Hush </em>if you’ve lived through a home invasion can, for a lot of people, bring on the mental and physical symptoms of being back in the situation. 0/10, do not recommend.</p>
<p>On my way out, I’ll leave a helpful link: <a href="https://www.doesthedogdie.com/">https://www.doesthedogdie.com/</a>. This is a really good resource for vetting movies for really specific stuff. It won’t get inside your brain and tell you what’s really going to bother you, but a quick search will bring up most common phobias. Some of the entries paint with a pretty broad brush, ie considering Grizabella’s ascension to the Heaviside Layer in <em>CATS </em>a “cat death.”</p>
<p>Which yes, is still on topic, because <em>CATS </em>(2019) is a horror movie and no one can tell me different.</p>
<p>Anyway, drop your “absolutely nope” movies in the comments, and I’ll see you all next month!</p>
<p><!-- Stephen King classifies scares in three categories: Terror, Horror, and Gross-Out. “The 3 types of terror: The Gross-out: the sight of a severed head tumbling down a flight of stairs, it's when the lights go out and something green and slimy splatters against your arm. The Horror: the unnatural, spiders the size of bears, the dead waking up and walking around, it's when the lights go out and something with claws grabs you by the arm. And the last and worse one: Terror, when you come home and notice everything you own had been taken away and replaced by an exact substitute. It's when the lights go out and you feel something behind you, you hear it, you feel its breath against your ear, but when you turn around, there's nothing there...” Far be it from me to argue with the master of horror. However, I want to subdivide these three categories a little further. The reason I started thinking about this was because I watched Apartment 1 Br, and even though it’s a good movie, I really didn’t enjoy it. I ended up watching Howl’s Moving Castle to calm down. But Eve, you like being scared! That’s your whole thing! *insert montage of me riding rollercoasters alone because my friends have reached their limit, watching horror movies in the dark, and generally spooking myself silly* Thinking about this seemingly contradictory idea: that I can love being scared sometimes and not others, led me to the idea that “fear” is a catch-all term that can be defined even further. So… Types of Terror Cosmic Horror “The universe and the laws thereof are absolutely not what I thought they were.” This is the heart of cosmic horror, and of course I’ve got to nod to Lovecraft for solidifying this genre. There’s a great line from Stephen King’s IT that explains it pretty well, I think. It’s from Stanley Uris’ POV, and it explains why he’s completely unable to cope with the monster that is It. “It's offense you maybe can't live with because it opens up a crack inside your thinking, and if you look down into it you see there are evil things down there, and they have little yellow eyes that don't blink, and there's a stink down there in that dark and after a while you think maybe there's a whole other universe where a square moon rises in the sky, and the stars laugh in cold voices, and some of the triangles have four sides, and some have five, and some have five raised to the fifth power of sides. In this universe there might grow roses which sing. Everything leads to everything, he would have told them if he could. Go to your church and listen to your stories about Jesus walking on the water, but if I saw a guy doing that I'd scream and scream and scream. Because it wouldn't look like a miracle to me. It would look like an offense.” What’s interesting is that this feeling of tininess in a world you don’t understand manifests much differently in other genres. In scifi, it can be a moment of awe and hope, while in religious tradition it can be sacred, proof of forces larger than us. Paul Tremblay posits (and pushes back against) the idea that horror is a fundamentally conservative genre. New, unknown things that break the rules of the world as we know it are scary and bad. Cosmic horror, anyway, reinforces his theory. Too Close For Comfort This one is anything that doesn’t exactly rearrange your concept of reality, but it hits a little too close to home. Babysitters getting mauled while they order pizza and ghosts hover just on the edge of your vision, for example, are scary because “hey, maybe that could happen, after all, you know that story about my friend’s cousin’s mom who…” This kind of fear has us checking over our shoulders and doubting the people we see every day. Types of Horror Profanity I almost wanted to categorize this one as “perversion,” but there’s connotations there I don’t mean. This kind of horror is what happens when something usually perceived as innocent is twisted into something frightening: possessed children’s toys, evil carnivals, cannibal clowns. Spooky Stuff This one is simple: things that creep us out on a cultural or species level like dead bodies that zombify, ghosts, curses, haunted objects or houses. This kind of fear explores things we find disturbing on the best of days (but also sometimes find fascinating). Types of Gross-Out Phobia Sometimes, whether there’s a reason for it or not, specific things can put a person into a deep state of fear, even if they aren’t in any danger. Phobias range from “hey, don’t ever ask so-and-so to hold your pet tarantula” to medical diagnoses that can be debilitating. An ophidiophobe would rather fight a bear than go into the reptile house and a claustrophobe might find a tanning bed intolerable. Some movies play on these fears and allow viewers a form of DIY exposure therapy that rarely works. And they create their own audiences, because some children form phobias just from seeing something scary on screen. Adrenaline Rushes Jump scares! VR horror experiences! Sitting next to me in a theater during a jump-scare-heavy movie because I always grab my companion! I think this one is so much fun. It’s reasonably easy to do: set a tense atmosphere (a POV short where a character creeps down an empty hallway with plenty of places for the big bad to hide, for example, or a scene where the viewers can spot the danger but the character can’t), draw it out for as long as your sadistic little heart thinks is necessary, and then BAM! Hit ‘em with a shock to the senses like sudden movement or loud noise. Body Horror This one is very evolutionary in nature – where Lovecraft terrorizes our frontal cortexes, squeamish body horror goes straight for the hindbrain. Messy kills, buckets of blood, snapping bones—either you love this stuff or you hate it. We’ve got the effects team to thank for the images that stick in your mind and the sympathy pain you experience. Trauma-Triggers This one is probably the least fun. Watching The Shining if you grew up with an abusive alcoholic or Hush if you’ve lived through a home invasion can, for a lot of people, bring on the mental and physical symptoms of being back in the situation. 0/10, do not recommend. On my way out, I’ll leave a helpful link: https://www.doesthedogdie.com/. This is a really good resource for vetting movies for really specific stuff. It won’t get inside your brain and tell you what’s really going to bother you, but a quick search will bring up most common phobias. Some of the entries paint with a pretty broad brush, ie considering Grizabella’s ascension to the Heaviside Layer in CATS a “cat death.” Which yes, is still on topic, because CATS (2019) is a horror movie and no one can tell me different. Anyway, drop your “absolutely nope” movies in the comments, and I’ll see you all next month! wp:paragraph /--></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/scares-of-all-shapes-and-sizes-categorizing-fear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taxed</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/taxed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 10:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many of my favorite artists and content creators cannot be found on the shelves of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many of my favorite artists and content creators cannot be found on the shelves of Barnes &amp; Noble, or within the hydra warehouses of Big Box stores. But I try to support them as individuals through monetization platforms such as Etsy, Kickstarter, Patreon, Society6, and YouTube. These platforms are far from perfect, but that is not my main point today: I’m worried about the 2023 tax season, and how it’s going to negatively affect the US-based creators that I love.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27402 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/jon-tyson-qAQsVsSxp_w-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />The purpose of <a href="https://www.irs.gov/businesses/understanding-your-form-1099-k">IRS form 1099-K</a> is to tax individuals for the money they earn based on goods/services that are filtered through a third-party payment network. For example, if someone sells a sculpture on Etsy and the payment of that sale is processed via Paypal. Previously, mandatory reporting of such sales was only required for those earning over $20,000 through at least 200 unique transactions. This rule makes some sense to me – many people earn a hefty living through such transactions on platforms like Airbnb.</p>
<p>However, as of March 11, 2021, reporting such transactions for tax purposes has been lowered to a mere $600 per year, and the threshold of transactions lowered from 200 to 1. One! This legislation, passed in Section 9674 of the American Rescue Plan, confuses me beyond belief. It’s so ridiculous that it makes me question my own reading comprehension. Why, in the middle of a pandemic that has forced millions into economic insecurity, would the government punch down this way?</p>
<p>The creation of art already costs plenty in labor, love, and time. But it also costs in materials and fees. For example, <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/economy/why-etsys-latest-fee-increase-has-inspired-thousands-of-sellers-including-its-most-marginalized-to-strike">Etsy charges sellers a flat 6.5% fee for every transaction</a>, a 20-cent fee for listing any item that is then <strong>re-charged </strong>every time it sells, and a whopping 12-15% fee for transactions that the almighty-algorithm determines to have been made as a result of on- or off-site advertising efforts. <a href="https://www.etsy.com/legal/fees/">This fee chain</a> doesn&#8217;t even address the monetary loss associated with returns/complaints due to supply-chain issues beyond creator control, or VAT on overseas shipping, or high consumer expectations that shipping be fast/free. The struggle of the artist is real.</p>
<p>Another concern I have with this newly altered legislation is privacy. For instance, content creators on Onlyfans are self-employed contractors in the eyes of the IRS. But the internet can be a dangerous place, and a creator having their <a href="https://pappas.house.gov/sites/pappas.house.gov/files/1099%20Letter%20-%20FINAL.pdf">social security number</a> confirmed to their account may place them in undue risk of social or financial repercussion. No commercial website is too big or small to be hacked and exploited.</p>
<p>I hope these tax changes become common knowledge for people who engage with and support individual content creators in the United States. There is no science to the price of art &#8211; but for many the cost of doing business has just risen. Thankfully, April 2023 is an entire year away, and <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/internal-revenue-service-taxes-irs-1099-k-form-tracking-payment-transactions-credit-card-venmo-privacy-breach-cybersecurity-11648745007">opposition</a> to the change is gaining traction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: The Secret Skin by Wendy N. Wagner</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/review-the-secret-skin-by-wendy-n-wagner/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joanna Z. Weston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 11:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Noteworthy Novellas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=27271</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[People love haunted houses, the grander the better. That fear becomes all the more delicious&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">People love haunted houses, the grander the better. That fear becomes all the more delicious when it is bound to family legacy, when the house in question is an ancestral estate. <a href="https://www.neonhemlock.com/books/the-secret-skin"><em>The Secret Skin</em></a>, a gothic tale by <a href="https://winniewoohoo.com/">Wendy N. Wagner</a> and set in Prohibition era Oregon, is an excellent example of the genre. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-27362 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/56559011._SY475_-188x300.jpg" alt="" width="188" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/56559011._SY475_-188x300.jpg 188w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/56559011._SY475_.jpg 297w" sizes="(max-width: 188px) 100vw, 188px" />Storm Break was completed the day that June Vogel was born, but it was never a happy home – </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">for her, or for anyone else. Her mother – a grand lady, obsessed with entertaining –</span> <span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">had no time for a shy, homely daughter. June</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> left </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">to become an art teacher at a boarding school</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> as soon as </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">s</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">he could, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">and</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> even found some measure of happiness </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">for six years</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">.</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> But now her brother, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Franklin,</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> has asked her to return </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">for the summer. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">He needs her</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> to look after her niece, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Abigail,</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> while he honeymoons with Lillian, his new wife, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">and June can’t tell him no</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">As she slowly gets to know her niece – and later, Lillian herself – her presence awakens the house, and she uncovers secrets. </span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">T</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">he Se</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">cret</span></em><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"><em> Skin</em> has everything </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">you could want from</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> a gothic </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">style</span> <span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">novel</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> – an imposing and forbidding estate, the continued impact of an overbearing mother (now deceased), a half-feral child, a hateful housekeeper who clings to the memory of her deceased mistress, a forbidden</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> queer romance</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">, and </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">endless</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> family shame and secrets. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Richly detailed, atmospheric writing bring</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">s</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> it all together for some delicious dread.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">T</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">h</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">is story beautifully demonstrates the insidious trap of</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> societal expectations and pressures. Frederick has inherited his father’s business and estate, but has no real interest or skill for either. His new wife, Lillian, struggles to play the role of the fancy lady, and copes with both that and other trauma through the use of opium. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Abigail, a nine year old wild child, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">sees the rot at the center of all of this, but has </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">little</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> power to do anything about it</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">June, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">who always </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">chafed against the role she was born into, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">is the </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">only</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> character who has successfully escaped. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Now that she is back home she struggles to play the part of the lady of the house, and keeps slipping back into childhood habits of silent observation and obedience. </span>None of them can live as themselves, as Storm Break &#8212; its expectations and its demands &#8212; threatens to consume them all.</p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">While I loved the social dynamics and the lush atm</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">os</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">phere, </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">t</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">here are several intriguing plot threads that are not developed as fully as I wanted. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Wagner introduces compelling characters in Frederick’s foreman and a Black truck driver whom he bullies, but they only tangentially connect to the main plot. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Of course, there is only so much space in a novella, but it was frustrating to get these tantalizing glimpses and then have very little come of them</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">. </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Still, the atmospheric writing and compelling characters made for an enjoyable reading experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">In the end, June chooses to leave Storm Break and its malevolence behind her. I think that f</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">ans of </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">both </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">Shirley Jackson and the gothic genre </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">will love </span><em><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">The Secret Skin</span></em><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">, but </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">it will also appeal to </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">those</span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;"> who </span><span style="font-family: Liberation Serif, serif;">have needed to make peace with their past, in order to build a future.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of &#8220;Trash Fantasy&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-trash-fantasy/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-trash-fantasy/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Greta Hayer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 14:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search of the Dream World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I don’t know if I could have gotten through quarantine* without my books. I think&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25674 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fantasy-3077928_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I don’t know if I could have gotten through quarantine* without my books. I think a lot of people were/are in the same boat as me. I’ve read more books than I have since high school, back when I used to devour inches-thick fantasies in a matter of days. During quarantine, I fell back into some of those habits, and my bookshelves have borne the weight of my renewed hobby with silent distress. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But this past year, I haven’t exactly been reading “good” books. Not the deep, complicated epics the genre is known for, or even the thoughtful and acclaimed literary novels I got used to in graduate school. Sure, I’ll pick up one or two like that and slip it into my To Be Read shelf, but the majority of what I’ve been reading is what I lovingly call “Trash Fantasy.”</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trash Fantasy, as I define it, are those lighthearted fantasy books full of tropes and romance that aren’t necessarily well-written in a literary sense. Sometimes, they seem like they should have gone through one more round of revisions to close up plot holes or explain this point or that one. The characters are the focus, and the most compelling part, rather than the world or some grand political plot. Sometimes, they’re called YA, but I think that’s often a misnomer.**</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another way to define it? Comfort reads. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s just that during this time of upheaval, plague, and injustice, I want to see happy endings. I want the knight to rescue the princess, or the princess to rescue herself. I want the kings to rule fairly and the gods to be just, and I want the enemy mages to kiss at the end, all problems fading away before their love. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I don’t know if I have the internal strength to read about another grand library burning down, or the lovers torn apart, or an empire falling into dust. Things like that seem too real. Too close to home. So I&#8217;m reading more and more books to escape, and rediscovering my love of lighthearted, charming stories. </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though I still love deep, thought-provoking novels, even sad ones, taking breaks between them<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25676 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920-300x138.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="138" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920-300x138.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920-1024x470.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920-768x353.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920-1536x706.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/horse-3395135_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> by reading &#8220;trash fantasy&#8221; books has certainly helped me this past year. It&#8217;s w</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">hat’s kept me afloat&#8211;knowing I can crack the spine of one of my beloved “trash fantasy” novels and believe that there will be a happily ever after.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you have any favorites that could fall into my affectionately titled “trash fantasy” genre? Let me know in the comments!</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">*I know Covid’s not over. It’s complicated. Please get vaccinated.  </span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">**A lot of adult fantasy books written by women are considered YA even though they aren’t. It’s a sexism thing. It sucks. Other people have written about it <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/shortcuts/2019/jan/30/women-write-fantasy-for-grown-ups-too">here</a>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-importance-of-trash-fantasy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Got Writer’s Block? There’s a Frog for That.</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/got-writers-block-theres-a-frog-for-that/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaya Kanda]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 11:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Atmosphere as Character]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=23944</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’re stuck on a writing project, I want you to watch this video about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-24413 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/jack-hamilton-EP_OHkgn1JI-unsplash-300x234.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="234" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/jack-hamilton-EP_OHkgn1JI-unsplash-300x234.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/jack-hamilton-EP_OHkgn1JI-unsplash-1024x800.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/jack-hamilton-EP_OHkgn1JI-unsplash-768x600.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/jack-hamilton-EP_OHkgn1JI-unsplash-1536x1199.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/jack-hamilton-EP_OHkgn1JI-unsplash-2048x1599.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />If you’re stuck on a writing project, I want you to watch <a href="https://www.illogicstudios.com/project/gardenparty">this video</a> about frogs. It’s only 7 minutes, and honestly adorbs. Did you do it? Good.</p>
<p>I’ll know if you didn’t.</p>
<p>I’m a sucker for this kind of story. Nothing boring like a template, nothing at all like a blank slate. Stories like this are a playground for ideas and possibilities.</p>
<p>So let’s play.</p>
<p>It’s a little game called “How did we get here?”</p>
<p>The best balm for writer’s block is to start at the ending – to treat your story like a crime scene. Your job is to look at the end result of how events have unfolded, and answer that all-important question: “How did we get here?”</p>
<p>First, we set the stage: Dead man floating in the pool of a lavish villa. Bullets everywhere, along with a big mess of frogs. Phone off the hook, safe busted open, big (apparently useless) security system. The appearance of a large party interrupted – yet no blood.</p>
<p>So what happened? This is where you get to play detective. To daydream scenarios and investigate the characters, take roll call and sniff out relationships.</p>
<p><em>Maybe</em> this is a story about bullets that turn good people into frogs and bad people into…dead bad people? <em>Maybe</em> this is a story about a bored billionaire who licks a frog and gets so high on toxins that he hallucinates a robbery. <em>Maybe</em> this is a story about a friendly herpetologist winning the lottery, only to be murdered by his old-money neighbors who disdain him.</p>
<p>The important thing is to think of <em>all the maybes</em> you can manage – don’t judge anything as too weird or outlandish. That’s where all the innovation is hiding.</p>
<p>After you’ve got a play-by-play you can rally behind, the next important question arrives: Who gets to tell the story? Imagine, if a bored billionaire licks a frog and goes off his rocker, that story is going to sound very different depending on narration. Told from the frog’s perspective? How about the nosy neighbor? How about the security guards who arrive after the alarm is tripped?</p>
<p>Who gets to tell the story is just as important as the physical scene.</p>
<p>“Garden Party” is a gorgeous piece of animation, and I enjoy it just the way it is. But it’s clear to see that something has happened, something momentous, off camera. Considering the <em>whys</em> and <em>hows</em> of a whodunit is one of the reasons I love writing.</p>
<p>So, if you’ve lost momentum in your story, try drafting the final scene first. It’ll give your compass a heading and, for sake of sanity, to stop swimming in circles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
