<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 037 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-037/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:18:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 037 Author Interview: Mab Morris and &#8220;Laughter in the Graveyard&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-mab-morris-and-laughter-in-the-graveyard/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 10:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 037]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello again and welcome to another interview with one of our fabulous Issue 037 authors!&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15321 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/scott-rodgerson-369593-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/scott-rodgerson-369593-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/scott-rodgerson-369593-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/scott-rodgerson-369593-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Hello again and welcome to another interview with one of our fabulous <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-037/">Issue 037</a> authors! This week we chat with Mab Morris about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/laughter-in-the-graveyard/">Laughter in the Graveyard</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The world of your story spurns women, yet much of it takes place in a temple that once revered a queen. How do you think huge societal shifts like that come to be?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mab: Oh, there are so very many reasons. We only have to look at our political climate and not be surprised. It took a ridiculously short time for that shift. Time changes everything. New knowledge, science, and so on. Agricultural shifts can change things.</p>
<p>There was an article that I read not too long ago about the worst year to be alive. Somewhere in the 600s, I believe. There were a series of volcanic eruptions, including a super volcano. Then a plague. So . . . the Dark Ages started. To give you a comparison, the super volcano was similar in size to the one that caused the year without summer in the 1800s—which killed more people by starvation because of a lack of, well, food. Food doesn’t do well without sunlight, or in unseasonably cold weather. When people get desperate, or feel threatened, they . . . get back to “basics.” One could say they get selfish and nasty.</p>
<p>There’s a great passage in Steven Pressfield’s book <a href="https://stevenpressfield.com/books/the-war-of-art/"><i>The War of Art </i></a>called “Resistance and Fundamentalism”. A revealing quote:</p>
<blockquote><p>“The beleaguered individual who comes to embrace fundamentalism . . . cannot stand freedom. He cannot find his way into the future, so he retreats to the past . . . He gets back to basics. To fundamentals . . . In [the humanists’] view things do progress, life does evolve; each individual has value . . . The fundamentalist cannot conceive of this . . . When fundamentalism wins, the world enters a dark age.”</p></blockquote>
<p>In creating a planet the way I am, it was an interesting idea to change a society over time. There will be other stories that look at how mythology changes—it’s mentioned in <em>Sen of the Woods</em> which I’m still working on. I think there’s always this seesaw balance or cyclical movement of light and dark, reasoned and unreasonable, humanist and selfish. I like to believe that we continue to evolve into increasingly better, more humane societies. A more specific example, related to this story, that reflects this idea: even if one is ruled by a woman, there will always be men to objectify her. One can be fully clothed, completely covered and still be objectified by men. There are many incredible men out there who don’t, and never would, but . . .</p>
<p>The revered queen, Kuen from <i>Fate of the Red Queen</i>, wouldn’t have suffered such temerity, and the people she saved were pretty much focused on survival, even working and befriending their enemies. I could say they didn’t have time to show off more revolting sides of human behavior. It’s not as if it wouldn’t have happened on that planet somewhere, and probably did. I just didn’t write it. Still, I like to think all of Yezgini people in Fate would be turning in their graves to see what happened ages later. If they’d have known they might have gone, “Hang on a minute . . . let&#8217;s re-think this.”</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are the xidachene creatures of your own invention? Could you tell us a bit more about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mab: I believe the <i>xidachene</i> are my invention. Around the time I wrote the first draft of “Laughter in the Graveyard” I was working on a draft of my novel <i>Sen of the Woods</i>, and doing this crazy culture crafting of blending Ndeble healing ritual with Etruscan mythology. I found notes where I was working on some conlang for that book. There’s a lot of mythology and healing based on ancestors. I do remember looking at different words for spirit, ancestors in both African and Asian cultures, though I can’t find the specific blend of those words to come up with <i>xidachene</i>.</p>
<p>In many African cultures the ancestors can haunt someone, usually making them ill if they haven’t been respected. Many Asian cultures have something similar. It’s where the idea of the cursed land, the Jungle of the Dead came from in <i>Fate of the Red Queen</i>—that and the Swamp of the Dead in Tolkien’s books.</p>
<p>In Manila’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2017/06/25/world/asia/manila-north-cemetery-philippines.html">North Cemetery</a> there are people who are paid to visit graves so that a family’s dead are not forgotten. They pay someone to let their ancestors know they’re still being thought of, even if they don’t have time to visit. If you see pictures of the trash between isles of stacked tombs, it is really not a place to visit, much less live—though people do. It’s better than the slums that often get flooded.</p>
<p>Frankly it was interesting to play with how the people who once lived in the Jungle of the Dead became something more zombie-like, or even similar to the <i>xidachene</i>. Mythological shifts are interesting to contemplate as I age the planet.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Gazev takes on her sister’s burdens as a way to hold onto her, rather than more positive memories or feelings. Does this speak to the atmosphere of your world as a whole, or is this Gazev’s choice and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mab: There are two somewhat dark elements that inspired the atmosphere. Not, perhaps, as a world as a whole—since I have a distinction of culture crafting as I world build a multi-cultural planet book by book, story by story. I could say that it is a servants’ world. Gazev only has a few <img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15322 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/luis-alvoeiro-quaresma-118738-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/luis-alvoeiro-quaresma-118738-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/luis-alvoeiro-quaresma-118738-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/luis-alvoeiro-quaresma-118738-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/luis-alvoeiro-quaresma-118738-unsplash.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />good memories of her older sister Sonalie. I probably wrote both women into a menial position not just to make it harder for them, but also because of memories or stories about servants my relatives had in South Africa.</p>
<p>Years before apartheid ended, one of my aunts had a servant she, supposedly, considered her best friend (I’ll admit the inequality of their status makes it repulsive if I could believe it, especially since many members of that side of the family tend to be fairly racist). Her house was huge. He lived in a room only as large enough for a narrow bed and a small desk. If his wife came to visit, she had to have an overnight pass. Getting one was not always easy, because it had to be proven she had work. He was rarely given full days off; I believe it was once a month? Bussing to and from any city residence was ridiculously long, and getting caught out past curfew, he was subject to fines. He actually built a house for his family on those rare visits. Despite fuzzy details, I do know his family time was rare.</p>
<p>I know that often in poorer cultures that’s sometimes the norm. Get a job in the city, send money back home. The stories of my South African family’s servants told me that clearly there could be some very strong family bonds, even without daily contact. I still find it depressing to think of, and I’m glad that apartheid ended. However much we can celebrate that, it didn’t end the unfortunate tendency towards unequal, and demeaning relationships. My own upbringing by South African parents was far more open minded and celebrated the cultural diversity rather than the divisions of that country. Still, those memories and stories give me a wealth of things to draw on when I craft culture and world build. Some even darker than that, some even more sad.</p>
<p>So for Gazev to have very few happy memories of Sonalie was realistic, along with the deep love she had for her. There was this social, cultural knowledge that I brought to the plate to write the story and . . . well . . . there’s a bit of a depressing “And . . .”</p>
<p>Part of the story was inspired by trying to understand someone’s PTSD from years of sexual harassment. Women are harassed every day of the week to varying degrees of harm. I’ll admit, as close as I am to this person I couldn’t quite come to grips with her pain. She’s like one of the first people you’ll see to bow up and defend someone. Sadly there are times there’s only so far one can empathize with another person’s reality. One can still love them.</p>
<p>Gazev’s burden to a large extent started out as an echo of my distress. I wanted to try and bring some compassion into my thinking. It made the story one of the hardest I’ve written. Earlier drafts were not satisfying. I’ll admit I don’t feel as if I achieved a real sense of understanding for Sonalie. And still: Sonalie saves Gazev, really. I’d like to believe she saved herself in the end as well, even if she didn’t believe it possible. I left that open to interpretation.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mab: I think perhaps my favorite part is the photo series that inspired some of the imagery. I’ve looked for the series so I could reference it. I can’t find it. I would love to stumble across it again! It was posted sometime in 2015, maybe earlier. I think it made the rounds on Facebook. The images were: the children under the table; the stacked graves which echo Manila’s North Cemetery with their broken lights and radios, people eating on tombs, or using a tomb as a bedroom; the image of someone on a ledge in a lit city on their prayer rug; an ornate brilliantly white mosque. I believe that the images are by a Filipino photographer named Noel Celis, but I can’t get more than a couple of images such as the one featured in this <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2015/jan/21/death-in-the-city-what-happens-cemeteries-full-cost-dying">article</a>.</p>
<p>Those images have stayed with me. I can see those two faces from under the rug. I can’t find the reference, and would love to. It made me think about Yezgin in a much different time—farther in the future than our modern time, but probably not too much out of it.</p>
<p>I think that I enjoyed using these images as a reference. It added a cerebral side to a rather difficult story.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mab: That’s almost always elicits a “Where to begin” answer. Currently I have seven novel projects in various stages of completion. <i>Seek the Monster</i> is at my editing chair. I’ve already started going through my developmental editors’ notes. She and I talked about what her work has so far inspired. “Seismic shifts” was the word she used. She’s not far wrong. It is taking some work to get it ready, and I’ve been sidetracked by getting ready for the Dahlonega Literary Festival as a regional writer, the Wine &amp; Words monthly events I’m setting up for DLF, The Southern Penn Bookstore’s upcoming workshop, where I’ll talk about editing, as well as judging their Self Published book award, and starting up my editing service. The book requires more focus than I could give it. It’s not a sequel to <i>Fate of the Red Queen</i>, but Kuen is in this book, as is Humna from <i>The Red Khémèresh</i>.</p>
<p><i>Sen of the Woods</i> is with a beta reader while I let it percolate till the next revision phase. It’s the one I started when I first crafted “Laughter in the Graveyard.” It’s also set in Ihyel, but an island country north of Yezgin. There’s enough time after <i>Fate of the Red Queen</i> where there’s a lot more seafaring trade, and Sen gets to drink famous Yezgini tea—but not the kind that gives you endless life and turns your teeth red. Just plain green I’m afraid.</p>
<p>Neither Kuen nor Humna are in this one—though they have been known to travel to different countries. There are new demi-gods based on Etruscan mythology, but also from the Gods I created in my first book. That book is lost. I wrote it on a Kaypro in the early 80s, and different computers and formats after that . . . well . . . I have pages. Not a full story.  It would probably be a trunk book, anyway. I mean, I wrote the thing in high school. Someone described it as histrionic. It did teach me a lot about writing.</p>
<p>Both <i>Seek the Monster</i> and <i>Sen of the Woods</i> are set in Ihyel during their of Age of Reason, like our Renaissance. I jokingly say that Seek is at the last gasp of the Age of Heroes.</p>
<p>After I do the massive revisions first up in the queue, I want to finish writing <i>The Lost Ship Queen Amadelia</i>—it’s a science fiction novel—and the second Bone Reader novel <i>Blackened Bones</i>. I absolutely could go on with this list. When I finish a full draft, I generally start work on something else, so that when I get back to it, I’ve got fresh eyes on it. When I’m happy with it, I send it to an editor, and go at it again. So there’s always a pile of work to do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 037 Author Interview: Kathryn McMahon and &#8220;Green is for Wishes and Apples&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-kathryn-mcmahon-and-green-is-for-wishes-and-apples/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 10:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 037]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We have a special treat for you, dear readers. We recently sat down and had&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-15257 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/kotagauni-srinivas-471899-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/kotagauni-srinivas-471899-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/kotagauni-srinivas-471899-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/kotagauni-srinivas-471899-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />We have a special treat for you, dear readers. We recently sat down and had a chat with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-037/">Issue 037</a> author Kathryn McMahon about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/green-is-for-wishes-and-apples/">Green is for Wishes and Apples</a>.&#8221; Enjoy!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The setting for this story is a magical and somewhat spooky apple orchard. Why apples? Is there real-life inspiration for this setting?</strong></em></p>
<p>Kathryn: Sort of. The idea for this story came from <a href="https://www.motherearthnews.com/diy/applehead-dolls-zmaz80jazraw">apple dolls</a> themselves, and actually, the recipe and method that Abigail uses are fairly standard ones I discovered during my research (minus the magic, sadly!). Apples have long been associated with the supernatural, most obviously in the story of Adam and Eve, as well as Snow White. But when we hear about the color of magic apples, it’s only ever red, so I wondered if using green would make a difference. The farmers’ market in this story is a bit like the one near me in rural (and touristy) Washington State. I spend a lot of time between there and southwest England—both of which are apple country. What apple orchards look like varies depending on the region, age, and commercial value, and I really love the small ones on old family farms which seem to have the craggiest trees. Looking at them, I feel like there really could be magic bound up in their branches.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story creeped me out in the best possible way, especially the ending. What are your favorite elements of this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Kathryn: Probably the undead raccoon! I love raccoons. They have such uncanny, human-like hands. I don’t know why foxes get all the glory for being tricksters. On a broader note, something I set out to do was to upend expectations of familial love. I didn’t want to be overtly violent, but I did want to explore love at its most desperate while somehow still keeping it tender. I also wanted to take death and darkness and soften them through familiarity. I wanted to blur a lot of lines and I think I succeeded at that.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: You use suspense masterfully in this piece. What is your secret for giving readers that nail-biting feeling of anticipation?</strong></em></p>
<p>Kathryn: Undermining expectations is one way to do it. A writer can’t unmoor a reader too much <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15258 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/guillaume-bourdages-637861-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/guillaume-bourdages-637861-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/guillaume-bourdages-637861-unsplash-768x1150.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/guillaume-bourdages-637861-unsplash-684x1024.jpg 684w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />at the beginning or they risk losing them, but providing the sense that things are not quite right can hold the audience&#8217;s attention. It’s also important to drop hints of what’s to come so that when things appear “normal” a reader still senses the shadows edging closer. Here, I used backstory for foreshadowing. I think backstory gets a bad rap because it’s so often used as filler which makes it boring. But taking elements of backstory that are relevant (and if it’s a horror story these are elements that are usually unsettling or suspect as well as informative) and tying them into a present moment of calm can keep up the suspense as well as make the story richer and the ending more worthwhile.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: If you could do magic like the kind Abigail and her grandmother do, what would you do with it?</strong></em></p>
<p>Kathryn: That is a dangerous question! I would live in a little house in the woods and amass an army of undead animals to carry out vigilante justice.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any writers who have influenced your work?</strong></em></p>
<p>Kathryn: I try to read widely because I think writers can learn from every genre no matter where their own work might fall. I don’t know how much they’ve influenced me, but some of my favorites include Aimee Bender, Helen Oyeyemi, Gwendolyn Kiste, and Alyssa Wong.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 037 Author Interview: Britani Baker and &#8220;Sirens&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-britani-baker-and-sirens/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 10:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 037]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to another Issue 037 author interview! Today we chat with Britani Baker about her&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15217 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/rene-bernal-353739-unsplash-300x219.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="219" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/rene-bernal-353739-unsplash-300x219.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/rene-bernal-353739-unsplash-768x560.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/rene-bernal-353739-unsplash-1024x747.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Welcome to another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-037/">Issue 037</a> author interview! Today we chat with Britani Baker about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/sirens/">Sirens</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: In our climate-changing world, the danger in “Sirens” feels uncomfortably close. This uncomfortable topic is made even more so by the protagonists being children. What was your motivation behind this choice?</strong></em></p>
<p>Britani: There are several reasons I made the protagonists children – I believe that children are the ones who ultimately are most affected by the dangers posed by climate change; they are the ones who will have to deal with the fallout of mankind’s effect on the environment, and that fallout is everyday becoming more of a reality. So, it was important for me to make the protagonists children in order to think through and expose climate change as a very real threat that will have very real consequences for mankind’s most vulnerable group. I also find there is something about child protagonists that everyone can relate to, which makes the danger in “Sirens” feel still closer. Everyone can relate to the feelings of loss, fear, and confusion Isaac and Denver experience throughout the story, and when you displace these intense emotions and hardships on to children, their impact and the impact of environmental disaster is felt still more intensely. At least, that’s the idea.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I hope I’m not wrong in my reading of Denver being autistic. Was this a conscious choice, or did she come to you fully formed?</strong></em></p>
<p>Britani: You aren’t wrong! It was a conscious choice to make Denver autistic, but she didn’t come to me “fully formed” per se. I definitely tried to do my research on autism when writing Denver, as I wanted to do her character and those with autism justice. I’m sure I still made some faux pas in the story, but I aimed to show the need the world has for individuals with disabilities and differences. With the current advances and strides being made in genetic engineering, and the conversations surrounding “cures” for genetic variations such as Downs Syndrome, it was important for me to show that the world needs differences and that we can all learn from each other. Denver needs Isaac, but Isaac also needs and learns from Denver. Without adults to tell Isaac that Denver is autistic, he doesn’t have or need a label for her; he calls her “weird,” but that same descriptor can be applied to most kids. Ultimately, Isaac accepts Denver despite and because of her differences.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story? What was the hardest part?</strong></em></p>
<p>Britani: I enjoyed just about every aspect of writing this story, so I’m not sure I can say I had a favorite part. But, a particularly enjoyable part and one of the hardest parts was writing Denver. As I said, I wanted to do her justice and watched many interviews with individuals with autism and did a lot of research in making her character. I also found the scene with the adults <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15216 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/annie-spratt-709287-unsplash-300x230.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="230" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/annie-spratt-709287-unsplash-300x230.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/annie-spratt-709287-unsplash-768x589.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/annie-spratt-709287-unsplash-1024x785.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />particularly difficult – I found it somewhat difficult to inject the right amount of “drama” and “realism” into the scene to make it readable and not feel forced; action scenes are fun but not my usual cup of tea.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any writers who have influenced your work?</strong></em></p>
<p>Britani: I’m sure a lot of writers have influenced my work – I believe that everyone I have ever read has probably had some sort of influence on what I write. But, I guess that’s kind of avoiding the question. I particularly enjoy reading George Saunders’ and Stephen King’s short stories. I also enjoy Karen Russell, although I can’t say exactly what aspects of their work have overtly influenced mine – perhaps they all include a speculative element in many of their stories, so thematically they have influenced me. I also have a soft spot for YA literature, like Suzanne Collins, which may also have encouraged me to use children protagonists. The writers I have learned the most about writing from however are those I know personally in the graduate English program at the University of Southern Mississippi. Because I’m a PhD Literature student, I don’t take creative writing workshops, so the conversations I have with Fiction PhDs about writing, the feedback I get from close writer friends on my work, and being able to read and give feedback on their writing has been the largest influence on my work thus far. I’m not sure that’s really the answer you were looking for, but there you go.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 037 Author Interview: Ella Syverson and &#8220;Call To Mind&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-ella-syverson-and-call-to-mind/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 10:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 037]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you read Issue 037 yet? If not, what are you waiting for?! GO! Today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15097 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/ddp-1273597-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/ddp-1273597-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/ddp-1273597-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/ddp-1273597-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Have you read <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-037/">Issue 037</a> yet? If not, what are you waiting for?! GO! Today we chatted with Issue 037 author Ella Syverson about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/call-to-mind/">Call To Mind</a>.&#8221; Enjoy!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your characters undergo something called “artificial amnesia,” leaving them with their names but not much else. What are the challenges of writing characters with memory loss?</strong></em></p>
<div dir="auto">Ella: The main challenge of writing characters with artificial amnesia was that it was hard to imagine what their reactions would be when they learned about actions they took in the past, both when Aliyah tells them that they joined her alliance, and when they receive the letter of instructions that they wrote for themselves. For anyone else, the scenarios they learn about would seem crazy, but to agents who are used to routine memory loss, how can they do anything but trust the information they&#8217;re given to solve the puzzle of their past? Amnesia also made some aspects of writing easier. At the beginning of this story, you&#8217;re really jumping into the middle of Sam and Diesel&#8217;s adventure, but because their memories have just been erased, it&#8217;s a new beginning for them too. You get to discover what happened before along with the characters.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: Paranormal creatures incorporating into the normal world is one of my favorite subjects to read about. Where do you find your inspiration?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Ella: Paranormal/magical beings in the real world is also one of my favorite subjects to write about for many reasons, not least of which is that it&#8217;s easier to write fantasy in a world you don&#8217;t have to create entirely. I like to build on real places and legends I already know. I find inspiration in settings I know, imagining what they would be like in a world where magic existed. I find inspiration in familiar myths like witches and werewolves; their rich literary history brings depth to my world building. One author I look up to on this subject is Neil Gaiman, particularly his books <em>The Ocean at the End of the Lane</em> and <em>American Gods</em>. He does an excellent job of building worlds that are both wholly real and wholly magical. One of the many things I love about his writing is that the rules of the worlds in his books are not always explicitly stated, so he leaves a lot up to inference.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Ella: My favorite part of writing any story is developing my characters. While the two main <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15098 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/ddp-1219070-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/ddp-1219070-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/ddp-1219070-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/ddp-1219070-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />characters may have lost their memories, their personalities remain intact. Sam is the optimist, the one who believes in escape. Diesel complements her by adding a valuable cynicism at times. Their relationship is very close, as they&#8217;ve been working this job together for years, and find it impossible to lead a normal life with normal friends when they&#8217;re constantly traveling and losing their memories. One thing that&#8217;s especially important to me when I&#8217;m writing is making sure that I have strong, realistic, active female characters. I intentionally made Sam the leader, the driver, the decision maker in her friendship with Diesel, and made Aliyah the leader of the alliance with the paranormals.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"><em><strong>LSQ: You’ve built up quite the cast of characters here. Do you have plans to work with them again? What kind of adventures do you see them getting up to?</strong></em></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Ella: I don&#8217;t currently have plans to expand on anything in this story, but I&#8217;m very prone to changing my mind. I would love to further explore the moral implications of humans and paranormal beings living together. While I don&#8217;t exactly paint the Department of Supernatural Control as a villain, it is definitely a cruel and inhumane institution. On the other hand, some paranormal beings present a real threat to people. Vampires need to drink blood. Werewolves may hurt people at the full moon. Goblins tend to hunt household pets. The reason that the alliance in this story is appealing to me is because it shows another way to live, with people and supernatural beings living and working together in peace. I would also love to keep learning about and developing the supporting characters. This was a very short story, and I didn&#8217;t get to spend as much time as I wanted with Aliyah, Saphury, Cora, and the rest of their group.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 037 Author Interview: Amanda McGee and &#8220;At Love&#8217;s Heart&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-amanda-mcgee-and-at-loves-heart/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 037]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another Tuesday, another Issue 037 author interview! Today we have the pleasure of featuring author&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15069 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/osman-rana-1313818-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/osman-rana-1313818-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/osman-rana-1313818-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/osman-rana-1313818-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Another Tuesday, another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-037/">Issue 037</a> author interview! Today we have the pleasure of featuring author Amanda McGee and her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/at-loves-heart/">At Love&#8217;s Heart</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Your story is rife with amazing visuals, from the frigid sea to the icy tundra. Just reading all of it made me feel cold! But it wasn’t mired in description, either. How do you find the balance between too much and too little description?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Amanda: I actually consider settings in stories to be one of my weak points, so I&#8217;m really glad to hear that you felt this one! Working in short stories more has allowed me to really drill down on sensation in setting by being very slow and deliberate in my descriptions and visuals. It usually takes me a lot longer to write three thousand words of a short story than it does to write the same amount of a novel. I often read back over what is written every time I return to the text and tweak the language, which I don&#8217;t let myself do for novel or novella-length works.</div>
<div></div>
<div>For Bronne&#8217;s world I spent a lot of time just trying to visualize the landscape in my head. Pinterest certainly didn&#8217;t hurt! I also took a lot of winter walks, which I enjoy doing anyway, especially when there&#8217;s snow on the ground. There&#8217;s something really lovely about being cold when there&#8217;s no expectation to be warm. It&#8217;s very peaceful.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Bronne’s transformation throughout the story is subtle, yet striking. How did you get the idea for a woman slowly becoming part of the ice?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>​Amanda: I actually wrote another story before this one that is set in the same world many years later. Bronne features in that one as well, though not by name. I found myself really interested to learn how she came to be in the place she found herself, and telling her backstory turned into something far more poignant and heart-wrenching to me than the original tale. I do still enjoy that story though, and I hope it finds a home someday.</div>
<div><span style="color: #c82613;"> </span></div>
<div>My inspiration for the original story was actually a little bit based on George R.R. Martin&#8217;s <a href="http://www.georgerrmartin.com/grrm_book/the-ice-dragon/"><em>The Ice Dragon</em></a>, which is a short novella he published a few years ago that featured a little girl immune to cold who rode on the back of a dragon that could freeze things with its breath. In the end it became a very different story, as these things do.</div>
<div><span class="im"><br />
<em><strong>LSQ: Despite the frozen motif, your story has a surprising amount of warmth to it brought by the characters’ love. Do you have any advice on writing about this abstract concept?</strong></em></span></div>
<div><span class="im"><br />
</span>​Amanda: One of the challenges of writing a story when you know the ending you have to get to is that it can be hard to give the characters volition and to make the reader feel for them and to feel their emotions. I wanted this story to be about making hard choices, and loss, and mostly gentleness.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I can say that, for a short story especially, if I read over the story myself as the writer and don&#8217;t feel at least a little echo of the emotions I intended to evoke, then I feel that I have failed. If I can make myself cry, or laugh, or feel love, then that is the first hurdle. This obviously makes editing hard sometimes!</div>
<div></div>
<div>Writing any emotion is tricky but love is especially tricky because we don&#8217;t always realize it is there. It&#8217;s a very quiet emotion that you have to stop and listen to when other, louder feelings are banging the drums. It is the genesis of many of those louder feelings. So I think that is probably the best advice I can give when thinking about writing it &#8211; pay attention to those louder feelings, but walk them back to find the core of what has motivated your character to feel that way. It&#8217;s good advice for life, too, I think.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>​Amanda: I think my favorite part of writing the story was all of the colors that it turns out ice can be. It&#8217;s really very beautiful. Otherwise, I actually discovery-wrote a lot of this. I knew I needed Bronne to get to where she was going, but I didn&#8217;t know how she would grow on the journey. Her relationships and the people she touched &#8211; a lot of it was a surprise for me, but in the best way.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Amanda: ​I am working on so many things! Right now I&#8217;m actually revising a serial novella I plan to publish through my Patreon over the next year. It&#8217;s a modern-day Bluebeard retelling set in Vermont. A little dark, but I really enjoyed writing it.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I also am working on two novels simultaneously because I am a glutton for punishment. One is a science fiction story with flooded cities, soaring towers of glass, and one very unlucky thief. The other is an urban fantasy with murders, what I suspect are probably demons, and an unwise romance. We&#8217;ll see how they go! I would have much rather just picked one, but both of them keep knocking around in my brain so I&#8217;ve given in.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 037 author interview: Janna Layton and &#8220;The Mare of the Meuse&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-janna-layton-and-the-mare-of-the-meuse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 10:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 037]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12909</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the wonderful world of Issue 037! Are you enjoying the stories as much&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14973 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/annie-spratt-195259-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/annie-spratt-195259-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/annie-spratt-195259-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/annie-spratt-195259-unsplash-1024x682.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Welcome to the wonderful world of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-037/">Issue 037</a>! Are you enjoying the stories as much as we are? How about getting a glimpse into the mind of one of our authors, Janna Layton? Read on to learn more about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-mare-of-the-meuse/">The Mare of the Meuse</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p class="m_1183893313031520355ydp3e7a781MsoNormalCxSpFirst"><b><em>LSQ: The setting of this story is as important as the characters René and Armand. What inspired you to place this story during the French Revolution?</em> </b></p>
<p class="m_1183893313031520355ydp3e7a781MsoNormalCxSpMiddle">Janna: The French Revolution is just so . . . bonkers. It’s history and humanity at their most complex and messy. If you want black-and-white, clear-cut heroes and villains, look elsewhere. Robespierre, that civil rights lawyer who was against the death penalty? He becomes a mass murderer strutting around a fake mountain as part of the Festival of the Supreme Being. Charlotte Corday assassinated politician Jean-Paul Marat in an attempt to stop the state-ordered killings, but they ramped up instead. People took action with intention, but everything just kept spiraling out of control.</p>
<p class="m_1183893313031520355ydp3e7a781MsoNormalCxSpMiddle">The current reality here in the US is obviously different, but there’s still that sense of extreme disorientation, that reality has been pulled out from under us, and no one knows how it’s going to end up. That was definitely on my mind when putting myself in René and Armand’s shoes.</p>
<p class="m_1183893313031520355ydp3e7a781MsoNormalCxSpMiddle">Being able to include late 18<sup>th  </sup> century fashion was a clear bonus.</p>
<p class="m_1183893313031520355ydp3e7a781MsoNormalCxSpMiddle"><em><b>LSQ: Your story points out that unicorns are historically dainty and white while the one here is strong and piebald. Tell us why you made her look the way she does.</b></em></p>
<div>Janna: Well, she had to carry two adult men, so there’s that! I love <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lady_and_the_Unicorn" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lady_and_the_Unicorn&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1550796520692000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG0K5yz2vTvnbVygEy2hUzuTxk2lw">The Lady and the Unicorn tapestries</a>, but no one is riding that animal. The fun thing about unicorns is that since they’re imaginary, you can have them look however you want and however best fits the story. Haruki Murakami’s inventive take on them in <i>Hard-Boiled Wonderland and the End of the World </i>is very different than Peter S. Beagle’s in <i>The Last Unicorn</i>. I have another story where unicorns are shorter and stocky, a bit more like wild Przewalski&#8217;s horses. Do unicorns look more like Shetland ponies or rhinoceroses? Up to the writer/artist/daydreamer!</div>
<p class="m_1183893313031520355ydp3e7a781MsoNormalCxSpMiddle"><em><b>LSQ: Virgins handling unicorns and the Cheval Mallet &#8211; various unicorn folklore is mentioned in this story, but Orinda doesn&#8217;t follow the pattern. In writing this piece, how much did you want to follow the known unicorn folklore versus making up your own?</b></em></p>
<div>Janna: For this story’s folklore, I stuck with what Armand and René would “know” of unicorns for their time and place. Nowadays we tend to think of unicorns as sweet and gentle, but that wasn’t always the case—hence their fear. Stumbling across the Cheval Mallet was a fortuitous Wikipedia find (full disclosure: I work for the Wikimedia Foundation). There seem to be a few stories across cultures warning against getting on some random horse (kelpies, Cheval Gauvin, etc).</div>
<div></div>
<p class="m_1183893313031520355ydp3e7a781MsoNormalCxSpMiddle"><em><b>LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect of this story to write and why? What was the most fun?</b></em></p>
<p class="m_1183893313031520355ydp3e7a781MsoNormalCxSpMiddle">Janna: I’ll be honest: this story started as a submission to an anthology with a very specific <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14974 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/pierre-chatel-innocenti-1132335-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/pierre-chatel-innocenti-1132335-unsplash-240x300.jpg 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/pierre-chatel-innocenti-1132335-unsplash-768x960.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/pierre-chatel-innocenti-1132335-unsplash-819x1024.jpg 819w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" />prompt, and was rejected. I was disappointed, because I had thought it would be a good fit. But I loved René and Armand, and couldn’t give up on them and their story, so I had to rework it without the anthology-specific element, which was significant. I doubted myself a lot, but kept going, and loved the eventual outcome.</p>
<div>The most fun was being with the characters and also being vicariously back in France. A few years ago, my sister and I were vacationing in Paris and made a day trip to Sedan, because I’m also really interested in the Franco-Prussian War. We saw the Meuse River there, so I was excited to bring that into the story.</div>
<div></div>
<p class="m_1183893313031520355ydp3e7a781MsoNormalCxSpMiddle"><em><b>LSQ: In your mind, does Orinda take the men to safety or to hell? Or, given their circumstances, is there really a difference, as the men seem to deliberate themselves?</b></em></p>
<p class="m_1183893313031520355ydp3e7a781MsoNormalCxSpMiddle">Janna: Where do they end up? I’ll leave that to the reader!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 037 Author Interview: Jennifer Donohue and &#8220;For Whatever We Lose&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-jennifer-donohue-and-for-whatever-we-lose/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 037]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 037 continues to rock and today we&#8217;re excited to share an interview with author&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-037/">Issue 037</a> continues to rock and today we&#8217;re excited to share an interview with author Jennifer Donohue about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/for-whatever-we-lose/">For Whatever We Lose</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Popular music is significant to your characters. Can you comment on how a certain song can evoke powerful memories and why this is so important in your story?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14918 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63029-unsplash-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63029-unsplash-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63029-unsplash-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63029-unsplash-768x770.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63029-unsplash-1022x1024.jpg 1022w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63029-unsplash-550x550.jpg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Jennifer: I think research states that scent memories are the strongest, but it seems like music memories produce a far more visceral feeling for me. Certain songs are like a needle dropping into the record grooves of my brain, and there are some songs that I know I&#8217;ve heard all my life; there&#8217;s such a deep seated sense of satisfaction every time I hear one, like finally reaching an itch. Anytime I got in the car with my dad, the radio was on. I have the same habit.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I also think that sometimes, when you don’t have the emotional vocabulary for what’s going on, music can help bridge that gap. Sometimes things are just too sensitive to touch, emotionally speaking, but if you can hear the right song, share the right song, it helps to get around that.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: How far in the future do you imagine this story taking place?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Jennifer: I didn’t have a specific year in mind for it, but before a crewed mission is sent to Mars proper. I think NASA pretty recently put the year 2029 on that goal, so I&#8217;d have to say 2027, if they&#8217;re going to meet that deadline. I wrote this story prior to that announcement, though, so in my head it was more like 2040. If we get there sooner, that&#8217;d be great.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It&#8217;s actually been a profound disappointment of mine that humans haven&#8217;t yet returned to the moon during my lifetime. I don&#8217;t think we ever should&#8217;ve stopped those missions, and I feel like there might be a better sense (any sense?) of global unity had they continued. I think of this often, especially when considering the <a href="http://www.planetary.org/explore/space-topics/earth/pale-blue-dot.html">Pale Blue Dot photo</a> taken by Voyager 1. Earth is what we have. It&#8217;s everybody, living and dead, right here. That is humbling and terrifying and other -ing words I&#8217;m sure about, and that perspective is I think a valuable one to keep in mind.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Some of the most intriguing aspects of the main character, Suzanne, are unsaid. For her to be chosen as the one astronaut for the mission, she must have been extremely qualified (even to become an astronaut to start with) and yet she doesn&#8217;t mention her accolades at all. Can you comment on her character?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Jennifer: I suppose I could’ve covered her Top Gun journey in some way, but honestly, I didn’t think of it. The story is such a narrow slice of crisis-time, and those earthbound exploits don’t really intersect with her musings on her dad and those involved feelings. It didn’t seem like it needed to be told, which does admittedly leave gaps for the reader. Maybe someday I’ll write a prologue of sorts, or a companion piece, but there’s something I like about a story that happens later. After the main adventure, after the dragon was slain, after all of the blood and sweat and tears to become an astronaut.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: What did you draw on to create such a strong father-daughter bond in the story? Where did your inspiration for the characters, their relationship, and the NASA mission come from?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Jennifer: I am not a pilot or an astronaut; other than that, this story is entirely autobiographical. I <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14919 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63032-unsplash-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63032-unsplash-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63032-unsplash-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63032-unsplash-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63032-unsplash-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/nasa-63032-unsplash-550x550.jpg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />did meet an astronaut, <a href="https://www.spaceanswers.com/space-exploration/heroes-of-space-pete-conrad/">Pete Conrad</a>, when he was on some kind of a speaking tour to get kids interested in space. I was younger than the age range the program dictated, and I do still have his autographed picture. I did lose my balloon.</p>
<p dir="ltr">When I was little, I thought that radio worked the same was TV did, so I would ask my dad when “Werewolves of London” would be on, and he’d tell me something like “oh, five minutes.” When I was little enough to have the radio confusion, I also couldn&#8217;t really tell time yet, so this strategy worked out pretty well, I guess. I don’t remember what beer it was that had that werewolf cutout at the liquor store (Bud Light? Was that the silver bullet, in the 80s?) that howled and talked when you walked past. I did swim out just a little too far out once, a little too close to the jetty at Asbury Park, and my dad did beat the lifeguard to me. I do remember saying “I’m okay” and his reply.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I do have that empty Wish You Were Here jewel case. I do have his watch. He and Pete Conrad did both pass in the same way.</p>
<p dir="ltr">My family did go to Florida one spring break, and woke up in the middle of the night to hopefully see a shuttle launch (it must have been delayed; we didn’t have quite the connectivity, in the 90s, to be able to check live updates). With these tidbits of space interest, it’s kind of a wonder that I never tried to go down any kind of NASA career path, but I didn’t.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: It seems Suzanne&#8217;s situation is fatal, but can the reader interpret NASA&#8217;s reply that there are &#8220;a couple of options&#8221; with a glimmer of hope?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Jennifer: I suppose there’s always hope? ‘Does she survive’ isn’t a question I was asking.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 037 Author Interview: Jasmine Smith and &#8220;Into the Flames&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-jasmine-smith-and-into-the-flames/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-jasmine-smith-and-into-the-flames/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 037]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 037 is filled with 12 stories by women-identifying authors and is ready for your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14808 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/color-crescent-536330-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/color-crescent-536330-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/color-crescent-536330-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/color-crescent-536330-unsplash-1024x681.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Issue 037 is filled with 12 stories by women-identifying authors and is ready for your eyes! Today we get to pick the brain of Issue 037 author Jasmine Smith, about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/into-the-flames/">Into the Flames</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div><b><em>LSQ: Given the political intrigue as well as the literal funeral pyre in your story, can you speak to the meaning behind the title?</em><br />
</b></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jasmine: Usually, as I&#8217;m writing a story, my title changes drastically as I rewrite and dig deep into what the story is really about. But, I knew that flames were going to be a part of this title from the very beginning. I came up with the initial idea while sitting in my Shakespeare class discussing <em>Julius Caesar</em> and I had thoughts of love and betrayal and revenge running through my mind. That&#8217;s when I imagined the character that would become Laila standing in front of this massive fire and I knew that it was her lover&#8217;s funeral. So, the title has always just made sense to me, not only because of Jamila&#8217;s fate but also because Laila is jumping into the flames in a sense by seeking revenge for Jamila&#8217;s death.</div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div><b><em>LSQ: Can you talk a bit about the goddess Baast in your story? Is your world inspired by ancient Egypt in any way? What were your inspirations and influences for the culture you&#8217;ve created?</em><br />
</b></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jasmine: Growing up, I didn&#8217;t read a lot of fantasy stories with dark skinned characters who looked like me. They were mostly inspired by European history and filled with white princesses and my early writing reflected that. I didn&#8217;t write about black girls because I didn&#8217;t realize that we could be the protagonists of our own stories. It&#8217;s only been more recently with the push for more diversity in publishing that I&#8217;ve been able to see characters who look like me. So, I wrote a story where everyone is a person of color. Laila is a beautiful black girl with thick braids and dark skin. Her mother, Baast, is certainly inspired by the Egyptian goddess Bastet or Bast, but they&#8217;re not the same. Baast is the goddess of war and she is not a cat goddess at all.</div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div><b><em>LSQ: How nice and notable it is that Laila herself is a palace guard. Tell us a bit more about her character and why you gave her the profession she has.</em><br />
</b></div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div>Jasmine: Laila is the daughter of the goddess Baast and the Emperor of the Khenesian Empire. Before she works for Jamila, she is a soldier in her father&#8217;s army. War is in her blood, literally. Look at who her mother is. She is supposed to be able to protect her loved ones, so it makes the situation with Jamila that much more tragic.</div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div><b><em>LSQ: What was the most challenging part about this story to write, and why? What was the most enjoyable part?</em><br />
</b></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jasmine: The ending was both the most challenging and the most enjoyable part of writing this <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14809 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/oscar-obians-251885-unsplash-300x201.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="201" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/oscar-obians-251885-unsplash-300x201.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/oscar-obians-251885-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/oscar-obians-251885-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />story. I am so grateful to the members of my fiction writing workshop. They gave me so much great feedback and I wouldn&#8217;t have ended up with the draft I did without them. The ending was such a struggle because at first I ended it too quickly. I wanted to wrap the story up with a pretty bow and a satisfying end, but I realized that wasn&#8217;t going to happen. Yes, the story is the end of Laila&#8217;s journey of revenge, but it&#8217;s certainly not the end of her grief and it&#8217;s not the end of her journey in life. So, I ended it the only way I knew how, which was allowing her the chance to finally grieve. To cry in her mother&#8217;s arms, the arms of an unyielding warrior goddess, who at the end of the day is just her mom. Writing an ending you&#8217;re happy with is the most satisfying feeling in the world. <b></b></div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div><b><em>LSQ: Do you know what the future holds for the citizens in this story? Will Laila ascend the throne? Why or why not?</em><br />
</b></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jasmine: I do know what the future holds for the people of el-Faiyum. I love this world so much. Laila is one of my favorite characters I&#8217;ve written and I definitely have more stories in my head waiting to be released into the world. So, I don&#8217;t want to say too much, but Laila is not going to ascend the throne. el-Faiyum will become the tenth territory in her father&#8217;s empire. She has two older brothers, as mentioned in the story, so she&#8217;s too far down in the line of succession to ascend any throne most likely. As the daughter of a goddess, she is one of the most influential people in her world, so there will be more adventures in store for her.</div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us about them?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jasmine: I&#8217;m currently editing a draft of a young adult contemporary novel. It follows a sixteen-year-old girl as she navigates her first romance and the toll that it unexpectedly takes on the most important relationship in her life which is her relationship with her best friend. It also deals with mental health and is very near and dear to my heart.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-jasmine-smith-and-into-the-flames/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 037 Author Interview: Sarah Pauling and &#8220;Auger&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-sarah-pauling-and-auger/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 037]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 037 is out with twelve speculative fiction stories by women-identifying authors. This week we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-037/">Issue 037</a> is out with twelve speculative fiction stories by women-identifying authors. This week we chatted with author Sarah Pauling about her Issue 037 story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/auger/">Auger</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14742 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/jeremy-bishop-127366-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/jeremy-bishop-127366-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/jeremy-bishop-127366-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/jeremy-bishop-127366-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />LSQ: Let&#8217;s talk mermaids (and sirens). Your mermaid appears to have legs. Can you explain why you gave her the features, both physical and emotional, that you did? Is there a larger backstory (or origin story) to her than what appears in your story? </strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: Readers tend to notice the legs! While our current popular mermaid lore does include the tail, “sea women” appear in various myths around the world with varying physical qualities. Sirens, those evil creatures that influenced the mermaid myth down the line, often had wings and bird legs rather than fish tails. Most of these myths are tied together by two basic themes: the ocean and an essential female-ness viewed through male eyes.</p>
<p>That femininity is often read as predatory. Sailors say men are lured to their dooms by evil temptresses who want to be chased. The reverberations of that story sounded too familiar to me; they read differently in this era. I find myself wanting to know the siren’s side of the story.</p>
<p>As to this particular mermaid’s backstory, I believe she’s always been this way: an alien intelligence who isn’t opposed to meeting the young species up on the shore. They seem nice, right? What could go wrong?</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This mermaid seems to be a complicated creature. Can you talk about her ultimate reaction toward Bartram versus her response to Inga? Is there an unspoken connection between the two young women, perhaps having to do with Bartram? </strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: The mermaid believes that Inga needs a knife. She sees what this boy they both trusted is capable of, and she sees a person who has not been taught to defend herself—or that she is allowed to. While I don’t know that the mermaid is a “woman” in the same way that Inga is—being a “woman,” I think, requires interaction with a larger society—she does feel a connection in the way she’s been treated in her short time on shore.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Can you compare and contrast the two brothers, Bartram and Henrik? How do their differing personalities impact their fate? </strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: Someone who studies domestic violence once told me that although the “cycle of abuse” is real (especially when intersecting with cultural notions of masculinity and toughness), many men who were treated badly in childhood instead learn to tune into their own emotions in a healthier way. They gain empathy for the abused, and they turn their thoughts towards gentleness. Many of the wonderful men in my life share this trait.</p>
<p>While this story is more about cultural violence—I doubt Bartram and Henrik’s father is out of the ordinary in this world—I believe that a “sensitive kid” in a pressing culture of hypermasculinity can react to that pain in a few ways. It’s not so much that Bartram and Henrik started out differently, but that they started the same.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Can you talk about the recurring sea items in the story, such as the auger shells and the amber? What made these items special to you to include here? </strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: I had the chance to visit Copenhagen for work a couple of years ago. I visited a couple of <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14743 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/brianda-maldonado-741347-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/brianda-maldonado-741347-unsplash-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/brianda-maldonado-741347-unsplash-768x1155.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/brianda-maldonado-741347-unsplash-681x1024.jpg 681w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" />museums, one of which told me all about Vikings and the ancient cultural importance of amber in Scandinavia. Necklaces and honey-colored animal trinkets—elk and bears—lay side-by-side. They were used for trade, for art, and possibly for protection. Besides grounding the story more thoroughly in a sense of place, the mermaid’s gift of amber could be read as a clue to her great age. It also ties her to Inga, whose first amber necklace was cut and polished by her culture but made up of the same wild substance as the mermaid’s gift.</p>
<p>Auger shells, on the other hand, are not culturally-specific. They come from a predatory sea creature and they’re sharp.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Where did the inspiration for this story come from? </strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: I was fortunate enough to study abroad in college, where I took a course on Spanish love stories (broadly-defined and often tragic). Sirens were a recurring element. I realized that there is no special word for “mermaid” in Spanish: mermaids and sirens are the same concept entirely, with some stories making them more predatory than others. This prompted me to do a lot of research on the origins of the myth(s). Things came together further during that work trip to Scandinavia when I saw the Little Mermaid statue on a promenade near a grove of cherry trees and a bastion fort. She’s smaller than she looks in the pictures.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging part of this story to write and why? What was the most enjoyable and why? </strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: My first draft made Bartram a hero. The climax left all wrongdoing to a third-party teenage sailor-jock in the afterglow of his first trip to sea. With some helpful feedback, I realized that this was the easy way out. To say what I wanted to say, the conflict had to be between the brothers. Bartram of the scrawny arms and soft feelings for Inga had to be the one who went over the edge for this plausibly-deniable “temptress.” Creating this story, rather than the previous one, was much harder.</p>
<p>As for the positives: it was a joy being inside Henrik’s head. I liked trying to capture a certain innocence in his burgeoning friendship with a creepy but curious newcomer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 037 Author Interview: K. Noel Moore and &#8220;A Song for Hardy Connelly&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-037-author-interview-k-noel-moore-and-a-song-for-hardy-connelly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 10:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 037]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another week, another celebration of the amazing stories and their authors in our latest Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14689 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/jon-tyson-767250-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/jon-tyson-767250-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/jon-tyson-767250-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />Another week, another celebration of the amazing stories and their authors in our latest <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-037/">Issue 037</a>. This week we&#8217;ve chatted with K. Noel Moore about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/a-song-for-hardy-connelly/">A Song for Hardy Connelly</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The presence of Celtic history and culture is strong throughout the story. Do you have an Irish background? What made you pick this backdrop for your story? Have you written other pieces that involve Celtic folklore?</strong></em></p>
<p>K.N.: I am utterly fascinated with the history, culture, and lore of Ireland. Funnily enough, it has nothing to do with being raised in that culture; while I have some Irish roots on my dad&#8217;s side, I was primarily raised in my mom&#8217;s culture, which is Eastern European. The pull I felt to Ireland developed as I grew up, and I can&#8217;t really explain it. Hell, maybe I had a past life there &#8212; that would make as much sense to me as anything! I&#8217;ve written a lot based in both Ireland and Irish America (a fascinating entity in and of itself), including my in-progress second novella, which I&#8217;ll elaborate on later.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your description of American Sign Language in the dialogue feels natural and authentic. Do you have experience with ASL yourself? Where there any challenges in including this form of language in your writing? </strong></em></p>
<p>K.N.: I’m actually studying to be an ASL interpreter! I deliberately wrote the Signed phrases in “A Song For Hardy Connelly” as exact transcriptions of ASL word order, because I wanted it to feel as authentic as possible. I wanted to get people interested in this wonderful language through my story. Sometimes, it was a challenge to communicate what I wanted in that way — as it is when I’m actually Signing; I’m still far from fluent but I considered it a learning experience.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us more about the relationship between Hardy and her parents and then between Hardy and Moira. What creates that bond between Moira and Hardy? Is it because they both feel like outcasts? Did Moira choose her standing in the family or was it put upon her?</strong></em></p>
<p>K.N.: Hardy and Moïra’s relationship was somewhat inspired by my own with my aunt Kelly <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-14690 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/david-papillon-1142305-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/david-papillon-1142305-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/david-papillon-1142305-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/david-papillon-1142305-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />(whom this story is dedicated to). She had a stroke in 2009 that left her paralyzed on her left side, and has been a cane and wheelchair user ever since. During her recovery, she briefly lived with my family, and we got very close. I’d still say that she’s the member of my family that I’m closest to. Within the context of the story, though, the relationships between members of the Connelly family revolve around their responses to the curse. I think Moïra’s outcast status is a combination of chosen and assigned: she was frustrated with the passive way the rest of the family handled it, and so she acted out, raging against this thing she didn’t want to define her. That rage alienated her from her brother, and eventually his wife. Hardy feels immediately drawn to Moïra because she feels the same frustration. (I think she also resents her parents for treating her disabilities as burdens or punishments, so at the time she meets Moïra she is desperately searching for someone else to lean on — someone who will actually support her.)</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do you know what&#8217;s in Hardy&#8217;s future? Does she get to hear her song? </strong></em></p>
<p>K.N.: I think the ending implies that she’s already hearing her song — “the flute music of the Other Place,” as Moïra puts it — and she’s chasing after it. What she’ll find on the other side, I have no idea. I leave that to your imagination.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>K.N.: I’m pretty much constantly working on new short stories. As I write this, my current WIP is what I describe as a “superhuman de-origin story” (about a character losing his superpowers, rather than gaining them), based around the Whitey Bulger years in Boston and the beginnings of WITSEC. It’s fascinating, although the process is moving at a snail’s pace. I’m also, as I said, working on my second novella, tentatively titled <i>Incendiary Devices</i>. It’s set in Belfast at the height of the Troubles; its main character makes a bargain with the mythical figure An Mórrígan, using the war goddess&#8217;s magic to aid in IRA campaigns&#8230;only to find herself growing disillusioned with the movement, and her newfound abilities spiraling out of control. It&#8217;s much grander in scale than my first novella, so it&#8217;s a challenge, but an exciting one!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
