<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Heart of the Genres &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-heart-of-the-genres/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:09:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Save Me from Modern YA Girls</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/save-me-from-modern-ya-girls/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Calee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Heart of the Genres]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15676</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many books have some flaws, particularly character flaws. I understand that since my genre of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Many books have some flaws, particularly character flaws. I understand that since my genre of choice is paranormal romance. As I ranted many times before, romance is predictable and unrealistic since the woman always “gets” her man in the end. However, paranormal is flawed as well in its overly masculine approach to strength. Big burly men—excluding vampire (I don’t know why vampires are usually tall, lean, and refined) of course—dominate the paranormal worlds. Even the paranormal heroines have a masculine edge with their “ponytails swishing ass-kicking boot-wearing no time for sensitivity or skin care” attitudes.</p>
<p>Authors’ worlds are imperfect, and I’m fine with that imperfection. Please understand that I am not unreasonable even as I tell you a current Young Adult (YA) trend angers me beyond reason&#8211;the school bully trope.</p>
<p>I hated high school, and YA just made the experience worse.</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-15677 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Lunar-Chronicles-Collage-Final-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="257" height="257" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Lunar-Chronicles-Collage-Final-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Lunar-Chronicles-Collage-Final-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Lunar-Chronicles-Collage-Final-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Lunar-Chronicles-Collage-Final-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Lunar-Chronicles-Collage-Final-550x550.jpg 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Lunar-Chronicles-Collage-Final.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 257px) 100vw, 257px" />I browse YA because they often have fun reads. The plots are thoughtful, and the characters may be interesting interpretations of common characters like Marissa Meyer’s <em>Lunar Chronicles</em>, a science fiction twist on well-known fairy tale princesses like Cinderella, Snow White, and Little Red Riding Hood. These ladies are badass, strong, and smart even as they live up to the fairy tale standards—making bad decisions, meeting some guy, and falling in love.</p>
<p>However, many recent YA girls have entered their last years of high school—according to    many, many authors—and they are being bullied. These protagonists are bullied by the popular kids, the poor kids, the smart kids, the misfit kids. Everyone hates these girls, and again, I understand this situation.</p>
<p>Novels are often based on imperfect worlds. Besides, bullying is a particularly hot button issue in our schools today, so fiction is a great opportunity to address the challenges of modern high schools. Authors should use their voices—<em>excuse me,</em> pens—to shed light on discrimination, mistreatment, abuse, and more that occur within modern schools. <img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-15681 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Shadow-Academy-3-s-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="174" height="261" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Shadow-Academy-3-s-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Shadow-Academy-3-s.jpg 500w" sizes="(max-width: 174px) 100vw, 174px" /></p>
<p>However, I cringe and shake my head when I read the implications of the protagonist&#8217;s actions. The trend conveys horrible messages to vulnerable girls.</p>
<p>First, female protagonist after female protagonist hangs her head in shame as she is bullied. The characters vow to just suffer through <u>one more year</u> of the uninvited (no, bullying is never invited) pain and ridicule of faculty, students, even parents. The girls’ salvation is knowing they will be legal adults by graduation. These girls never go to an adult. They never talk to the police. They never show evidence of their abuse. And even worse, no adult seems to notice or care. <img decoding="async" class=" wp-image-15682 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/shadowspell-book-2-189x300.jpg" alt="" width="173" height="274" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/shadowspell-book-2-189x300.jpg 189w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/shadowspell-book-2.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 173px) 100vw, 173px" /></p>
<p>Sure, seeking help in these situations can feel impossible. Plus, I recall instances when reporting the behavior hurt the victim more than the assailant, so reporting bullying is difficult and not for everyone. However, how about a little therapy because “put your head down and wait for the pain to end” is not a good lesson for teenage girls. Yes, some adults can become caught up in their own life drama, but usually, someone in the world cares and responds to abuse. And yes, unfortunately, the victim is mistreated for coming forward, but do we want our young women believing they should hide their mistreatment rather than speak to someone—even a counselor or a therapist—rather than hang their heads and hide behind the thick curtains of hair hiding the girls from watchful eyes? <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-15683 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/supernatural-academy.jpg" alt="" width="241" height="241" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/supernatural-academy.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/supernatural-academy-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 241px) 100vw, 241px" /></p>
<p>Second, these young characters fall in love with their abusers. In every one of the high school books, the rich, popular, attractive people (also known as the kings and queens of the schools) bully these girls. The bullying takes on an array of mistreatment from physical pushing and beating to name calling and mind games.</p>
<p>One magical bully cast a spell to cause the protagonist to relive her parents’ murders in her nightmares. Another girl’s magical mistreatment was so severe, she thought she was losing her mind. Another group of bullies bets on which of them would have sex with the girl first. At the graduation recital, the students beat her up off stage, displayed nude photos of her on stage, then another group kicked and shoved her in the mud off stage. These events occurred after the bullies had driven away from the protagonist&#8217;s two friends. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-15684 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/brayshaw-high.jpg" alt="" width="183" height="275" /></p>
<p>These situations are too horrible for any child to endure, but when the girls fall in love with these guys, I dry heave as I question the author&#8217;s sanity. How could anyone love these men? (Yes, I’ve heard of Stockholm Syndrome. And yes, some of the girls are wooed.) The guys who kicked the muddy girl on graduation day spent half of the day drawing her in even as they criticized and subtly heckled her. I suppose if the girl ignores the males’ initial bad behavior and focused on the recent indifferent behavior, then it looks like love, right?</p>
<p>Ah, naw. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-15678 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/secret-girl-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="214" height="214" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/secret-girl-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/secret-girl-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/secret-girl-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/secret-girl-550x550.jpg 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/secret-girl.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 214px) 100vw, 214px" /></p>
<p>Despite what these authors tell, good behavior doesn’t negate bad behavior especially if there are no apologies, public correction, amends, or demand that other students stop their bad behavior. One girl slept with three of her four male bullies, within a month, and recognized her mistake the next day after each encounter.</p>
<p>I don’t fault an adult for having sex with three guys in a month. I don’t fault her for making bad choices—they were the wrong guys. However, I fault the author and the character for assuming bullies are okay when they stop bullying. I fault the author and character when hot and rich trumps broadcasting the girl’s personal business and mocking her feelings for her dead parents.  I fault an author who pairs a girl with a guy who said she can apologize on her knees and her mouth open. (Yeah, he’s a catch.) <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-15687 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/void-181x300.jpg" alt="" width="160" height="265" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/void-181x300.jpg 181w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/void.jpg 302w" sizes="(max-width: 160px) 100vw, 160px" /></p>
<p>Again, this choice sets a bad example for young girls. The girl’s behavior and her quick acceptance of these lovers look like emotion over reason. Girls need to think about the choices they make and not jump into behaviors they’ll regret the next day. Plus, these stories tell their readers the girls are bullied because the guys like the girls (come on, that’s a terrible excuse) and ignore the feelings of hurt, betrayal, and anxiety because he’s cute and rich (which is awful advice). Even worse, the girls accept such superficial affection: he spends time with her (away from his bullying friends); they talk (like most humans should); he does something nice for her (again, like a good human); his touch made her feel good (umm, doesn’t that happen when reasonably intelligent and attractive men engage?).</p>
<p>Yes, YA paranormal romance needs some romance, but could we please raise the bar a little and teach readers some self-respect and thought?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Confessions of the Unread</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/confessions-of-the-unread/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Calee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Heart of the Genres]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OMG! I’ve been reading the same book since November; I&#8217;m still not done. This situation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OMG! I’ve been reading the same book since November; I&#8217;m still not done. This situation is not normal.</p>
<p>&lt;I shake my aching head.&gt;</p>
<p>I eagerly awaited this book. It&#8217;s the final installment of a series that I love, a series that I discovered and read within two years. I finished reading each book within a couple days. I laughed and cried over these books. I highlighted the books’ fantastic lines. When I thought of a poignant plot moment, I read the entire series again. I eagerly anticipated the series’ end.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t understand it. Why haven’t I finished the last book?</p>
<p>I haven’t lost my reading mojo. This book is approximately 250 pages, just a couple hundred pages. That’s nothing to an avid reader. For someone who’s anticipated the book for six months, 200 pages is a same day read. I read several books per week. I&#8217;ve read so many other books and series while I trying to read this one. In fact, I finished a 20-book series back-to-back without hesitation. I excel at binge reading.</p>
<p>Binge reading. I race through books whether they’re sci-fi, fantasy, or romance. There’s no need to rush, yet I do. Because I want to read just one more chapter before I sleep. Then I want to reach the climax. Oh, then I need the protagonist to discover the truth. The stories are so exciting I can’t stop despite early hour on my alarm clock and my swiftly approaching wake up time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-15413 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Pain-188x300.jpg" alt="" width="148" height="236" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Pain-188x300.jpg 188w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/Pain.jpg 217w" sizes="(max-width: 148px) 100vw, 148px" /> And <em>Pain </em>(book 5 of <em>Cursed by the Gods</em>) is exactly what I love to read—i.e., supernatural, romance, reverse harem. So there’s nothing wrong with the story. Well, that’s not true. The characters are all wrong for me. Somehow, the characters ruined the story for me. They changed. The protagonist is no longer the happy-go-lucky klutz I came to love and laugh with. I admit it; after waiting for months, speculating since the beginning, I no longer care about the character’s ending.</p>
<p>To be completely honest, this isn’t the first time I didn’t finish a book. And some of the reasons are kind of silly. I can’t read Mark Twain because I hate the southern accents. I find the language grating and written pronunciations difficult to follow. I never read more than a few pages.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-15414 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/A-simple-favor-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="123" height="186" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/A-simple-favor-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/A-simple-favor.jpg 230w" sizes="(max-width: 123px) 100vw, 123px" /> Recently, I started and stopped a few books—like <em>A Simple Favor</em> by Darcy Bell even though I liked the movie—because of their tones, too. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-15412 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/LeGuin-Gifts-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="122" height="184" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/LeGuin-Gifts-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/LeGuin-Gifts.jpg 230w" sizes="(max-width: 122px) 100vw, 122px" /></p>
<p>I couldn’t finish Le Guin’s <em>Gifts</em> because its pace was too slow.</p>
<p>I can’t read any Neil Gaiman books because I dislike his style.</p>
<p>&lt;My head falls as I cup my heated cheeks.&gt;</p>
<p>Yes, I confess: I don’t like some of the most popular sci-fi and fantasy authors out there. Disliking these treasured authors created so much doubt for me. Am I too dumb for the genre? Has binge reading stripped me of my appreciation of nuance?</p>
<p>Then I delve into excuses. I suspect rebellion. I read authors like Le Guin and Gaiman (and ah, ahem, Octavia Butler) because they were popular, not because I was interested. I worry that mentally they’ve become the line I’ve drawn simply because I’m stubborn. Like how I refused to watch the <em>Godfather</em> movies. (Yep, never.) Now, it is the badge of my uniqueness.</p>
<p>Maybe, I’ll like them later, right?</p>
<p>However, with this confession and a few mantras, a weight has lifted. Not finishing a book doesn’t mean the books are bad. Not finishing a book isn’t shameful. Not finishing a book leaves time to finish a different book.</p>
<p>I realize it&#8217;s not just about admitting my dislikes, it&#8217;s about admitting preferences. Admitting I like romance&#8211;the somewhat predictable, touchy-feely, and occasional formulaic writing&#8211;or even fantasy&#8211;the magic of the unreal&#8211;over sci-fi&#8211;the thoughtful stories that challenge readers&#8217; perceptions&#8211;seems wrong. If I&#8217;m intellectual, then I would prefer a thought-provoking story, right? What does it say about me that I don&#8217;t enjoy innovative writing, embodiment of the genre, and a classic in the making? Don&#8217;t great minds appreciate great works?</p>
<p>However, my confessions&#8217; effects are two fold: worrying that another genre seems smarter than mine seems petty. Maybe. Sometimes. If I love it, does it matter? And I am not alone since not everyone appreciates the classics and the popular.</p>
<p>I know. I know. Just read the book.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Perfectly Wild Premises, How I Love Them</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/perfectly-wild-premises-how-i-love-them/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Calee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Heart of the Genres]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14747</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have you found book perfection? Have you found the book you haven’t mentally rewritten in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you found book perfection?</p>
<p>Have you found the book you haven’t mentally rewritten in your head?</p>
<p>That book you would’ve loved except for [fill in the blank]?</p>
<p>A book that despite its flaws you wouldn’t change a thing because it’s…[sigh] perfect. Well, perfect for you since nothing is truly perfect for everyone. So, I mean the ‘perfect for you’ book.</p>
<p>It’s surprising how rare the perfect book is. After all, I—probably like you—read lots of books each year. I hate a few, but I love many more. I even have dozens of favorites. Yet, something about those beloved books need some changes or just seem wrong somehow. The character’s personality changed a little too much. The dialog’s annoyingly silly. The premise is a little unbelievable.</p>
<p>Well, I recently found my perfect book, books since they’re two series: <a href="https://www.cmowensbooks.com/copy-of-the-dark-side"><em>All the Pretty Monsters</em></a> by <a href="https://www.cmowensbooks.com/kristy-cunning">Kristy Cunning</a> and <a href="https://www.daryndajones.com/category/books/"><em>Charley Davidson </em></a>series by <a href="https://www.daryndajones.com/">Darynda Jones</a>. They’re more than favorites because, despite some flaws, I wouldn’t change a single word.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-14749 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/charley-davidson-272x300.jpg" alt="" width="285" height="314" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/charley-davidson-272x300.jpg 272w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/charley-davidson.jpg 554w" sizes="(max-width: 285px) 100vw, 285px" />So why are they perfect?</p>
<p>It’s everything about them. The characters make me feel, and the flaws seem irrelevant. Today, I want to focus on the premises that enthralled me.</p>
<p>For me, the perfect premise must not only be enjoyable but also be plausible, which is probably why I struggle with sci-fi, which has always been hard for me. I understand the worlds authors have layered into fantastic stories, yet I can’t buy it. Somehow the situation, the conflicts, the characters’ new worlds are too much for me to accept.</p>
<p>The military and robotics engineers teamed up with doctors to create the perfect soldier, but they couldn’t disconnect his feelings from his programming? <em>Ah, naw.</em></p>
<p>Astronauts encounter an unknown species that slowly and methodically kills everyone it encounters? <em>Umm, nooo.</em></p>
<p>But if the premise is a bit fanciful…</p>
<p>A vaguely defined supernatural male needs a vaguely defined supernatural woman’s help in recovering the lost stones of sin before the bad guys find them and enslave the world? Tell me more about those wacky stones.</p>
<p>A grim reaper detective and the devilish convict she dreams about are more than they seem? Oh yeah. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-14753 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/darynda-13-197x300.jpg" alt="" width="171" height="260" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/darynda-13-197x300.jpg 197w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/darynda-13.jpg 329w" sizes="(max-width: 171px) 100vw, 171px" /></p>
<p>A woman who cannot die; instead, she panics, faints, and  become a violent mindless creature? I want the whole series.</p>
<p>I know. I know. How is this plausible? It’s not, but I’m a sucker for paranormal, supernatural, and fantasy. Toss a little romance into the mix, and I love them. Oddly, sci-fi’s romances are mere suggestions.</p>
<p>Anyway, the plots’ cores, as well as the fantastical details, are important.</p>
<p>The two ‘perfect for me’ premises share a common purpose. Charley Davidson is a grim reaper who’s had her power since birth, and Violet Portocale (<em>All the Pretty Monsters</em>) is an unusual monster unlike any seen in a century. And while both women are powerful, they must discover their true powers, purposes, and loves as the stories progress.</p>
<p>This premise is so simple; it’s relatable. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-14748 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-freak-186x300.jpg" alt="" width="165" height="265" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-freak-186x300.jpg 186w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-freak.jpg 310w" sizes="(max-width: 165px) 100vw, 165px" /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-14751 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-blood-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="177" height="266" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-blood-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-blood.jpg 333w" sizes="(max-width: 177px) 100vw, 177px" /></p>
<p>Well, I can’t relate to the plain Jane panicky monster being seduced by four alpha monsters. And, sure, I can’t relate to the grim reaper who falls in love with Satan’s son while working to help her human daughter prepare for Satan’s army.  Those experiences are…unique.</p>
<p>But who hasn’t thought of their life, personhood, or experiences one way, but sudden obstacles or challenging people have created a fresh perspective on them? Who hasn’t struggled to understand who they are and what they contribute to the world? No matter how outlandish the details, the basics connect with me.</p>
<p>Empathizing with the characters’ experience keeps me anxious to know what happens next. My perfect books make me feel.</p>
<p>As I read the last Charley Davidson book, I realized a major plot twist near the story’s end even though I still had 15% of the story to read. The sudden realization should have ruined the book for me. After all, don’t audiences hate it when the plot twists and resolutions are obvious?However, the realization had an opposite effect on me. Charley makes a heartbreaking choice. Even worse, the author deliberately made me see Charley’s sad choice, yet the character maintains her determined, happy disposition so that her friends and family wouldn’t realize the truth. The character struggles with the choice, and I can’t look away. I dragged myself along with her as she moved the preparations.</p>
<p>I felt her despair; I ached for her.</p>
<p><em>All the Pretty Monsters</em>, although the series isn’t over, had the same affect me. Like Charley, Violet finds herself slapped by reality.</p>
<p>Violet struggles to discover why—why her mother’s ghost didn’t come to her, why her mother taught her to faint rather than fight, why is she the only monster of her kind, and why did her mother send her to a monster hunter? So many unanswered questions. As the story progresses, she spends more time with the monsters, and she discovers her answers to her whys, answers she neither hoped for nor expected. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-14752 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-origins-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="175" height="263" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-origins-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-origins.jpg 333w" sizes="(max-width: 175px) 100vw, 175px" /></p>
<p>Sadly, Violet discovers she is not special; instead, she is a means to an end, no matter how much her guys deny it. Her guys disappoint her; her mother disappoints her. She learns to trust unexpected allies, and she loses those who are important to her. She discovers a flippant comment from a friend is true. They hurt my heart to share her experiences as her hopes for <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-14750 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-moon-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="186" height="278" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-moon-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/gypsy-moon.jpg 333w" sizes="(max-width: 186px) 100vw, 186px" />more love, meaning, and loyalty are dashed.</p>
<p>Like many people, I can relate to wishing a relationship is more than it is, hoping to achieve grander aspirations but realizing destiny is ordinary.</p>
<p>Still, Violet’s story includes a little too much sex, but it is a reverse harem story. And Charley’s level of crazy is “laugh out loud” over the top at times. However, every word draws me closer to the characters until I feel like they are best friends I know better than anyone else.</p>
<p>Making <em>All the Pretty Monsters</em> and the Charley Davidson series perfect for me.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Laughed, I Cried with the Characters</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/i-laughed-i-cried-with-the-characters/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/i-laughed-i-cried-with-the-characters/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 10:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Heart of the Genres]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=14727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are Janet Evanovich’s novels romance, fantasy, or paranormal? No matter which genre I search, her&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are Janet Evanovich’s novels romance, fantasy, or paranormal? No matter which genre I search, her books appear, but I avoided her because of my current frustration (check out <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/just-one-or-twelve-whichever-2/">February&#8217;s post</a>). Evanovich’s books <em>aren’t</em> sci-fi, fantasy, or paranormal; technically, her works might not even qualify as romance.</p>
<p>So why does she keep appearing? Why is she so popular?</p>
<p>I finally gave in to temptation. I tried the <a href="https://www.evanovich.com/lizzy-and-diesel-series/"><em>Lizzy and Diesel</em></a> series; then I tried the <em>Stephanie Plum</em> series. Well, five books later, I was shocked. <a href="http://b60.a63.mwp.accessdomain.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/stephanieplum.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-12693 alignright" src="http://b60.a63.mwp.accessdomain.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/stephanieplum.jpg" alt="" width="368" height="368" /></a> Stephanie Plum is a New Jersey bounty hunter, who quite luckily finds her criminals, with twenty-five novels in her series. Twenty-five criminals, plans that go awry, near misses, and eventual take downs. I read the books, and I know what to expect every time, yet I keep reading.</p>
<p>Janet.</p>
<p>Evanovich’s.</p>
<p>Characters.</p>
<p>Are.</p>
<p>Awesome.</p>
<p>The plots were interesting, with events funny and unexpected, but her characters made me keep reading. The people in these stories seem unique, real, and authentic.</p>
<p>A lot of writing advice talks about character development: the character mustn’t be too perfect. She must be flawed, relatable, and unique. This advice is mostly true since my favorite characters blurt out the wrong things at the wrong time, act aggressively, or are moody SOBs. However, those flaws become annoying quickly if they are the only distinguishing characteristics. Honestly, I know quite a few “unique” real personalities, but I wouldn’t want to read their stories. So, the advice doesn’t capture what is truly important about a character.</p>
<p>Why are Evanovich’s characters great? What makes great characters?</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://b60.a63.mwp.accessdomain.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/lizzy-and-diesel.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-12692 alignleft" src="http://b60.a63.mwp.accessdomain.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/lizzy-and-diesel-300x165.jpg" alt="" width="362" height="199" /></a>Great characters have nothing to do with the plot.</strong> I’ve read books that frustrate me. The plot makes no sense. The world is too far-fetched, and the events are too ridiculous to draw me in, but I kept reading. I made it to the end, and sometimes, I bought the next book in the series. And I wasn’t plot-motivated. Instead, I was invested in the character. I wanted her or him to be happy or to be safe, but the plot didn’t guarantee it. I <em>needed</em> to finish the book.</p>
<p>For me, Janet Evanovich’s series do that to me. I like the stories, but the characters draw me in.  They feel like people I know and care about. They feel real, which is the next requirement.</p>
<p><strong>The characters must feel like real people</strong>. An author shouldn’t follow her grand-aunt Bess around to cultivate her mannerisms for a book persona, but the character must feel like a living, breathing person.</p>
<p>Janet Evanovich does a great job in her series. Everything about Stephanie Plum feels like a real person rather than a façade. As I read her dialogue, I can hear her accent and envision her gestures. Even her responses seem real rather than silly slip-ups and mishaps to make her more interesting than she is. Every eye roll, every snort, every joke seems in character. She feels like someone I’ve met in Jersey. She is familiar without being a stereotype.</p>
<p><strong>Characters should draw the reader back in</strong>. No, not the plot. I don’t mean the reader is anxiously biting a nail and tapping a foot <a href="http://b60.a63.mwp.accessdomain.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Heart-of-Fire-by-Linda-Howard.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-12689 alignright" src="http://b60.a63.mwp.accessdomain.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Heart-of-Fire-by-Linda-Howard-179x300.jpg" alt="" width="179" height="300" /></a>while jonesing for the results of a particularly frustrating cliffhanger. That’s the plot keeping the reader hooked.</p>
<p>Instead, the great character comes to mind when a word or phrase or situation comes to the reader’s mind. A clumsy colleague reminds me of the moment Jillian’s brother slips off the side of the mountain, and the protagonist dove to catch him. She caught him, clinging to his hand as he kicked and screamed and slowly drug her lighter weight over the edge with his heavier form (Linda Howard, <em>Heart of Fire)</em>.</p>
<p>Yes, the moment is pivotal, but as a reader, I remember Jillian’s instinctual response to protect a brother. I remember her quiet determination, despite a dislocated shoulder, not to drop him. I remember her refusal to let him go. And I admired her.</p>
<p><a href="http://b60.a63.mwp.accessdomain.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Jeannie-Frost-Destined-for-an-early-Grave.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-12690 alignleft" src="http://b60.a63.mwp.accessdomain.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Jeannie-Frost-Destined-for-an-early-Grave-186x300.jpg" alt="" width="186" height="300" /></a><strong>Characters should draw the readers&#8217; response</strong>. The character makes me laugh because the character said something that still makes the reader shake his/her head. Like Mencheres, a reserved Egyptian pharaoh who is now one of the most powerful vampires in the <em>Night Huntress </em>series. I see a stiff character in a movie and laugh because I think of Cat (the main character) complaining that Mencheres should speak English to which he replies: “The shit’s gonna splatter, start bugging yo.” (Jeannie Frost, <em>Destined for an Early Grave</em>).</p>
<p>The character who makes readers cry because I remember the heartbreak or laugh at the shock, the vampire who makes me forget that vampires aren’t real&#8211;those characters—their tangle of complex behaviors, their humor, and sorrows, are why readers read.</p>
<p>So, writers, could you give me more of them?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/i-laughed-i-cried-with-the-characters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Just One. . . or Twelve &#8212; Whichever</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/just-one-or-twelve-whichever-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Calee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Heart of the Genres]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Is &#8220;one and done” not a thing anymore? No, I&#8217;m not talking about one-night stands.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/hope-house-press-leather-diary-studio-127595-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12867 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/hope-house-press-leather-diary-studio-127595-unsplash-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Is &#8220;one and done” not a thing anymore?</p>
<p>No, I&#8217;m not talking about one-night stands. Get your minds out of the gutter. This is a fantasy/sci-fi blog after all, not romance. Although I must admit, there is a distinction is most notable among the three genres, a distinction that romance has barely touched. I’m talking about: the series.</p>
<p>Romance fans probably disagree since dozens of romantic series come to their minds. Yes, romances—particularly paranormal romances—have series, too; however, more often, romances have <em>collections</em> rather than <em>series</em>. The authors tell their stories of meeting “the one” in only one, rarely two, novels. The romantic collection is a series of stand-alone novels about a big loving family or close-knit friends. <a href="http://pennyreid.ninja/series/knitting-in-the-city/">Penny Reid’s <em>Knitting in the City</em></a> and <a href="https://lisakleypas.com/">Lisa Kleypas</a> have great friend collections that make readers feel part of the gang while offering differing perspectives—friend, lover, supporter&#8211;of beloved characters. Yet, R.L. Mathewson and <a href="http://www.mcnaughtized.com/">Judith McNaught</a> are queens of the family. <em>Neighbors from Hell</em> (Mathewson) and the Montgomery family (McNaught) finesse these family collections better than anyone. Every single&#8211;well, eligible&#8211;bachelor and bachelorette in the family deserves his/her novel with cameo appearances from previous novels’ characters.</p>
<p>A reader cannot skip a book within a series, but a reader never loses the plot in a romantic collection.</p>
<p>However, that’s not what sci-fi/fantasy series are. By <em>series,</em> I mean book after book after book with the same characters and conflict/issue that the protagonists steadily try to resolve. Sci-fi and fantasy genres have plots and problems too big to resolve in a single book. Each novel is a separate episode with a conflict, climax, and resolution that reveal more about the characters and locations, but the novel doesn’t resolve an overarching issue that drives the major plot, like a television show’s season.</p>
<p>In fact, I&#8217;ve read dozens of series that could not do their plots justice within one novel. The series has become the Netflix of the genres. They are long, action-packed stories with an overarching issue or conflict that cannot be resolved easily. Instead, the characters experience challenge after misadventure until the primary conflict is resolved. And each episode—oops, I mean book&#8211;has a beginning, conflict, and satisfying end that inches the protagonist a step closer to the bigger problem. These series are perfect for binge reading and hooking the reader.</p>
<p>Right?</p>
<p>Of course.</p>
<p>But are five, ten, twelve, twenty books necessary to finish a story? Ah, no, if the author eliminated all the subplots and story shifts. Here’s a litmus test to prove it:</p>
<p>Could s/he finish the real story plot within one book, two tops? Probably. Some books devote only portions of the book to the major conflict.</p>
<p>Couldn’t the other issues and challenges the protagonist faces in book after book be the next segment in his/her wild misadventures? So wouldn’t the slow march to the primary conflict and its inevitable conclusion be just a doughnut on a string leading readers around? Maybe authors worry their readers will lose interest after a conflict is resolved; however, I doubt it.  Readers (like TV watchers) can be loyal to great characters and will stick with the stories until the plot becomes formulaic or the characters no longer feel like familiar friends.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/thought-catalog-188056-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12866 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/thought-catalog-188056-unsplash-300x202.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="202" /></a>Do we need to trudge through her version of romance and ultimate marriage of two characters for three books only to trudge the exact romance and marriage from his perspective? No.</p>
<p>Do we need a cliffhanger at the end of the book when the issue is resolved within two chapters in the next book? No.</p>
<p>Are these drawn-out plots just the author’s cash grab? Well, $4.99 per book for twenty books adds up, and some authors increase the price as each book is released. One author, whom I will not name, began her series at $7.99 (for an e-book?!!), and thirteen books later, the final book is $14.99.</p>
<p>Is the protracted plot the reason these books are so appealing? Ah, well…yeah.</p>
<p>OK, I vented enough. Where’s that final book for $14.99</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brokenhearted, I Read</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/brokenhearted-i-read/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Calee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Heart of the Genres]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am a heartbroken reader. The end of a series is a reasonable guess for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/ben-white-139141-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12530 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/ben-white-139141-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>I am a heartbroken reader. The end of a series is a reasonable guess for my ennui, but it’s not that simple.</p>
<p>In the last two years, the awesome <a href="http://janewashington.com/books/"><em>Curse of the Gods</em></a> series has been one of my favorite reads<em>.</em> The protagonist is an accident-prone smart ass who draws five beautiful, strong, and arrogant men&#8211;future gods. While she’s practically a slave, there to serve their every whim, she quickly becomes more important to them than anyone expected. Their connection draws the attention of the God of Chaos along with the chaos and deadly experiences that godly attention can create.</p>
<p>The series is filled with humor, daring attacks, and romance that kept me anticipating each new book’s plot. I devoured each book within hours of its release; then I reread the book only hours after I finished the last page. I highlighted memorable lines and jokes. I laughed with the protagonist at her humor, and my eyes teared at her pain. When I finished the tale, I checked the authors’ websites, Amazon, Goodreads, and everywhere else I could think of for the next book’s availability. I didn’t want to miss a minute of reading because the books are perfect. I waited for months for the final book of the series.</p>
<p>Finally, after two surprise novellas, the fifth and final book of the series was released a couple months ago.</p>
<p>And I can’t finish the book.</p>
<p>After two months, I’ve read less than half the book when I’d typically read the newest book until dawn’s early light. This slow pace is not normal. In fact, I’ve read twelve books of a completely different series. I listened to two audiobooks while reading a completely different book. Yet, whenever I open <em>Curse of the Gods</em>’s fifth, I stumble through a few paragraphs, maybe a page or two, before I wander away to another novel.</p>
<p>And no, I’m not sentimental or dragging out the end of the series. Normally, I race through a book so I can savor the second reading. . . and the third reading.</p>
<p>However, this time, I lose interest. I don’t care that I haven’t finished the story.</p>
<p>So what caused this disenchantment? Why couldn’t the authors keep me invested for one last book?</p>
<p>The protagonist has changed too much. Her personal evolution isn’t unreasonable since she’s experienced her death as well as others’ deaths, betrayal, and sorrow, but now I don’t like her. I expected her to change—to become stronger, more confident, even more controlled. But she’s no longer the fun-loving, bold personality who made me laugh and cry and sympathize with her. Instead, her weighty thoughts weigh down my enjoyment. I focus on how much she must accomplish before the story’s end.</p>
<p>In other words, she’s too serious and too boring. The protagonist is another person, a person I wouldn’t read about. I no longer care what happens to her. I just assume she will conquer her enemy, the God of Creation. She will free the people who were mistreated and create a fairer democracy. She will find love and marriage.</p>
<p>I just don’t care how she accomplished any of it. So, I mourn the loss of a favored character as though she is lost to the world instead of a more mature character.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fairy Tale Re-reb-rebo-reboot-boot-boot-boot</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fairy-tale-re-reb-rebo-reboot-boot-boot-boot/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Calee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 11:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Heart of the Genres]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pardon my grogginess (and possible rambling), but I just finished a bender, no, a binge.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pardon my grogginess (and possible rambling), but I just finished a bender, no, a binge.</p>
<p>Two actually.</p>
<p>In recent weeks, I plowed through Marisa Meyer’s <em>Lunar Chronicles</em>, then Chanda Hahn’s <em>Unfortunate Fairy Tales</em>, with more fever than I expected to muster for fairy tales. I’m not much of a fairy tale person since reading them in elementary school. The reboots—yes, even the TV shows—leave me with a bored eye roll and mock sigh feeling.</p>
<p>No fan fiction, please! If I’ve read one, then I’ve read them all, right?</p>
<p>In fact, I bought the <em>Lunar Chronicles</em>’s first book, <em>Cinder</em>, more than a year ago. Yet, I never read it. Instead, I kept it in a shed, gave it away, received another copy, and gave away the book again still unread. My local library’s <em>Cinder</em> audiobook caught my eyes another six months later. I couldn’t stop reading until the series’ end. Sure, all the fairy tale elements are still there—the stepfamily, the prince, the shoe.</p>
<figure id="attachment_12004" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-12004" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://www.marissameyer.com/the-lunar-chronicles/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-12004 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinder-first-of-Lunar-Chronicles.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="280" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-12004" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>The first <em>Lunar Chronicles</em></strong></figcaption></figure>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>However, Meyers steps away from the fairy tale premise and immerses the reader into the sci-fi world of hackers, stolen identifies, bioterrorism, and robotics. She managed to recreate the whole fairy tale mold into an unexpected sci-fi fantasy, so despite reading a well-known fairy tale, the story and characters are reborn and fresh.</p>
<p>This sci-fi/fantasy switch is more dedicated than romantic fairy tale reboots. Many romantic fairy tales keep the entire story but modernize it so that the prince’s mustang is a Mustang. The story doesn’t change, so the plot predictably marches toward the old-fashioned happily ever after ending that romances and fairy tales prefer. To that end, the rich prince remains enamored with a commoner who stumbles into love but must overcome her pointlessly mean-spirited step-fam&#8211;</p>
<p><em>Umm.</em> <em>Oops. </em>&lt;Cliquishly, biting my bottom lip&gt;</p>
<p>Yeah, so, those parts are still in <em>Cinder</em>, but it’s not the same because . . .well . . . because Cinder is a partially bionic woman trying to save a humanity from a fast-moving plague that’s slowly killing the population. And her nemesis is an evil queen—</p>
<p><em>Wait! Wait! Let me finish</em>!</p>
<p>The evil queen of Mars who may have created the plague to ease her overthrow of Earth.</p>
<p>Sure, there’s a niggling love at first sight moment, coy flirting, and a ball in this fairy tale turned sci-fi fantasy. Yes, the characters find their true loves and live happily ever after, but . . . but it’s different I swear.</p>
<p>&lt;sigh&gt;</p>
<figure id="attachment_12007" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-12007" style="width: 193px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://www.fantasticfiction.com/h/chanda-hahn/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image wp-image-12007 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/unenchanted-first-of-the-unfortunate-fairy-tales-193x300.jpg" alt="" width="193" height="300" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-12007" class="wp-caption-text"><strong>The first <em>Unfortunate Fairy Tale</em></strong></figcaption></figure>
<p>The <em>Unfortunate Fairy Tale </em>series is a better example. <em>Unfortunate Fairy Tales’s</em> Mina Grime, the teenage descendant of the brothers Grimm, is cursed with reliving all the fairy tales ever told. If she plays her part correctly, she lives tale after tale until she ultimately breaks the curse on the Grimm line. If she fails, she dies, and the curse forces the next Grim, her mute younger brother, to accept the challenge.</p>
<p>There are hundreds of fairy tales, and she completed two in <em>UnEnchanted</em>, the first book of the series. That pace requires too many books.</p>
<p>However, the second book shifts away from the fairy tales with Mina in the protagonist role.  Instead, the plot devolves into the evil prince’s revenge on the Grimm line. See, he believes a certain Grimm betrayed him and caused his subsequent power loss. Three guesses who’s to blame for the curses. Meanwhile, our put-upon heroine Mina suffers to overcome villains, spells, and royalty from a mystical land.</p>
<p>&lt;sigh&gt;</p>
<p>Do reboots ever escape their predecessors?</p>
<p>Do fairy tales ever escape their genre?<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/everafter-series.jpeg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12005 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/everafter-series-198x300.jpeg" alt="" width="198" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Both <em>Lunar Chronicles</em> and <em>Unfortunate Fairy Tales</em> appear worlds away from the simple fairy tales that inspired them.  Nonetheless while most notable&#8211;the word of mouth retelling and once upon a time&#8211;elements are gone, the <a href="https://www.thecurriculumcorner.com/thecurriculumcorner123/2012/11/fairy-tale-unit/">core fairy tale characteristics</a> remain: a make-believe story of magic, castles and forests with villainous royalty, nice princesses and princes, and mistreated good guys aided by human-like animals. Even the large, bloody body count is a fairy tale tradition. And of course, the protagonists {spoiler alert} will fall in love with the handsome secondary character. {I’ll be kind and not tell you who, but it’s obvious when you read the novels.}</p>
<p>So, my been there, read that attitude is justified . . .</p>
<p>Sure, the stories’ plot patterns are predictable—if there’s a prince, the bionic woman’s going to the ball, right? However, the journey between the fairy tale elements was exciting, unpredictable, and binge-worthy. So, maybe reboots deserve an open-minded reading, and maybe romance does too.</p>
<p>&lt;Cliquishly staring out a window before shaking myself out of thought&gt;</p>
<p>OK, I need to track down Barbra Annino’s <em>Everafte</em>r series. I&#8217;ve heard good things.</p>
<p>I may be addicted.</p>
<p>Are there steps for fairy tale addiction?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Speaking of trust</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/speaking-of-trust/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Calee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Heart of the Genres]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaking of trust— Yes, we were talking about trust just last month (It’s about Control). &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Speaking of trust—</p>
<p>Yes, we were talking about trust just last month (<em><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/its-all-about-control-paranormal-control/">It’s about Control</a>)</em>.  I’ve noticed a weird trust trend.  Romance, fantasy, and sci-fi novels share a level of trust that I find impossible to believe.  It’s not that the protagonist trusts the villain, although that happens fairly regularly.</p>
<p>In Chanda Hahn’s <a href="http://chandahahn.com/books/reign/"><em>Reign </em></a>(book 4 of<em> An <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/reign.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11718" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/reign-188x300.jpg" alt="" width="138" height="220" /></a>Unfortunate Fairy Tale </em>series<em>)</em>, Mina Grime knows the man facing her has captured her brother and risked her life by sending fairy tales after her. He watched with indifference as she fought a grim reaper. Yet, when her friend/love interest is at the brink of death, the villain says trust me I can help. Mina hesitates for mere moments.  She doesn’t question why he would help.  She doesn’t contemplate what he might gain.  The main character does consider how he’ll help or if he’s lying.  These speculations are worth reflection.</p>
<p>Both Evies in Jessica Shirvington’s <a href="http://www.jessicashirvington.com/the-books/"><em>Embrace </em>series</a> and Amy A. Bartol’s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/70493-the-premonition"><em>Premonition </em>series</a> regularly trust the villains despite frequent lies, deceptions, and kidnapping.  However, these characters trust the bad guys repeatedly until the final book, when the characters learn from their mistakes—well, some of the characters learn from their mistakes, not <em>Premonition</em>’s Evie, who trusts villains in every book. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright" src="http://www.amyabartol.com/uploads/8/0/9/8/8098364/5147538_orig.jpg" alt="Image result for amy a. bartol premonition series" width="550" height="180" /></p>
<p>I realize trusting the villain is not that simple.  Often, the protagonist trusts the antagonist because the situation is dire: the heroine’s best friend is near death, or the villain is the only character that can help save the day.  I accept the villains are sometimes believable.  Lying and deception is the bad guy’s thing.  They need to be good at it, so the protagonist’s trust is completely unreasonable.</p>
<p>However, I see two problems with their trust.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/carnage.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11717" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/carnage-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="152" height="228" /></a>These main characters trusted a stranger, sinister or angelic, before they know the person well enough to trust them. True trust earned through familiarity, time, loyalty, experience, something that indicates the person is worthy of such faith.  For example, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40576587-carnage?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><em>Carnage</em></a>&#8216;s Carolena runs through a dark bayou to escape a man determined to make her his bride. Fortunately, a gargoyle—fangs, grey skin, horns, and all—swoops in, grabs her, and takes her into the trees to hide.  The creature’s actions save her from an unwanted marriage, but the woman didn’t know gargoyles exist.  She doesn’t know where he’s taking her. She doesn’t know if he’s dangerous, yet Carolena clings to the creature as if he is a long-lost bodyguard.</p>
<p>How unrealistic, and this immediate trust isn’t unrealistic because I am a suspicious person—although I am.  Instead, the trust is unreasonably swift and feminine.</p>
<p>Yes, swift, instinctual trust is a feminine trait I never honed.  Yet, countless novels&#8217; women say there was something about another character that makes her think, “There’s just something about him that made me trust, that made me want to share my secrets.” Men believe this in any of the aforementioned genres.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/veil-series.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11716" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/veil-series-194x300.jpg" alt="" width="146" height="225" /></a>Nope, this sudden belly tingling trust is a female thing since, of course, the trustworthy guy is hot. Whether the woman recently met the <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright" src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/517Gz1j-lfL._SX290_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg" alt="Image result for halfway to the grave" width="139" height="238" /><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright" src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/61iIQgtp0WL._SX327_BO1,204,203,200_.jpg" alt="Image result for ink by broadway" width="151" height="227" />handsome man she&#8217;s trying to kill (<a href="http://jeanienefrost.com/books/halfway-to-the-grave/"><em>Halfway to the Grave</em></a> by Jeaniene Frost) or she drools over the handsome man who wants to help her (<a href="http://www.blbrunnemer.com/the-veil-diaries.html"><em>The Veil Diaries</em> series</a> by B. L. Brunnemer), her gut—a.k.a. her attraction to the man—tells the female character she can trust the man with her secrets.  And the unrealistic trust works out by the novel’s end.  In <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32827036-ink?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><em>Ink</em></a>, Leora receives help from a boy a few years older than her.  Because of that initial meeting, she shares her fears and asks him to break the law with her. Before that request, they spoke twice.</p>
<p>Oddly, the ill-conceived trust seems to be the only way the story can move forward.  If the protagonist needs to learn the truth, then she must trust the villain so that she can stumble into enemy territory and discover the truth.  If the heroine needs to fall in love, the female must instinctively trust the love interest without reason.  If her best friend or parent might die, the main character must trust the enemy to gain a cure or stop an attack.  The character can grow up only if she trusts the wrong man. Leora remains uncertain of her beliefs and actions throughout <em>Ink</em>, but her betrayed trust helps find herself.</p>
<p>But why?</p>
<p>Why must readers abandon realistic behavior to ensure the plot moves forward? Why must women blindly trust while men in similar situations are slow to trust?  Why are male characters allowed to be suspicious, analytical thinkers?</p>
<p>Can’t we all just be skeptical?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It’s all about control . . . paranormal control</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/its-all-about-control-paranormal-control/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Calee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Heart of the Genres]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I dangled forty feet in the air. My toes, my body&#8211;more than half my weight&#8211;leaned&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/christina-boemio-472237-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11446 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/christina-boemio-472237-unsplash-300x231.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="231" /></a>I dangled forty feet in the air. My toes, my body&#8211;more than half my weight&#8211;leaned beyond a thin platform. I tried to hold the steel bar that dragged me away from the platform. Sweat seeped from my skin and rolled beneath my clothes as I swallowed my longing to scream. Only a woman half my size, her hand gripping my waistband kept me from falling. The trapeze artist’s job, along with the two safety bands, was to keep me from falling. I just needed to trust her.</p>
<p><em>Pish, trust.</em></p>
<p>In that moment, I realized the truth: I have trust issues with a bit of need to control tossed in.</p>
<p>I don’t trust anyone, not even myself when walking along a sidewalk. I try to control everything around me. Why would I trust a stranger? I don’t rely on others. I barely trust <em>me</em> much less strangers, friends, and family because I can’t control their success and failure, but I had to release my control to the trapeze artist.</p>
<p>I wouldn’t die. The trapeze artist preventing my plummet had held dozens of people by the waistband before. The safety harness would hold me. I needed to trust my expert.</p>
<p>That’s probably why I enjoy paranormal stories.</p>
<p>To a person with control and trust issues, witches are fortunate characters. Witches have more control over their lives than other people. Live in a bad neighborhood? They surround their homes and possessions with wards. Frizzy hair? Blemish? A quick spell can smooth those wild locks and hide that mountainous blemish. An untrustworthy significant other? That’s what truth spells are for.</p>
<p>Witches have an enviable power to control and reshape their lives.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/list/show/42274.Best_Adult_Shifter_Books">Shifters</a> also earn my envy. While witches are about controlling the world around them, shifters trust because they control each other. These man-beasts know what to expect from life. They know they can trust each other. <em>Obey the alpha and the beta. Find your mate. Respect your male and female.</em> It’s all about trusting the pack to be loyal, respecting the alpha and beta—the strongest and hopefully smartest of the pack—to be smart and honorable, and accepting the chain of command. It’s easy to trust and release control when everyone knows and follows those rules. When a pack functions properly—which rarely seems to happen in a shifter-focused story—pack member loyalty and trust are automatic.</p>
<p>Even vampires are the quintessence of trust and control issues as they control the two things people most fear and long to control—aging and dying. Sure, they’re powerful and beautiful&#8211;according to most recent storytellers. A regular supply of blood ensures eternal beauty and youth. And a snack is more efficient than any spell or charm that can be lost, broken, or damaged.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, paranormal power is not that simple . . . at least in <a href="https://www.barnesandnoble.com/blog/the-20-best-paranormal-fantasy-novels-of-the-last-decade/">paranormal fiction</a>.</p>
<p>Sure, the typical paranormal must adhere to some council’s rules or a special paranormal government. Applying too much magical influence or subverting free will is frown-worthy. These regulations don’t worry me since I have no plans to take over the world. I want to control my day-to-day existence—and the objects within them.</p>
<p>In fiction, I can’t trust my pack because some of those shifters bully weaker pack members. Someone always desires what the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ray-hennessy-118046-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11447 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/ray-hennessy-118046-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>alpha, and occasionally the beta, has, so that loyalty becomes questionable. So trust and control tend to slip in shifter tales.</p>
<p>Those issues are frustrating in witchy tales as many minor magical issues are resolved easily, but the bigger troubles—car trouble, job loss, and cheating partners—still plague a controlling witch. And heaven forbid, the fictional magical world limits the amount and type of magic a witch can wield.</p>
<p>Only the withdrawn, power-hungry vampires avoid these pitfalls. They maintain their control over youth and beauty and never trust anyone. But those were never my issues.</p>
<p>Paranormal fiction won’t fix me.</p>
<p>So I guess I’ll squeeze my eyes tight, slow my puffing, panting breaths, and scream loud and long as the trapeze artist releases her hold on my waistband.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hey, I know you!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/hey-i-know-you/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Calee]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 10:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Heart of the Genres]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Haven’t we met before? Yeah, we have. I’d recognize that wild tangle of hair and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Haven’t we met before?</p>
<p>Yeah, we have. I’d recognize that wild tangle of hair and quirky disposition anywhere.</p>
<p>Why are you shaking your head?</p>
<p>No, no. We’ve definitely met before. In fact, I can prove it.</p>
<p>You’re a witch, right? Ah, see, you paused. You are a witch.</p>
<p>No, that’s not an accusation, but don’t look so surprised. It’s one of the first things I learned about you.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/ricky-kharawala-71743-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11086 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/ricky-kharawala-71743-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Anyway, I remember you say these odd phrases that sound just a little off, like…  &lt;Snapping my fingers, I try to remember.&gt;  Oh <em>bat wings</em> or <em>flying broomstick</em>.  I can’t remember the exact phrase, but it’s some twisted cliché.  What else do I remember? &lt;I tap my chin. &gt; You’re powerful, but you have trouble with your craft sometimes so much so that the local authorities or magical government trouble you often. And you just solved another crime—a murder or conspiracy, right?</p>
<p>What?! No! I’m not a stalker. It&#8217;s just that, well, you witches are all alike.</p>
<p>Yeah, yeah. You claim every paranormal species has its areas of comfort that I call stereotypes. The werewolves—or shifters as they’re now known—are lovers; in most novels, they have three goals: claiming their mates, protecting their packs, or fighting over territory. Whereas vampires and elves tend to cause the problems. They seek political power and sometimes world domination.</p>
<p>Still, witches&#8211;no supernatural character is more stereotypical than the modern witch. They look alike, they talk alike, they work alike. They have the same hang-ups.</p>
<p>I’m not exaggerating. Ever since Hermione Granger flounced into the witching world, a novel’s lead witch (our protagonist) has had wild bushy hair (like Hermione) and brown or reddish-brown hair (like Hermione). Sure, Charli Goodwin of <a href="https://www.bookbub.com/books/moonshine-magic-a-southern-charms-cozy-mystery-book-1-by-bella-falls"><em>Southern Charms Cozy</em></a> is a blonde, but her hair’s still bushy. Yet witches somehow appear like every girl, remaining average—neither tall nor short, neither attractive nor ugly, neither genius nor stupid. But every protagonist witch has underappreciated intelligence, unrivaled skills or powers, and an a-dork-able attitude that is neither abrasive nor off-putting.</p>
<p>I can’t blame Hermione though. Even before Granger influenced witchy appearance, witches fell into a common female stereotype: women’s work. Most witches cook or work around food. They work at a bakery or a coffee shop. A few witches garden as well, but only as a hobby as they grow herbs and brew special foods for their customers.</p>
<p>Yes, you’re right. Food and cooking have obvious connections to witchcraft. Cooking and witchcraft share that whole standing over a bubbling pot thing, but so does chemistry. Where’s the chemist or botanist witch? How about a <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/freestocks-org-140598-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11087 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/freestocks-org-140598-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>zoologist or veterinarian witch since most witches have familiars? (Wouldn’t gathering eye of newt or tongue of toad be easier if a witch worked with animals? Or better yet, why aren’t witches environmentalists, geologists, even weather people who are in tune with nature? And I say “weather people”, but let’s face it, if a witch is a protagonist, then it’s a she, not a he. That’s a stereotype for another time.)</p>
<p>Yes, some witches evade this stereotype. Rachel Morgan (of <em>The Hollows</em> series) is a bounty hunter, and Ivy Wilde (of <em>The Lazy Girl’s Guide to Magic</em> series) is a taxi driver. But it’s a rare witch who earns her living without a stove nearby.</p>
<p>Fine, fine. Deny the cooking career stereotype if you must, but you can’t deny the most consistent stereotype among witches is their distrust of police. I suspect this distrust, quite reasonably, hails from the Salem Witch Trials and the various Inquisitions. Witches have become society’s problem solvers since if a witch is in the story, then she’s valiantly trying to solve a mystery—a murder, a conspiracy, or some other crime—because they don’t trust the police to handle it.</p>
<p>Witches make their distrust seem so reasonable. You need to help your friend or relative because the police suspect the wrong person. But, Katie of <em>Magical Bakery Mysteries</em>, the investigation began yesterday. Can’t the police have a day or two to gather some information or evidence? Besides, the police chief is a trusted friend, Katie, or your brother, Charli (of <em>Southern Charms Cozy Mystery</em> series). The police department could be corrupt, but can’t you trust your friends and family to investigate a situation thoroughly before they convict the wrong person?</p>
<p>I get it. The police can be corrupt like Cincinnati’s Inderlander Runner Service (<em>The Hollows</em> series). If given an hour, those vampires will have the suspect handcuffed, railroaded, and six floors underground in a magic-proof jail cell. So if a witch wants to help a friend out, she may need roll up her sleeves and pull out the truth potions or transformation spells.</p>
<p>But that doesn’t change the sad facts: if you’ve read one witch, you’ve read them all. . . sorry Rachel and Ivy. I love you guys.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
