<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Danielle E. Shipley &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/danielle-e-shipley/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 01:55:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Just Friends(hip): A Love No Less</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/just-friendship-a-love-no-less/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danielle E. Shipley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 15:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=4416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve seen bemoaned on many an occasion the comparative shortage of stories centered around female&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve seen bemoaned on many an occasion the comparative shortage of stories centered around female friendship. Quite often in fiction, The Girl is there to fall in love with The Boy (or two, but that’s a whole ‘nother post on love triangles, right there), and The Boy is there to fall in love with The Girl. There may be a best friend who pops into the narrative for five seconds any time The Girl needs someone to either share her problems with or hide her problems from, a mother to more or less fulfill the same function, a rival girl who exists to threaten The Girl’s desires and/or self-esteem; but the main relationship – the one shown to matter – is that between The Girl and Insert-Love-Interest-Here.</p>
<p>As a romantic fond of her heart-fluttery happy ever afters, I’ve got nothing at all against a good love story. But am I the only one who thinks a tale with no meaningful connections beyond the one between the lovebirds can seem a little… lacking?</p>
<p>Where I think much of the problem lies is the fact that, as a culture these days, we act like a romance is the only kind of deep relationship people can have. Show a pair of people – girl and boy, girl and girl, boy and boy, human and paranormal creature – start to get close, and suddenly the audience is shouting, “So kiss already!” As if there is no strong affection without the equally strong desire to make out. (There’s another post in there about the pervasive notion that life is sex, but we’ll leave that one alone for now, too.)</p>
<p>Sure, a good friendship can make a solid starting point for a romance. Best-friends-turned-<em>more</em>-than-friends is a thing. But to suggest that you can only care about a person so much before your feelings must automatically become erotic is not only straight-up wrong. It’s downright damaging. It’s a flashing red light warning people not to get too close to anyone unless they’re prepared to either take it to <em>that</em> level, or deal with the public assumption that they have and/or will. It’s sexual tension where sexual desire may not even exist. It’s just one more complication that human interaction doesn’t need – because come on, isn’t that enough of a minefield already?</p>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-4417 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/Code-Name-Verity-196x300.jpg" alt="Code Name Verity" width="196" height="300" />All that being said, Elizabeth Wein’s “<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11925514-code-name-verity" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Code Name Verity</a>” – a story conveying a female friendship and the horrors of World War I in equal poignant parts – had the right of it:</p>
<blockquote><p>“It’s like being in love, discovering your best friend.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Because it can be. There’s that giddy obsession. That drive to share – time, space, news, secrets, joys, sorrows, your lives, your <em>selves</em>. There’s the pride of ownership (“She is mine) and of belonging (“I am hers”). There’s the thrill of knowing she’s looking at you, smiling at you, thinking of you. There’s the ache when she’s out of sight, and you’re out of mind. There’s the selfish needing, and the selfless giving.</p>
<p>And it is enough.</p>
<p>Adding a sexual component can sometimes enrich a relationship, true. But it can also sometimes cheapen it.</p>
<p>A deep friendship is a powerful love story, as worthy of any ballad or song as any heart-to-heart interaction ever was. And the hopeless romantic in me would be glad to see more of it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why the Phrase “Strong Female Heroine” Needs to Die</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/why-the-phrase-strong-female-heroine-needs-to-die/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danielle E. Shipley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 16:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First and Foremost… Because “female heroine”, guys. Think about it. Wince with me. Not My Type. Maybe&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>First and Foremost… </strong>Because “female heroine”, guys. Think about it. Wince with me.</p>
<p><strong>Not My Type. </strong>Maybe the kickass, badass, hardass, [insert any other ***appropriate*** “ass” term here] heroine really resonates with/appeals to some people. Fair enough. Just don’t give me the stink eye if “strong female <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">heroine</span> lead” isn’t that high on my list of things that excite me about a book. Tell me she’s a British thief? I’m all ears. Tell me she’s strong? Meh.</p>
<p>And that’s okay! There’s no one-and-only right way to write a heroine or to feel about her. The best thing we writers and readers can do for female characters is to let them breathe well outside of an arbitrary, restrictive box.</p>
<p>The kind of heroines I tend to most enjoy and relate to don’t kick butt for a living. They’re goofy (not like “<em>lol, look at me, I think I’m so awkward</em>&#8230;”, but like actually kind of insane), dramatic, maybe a bit stuck on themselves. They sulk, they stew, they hurt and maybe don’t bother to hide it. They love their friends, and hate their friends, and lament to their friends that they have no friends. Sometimes they do things I wish I could do, sometimes they do things I would totally do, sometimes they do things I cringe at them and/or me for having done. Maybe “heroine”s not even always the word for these girls; there are times “anti-heroine” might better apply. But they make me laugh. They make me nod and sigh and ache. They make me want to shout at or shake them. I feel like we’d understand one another. I don’t know about females in general, but feeling understood means much to me.</p>
<p><strong>Could You Be More Specific? </strong>Speaking of understanding, can we get some clarity on what everyone even means by “strong”? Because the more I see it slapped with seeming carelessness onto the front of the words “female lead/character/oh, mercy, no, not ‘heroine’, not again”, the less weight it carries with me. It’s like people use it to avoid having to actually think about how to describe the character. And y&#8217;know what that is? <em>Weak</em>. Here, let me show you how it’s done. I’ll use some of the leading ladies in my own writing as examples.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Wilderhark-Inspired-Covers-Lineup.png"><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3778" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Wilderhark-Inspired-Covers-Lineup-1024x325.png" alt="Wilderhark, Inspired Covers Lineup" width="640" height="203" /></a></p>
<p>Sula (<em>The Swan Prince</em>, <em>The Seventh Spell</em>) = surly, resistant, mistrustful, thoughtless</p>
<p>Rosalba (<em>The Stone Kingdom</em>, <em>The Seventh Spell</em>) = gracious, straightforward, quick-tempered, practical</p>
<p>Laraspur (<em>The Sun’s Rival</em>) = insecure, compassionate, meditative, courageous</p>
<p>Annabelle (<em>Inspired</em>) = imaginative, sensitive, excitable, immature</p>
<p>Uri (<em>Inspired</em>) = cynical, antisocial, pious, mouthy</p>
<p>You see what I did there? A well-rounded girl is more than “strong”; more, even, than “feisty”, “plucky”, “headstrong” and “snarky”, other go-to adjectives for female characters. If you call my characters strong, I’ll assume you meant it as a compliment and will take it as such. But if you label my characters something a little more unique to who they are as individuals, I will be all the happier.</p>
<p><strong>Who are some of your favorite fictional girls and women? What non-“strong” words would you use to describe them?</strong> Just, whatever you do, please: Never, EVER call them “strong female heroines”. We all deserve better than that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Merry [Wo]man’s Guide: Equality vs. Fairness</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-merry-womans-guide-equality-vs-fairness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danielle E. Shipley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 18:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=3105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello again, Internet. Marion Hood here, courtesy of Danielle E. Shipley (a.k.a. my author, notwithstanding that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello again, Internet. Marion Hood here, courtesy of Danielle E. Shipley (a.k.a. my author, notwithstanding that it may be another year or two before the <em>Outlaws of Avalon</em> series she’s written me into hits the market), to further air my opinions on women-related whatsits (because I&#8217;m no longer in the Middle Ages, meaning a worldwide platform is mine for the taking; huzzah). What say we jump right into today&#8217;s topic with some good old-fashioned stats.</p>
<p>Prior to my husband Robin Hood’s admittance of Allyn-a-Dale into the band, the ratio of women to men among the Merry Men of Avalon Faire was 1 to 4. With the addition of Allyn, it slid down to 1 in 5.</p>
<p>Well, there you have it: Minstrels are damaging to women’s rights.</p>
<p>Not actually. Yet it seems like the sort of conclusion some would be quick to draw.</p>
<figure id="attachment_3106" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-3106" style="width: 640px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Merry-Men-Women-Ratio.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-3106" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/Merry-Men-Women-Ratio-1024x488.jpg" alt="I stand corrected. This infographic was not particularly quick to draw at all. No end amusing, though." width="640" height="305" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-3106" class="wp-caption-text">I stand corrected. This infographic was not particularly quick to draw at all. No end amusing, though.</figcaption></figure>
<p>My author finds it a bit irritating when she happens across statements like, “Only X percentage of fill-in-the-blank are women! This is an outrageous, unacceptable disgrace!” <em>Is it really?</em>, she wonders. Is it all to do with an oppressive glass ceiling keeping us ladies down? Are we to blame the shopping aisle with its profusion of pink and dearth of raw building materials for hoodwinking our little girls out of their bright futures in engineering?</p>
<p>Some while ago, Danielle happened across <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2013/06/29/five-facts-about-professional-artists-in-the-united-states/?utm_source=social&amp;utm_medium=all&amp;utm_campaign=071213_soc_FiveFacts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">an article with a paragraph lamenting how few architects were women</a>. Do you know she considered becoming an architect, once? Or perhaps a landscape or interior designer. All those hours of building homes and amusement parks on her Sims and Rollercoaster Tycoon computer games (whichever gender they may or may not have been marketed toward) sparked her interest. What stopped her from pursuing a career in these fields? Did she discover them to be an unwelcoming boys club? Was she told such pastimes were unsuitable for young ladies? Not at all. She’s not an architect for the same reason she’s not a master chef, an accountant, or a naval officer: Because a writer’s what she is and wants to be.</p>
<p>She doesn’t write because she sees it as a woman’s job, or to stick it to anyone who sees it as a man’s job. It’s <em>her</em> job. Her passion. Her talent developed into skill over thousands of hours and millions of words. How many men or other women write or don’t write has nothing at all to do with it.</p>
<p>Why say we <em>need</em> more women in any given field? Is it for what we feel they would bring to the table? Or are we simply obsessed with the numbers? Must women = men in every sphere before we lower our cry of discrimination, or can there be fairness without numerical equality?</p>
<p>Why so few Merry Women, anyway? If Robin Hood cares so much about justice, how come his wife’s the only girl in the band? Have sexism and nepotism combined to land me the role of Token Chick?</p>
<p>In absolute honesty, I’d say the answer’s a mix of “yes” and “no”.</p>
<p>There’s no pretending young ladies in my day were encouraged to be outlaws. (Which isn’t to say the authorities were exactly rooting for the men to turn criminal, either…) I grew up with my own version of the pink aisle, raised to be a noblewoman with all the feminine trappings that came with the gig. While I don’t recall it ever striking me as the most entertaining future, I made no plans to openly rebel. …Until the man I loved absconded to Sherwood.</p>
<p>That settled that. I put in a few months of basic weapons training to lessen the chances of making a fool of myself and/or getting killed, then found my Robin and made it clear I meant to stay with the band, never mind society or chivalry or the Law telling me it was no place for a girl. When you love something enough, you go after it.</p>
<p>Robin let me in because he loved me. He let me stay because I showed I could. He is as fair, and as in favor of equality, as any man I’ve ever known or heard of. And he has one woman in his band.</p>
<p>Is it an outrageous, unacceptable disgrace? Do the Merry Men need more women? Should I petition for a new quota to ensure females aren’t getting elbowed out by the patriarchy? I suppose I could. Or I could rest content in the knowledge that, had Allyn-a-Dale been a woman, the Men would have been no less eager to welcome her as our minstrel.</p>
<p>No getting around it: There is injustice in the world. A Merry Man is more keenly aware of that than most. But not all inequality is unfairness. Not every woman wants to be an architect, no matter how many “boys’ toys” she happily played with in her youth. By all means, do not force her out. Likewise, do not pressure her in. Out of every “women’s right” – out of every right for all – the right to pursue passion sits atop the list of those Danielle and I stand most firmly behind.</p>
<p><strong>Your thoughts welcome below. …Unless You’re A Girl! (*laughs* I jest.)</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Merry [Wo]man&#8217;s Guide to Writing Female Characters</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-merry-womans-guide-to-writing-female-characters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Danielle E. Shipley]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 17:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=2530</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, Internet. My name’s Marion Hood – perhaps more popularly known as “Maid Marian”, except&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello, Internet. My name’s Marion Hood – perhaps more popularly known as “Maid Marian”, except I don’t use that spelling and I’m quite consummately married – and I’ve been most graciously asked by Danielle E. Shipley (a.k.a. my author, notwithstanding that it may be another year or two before the <em>Outlaws of Avalon</em> series she&#8217;s written me into hits the market) to tackle a writing topic she’s seen all over the web. That topic is female characters. And I chance to be a female character. (Ah, yes… it’s all coming together for you now, isn’t it?)</p>
<p>It has lately come to Danielle’s attention that writing satisfactory women is challenging for her. She’s not sure why, though I’ve got my suspicions (among them, that women don’t inspire red-hot crushes in her the way fellows do and therefore interest her significantly less, and that she hasn’t the foggiest idea what it’s like to be a half-normal girl anyway). Well, admitting you’ve got a problem is the first step, and she’s been giving increasing thought toward how she might populate her stories with more female characters she actually likes.</p>
<p>She likes <i>me</i> well enough, I’m happy to say. But then, I’ve got an “in”: I’m a Merry Man.</p>
<p>There might be some readers who cry “boo” at this. Why call Robin’s band the Merry Men? Isn’t that terribly sexist? Oughtn’t we to be the Merry People or the Merry Unisexual Outlaws or some such? I could take it up with my husband, if you like, but I warn you now, we’ll only both of us laugh it off and continue on as we have been since the Middle Ages. I take no issue at all with being a Merry Man. If anything, I’ve got the best of it, being a Merry Man and a Merry Woman both. Nothing to get offended about at all, though doubtless somebody will be. Somebody always is.</p>
<p>That’s the first thing to keep in mind when writing female characters: <b>You can’t please everyone</b>, so try not to lose too much hair over it. That goes for any character, any story world, any plot, any prose style, and we lady charries are no exception. …No, I take that back, we may actually spend a disproportionate amount of time under the critical microscope. No matter how we’re written, somebody, somewhere, will think we’re not good enough. Not strong enough. Not flawed enough. Not feminine enough. Not masculine enough. Really, I don’t know that even the readers are entirely certain of what they want, though they’re very good at deciding what they don’t.</p>
<p>Talking of strength, though, that does come up a lot: <b>The Strong Female Character</b>. Unfortunately, there’s no consensus on what exactly is meant by that, and so you end up with a lot of fictional women who – as one Rewan Tremethick (charming bloke, Rewan; <a href="http://www.rewantremethick.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">look him up</a>) so elegantly put it – “have a left hook that could knock a bison over”, and who feel nothing beyond a cold anger that prompts them to out-swear every male character within a hundred yards. Danielle avoids writing such characters, because she can’t stand them. Her idea of a strong female characters is— well, why should I presume to tell you? Author Girl, tell the good people: Your idea of a strong female character is…?</p>
<p>“Mm?” says Danielle, startled to find herself in a place to be quoted and narrated about as if <i>she</i> were the imaginary person, here. “Oh, well, the way I see it, <strong>strength of character is about being multidimensional and a person</strong>, not just a name and a role. It’s about the character having her own feelings and motives and self, beyond whatever the story calls for. That’s where I used to go wrong a lot, actually; I didn’t bother about who the girls were apart from what I wanted them to do. Frankly, a lot of the guys weren’t much better, in the beginning. I only improved on them quicker because I wrote more of them.”</p>
<p>Very nice, thank you. There you have one opinion on the issue. A cursory search online can produce countless others, but in the meantime, that’s our premise: Strength is more than muscles. Or superpowers. Or, I don’t know, political clout. And it’s certainly more than slathering the worst sort of male stereotype in lipstick and calling it a heroine. I’m not by any means the physically strongest Merry Man. For pity’s sake, the band includes Little John! Robin and Will are far from feeble themselves, and Allyn-a-Dale’s not even fair, he’s got otherworldly whatsits powering him up. I’ll never win an arm-wrestling match with this crowd, never mind a stave match with Little John, a sword fight with Will Scarlet, or a shoot-off with one of the best archers legend’s ever seen. But with a lot of practice on my end, I don’t slow them down, and none of them yet can throw a knife like I do.</p>
<figure id="attachment_2533" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2533" style="width: 600px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Who-are-the-Merry-Men-e1408508342934.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-2533" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/Who-are-the-Merry-Men-e1408508342934.jpg" alt="I mean, honestly, look at the size of these people! If strength of character were measured in body mass, I’d be bloody out of luck." width="600" height="465" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2533" class="wp-caption-text">I mean, honestly, look at the size of these people! If strength of character were measured in body mass, I’d be bloody out of luck.</figcaption></figure>
<p>More importantly, though, I do more in the books than just poke my head in from time to time and say, “Oh, by the way, I’m a woman. Hear me roar. Carry on, lads.” I talk among them. I fight alongside them. I’m off living my own life, when adventure permits. I’m certainly not sitting about analyzing every action, wondering, <i>Was what I just did girly enough? Or was it perchance </i>too<i> girly? Phooey, how do I balance this?</i> I don’t worry about balance, I’m just me. I don’t even have to take on the role of the sex symbol. (According to Will Scarlet, that’s what <em style="font-weight: inherit;">he’s</em> there for.) I act and I react – not the way a man would, not the way a woman would, but the way Marion Hood would. Is Marion Hood a strong character? I would jolly well like to think so! Some will say yes, some may say no. Some won’t be satisfied until I yank the longbow from Robin and bark, “All right, gentlemen, enough’s enough. It’s my band, now, and things are going to change around here…”</p>
<p>Don’t hold your breath for that plot twist, readers. You ask me, <strong>real strength isn’t too intimidated to acknowledge the (occasionally superior) strengths of others</strong>. I’m quite happy to let Robin Hood be Robin Hood, with me as his staunch supporter slash lover. Because, let’s be honest about it, Danielle can write red-hot-crush-worthy male characters rather well.</p>
<p>That’s where the authoress and I stand on the matter. If you’ve got aught to add – agreements, disagreements, mini-rants, links to other posts on fictional females, requests for my autograph or something – prithee do weigh in. Ta-ta, and thanks to the women of Luna Station Quarterly for the guest spot. Cheers, all!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
