<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Columns &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/columns/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>LSQ Loves Birds!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-loves-birds/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 11:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=26459</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s almost time for our special bird-themed issue, dear readers! To celebrate, we asked the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26460 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/timothy-dykes-_aNtQKnffAA-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/timothy-dykes-_aNtQKnffAA-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/timothy-dykes-_aNtQKnffAA-unsplash-1024x680.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/timothy-dykes-_aNtQKnffAA-unsplash-768x510.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/timothy-dykes-_aNtQKnffAA-unsplash-1536x1021.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/timothy-dykes-_aNtQKnffAA-unsplash-2048x1361.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />It&#8217;s almost time for our special bird-themed issue, dear readers! To celebrate, we asked the LSQ team what their favorite birds are and why. Let us know what your favorite birds are in the comments, and be sure to tune back in tomorrow when Issue 048 goes live!</p>
<p>Blogger <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/amanda-lien/">Amanda Lien</a>: &#8220;My favorite bird is definitely the cardinal, thanks to a silly childhood memory: When I was a kid, there was this red (male) cardinal who seemed to make it his life’s mission to bother my father. My dad worked overnights, and this bird would sit outside his window at 7 am, when my dad was about to go to sleep, and sing the song of his people as loud as possible. We figured it was just birds being birds…until my dad was outside working in the yard one day and that same cardinal dive-bombed him and made off with the remnants of his granola bar. He and his mate later went on to build a nest atop our back porch extension, and in the interest of brokering peace, we left that nest alone!&#8221;</p>
<p>Editor <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/katrina-brown/">Katrina Brown</a>: &#8220;I have an absurd love for pigeons and seagulls. My mom loves both, and any time we had stale bread or cereal that needed using, we would dump it all in a bag that we hung behind our back door. Whenever it was full or we had to run a lot of errands we would grab the bag and take it with us. While running errands my mom would look for seagulls on light posts in parking lots and we&#8217;d stop and throw out the crackers or whatever and feed the seagulls. They&#8217;d all come flying down to get it and eventually loads of them would be waiting for food. Whenever we would head toward a freeway overpass we&#8217;d roll down our windows with handfuls of mix from the bag and throw it out for the pigeons living under the overpass (while the car was<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26461 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hkyu-wu-zmomoe5SQoY-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hkyu-wu-zmomoe5SQoY-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hkyu-wu-zmomoe5SQoY-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hkyu-wu-zmomoe5SQoY-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hkyu-wu-zmomoe5SQoY-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/hkyu-wu-zmomoe5SQoY-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> moving) like we were crazy people. I know now that seagulls and pigeons should probably not be eating the things we would feed them when I was little (thankfully) but now as an adult, whenever I see seagulls or pigeons I have a weird need to reach behind me in the car for something to throw out to them <span class="c-emoji c-emoji__medium c-emoji--inline" data-qa="emoji" data-sk="tooltip_parent" aria-describedby="sk-tooltip-355"><img decoding="async" src="https://a.slack-edge.com/production-standard-emoji-assets/13.0/google-medium/1f602.png" alt=":joy:" aria-label="joy emoji" data-stringify-type="emoji" data-stringify-emoji=":joy:" />&#8220;</span></p>
<p>Editor <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/sarah-pauling/">Sarah Pauling</a>: &#8220;Since moving to Seattle I&#8217;ve grown more fond of crows! I already knew they were intelligent, but there&#8217;s something very charming about these big birds hopping in front of you on the sidewalk like pigeons looking for breadcrumbs. They&#8217;re absolutely fearless here. My cat still thinks she could take one, and she&#8217;s wrong.&#8221;</p>
<p>Editor-in-chief <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/jennifer-parsons/">Jennifer Lyn Parsons</a>: &#8220;I’m going to sound like a broken record, but for me it’s cardinals and crows! My grandmother loved cardinals and since she passed away many years ago now, the whole family has adopted her love of the birds. When one of us is having a tough time, inevitably a cardinal will show up and we all recognize it as a sign Gram is looking out for us and everything will be okay. Those little red friends have been a beacon of joy in dark times.<br />
I also love crows, though putting my finger on why is a challenge. They’re gother than goth? They’re so sociable? They’re smart? I’m not sure, but something about them is so magical and cool.&#8221;</p>
<p>Editor <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/shana-ross/">Shana Ross</a>: &#8220;Hoopoes. They&#8217;re clever and cheeky and look &#8211; to my eye &#8211; mismatched, with their bright crest of headfeathers, wings that look like they&#8217;re from a woodpecker stuck on the body of a mourning dove, and a beak that&#8217;s just a little too long and curved&#8230; they tend to take on a trickster role in Middle Eastern folk tales, or at least are entirely unintimidated by human characters. And that part was true, in my experience. Hoopoes will look you in the eye as if they&#8217;re about to give you a piece of their mind or start a philosophical conversation with you. I used to feed a bunch in my backyard when I was a kid, and I was convinced I had an understanding with them, that these were my friends. I would also like to shout out Big Bird, who has been working hard to help kids grow smarter, stronger, and kinder since 1969.&#8221;</p>
<p>Editor <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/angelica-fyfe/">Angelica Fyfe</a>: &#8220;I really love starlings because of the murmurations they do (where they all fly in motion together and it looks like a choreographed performance). Also emus because even if they’re flightless, they are very speedy (great leg muscles!) and resilient (see: the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emu_War">Emu “War”</a>, or many other unsuccessful attempts to reduce their population). They are grouchy but loveable. And while we don’t have them over here in the UK, hummingbirds are wonderful too! I used to see them often in California, and they are tiny but very maneuverable as they’re the only birds that can fly backwards (which you can see if you watch them drinking nectar as they fly between flowers).&#8221;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-26462 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/james-wainscoat-hjmED1qivmc-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/james-wainscoat-hjmED1qivmc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/james-wainscoat-hjmED1qivmc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/james-wainscoat-hjmED1qivmc-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/james-wainscoat-hjmED1qivmc-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/james-wainscoat-hjmED1qivmc-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Blogger <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/ella-syverson/">Ella Syverson</a>: &#8220;My favorite bird is the crow. They are smart, creative, social, and unfairly outcast as both common and creepy. They are ominous and spooky, while also being adjacent to the categories of animals deemed city vermin like rats and pigeons. Their call is guttural and ugly in its rawness. They seek the things that shine and gleam in the sun. They are goblin core. I love these creatures with all my heart.&#8221;</p>
<p>Editor <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/cait-ryan/">Cait Ryan</a>: &#8220;My favorites are hummingbirds and cardinals. Hummingbirds I love because every time I see one I feel a little burst of joy. They make me think of little fairies. My reason for loving cardinals is the same as Jennifer&#8217;s. They were my grandma’s favorite bird and she had pictures and figurines of them all over her house. Whenever I see one, I know she&#8217;s looking out for me.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Circus is in Town!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-circus-is-in-town/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 10:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy Thursday, everyone! In case you haven&#8217;t heard, LSQ is now open for submissions! Our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19003 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/william-fitzgibbon-yHZdxNvxdaw-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/william-fitzgibbon-yHZdxNvxdaw-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/william-fitzgibbon-yHZdxNvxdaw-unsplash-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/william-fitzgibbon-yHZdxNvxdaw-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/william-fitzgibbon-yHZdxNvxdaw-unsplash-1536x1021.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/william-fitzgibbon-yHZdxNvxdaw-unsplash-2048x1362.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Happy Thursday, everyone! In case you haven&#8217;t heard, <em>LSQ </em>is now <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/submissions/">open for submissions</a>! Our theme this year is the circus, so we put together a little reading list to help get those creative juices flowing. Get them from a <a href="https://www.elitedaily.com/p/22-black-owned-bookstores-you-can-order-from-online-22952386">Black-owned bookstore</a>, find an independent bookstore <a href="https://bookshop.org/">in your neighborhood</a>, or see if your local library has them available in digital format!</p>
<p><strong><em><a href="https://www.angelacarter.co.uk/nights-at-the-circus/">Nights at the Circus</a> </em>by Angela Carter</strong></p>
<p>Follows the story of Sophie Fevvers, an acrobat who&#8217;s part woman, part swan. She&#8217;s followed by American journalist Jack Walser, who wants to know if she really is part swan, or just a sham. A dreamy, whirlwind adventure through turn-of-the-century Europe, with a dash of societal commentary that&#8217;s expected from Carter.</p>
<p><strong><em><a href="http://akemidawnbowman.com/harley-in-the-sky">Harley in the Sky</a> </em>by Akemi Dawn Bowman</strong></p>
<p>You&#8217;ve heard of the running-away-to-the-circus trope, but what about running away to the circus from another circus? Enter Harley Milano, a budding trapeze artist, who joins a rival circus after a fight with her parents. This is realistic fiction, but gives readers a good idea of what circus life is really like.</p>
<p><strong><em><a href="http://www.lauralam.co.uk/book/pantomime-micah-grey-1/">Pantomime</a> </em>by Laura Lam</strong></p>
<p>The first book in the Micah Grey series, it tells the story of Micah, an intersex genderfluid aerialist who discovers circus life isn&#8217;t as glamorous as it might at first appear. Rife with steampunk and magic, this book is a treat for the imagination.</p>
<p><a href="https://erinmorgenstern.com/writing/the-night-circus/"><em><strong>The Night Circus</strong></em></a><strong> by Erin Morgenstern</strong></p>
<p>Of course this one would make the list! The story of two talented magicians pitted against each other, set against a vibrant and magical circus, with a dollop of romance plopped in. If you&#8217;re a fan of dreamy prose, this one&#8217;s for you. And we just so happen to have <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-night-circus-2012-by-erin-morgenstern/">a review</a> of it in our blog archives if you&#8217;re looking to find out more.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s your favorite circus story? Let us know in the comments! And don&#8217;t forget to submit; you have until August 22!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why the RWA Implosion Is Relevant to ALL Writers</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/why-the-rwa-implosion-is-relevant-to-all-writers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 11:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, Y/N. I’ve got no jokes today. I’m no fun and no games, either. See,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17120 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Hello, Y/N.</p>
<p>I’ve got no jokes today. I’m no fun and no games, either. See, recent events in the Romance Writers of America, an organization I’ve paid dues to, has my smile turned upside down and with d*mn good reason.</p>
<p>If you have not heard the ugly basics of this ongoing scandal/mess, there are a couple of resources to peek at first. Author Clair Ryan <a href="https://www.claireryanauthor.com/blog/2019/12/27/the-implosion-of-the-rwa">composed an excellent article</a> featuring an incredibly useful timeline of events. <a href="https://medium.com/the-aambc-journal/a-tragic-fall-from-grace-rwas-public-implosion-bf9b1f279b6a">Medium’s Phoenix Williams</a> offers her experience and a succinct overview of the trash fire,<a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/trade-shows-events/article/82100-rwa-cancels-2020-rita-awards.html"> Publishers Weekly</a> covered the cancellation of the RITA awards, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/1/10/21055125/rwa-what-happened-resignations-courtney-milan-damon-suede-backstory-2020-ritas-conference">Vox has a piece</a> updated to actually feature content from writers of color, and which displays the offensive, recent, and monstrously tone-deaf Romance Writers Report cover.</p>
<p>It’s a lot to follow. TL:DR of the most micro&#8230;the RWA, an organization meant to unite and support romance writers, has engaged in non-inclusive and unethical practices that are harmful to PoC writers, and underrepresented writers from a variety of communities. The precipitating events centered around the ever-awesome Courtney Milan, a Chinese-American romance author and lawyer, are just the tip of the iceberg.</p>
<p>Why is this relevant to you, dear Y/N? Rampant racism, bigotry, and ethical violations in publication are not new (*cough HUGOS cough*). Romance fiction, though, is a huge industry. It is escapism, when done well; at its best, empowering, inclusive, and inspiring. For scandal, hatred, and breaches of ethics to infest what is supposed to be entertaining and empowering means that, for all of those excluded and harmed, their right to enjoyment, to their own voices, to inclusion in not just publishing but hobby-reading, reviewing, and fun in general is tenuous at best.</p>
<p>I can carry this over to the importance of diversity in fanfic and any other popular media, and will in other posts. For now, I’ll say this: if writers of color, LGBT+ authors, and writers with disabilities cannot find a safe haven in creating and sharing love stories, then there is a serious freaking problem. And there has been for years. Again, this is not new, but it is very loudly, brightly obvious to the publishing, reviewing, and reading world now more than ever after the RWA implosion.</p>
<p>The up-side, if there is one? Maybe someone being stupid enough to go after Courtney Milan (I hate that I even have to do this silver lining crap) will lead to greater transparency within publishing communities, and will boost support and readership for authors of color and underrepresented authors. Maybe the mess that is currently the RWA will be reborn in a better form, or will pave the way for stronger support organizations that are truly inclusive.</p>
<p>RWA’s recent events prove that yes, hand-wringing do-gooders that want everyone to be nice, there is a reason for authors affected by these practices to be angry. Leave the nice to those of us with the privilege to do so. The RWA’s implosion is relevant to all (by which I mean to emphasize traditionally privileged, white) writers because we <i>have </i>to do better. White fragility and professional gripes or jealousies have NO place in the conversation right now. This is not about those of us who have enjoyed privilege throughout our careers or, if hobbyists, our experiences posting and sharing our fics. This is the time for us to listen, learn, and make changes based on the advice and recommendations of those who have been most hurt by <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17121 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />scandals like this.</p>
<p>Yes, this is a soap-box moment. A teachable moment. And yes, it is relevant and important to anyone, even those who do not read or write in the romance genre. Where can we start, you might be wondering&#8230;well, it’s actually not that difficult. Support PoC authors by buying, reading, blogging about, featuring their work. Consult sensitivity readers when you write outside of your perspective and demographic. Read blog posts and listen to author talks that address inclusivity, sensitivity, and DEI issues in publishing and writing. And when someone who is NOT you but who has been gaslighted, taken advantage of, been excluded from professional outlets, and so on is talking about their experience, be quiet and LISTEN.</p>
<p>I hope that this series of painful experiences and scandals can help shed light on the pervasiveness of racism, exclusivity, and bigotry, and that this light shines on better practices and opportunities and a future where such implosions are a thing of the past. Till then, Nice White Ladies, we have work to do, so get to it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self Care in the New Year: Back to Life, Back to Reality</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/self-care-in-the-new-year-back-to-life-back-to-reality/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17017</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well hello again, Y/N⁠—happy 2020! So, I am a Gen-X’er,  hailing from the ancient days&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17018 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/pexels-photo-3496995-300x285.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="285" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/pexels-photo-3496995-300x285.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/pexels-photo-3496995.jpeg 653w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Well hello again, Y/N⁠—happy 2020! So, I am a Gen-X’er,  hailing from the ancient days of cassingles and acid washed, tight-rolled jeans. In 1989, the band Soul II Soul released a song that pops into my head to this very day⁠—&#8221;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TB54dZkzZOY">Back to Life&#8221;</a>. A good beat, smooth af vocals, earworm-worthy in every way.</p>
<p>And now that I’m back to work after the holiday break, the song loops in my head and rings with relevance all these years later. The holidays here in the U.S., for many, are a liminal space. Even if you are working, it’s not the same flavor of &#8220;working&#8221; as other times of year. Projects, workflows, customers, tasks gain a strange mix of urgency and hazy-lazy. I’ve worked a wide variety of jobs over my lifetime: cashier in a variety of retail outlets, barista, legal clerk, temp agencies, teaching, administrative stuff, editing. In every one of these disparate jobs, the Holiday Time Vortex applied. Like the olden dank meme says, I tumble out of them “confused, full of cheese, unsure of the day of the week.”</p>
<p>Then, suddenly, I find myself “back to life, back to reality, back to the here and now.” Work continues apace, sorta. Routines reassert themselves, or I forge new ones. Usually. Sometimes, though, it’s not that easy. Post-holidays malaise can carry into daily life in surprising ways. Like, forgetting to actually cook nourishing food or shop for said food. Staying up till 3 a.m. staring at a screen like I don’t actually have to haul my @ss into the office the next day.</p>
<p>Another extreme of non-routine exists: Resolutions Zealotry. I have plans! I have goals! I have agency! Yes, yes, and heck yeah, you do. But you also have only so much time and energy (by you, I mean me, and anyone else who does this). It’s easy to slump into feeling defeated and unsuccessful when the millions of well-meaning goals we set are left unchecked in those shiny new planners. I have to ask myself, what are some goals I can let go, and which ones can I keep and actually accomplish in a way that alleviates rather than causes stress? For me, meal-planning is a big one this month. Simple meals, allowing myself pre-packaged ingredients but things I will cook, that will not leave me feeling that just-ate-a-box-of-cheezysnacks yuck.</p>
<p>It’s a simple thing, but it supports my health which supports my writing, my life.</p>
<p>So, dear Y/N, what are some small, check-offable goals that will bring you back to the here and now?</p>
<p>Here’s wishing you all a New Year filled with peace, light, and every good thing&#8230;thanks for reading!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holiday Self Care</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/holiday-self-care/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 11:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello again, Y/N! Yeah, I’m sticking with the whole fanfic thing here. So, at least&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16907 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/self-love-3969644_1920-1-288x300.jpg" alt="" width="288" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/self-love-3969644_1920-1-288x300.jpg 288w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/self-love-3969644_1920-1.jpg 318w" sizes="(max-width: 288px) 100vw, 288px" />Hello again, Y/N! Yeah, I’m sticking with the whole fanfic thing here. So, at least here in the U.S., winter holidays are fast upon many of us. Even if you do not celebrate a particular holiday, the trappings are all around: decorations and music in retail outlets, commercials full of red bows and jingling bells, movies and TV shows featuring holiday themes, and even for many folks either extra work time (customer service this time of year is no joke) or less work time than usual due to closures at your places of school/employment.</p>
<p>In other words, we are immersed. This can be a wonderful thing, in many ways—lights, good food, focusing on gifts and gratitude, and so on. For many others, it can be a remarkably stressful time of year. Many people find themselves feeling lonely, especially when comparing themselves against the happy-family-and-friends-perfection they find all over popular media. For those who have experienced trauma, grief, and loss around this time of year, anniversary syndrome can strike hard. For many others, the lack of sun and sometimes cold temps (here in the Northern Hemisphere at least) can result in Seasonal Affective Disorder, or even just winter blahs.</p>
<p>These things, Y/N, are not to be taken lightly. It’s all too easy to skim through your Insta feed or let your eyes glaze over back to back commercials chock full of picture-perfect joy. And yes, these moments of exquisite, sparkling, gift-wrapped happiness can indeed exist. But so can missing family and friends who are not there, dealing with illness or financial troubles, or feeling trapped in family events amongst those who are not accepting or gentle. Most people have some sort of stress that hits with the holidays and we can’t always see this in the perfectly curated social media feeds or too-bright smiles they show the world.</p>
<p>Bearing this in mind, please know that you are NOT alone in feeling alone, stressed, depressed, or any of it. And with this knowledge close to your heart and forefront in your mind, take time for self-care. I’ll repeat this again, Y/N&#8230;the holidays are not all fun and games so yes, TAKE TIME FOR SELF-CARE.</p>
<p>Self-care does not look the same for any two folks, but it can be as simple as treating oneself to nourishing, tasty meals; taking time off work to sleep in or engage in activities that make you smile. It can be volunteering to help those less fortunate (and there are more than enough opportunities to fit a variety of personalities, physical ability, and talents). It can be re-reading that one book that always makes you smile, not taking phone calls from people you know will bring you down, not leaving the house if you’re feeling extra social anxiety, or taking a brisk walk even though there’s four inches of snow on the ground. Nobody knows what caring for yourself looks like better than you, Y/N, and I am giving you a permission slip to take the time you need to be the best possible you this holiday season and always.</p>
<p>Here’s wishing you all peace, joy, and good things now and into the new year!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LSQ&#8217;s Holiday Wish List</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsqs-holiday-wish-list/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tis the season, dear readers, tis the season. Here&#8217;s a sample of a few things&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tis the season, dear readers, tis the season. Here&#8217;s a sample of a few things the <em>LSQ</em> staff has on their wish lists for the holidays.</p>
<figure id="attachment_16859" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16859" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-16859 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/moon1_900x-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/moon1_900x-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/moon1_900x-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/moon1_900x-550x550.jpg 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/moon1_900x.jpg 600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16859" class="wp-caption-text">Moon lamp!!!</figcaption></figure>
<p>Editor Sarah McGill thinks this <a href="https://www.lampsfromspace.com/products/moon?variant=29771855331400&amp;currency=USD&amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMIl9LLtril5gIVBdbACh1AUA-DEAkYCSABEgLTzfD_BwE">Moon Lamp</a> would do just fine, plus yelling &#8220;Lamps from Spaaaaaaaaaaace&#8221; is really fun. (Try it.)</p>
<p>Editor Shana Ross wants some <a href="https://www.redbubble.com/people/thelatestkate/portfolio">Latest Kate</a> stickers because hello, Lisa Frank-style positivity dragons. Another must-have is the <a href="https://www.hottopic.com/product/her-universe-she-ra-and-the-princesses-of-power-girls-hoodie/11899755.html">She-Ra hoodie</a>. (No explanation required and this was given a second thumbs-up by blog editor Jen Gheller.)</p>
<p>Blogger Tracy Townsend has her eyes on the book <em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Writers-Map-Atlas-Imaginary-Lands/dp/022659663X/ref=asc_df_022659663X/?tag=hyprod-20&amp;linkCode=df0&amp;hvadid=312034012774&amp;hvpos=1o2&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvrand=1558792093329400254&amp;hvpone=&amp;hvptwo=&amp;hvqmt=&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvdvcmdl=&amp;hvlocint=&amp;hvlocphy=9021656&amp;hvtargid=pla-553437381094&amp;psc=1">The Writer&#8217;s Map: An Atlas of Imaginary Lands</a></em>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_16861" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16861" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-16861 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/raven_gloves_01_2000x-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/raven_gloves_01_2000x-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/raven_gloves_01_2000x-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/raven_gloves_01_2000x-768x768.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/raven_gloves_01_2000x-550x550.jpg 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/raven_gloves_01_2000x.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16861" class="wp-caption-text">Writing gloves featuring &#8220;The Raven&#8221;</figcaption></figure>
<p>Editor Shel Graves has added <a href="https://storiarts.com/collections/gloves?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_campaign=branded_exact_us&amp;gclid=CjwKCAiAob3vBRAUEiwAIbs5ThSPV2CrBrsJ-eH50houKqA7ImcgLEhuAebF_UEglwPy-tu2bel82hoC-hcQAvD_BwE">writing gloves t</a>o the list.</p>
<p>Blogger D.M. Domosea is dreaming of some wearables like this <a href="https://www.theshirtlist.com/coexist-t-shirt-2/">COEXIST</a> shirt and <a href="https://www.neatoshop.com/product/Neverending-Christmas-2"><em>The Neverending Story</em></a> on a sweater.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-16860" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/436915-201572933582t-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/436915-201572933582t-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/436915-201572933582t-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/436915-201572933582t.jpg 450w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Faves</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/friday-faves/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looks like we made it to Friday&#8211;fantastic. Here are a few things we&#8217;d like to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looks like we made it to Friday&#8211;fantastic. Here are a few things we&#8217;d like to share that brightened our day. We hope they brighten your day, too.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Baby Yoda - Toto Africa" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zbA62fvGGyw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Nirvana - In Bloom - Drum Cover" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mlm0qws5kjE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>And <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/joinartemis/woman-on-the-moon">NASA&#8217;s logo for Artemis</a></p>
<figure id="attachment_16782" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-16782" style="width: 730px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-16782 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/wotm_01_blue_desktop-1024x576.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="411" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/wotm_01_blue_desktop-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/wotm_01_blue_desktop-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/wotm_01_blue_desktop-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/wotm_01_blue_desktop-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/wotm_01_blue_desktop.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-16782" class="wp-caption-text">Image courtesy of NASA</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self-Care for NaNo and Beyond, Part Two</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/self-care-for-nano-and-beyond-part-two/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Editor&#8217;s note: Part 1 of Self Care for NaNoWriMo posted November 8.] Well hello there,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<em>Editor&#8217;s note: Part 1 of Self Care for NaNoWriMo <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/self-care-for-nano-and-beyond-part-one/">posted November 8</a>.</em>]</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16667 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />Well hello there, Wri-mers . . . are you hydrated today? Have you taken a moment to breathe? Yeah? That’s great! You are well on your way to fostering some wonderful habits that you can carry over into your non-NaNo life!</p>
<p>But what’s that you’re saying? You’re creatively blocked? Sick of your story? Sick of spoken and written language altogether?</p>
<p>Ah, yes. Creative burnout is a very real phenomenon and not at all a pleasant one. Good thing I have, thanks to my personal experiences and suggestions from many other creatives I know, come up with some nice little block-breakers and creativity hacks!</p>
<p><b>NaNo Self Care: The Mind Edition</b></p>
<p><b>Here are some simple ways to not just survive NaNo, but to thrive in the process. These items can be done whenever you feel like your writing is stalled, your process is failing, or your mind is just not in the game.</b></p>
<p><b>Change up your scenery or work area. </b>While repetition and routine can work wonders for forming habits, these things can start to feel more like ruts when you are experiencing creative burnout. You can change your routine in a variety of ways: move your computer or notebook into another room; change the decorations on your desk or add some holiday decor, soothing scented candles, or other happy-place items; mix up your mix&#8211;music-wise&#8211;and listen to some new stuff; get out of the house/office/regular writing cave and attend a write-in, find a nook in a public library, write with a partner, or write at a different time of day than usual.</p>
<p><b>Don’t be afraid to suck.</b> Write a note to yourself and post it in your writing area that is a reminder to your writerly soul that IT’S OKAY TO NOT BE PERFECT. It’s okay for a first draft to suck. It’s MORE than okay, in fact . . . it’s normal. If it’s important enough to you, you can sand down the rough places in a later draft. We all go into this knowing that we are not writing our cleanest/best, and keeping that at the top of our thoughts can go a long way in breaking blocks that hold you back from getting out those words and having fun.</p>
<p><b>Talk about it.</b> Speak&#8211;aloud&#8211;to yourself or a friend (or houseplant or pet) about what is frustrating you most. Talk about why you think your piece stinks. Rant about how crappy your <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16668 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />word count has been, or about your insecurities or plot knots or whatever you feel is holding you back. At the end of no more than half an hour, make a plan: how can you move past these frustrations? What can you do to push forward? Articulating both problems and solutions aloud can go a long way in invigorating your process.</p>
<p><b>Remember to play.</b> Set aside an hour in the day where you do nothing but play. Allow yourself the luxury of sitting down and typing nothing but nonsense. Plop your broody MC into a ball pit at Chuck-E-Cheese, scribble whatever random words and phrases pop into your head, make a bullet-point list like this one of all of your MC’s most hated foods, visit a random generator to come up with absurd prompts, take your antagonist to your favorite coffee shop for an interview session, give your broody MC a perky makeover. If you can’t play on the page, step away and watch an episode of the show that inspired your piece in the first place, do some fan-art of your world or characters . . . you get the picture.</p>
<p><b>Remember you’re not alone, then get back in the chair. </b>Step away from your manuscript and visit the NaNo forums/blog/website to see how other people are dealing with their blocks and slogs. Engage, lurk, or whatever serves your process best, but purposely be aware that YOU ARE NOT ALONE in this . . . that the event itself is one big community of people doing the same thing: <em>writing</em>.</p>
<p>You are back in the chair now, write? I mean right?</p>
<p>I hope these lil’ tips and suggestions help you in your quest to crank out those words, and here’s wishing you a most lovely, joyful, and awesome NaNoWriMo 2019!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self-Care for NaNo and Beyond, Part One</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/self-care-for-nano-and-beyond-part-one/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the things I really love about the NaNoWriMo forums, website, and blog is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16466 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kaitlyn-baker-vZJdYl5JVXY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="354" height="236" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kaitlyn-baker-vZJdYl5JVXY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kaitlyn-baker-vZJdYl5JVXY-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kaitlyn-baker-vZJdYl5JVXY-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 354px) 100vw, 354px" />One of the things I really love about the NaNoWriMo forums, website, and blog is that there are oodles of helpful and inspiring posts and tips about cultivating creativity under pressure. The topic of self-care during this high-pressure month is a topic I see pop up time and again, and I never get tired of seeing these posts. Why? Well . . . yes, I’m a grown@ss adult (no, really I am) but sometimes I forget to do the little things that, uh, keep me alive and functioning.</p>
<p>Since I know many of you are already charging toward that 50K goal, I will keep this post short and simple. I should mention here that any of the bullet-points in this post apply not just to NaNoWrimers, but to creative professionals under deadlines, to students facing down the battle that is pre-finals projects, and to people whose lives have suddenly crossed the border into Busytown.</p>
<p>What I’m offering in this post today is a checklist that, optimally, you’ll use 2-3 times within your waking hours. I personally use Google Docs or Sheets so I can check in from my phone, but this would work well printed or integrated with planning apps like Trello. I’ve even known writers to use their fitness trackers to ping them for the goals those particular apps are able to track. Without further ado, here are some things to remember as you wade/march/rocket/waddle into the fray:</p>
<p><b>NaNo Self Care: The Body Edition [<em>editor&#8217;s note: stay tuned for Part 2 later this month!</em>]<br />
</b></p>
<p><b>Here are some simple ways to not just survive NaNo, but to <em>thrive</em> in the process, and keep your body and mind in the game. Note, setting reminders/alarms for the time-based tasks, at least for the first few days, will help form these healthy habits. </b></p>
<p><b>Drink a glass of water hourly. </b>Hydration is <i>everything</i>. Without it, our bodies cannot do what they need to do to heal, process nutrients, allow us to THINK (and therefore, write).</p>
<p><b>Stretch or, if you are physically able to do so, get up at least once an hour. </b>Physical <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16467 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/adeolu-eletu-DqWEAOHsAvc-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/adeolu-eletu-DqWEAOHsAvc-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/adeolu-eletu-DqWEAOHsAvc-unsplash-768x509.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/adeolu-eletu-DqWEAOHsAvc-unsplash-1024x678.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />activity&#8211;even something as simple as lifting your arms, readjusting your posture, or moving your legs where you sit&#8211;can wake up a sleepy writer, succeeding where caffeine fails. Take the bench, coffee&#8211;jazz hands, you’re up!</p>
<p><b>Every half hour, pause and take a few deep breaths.</b> Often when we are in the creative flow, we forget even to blink, and our breathing can be shallow, affecting our oxygen levels. Breathing purposefully can refresh and reorient our systems, allowing for greater mental clarity.</p>
<p><b>Eat regular meals/snacks and stick to your normal meal routine as much as possible. </b>If you can afford/manage quick meals and snacks (frozen meals, groceries delivered, PB&amp;J sammiches, batch meals or snacks like soups that you can freeze or large bowls of popcorn you can portion out), this is ideal. Setting aside a couple of hours a week for meal planning and prep can save you hours in the long run, and give your mind fuel for cranking out those words!</p>
<p><b>Sleep!!!</b> Keeping a regular sleep schedule, as much as possible, will work wonders for your ability to push through on days when you’re about ready to set your manuscript on fire then chuck it into the stratosphere. Even if you are getting less sleep than usual, staying on a schedule or at least allowing dedicated time to rest with purpose can make all the difference when fighting burnout.</p>
<p><b>Engage with others! </b>Yes, this is a physical/body self-care bullet-point. Engagement with other beings, sentient or otherwise, can do wonders for grounding you, bringing you back down to earth. While participating in the chaos of the month can be exciting, speaking to your housemates/SO’s/online friends or petting your kit-cat/doggo/birb/snek animal pals helps you remember that you exist as a corporeal creature, not just a big, word-addled brain. If you are the kind of person who likes hugs and can find them, do it (even hug yourself if you have to)&#8211;nurturing your physical self with the affection of those around is recharging in a way that nothing else is.</p>
<p>So that’s that, folks. Take care of your body, and the mind will thrive. Here’s wishing you all happy writing&#8211;remember, you’ve got this!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ready? Set? NaNoWriMo!</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ready-set-nanowrimo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to November, dear readers. If you&#8217;re a fiction writer, you may also know that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to November, dear readers. If you&#8217;re a fiction writer, you may also know that means welcome to National Novel Writing Month (<a href="https://www.nanowrimo.org/">NaNoWriMo</a>). Whether you&#8217;re still on the fence about committing to a month&#8217;s worth of word-slinging or you&#8217;ve got your novel outlined already (!) and your fingers are just itching to hit that keyboard, the editorial and blog teams here at <em>LSQ</em> have some words of advice for all you word warriors out there. In the words of our ed-in-chief Jennifer Lynn Parsons: &#8220;May your words flow freely, may your inner editor enjoy their vacation, but most of all, remember to have fun!&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p>I did Camp NaNo for the first time this July and won. One thing that really helped me was picking a dedicated time to write—for me, the morning, before I started work. Making it part of my routine helped me be able to focus on it. When I wrote, I used the Focus App’s Pomodoro timer and wrote in 25-minute increments. In between 25-minute sessions, I’d grab water or coffee and step away from my desk to rest my eyes. And I’d only check word count after the 25 minutes was up. This can make writing seem less intimidating—you only have to write for 25 minutes at a time rather than worry over word count.</p>
<p>Another tip is to get ahead on your word count early in the month while you’re excited about the project and have energy to write more than the allotted 1667 words. Being ahead on word count makes it easier for you later in the month when you’re busier, possibly less energized about the project, and have Thanksgiving plans. &#8212; <strong>Carolina VonKampen </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Speaking of app recommendations, if you work better in long sessions rather than shorter ones, <a class="c-link" href="https://www.notion.so/FocusTimer-Keep-You-Focused-3fbb277742b74d6884365f1966149d12" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.notion.so/FocusTimer-Keep-You-Focused-3fbb277742b74d6884365f1966149d12</a> is brilliant imo. &#8212; <strong>Gô Shoemake</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As a two time NaNoWriMo winner, two time loser (though you never really lose as long as you get SOMETHING down) I can give a bit of advice to all you WriMos out there: Enjoy the forums, but they will not contribute to your word count. Get the support when you need it, but then get back to that keyboard!</p>
<p>&#8211; Try sprints when you get really stuck, or a change of scenery, or take a little break. Change it up!</p>
<p>&#8211; If something isn&#8217;t working in your story, just skip to the next section where you know what happens. NaNoEdMo is there for when you&#8217;re ready to fix it. &#8212; <strong>Jennifer Lynn Parsons</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I have done NaNo for several years now! It&#8217;s helped me significantly flesh out many of my stories, even if I haven&#8217;t properly finished and fine-tuned any just yet. &#8212; <strong>Angelica Fyfe</strong><i class="c-icon p-member_profile_name__presence c-presence c-presence--away c-icon--presence-dnd-offline c-icon--inline" title="Away, notifications snoozed" aria-hidden="true" data-qa="presence_indicator" data-qa-presence-self="false" data-qa-presence-active="false" data-qa-presence-dnd="true"></i></p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
