<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Space &amp; Thyme &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/space-thyme/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 19:54:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Writing Spider</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-writing-spider/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shawna Bethell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 11:51:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space & Thyme]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Argiope Aurantia, aka Yellow Orb Spider, aka The Writing Spider. She was sitting in her&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Argiope Aurantia</em>, aka Yellow Orb Spider, aka The Writing Spider. She was sitting in her web at the corner of my home, just beyond my worn-wood deck beneath the soffit where she would surely fall prey to cascading rainfall from my eaves. She was there when I returned from my<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25952 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/DSCF7770-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/DSCF7770-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/DSCF7770-767x1024.jpg 767w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/DSCF7770-768x1025.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/DSCF7770-1151x1536.jpg 1151w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/DSCF7770-1534x2048.jpg 1534w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/DSCF7770.jpg 1786w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /> vacation two weeks ago. She remains there still. I am concerned for her. Winter is coming, and she is not the first spider I’ve lived with who&#8217;s quietly disappeared with the first hard frost. But right now the fierce beauty rides out the breezes, wrapping her kill of wayward wasps in silken shrouds, and providing me moments of pleasure when I see her each morning.</p>
<p>Before I moved to this small Midwestern town, I had rarely seen one of these colorful spiders, but they are plentiful here in the autumn months, and I find myself fascinated by their striking selves. This year was the first, however, that I looked them up to find their many aliases, and when I read they are called The Writing Spider due to the unique patterns of their webs, the synchronicity made me smile.</p>
<p>You see, fall is the time of year I return to myself, and when I left work last Monday evening, the vibrant blue sky and warm air verily crackled with the energy of change. Looking skyward, I scanned for our local wake of vultures and was pleased to find them flying. I watched as they cut and wheeled, riding the thermals just over the bluffs along the creek. Exhilarated by their merriment, I remembered the full moon would rise that night, and that fall would officially begin two days later.</p>
<p>I made my way home where I started evening chores, which kept me inside until nearly dark, but after dinner I stepped out to the deck and looked to the horizon, where a slash of blood-orange moon glowed through the trees. Pulling on my shoes I walked into the night hoping to get a better glimpse as streetlights, traffic, construction zones—the trappings of civilization—cluttered my view. Finally I caught her resting heavily just above the trees. I stood at the intersection as cars buzzed through, and took in her full breadth. Then circling back home, I returned to the deck where I continued to watch her ascend, red turning to gold as she eerily gilded drifts of cloud as she rose.</p>
<p>In the darkness, I thought of my recent vacation when I spent time with the tribe of creatives I had not seen for nearly seven years. I thought of the vitality that creativity lends an existence, and I thought of my recent efforts to re-establish my work as a writer. Obligation and responsibility had, over the years, drained me of any spark of creativity, and any written work I had done had often been done for the sake of a paycheck. What I realized under that full moon was that creativity had to be part of the deal or writing, too, became just another job, just another tick off the list. So with that powerful lunar entity in front of me, and with what I would soon learn to be The Writing Spider at my back, I made a vow to once again live a more creative life.</p>
<p>I understood that priorities will need to shift, and it would not be easy. But I also understand that change is inevitable and necessary in this living world. The moon phases and seasons turn. A spider lays her eggs for spring then quietly disappears.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stories We Leave Behind</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/stories-we-leave-behind/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shawna Bethell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 20:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space & Thyme]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many years ago I was in an antique shop where an old suitcase sat open&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25728 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fullsizeoutput_120d-300x200.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fullsizeoutput_120d-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fullsizeoutput_120d-1024x683.jpeg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fullsizeoutput_120d-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fullsizeoutput_120d-1536x1024.jpeg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/fullsizeoutput_120d-2048x1365.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Many years ago I was in an antique shop where an old suitcase sat open displaying a small mountain of sepia toned photographs. I shuffled the top layer and found three different women: one in lace petting her dog, one standing alone on a broad front porch, and another riding a narrow desert trail. I couldn’t help but wonder who they were and what their lives had been. Aside from the dog’s name, Bruno, written on the back of the first, there was no indication. I took them to the counter, paid my seventy-five cents, and took them home.</p>
<p>Women’s stories. So often ignored, set aside, disappeared, that the individuals who lived them were made inconsequential and the guidance they could have provided to future generations was lost.</p>
<p>It is getting easier. After decades—centuries—of being disappeared, many women’s lives are now being allowed the spotlight. The September issue of Smithsonian magazine <a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/arts-culture/land-ancient-ones-ann-axtell-morris-cinematic-treatment-180978344/">features a story on archeologist Ann Axtel Morris</a>, and I just saw an advertisement about women explorers from PBS. In recent writing classes I’ve encountered women who are documenting the stories of their mothers or of women who inspired them on their own journeys. And still others are writing the lives they are living today. They are creating a record for those who will follow.</p>
<p>And it matters.</p>
<p>I recently saw a social media post denigrating Joseph Campbell because the scholar of mythology had not theorized a Heroine’s Journey to compliment his Hero’s Journey. Many commenters agreed with the post, angry that there had been no mythologies to offer guidance as they made their way through the world. Others felt that Campbell’s ‘hero’ was symbolic of all people and was not gender specific even though most of the stories were about men. I could understand both arguments.</p>
<p>As a younger woman, I had been exposed to Campbell’s work through the <a href="https://billmoyers.com/series/joseph-campbell-and-the-power-of-myth-1988/">Power of Myth</a> series, and I liked his breadth of cultural reference and the ideas of the hero’s quest. But there was also a side of me that asked, “So, in all these thousands of stories, where are the women?” I was young, had grown up in a small, rural setting, and had no models of how to be a female that preferred travel and exploration over domestic expectations. I was disappointed that in all the world’s stories, none reflected the way I wanted to live my life.</p>
<p>Campbell taught at Sarah Lawrence College and was married to Jean Erdman, an accomplished woman in her own right, so it was hard for me to believe that he deliberately ignored women in myth. I was right. It just took a while for the information to surface. <a href="https://www.jcf.org/works/titles/goddesses/">Goddesses: Mysteries of the Feminine Divine</a> is a collection of lectures Campbell gave between 1972 and 1986. It explores mythologies based on women, and last night I turned the final page, putting my mind to rest about the scholar. Interestingly, however, the most useful idea Campbell gives us is not from the ancient texts at all but his own words.</p>
<p>“….all I can tell you about mythology is what men have said and experienced, and now women have to tell us from their point of view what the possibilities of the feminine future are.”</p>
<p>Indeed.</p>
<p>Over the past two years, we have become weary. We are tired and pulled from every direction, and writing—aside from what must be done to pay the bills—is easily set aside to focus on more pressing tasks. I do it all the time. But if we can, we need to keep writing because there are generations coming behind us, and they need to know what’s possible. Whether we present it in short stories or memoir, song or paint, it’s up to us.</p>
<p>And it doesn’t matter what your individual story may be, there is assuredly someone out there who will find relief in opening the book, in clicking the link, in seeing the image. There is someone somewhere who is looking for a way forward in this “future” Campbell referred to.</p>
<p>I got lucky. I eventually found women writers whose stories acted as guideposts, women who loved the wilderness and walked the land, who wrote it all down for me to find so that when I finally packed my bags, I had a path to follow. So far, it has been a good journey. I still look at those photos that I tucked away so long ago, and I still wonder about the lives those women lived. I am sure they all had stories to tell, and most certainly—considering the era in which they lived—there was someone out there who needed to hear them.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Migrations</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/migrations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shawna Bethell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space & Thyme]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had planned on writing something other than a book review this month, something a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_25504" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25504" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-25504 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fullsizeoutput_11ef-300x231.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="231" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fullsizeoutput_11ef-300x231.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fullsizeoutput_11ef-1024x787.jpeg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fullsizeoutput_11ef-768x591.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fullsizeoutput_11ef-1536x1181.jpeg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fullsizeoutput_11ef-2048x1575.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25504" class="wp-caption-text">Photo Credit: Stephen Hannington</figcaption></figure>
<p>I had planned on writing something other than a book review this month, something a bit more creative. But on a recent trip through Nebraska I stopped for a while at <a href="https://rowe.audubon.org/">Audubon’s Rowe Sanctuary</a>, which sits along the shore of the gentle Platte River. Eagles diving for their morning catch, blue herons wading in grace, the flick of redwing black birds among the lash of spiky cattails. The quiet ebb of the morning worked its will.</p>
<p>Eventually, I made my way to the visitor center for a quick look around and once there found myself in a passionately earnest conversation about bird migration with the woman behind the counter. She was preaching to the choir, but she was so determined to speak for the birds, I let her speak. As I listened, I remembered a novel I’d recently finished, and that memory has led us here to yet another recommendation for LSQ readers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.charlottemcconaghy.com/"><em>Migrations</em> by Charlotte McConaghy</a> is set in the future and helmed by main character Franny Stone. It is part pirate story, part eco-warrior story, and part love story. It is exquisite.</p>
<p>When we first meet her, Franny is in Greenland. It is nesting season and she has just tagged three Arctic terns with tiny transmitters with the hope she can follow this last known colony’s last migration south. In the future that McConaghy created, fishing has all but decimated our oceans, leaving little food for migrating birds to survive on. These birds are not expected to survive. Desperate to bargain for passage so that she can track the birds, Franny enters into an uneasy alliance with commercial fisherman Ennis Malone and his crew of diverse outcasts. Nearly as desperate as Franny, they are looking for their Golden Catch, the one to make them rich before it all comes to an end. Making a deal with her devil, Franny tells Malone the birds will be following the fish, so if he takes her on board, with the help of her transmitters, she and her birds will find him his fish.</p>
<p>But in this future, the fishing industry worldwide is heavily monitored and a voyage of such a distance wouldn’t go unnoticed by authorities. What Franny asks is risky, not only legally but also physically. The Arctic tern has a migration route of <a href="https://www.audubon.org/news/how-tern-broke-record-longest-known-migration">up to 30,000 miles</a> one way across deep-water oceans, some of which the captain has never navigated. Ennis Malone, however, is a gambler and he knows time is running short for his payload, so he agrees.</p>
<p>We learn early that Franny is an unreliable narrator: “I am of the leavers,” she tells us. “The searchers, the wanderers. The ilk of those taken by the tides.” We know she has been in prison. We know she has skipped parole to make this journey. She is feral in every sense of the word, especially when it comes to the sea, and McConaghy’s writing is never more powerful than when she writes from her character’s heart:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;There are empty shards of shells shining silver in the moonlight, and they grow into a shimmering trail I must follow…. [It] leads me into the water, so I take off my clothes and dive in, the cold a knife to my lungs and laughter flying from me in birdlike screeches.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>From the decks of the <em>Saghani</em>, Franny’s past emerges through flashbacks to her childhood on Galway’s shores, where she was left by her own wandering mother, to the National University of Ireland where she meets her husband Niall, a renowned conservation scientist. It is the moment of their first meeting that we get a further sense of Franny when she rescues three boys in a storm-tossed skiff by swimming out to reach them and bringing them home.</p>
<blockquote><p>“… My first few running steps into the sea are a familiar shot of adrenaline to the heart. I’ve swum this ocean all year round…which has taught me not how to best it or even, truly, survive it, but simply to be aware of its capriciousness even after so many years. It could take me tonight just as it could have done when I was a child or may do when I’m gray. Only a great fool, my mother once told me, does not fear the sea.”</p></blockquote>
<figure id="attachment_25505" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25505" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-25505 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fullsizeoutput_11e8-300x170.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="170" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fullsizeoutput_11e8-300x170.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fullsizeoutput_11e8-768x436.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/fullsizeoutput_11e8.jpeg 968w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25505" class="wp-caption-text">Photo Credit: Stephen Hannington</figcaption></figure>
<p>Franny’s perpetual lack of fear makes the <em>Saghani</em> crew uneasy, but as the fishing boat moves southward, friendships and loyalties bleed together. They become bound by fierce storms and moments of sacrifice. When an act of violence on land makes them fugitives, the crew realizes they are tied by more than their alliance, and Franny and Ennis understand that for them—each for their own reason—there will be no returning from the voyage.</p>
<p>While late night conversations on the shores of Galway or on the deck of the <em>Saghani</em> unspool the science of oceans and birds, <em>Migrations</em> is also steeped in the lyricism of poetry. Samuel, one of the crew who wants to retire, drink wine, and read poetry often quotes classics. And the essence of Emily Dickinson’s <a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/42889/hope-is-the-thing-with-feathers-314">&#8220;&#8216;Hope&#8217; is the Thing with Feathers&#8221;</a> breathes through the entire novel. Against the raging storms, both internal and those at sea, the Arctic terns—small, delicate, and white—are ever-present and moving. But when Ennis and Franny, alone at the end, barely survive one last storm, Franny gives over that hope:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;If they have died, all of them, it’s because we made the world impossible for them. So—for my own sanity—I release the Arctic terns from the burden of surviving what they shouldn’t have to….&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Migrations</em> is the kind of novel that should fill us with despair, but nature has a will to survive, as does the indomitable instinct of the tern. By the novel’s end they have given us clemency—at least temporarily— for the actions of our past and a path of redemption for our future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;The End of the Day&#8221; by Claire North</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-end-of-the-day-by-claire-north/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shawna Bethell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 11:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space & Thyme]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aside from perhaps the Virgin Mary herself, I don’t know of any other biblical myth&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25280 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fullsizeoutput_11be-300x208.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="208" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fullsizeoutput_11be-300x208.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fullsizeoutput_11be-1024x712.jpeg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fullsizeoutput_11be-768x534.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fullsizeoutput_11be-1536x1067.jpeg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/fullsizeoutput_11be-2048x1423.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Aside from perhaps the Virgin Mary herself, I don’t know of any other biblical myth more appropriated by artists than the <a href="https://www.britannica.com/topic/four-horsemen-of-the-Apocalypse">Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse</a> called forth in the <em><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Book_of_Revelation">Book of Revelation</a></em> as prophecy to a broken world. From artists such as Albrecht Durer with his 1498 print <a href="https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/336215"><em>The</em> Horsemen</a> to television shows such as <a href="http://www.supernaturalwiki.com/Four_Horsemen_of_the_Apocalypse"><em>Supernatural</em></a>, Pestilence, Famine, War, and Death have long inspired the creative mind. For the myth to be interpreted and shared again with any relevance or interest to contemporary readers, it would take something entirely unique. <a href="https://www.clairenorth.com/">Claire North’s</a> 2017 novel <a href="https://www.clairenorth.com/titles/claire-north/the-end-of-the-day/9780356507361/"><em>The</em> <em>End of the Day</em></a> meets the criteria.</p>
<p>Of all the books I’ve recommended over the years, I’m certain that this is the singular novel that people have never decided to read. And I do understand. <em>The End of the Day</em> is about Death, and we typically do not want to spend much time with Death. But North reinterprets the entity from the evil, looming black-robed figure depicted in Gustave Dore’s 1865 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Gustave_Dore_-_Death_on_the_Pale_Horse_resized.png"><em>Death on the Pale Horse</em></a> to an entity that is, albeit imminent, also thoughtful, respectful, and articulate. She does this by letting us glimpse Death through the eyes of his Harbinger, Charlie, an unassuming, somewhat naïve young man who simply needed a job and answered an ad in the paper.</p>
<p>It is Charlie’s story that we follow through the novel. His arc of becoming the Harbinger, his interactions with the people he meets, and how those interactions form who he becomes are what keep us reading. As Saga, the retired Harbinger, tells him, “you go before, and before there is death, there is life. You go to greet and to honour the living&#8230;.” So this book is also about life, being alive, and honoring that condition. Readers see the awareness grow in Charlie as he hesitantly dates, falls in love, and tries to sustain a relationship while meeting the demands of his job.</p>
<p>Beneath the arc of Charlie’s ‘becoming’ are also the stories of the individuals he meets. Sometimes in brief encounters and sometimes in chapters, we understand why the Harbinger has come into their lives. Because Charlie’s arrival does not always mean Death will come as expected, though Death always follows. Sometimes Charlie is a courtesy, offering a gift or allowing individuals to prepare. Other times he is a warning, allowing individuals the opportunity to change their behaviors. If they do, Death may pass them by, at least temporarily.</p>
<p>But the most unique element to North’s presentation is that Death does not only come for people. Death also comes for dreams, cultures, or ideas such as when he sits beside the dying man who laments the election of a woman president. “…And Death closes his eyes. Because here too is something worth saying goodbye to, in its own quiet way.”</p>
<p>In this manner North addresses many of society’s issues as Charlie travels the world. Hatred,</p>
<figure id="attachment_25281" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-25281" style="width: 240px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25281" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gustave_Dore_-_Death_on_the_Pale_Horse_resized-240x300.png" alt="" width="240" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gustave_Dore_-_Death_on_the_Pale_Horse_resized-240x300.png 240w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gustave_Dore_-_Death_on_the_Pale_Horse_resized-820x1024.png 820w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gustave_Dore_-_Death_on_the_Pale_Horse_resized-768x959.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gustave_Dore_-_Death_on_the_Pale_Horse_resized-1231x1536.png 1231w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Gustave_Dore_-_Death_on_the_Pale_Horse_resized-1641x2048.png 1641w" sizes="(max-width: 240px) 100vw, 240px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-25281" class="wp-caption-text">By Gustave Doré &#8211; A 20th century Swedish bible, Public Domain, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=23366303</figcaption></figure>
<p>racism, and violence against the LGBTQ community are here, as are war and the melting glaciers. At times you will need to put the book down. I’m sorry. <em>The End of the Day</em> is not a novel to binge. But that doesn’t mean it isn’t worthwhile. I would argue that it is imperative, especially now, because Charlie’s humanity is the force moving us through the darkest of moments. (And I should note here that when Charlie visits a member of the KKK, there is offensive language as North portrays the man. So please, be prepared.)</p>
<p>North’s use of somewhat ironic humor—and there is a lot of it—also moves us through, such as when the most powerful forces in the world are reduced to car rental:</p>
<blockquote><p>In the footsteps of the Harbinger of War comes her master. Today he comes by Honda, that being the only car available for hire at the local airport, and Death sits in the passenger seat and tries to find north on the map….</p></blockquote>
<p>Ultimately though, as in the tarot deck, Death is about change. The world as it changes. The inevitability of the world changing. Whether it is due to war or ideas or the passing of an individual life, the world thereafter is always different. Sometimes for the better and sometimes for the worse. Through the Harbingers (and we do meet them all) and the people Charlie encounters we see the simultaneous necessity of change as well as the heart-breaking lament of it. In this juxtaposition, <em>The End of the Day</em> is a complex novel. I’ve read it twice and know that when I read it again, I will find subtleties that I missed in earlier readings. It is a novel about perseverance. It is about the strength of being human.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harry Potter and the Ivory Vikings</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/harry-potter-and-the-ivory-vikings/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shawna Bethell]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 10:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Space & Thyme]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=24901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There was once an artist. Her name was Margret the Adroit, and she was one&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25061 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/lewischessmen2-300x200.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/lewischessmen2-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/lewischessmen2.jpeg 620w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />There was once an artist. Her name was Margret the Adroit, and she was one of the finest artists of her time. Her story—and her work—is documented in a 12th century Icelandic saga entitled <em>The Saga of Bishop Pall</em>. Unlike many sagas, this particular story was not written by a scribe looking back across decades or even centuries. It was written by the bishop’s son, Loft, who spoke of his and his father’s personal knowledge of Margret. Why does it matter? Because Margret possibly created of some of the most beloved carvings in the world.</p>
<p>If you remember the scene in <em>Harry Potter and the Sorcerer&#8217;s Stone</em> where <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IwjZ1J2b8UY">Ron is teaching Harry how to play Wizard’s Chess</a>, you will remember the ivory and crimson chess pieces they used (most likely it is the irritated queen who gets up from her throne and uses it to smash her opposing knight that you remember), but those pieces are replicas of the <a href="https://www.nms.ac.uk/explore-our-collections/stories/scottish-history-and-archaeology/lewis-chess-pieces/">original Lewis Chessmen (pieces)</a> found buried on the Isle of Lewis, Scotland, in 1831. Capturing the imaginations of avid HP fans everywhere, that scene launched the inscrutable and controversial carvings to worldwide fame. Often today, instead of being called by their rightful name, they are simply known as the Harry Potter Chessmen (pieces).</p>
<p>But the origins of the chess pieces are unclear. What we know for certain is that a total of 93 carvings were unearthed on that coastline. The hoard, as it is sometimes called, appears to be the remains of four different chess sets, as well as a handful of other small decorative pieces. They were quickly absorbed into private collections but eventually made their way into the British Museum in London and the National Museum of Scotland. The pieces have not been carbon dated, as experts prefer not to slice away even the smallest shaving of ivory to be used in testing. But in considering the style of the carvings, the hats the bishops wear, the horses and the trappings of the knights, and the shield-biting berserkers that stand in for rooks, it is thought that the pieces were carved at the turn of the 12th and 13th centuries, meaning that after they mysteriously landed on that beach, the Lewis Chessmen (pieces) waited for 600 years before being unearthed again.</p>
<p>Experts in both archeology and art agree that the craftsmanship of these small sculptures is impeccable. Carved from walrus ivory and whale tooth, the faces are unique with dour frowns, humor, or boredom. The decorative scrollwork of vines and dragons found on the thrones of the kings and queens is intricate. But the artist or artists are unknown. Indeed, even the legends of their finding—which happened in much more recent history—number no less than nine. For being such solid and enduring little icons, their past is as ephemeral as the Atlantic mists that shrouded them over the centuries.</p>
<p>Personally, I had not given much thought to the chess pieces used by Ron and Harry, and it wasn’t until I was researching the Viking raids of Britain that they were brought again to mind. In my research I ran across the book <a href="https://www.nasw.org/users/nmb/books.html#IV"><em>Ivory Vikings: The Mystery of the Most Famous Chessmen in the World and the Woman Who Made Them</em></a> by Nancy Marie Brown. True, it’s not a title that rolls off the tongue, but the story itself is fascinating.</p>
<p>Countering the current theory, that the game pieces were carved in Norway by multiple artists, Brown supports the interpretation of Frederic Madden of the British Museum. In 1832, Madden wrote that the depiction of the shield-biting rooks uniquely reflected Odin’s berserkers, who were<br />
characterized in early Icelandic sagas proving they had been carved in the tradition of an Icelandic artist. Taking up this thread, Brown weaves together such disparate aspects as Viking history and trade routes, the evolution of the church, women in religion and battle, and natural history. She traces Bishop Pall and his penchant for lavish arts and illustrious friends. She<br />
examines the nationalistic fervor between countries vying to claim the Lewis Chessmen (pieces) as their own. And she describes in detail the intricacies of the rooks, knights, kings and queens and how their design reflects other known archeological finds. Her enchantment with the droll little game pieces brings them to life and all the while she is leading us to the woman who she<br />
believes made them. In its first English translation to be published, Brown quotes from the saga:</p>
<blockquote><p>…Bishop Pall sent many gifts to his friends abroad, both gyrfalcons and other treasures. He sent Archbishop Thorir a bishop’s crozier of walrus ivory, carved so skillfully that no one in Iceland had ever seen such artistry before; it was made by Margret the Adroit, who at that time was the most<br />
skilled carver in all of Iceland….</p></blockquote>
<p>Because key locations have long since been developed and built upon, excavations of Margret’s<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25062 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/lewischessmen-270x300.jpeg" alt="" width="270" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/lewischessmen-270x300.jpeg 270w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/lewischessmen-923x1024.jpeg 923w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/lewischessmen-768x852.jpeg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/lewischessmen-1384x1536.jpeg 1384w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/lewischessmen.jpeg 1802w" sizes="(max-width: 270px) 100vw, 270px" /> workshop and other pertinent sites cannot be conducted. And because the chess pieces were not specifically referred to in the saga, the origin of the Lewis Chessmen (pieces) will remain a mystery without resolution. Perhaps it is only fitting, after these many years, that they be left to their veil of secrets. But what we can take away from Brown’s research is that there truly was a woman named Margret the Adroit, and she was hailed as the finest artisan of her day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
