<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 043 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-043/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 14:43:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 043 Author Interview: Avra Margariti and &#8220;The Lotus Wife&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-avra-margariti-and-the-lotus-wife/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 043]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=21868</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ready for the last Issue 043 author interview, dear readers? Here we have a very,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ready for the last <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-043/">Issue 043</a> author interview, dear readers? Here we have a very, ahem, transformative discussion with Avra Margariti, author of &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-lotus-wife/">The Lotus Wife</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Ah, elemental love! Can you share with us the idea behind the creation of</strong></em><br />
<em><strong>this story? What were its influences?</strong></em></p>
<p>Avra: &#8220;The Lotus Wife&#8221; is a fairy tale, which features elements such as transformation, magical <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-22245 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/lips-3490311_1920-300x170.jpg" alt="" width="386" height="219" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/lips-3490311_1920-300x170.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/lips-3490311_1920-1024x579.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/lips-3490311_1920-768x434.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/lips-3490311_1920-1536x869.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/lips-3490311_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 386px) 100vw, 386px" />meetings, and characters identified by their attributes rather than having ordinary names. The idea came to me after I read about the life cycle of the lotus flower. What intrigued me the most was how long a lotus can stay underwater before it rises from the river mud in full bloom.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: As the story progresses, “The blue of the sky was swallowed by a thick veil of smog.” How much of the lotus girl’s and the fisherman’s relationship was determined by the world around them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Avra: When I was writing my story I didn’t plan to use this particular literary device, but I suppose I did end up using it subconsciously! The weather and the environment reflect my characters’ journeys, and the lotus girl’s health, as she is a being inextricably tied to the natural world.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your story ends in a lovely statement of hope. As the author of the world you created, what do you think the future holds for your characters?</strong></em></p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22246 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/flowers-3294463_1920-300x201.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="201" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/flowers-3294463_1920-300x201.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/flowers-3294463_1920-1024x685.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/flowers-3294463_1920-768x514.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/flowers-3294463_1920-1536x1028.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/flowers-3294463_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Avra: Sometimes people love each other, but they aren’t ready to be together just yet. I really like the idea of the lotus girl and the fisherman growing up, becoming different people, then meeting again under better circumstances&#8211;a second first meeting, perhaps less magical, but no less important than their first one.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Anything else you would like to share about your story? Are you working on anything else at the moment?</strong></em></p>
<p>Avra: Thanks for asking! Currently I’m working on a Young Adult short story. It’s about dissociation, the power to freeze time, and self acceptance. It’s also, at heart, a genderqueer love story.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 043 Author Interview: Alexis Ames and &#8220;Halfway Through the Dark&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-alexis-ames-and-halfway-through-the-dark/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 043]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another Tuesday, another Issue 043 author interview! Join us as we chew the rag with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another Tuesday, another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-043/">Issue 043</a> author interview! Join us as we chew the rag with Alexis Ames about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/halfway-through-the-dark/">Halfway Through the Dark</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: In your story, Kate has an ability that seems to perfectly fit with her job at the morgue. What inspired your main character and her profession?</strong></em></p>
<p>Alexis: I love writing stories about people with superpowers or otherwise unusual abilities, but those abilities are always more interesting to me if there is a catch or a cost to them. A time traveler who can only travel to certain places in time, for instance, or a superhero whose powers<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22155 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/steampunk-2748905_1920-300x190.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="190" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/steampunk-2748905_1920-300x190.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/steampunk-2748905_1920-1024x649.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/steampunk-2748905_1920-768x487.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/steampunk-2748905_1920-1536x974.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/steampunk-2748905_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> cost them something whenever they&#8217;re used. Kate can get into the minds of the dead, but can&#8217;t communicate with them&#8211;she can only see their last few instances of life. At that point, it seemed natural to give her a job in a morgue so that she could continue to use her abilities and put them to good use. A short story doesn&#8217;t allow for much exploration of a character&#8217;s backstory, but I wrote her with the idea in mind that she feels as though she needs to use her ability for some good, otherwise what is the use of having it? So she has found a way to incorporate her ability into a career, and makes it a point to aid people where she can, like David.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: You are very good at the mystery/adventure/steampunk genre. Is this genre what you usually like to write in, or does it vary?</em></strong></p>
<p>Alexis: Thank you! This is actually my first mystery/adventure story. I have one other steampunk story out there, &#8220;The Edge of the World&#8221;, which was published this August in the <i>From The Farther Trees</i> &#8216;zine. While I do read a lot of mystery, I mostly write science fiction, and that&#8217;s what the majority of my published short stories are. I also have some science fantasy short stories out there, and I&#8217;m working on a couple of contemporary romance novellas. Steampunk in particular has always fascinated me because I love the idea of having modern technology (or a version of modern technology) in a historical setting. William Gibson&#8217;s <i>The Difference Engine </i>was highly influential in that regard, as was Cherie Priest&#8217;s <i>Boneshaker</i>. It seemed natural to take this steampunk world I dreamed up and make a mystery out of it, and set it in my hometown of Chicago in an era of that city&#8217;s history that has always interested me.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Tell us more about the possible relationship between the mech man, Edgar, and David.</em></strong></p>
<p>Alexis: I have always been fascinated by the portrayal of robots and androids in science fiction. <i>Star Trek: The Next Generation </i>introduced me to artificial life when I was a child, and it was hugely formative for me. Growing up, I also was influenced by androids/artificial life as portrayed in <i>The Questor Tapes, Colossus &#8211; The Forbin Project, </i>and <i>Get Smart</i>. All that to say, I have always been interested in the idea of artificial life and how it would relate to humanity, and <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22157 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/teens-629046_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/teens-629046_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/teens-629046_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/teens-629046_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/teens-629046_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/teens-629046_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />how humanity would relate to artificial life if androids or robots ever gained sentience in reality. I love exploring that idea in my science fiction stories. So here I have a mech man, my steampunk version of a robot, and the human who has fallen in love with him (and though Edgar doesn&#8217;t feature much in this story, I like to think those feelings are mutual). So much of science fiction seems to focus on evil robots or malevolent artificial life. I prefer to write about artificial life that co-exists with humanity, and how their lives might mingle with ours.</p>
<p><strong>LSQ: &#8220;Halfway Through the Dark&#8221; seems like an episode in a steampunk Sherlock Holmes universe. Are there more stories planned with these characters? Is there anything else you are working on?</strong></p>
<p>Alexis: I don&#8217;t currently have any more stories planned with these characters, but I wouldn&#8217;t rule it out completely! Writing-wise, I&#8217;m mostly focused right now on my novels. I signed with an agent in 2019, and since then have been pursuing traditional publishing. I have one novel in the editing stage with my agent, about a time traveler on Mars in the 26th century, and another novel that is still in the drafting stage. That one is a science fiction horror story that takes place on an abandoned spaceship. Once my larger writing projects are out of the way, I hope to return to writing and publishing short fiction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 043 Author Interview: Amy Porter and &#8220;Giant Beach&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-amy-porter-and-giant-beach/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 11:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 043]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19743</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tuesday again? No problem, especially when there&#8217;s a new Issue 043 author interview! Today we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tuesday again? No problem, especially when there&#8217;s a new <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-043/">Issue 043</a> author interview! Today we talk with Amy Porter about her otherworldly story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/giant-beach/">Giant Beach</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Your character, who has ALS, feels a strange connection to a giant’s eyeball. How much of his obsession came from the psychological aspects of his progressing disease?</em></strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-22060 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/eye-1587506_1920-300x300.png" alt="" width="230" height="230" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/eye-1587506_1920-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/eye-1587506_1920-1024x1024.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/eye-1587506_1920-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/eye-1587506_1920-768x768.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/eye-1587506_1920-1536x1536.png 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/eye-1587506_1920-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/eye-1587506_1920.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 230px) 100vw, 230px" />Amy: I would say a good deal of it. There is a sort of connection between his breaking body and the shattered fragments that litter the shore. He sympathizes with the thought of the giant species&#8217; slow decline into extinction, as that is what he is currently experiencing in his own life. The eye, on the other hand, is unbroken, and soulful. I think he might be obsessed with it because, to him, it&#8217;s a sign that something remains after life is gone.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: The landscape of your story is so unique. Washed up on the shore of Iceland: giant toes, pieces of brain, and yes, a giant eyeball. Is any of this inspired by mythology, or just your vivid imagination?</em></strong></p>
<p>Amy: I read a lot of mythology growing up, so while I can&#8217;t say that it <i>directly </i>inspired the way this story unfolded, it certainly shaped how I view story and the way I tell things to myself.</p>
<div>The landscape was inspired by a very real beach in Iceland called &#8220;Diamond Beach&#8221;, where shards of glacier routinely wash up. When I sat down to write this piece, what immediately spilled out was the first line about a seashore. Since I had no clue what to do with that, I had to find some real-life prompters. I started looking through different oceanfront settings, and as soon as I saw the pictures of black sand and blue ice, I knew that&#8217;s what I needed. It felt like a gift, as did the idea that these glacial fragments were parts of an extinct colossus.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Your MC enters into the eye three times, each time being shown something wondrous. Is there a significance to what he sees each time? Tell us about the tears.</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22061 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/blue-259458_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/blue-259458_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/blue-259458_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/blue-259458_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/blue-259458_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/blue-259458_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div>Amy: The progression of images could be connected with the feeling of futility and insignificance that the MC has at the beginning. Life blossoms, and it dies, and the eye (which could maybe be interpreted as God or Nature), has seen it all. The third image, I think, is the most important, because he is able to view himself as both seen <i>and </i>loved by this omniscient thing. It is an answer to his conviction of his own smallness earlier in the piece. There is more to the eye&#8217;s seeing than just observation; there is passion as well, and grief, hence the tears. Plus, where there&#8217;s saltwater and an eyeball in the same place, there&#8217;s got to be tears.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><em>LSQ: What is your favorite kind of genre to write? Is there anything you are writing currently?</em></strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p>Amy: I really like to write whatever occurs to me in the moment. However, if I was forced to pick, my favorite genre would be science fiction. I feel that its rules are the most flexible, and leave the most room to play, besides which every other genre can fit inside it. From fantasy adventure, to historical drama, to romance, everything can be written through a science fiction lens, which I find incredibly exciting.</p>
<div>I&#8217;ve got a few projects in my workshop at the moment. I have a couple of short stories I&#8217;m attempting to finish up, and one novel I&#8217;m almost at the halfway point for.</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 043 Author Interview: Anne Elise Brinich and &#8220;Assyrian Machinery&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-anne-elise-brinich-and-assyrian-machinery/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 17:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 043]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[November already? It&#8217;s true what they say: time really does fly. But Issue 043 is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>November already? It&#8217;s true what they say: time really does fly. But <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-043/">Issue 043</a> is still going strong! Today we have for you a thought-provoking interview with Anne Elise Brinich on her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/assyrian-machinery/">Assyrian Machinery</a>&#8220;.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: Your story is centered in the detailed mechanics and journey of one particular character. Are there engineering or historical influences from your life that set to inspire your MC?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22026 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/mihrican-atilla-bU9kic4IvRQ-unsplash-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/mihrican-atilla-bU9kic4IvRQ-unsplash-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/mihrican-atilla-bU9kic4IvRQ-unsplash-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/mihrican-atilla-bU9kic4IvRQ-unsplash-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/mihrican-atilla-bU9kic4IvRQ-unsplash-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/mihrican-atilla-bU9kic4IvRQ-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />Anne: I just wanted to use this story to talk about how the gripes we have with technology today are issues we&#8217;ve probably had since we started making and using tools on a large scale in our civilizations. Without diligent attention to its possibilities, good and bad, the power technology harnesses can be abused to stroke the egos of people who either don&#8217;t know, or don&#8217;t care, about the consequences of its use.</div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: The world-building in your story is immediate and rich. Could you explain the differences between this story and historical Assyria? What about the connection between religion and engineering? Anything else you would like to explain about your world?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Anne: This is a story very loosely based on ancient Mesopotamia. There are references to places, materials, practices, tools, and people who existed on wildly different timelines. I am not a historian, and my understanding of ancient history is totally amateur. From my very inexpert research, I know that of the Mesopotamian Empires, Assyria&#8217;s progress was very much focused on conquering neighboring regions, and a lot of the technology developed then was related to the military. I like to think of this story as occurring in a Sumer-like civilization before the rise of an Assyrian-like Empire, and with the destruction of so much technological documentation occurring in the story, perhaps even making way for it. Also, before the Assyrians, women were considered relatively equal to men, though it might be a bit of a stretch to think of a priestess as some kind of chief engineer.</div>
<div></div>
<div>And I&#8217;m usually completely game for a fictional story that discusses how science, technology, and religion deeply need each other. But in this case, Sumerian society really did assign religious leaders what we would consider secular responsibilities like developing agricultural technology. Which I think is really cool.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The last action in the story is unexpected, but fitting. Explore more for us the responsibility the MC felt for the princesses and what the King had become.</strong></em></div>
<div><b> </b></div>
<div>Anne: I wanted the ending to be jarring. This main character has a hard time identifying what she&#8217;s feeling as seething rage. Her realm of expertise is not emotion.</div>
<div></div>
<div>At her sister&#8217;s request, she&#8217;s devoted her life to creating new and useful information and tools. When she speaks to the king at the end, she&#8217;s realized that he conceives of everything and everyone, including his own daughters, as means for making himself appear powerful. He doesn&#8217;t feel love for or obligation to his family. He doesn&#8217;t feel wonder at technological advancement. He sees opportunities to capitalize on others for personal gain. When she realizes<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22027 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/william-krause-IkYuzPneQWs-unsplash-300x208.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="208" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/william-krause-IkYuzPneQWs-unsplash-300x208.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/william-krause-IkYuzPneQWs-unsplash-1024x709.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/william-krause-IkYuzPneQWs-unsplash-768x532.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/william-krause-IkYuzPneQWs-unsplash-1536x1063.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/william-krause-IkYuzPneQWs-unsplash-2048x1418.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> that she helped create the image of himself that justifies this behavior, she makes a decision.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><b>LSQ: How important is world-building in your writing? What else are you working on currently?</b></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Anne: I also write comics, where it&#8217;s relatively easy to convey how sound, light, and texture feel to me. But I love including these sensations in my text-only writing, because the reader gets to interpret them however they imagine, and potentially much more vividly than I can convey in a static image. I hope by including intimate descriptions of how things look, sound, and feel, my worlds become animated to the reader.</div>
<div></div>
<div>A short comic of mine, &#8220;Cookie Pouch&#8221;, just appeared in <i><a href="https://www.hobartpulp.com/web_features/cookie-pouch" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.hobartpulp.com/web_features/cookie-pouch&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1600798474168000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFVKT_3C4Be4yRQb5qKI9foIMrNeg">Hobart Pulp</a></i>. I have another comic appearing in <i><a href="https://www.mookychick.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.mookychick.co.uk/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1600798474168000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGOVYTPh3KmvOSETBhlPF41v29H2Q">Mookychick</a>&#8216;</i>s upcoming <i>Medusa Project, </i>and a load of short stories slowly being chipped away at.<i> </i>Unrelated to writing, I host a podcast about bisexuality with my buddy Rose, called <i><a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5ln2Tr068UUThAcb33s0jl?si=awNTwFsJToixdzuUEIU06w" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://open.spotify.com/show/5ln2Tr068UUThAcb33s0jl?si%3DawNTwFsJToixdzuUEIU06w&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1600798474168000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE0qNdGiVS_m6zU8ENGNuvdSCZQGw">Hello Good Bis</a></i>.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Also, I write a column about technology for this publication! It&#8217;s called <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/everybody-and-their-motherboard/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://2f5.f93.mwp.accessdomain.com/category/everybody-and-their-motherboard/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1600798474168000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFJw6z0CQhxfb80_bztow2ocIOLUQ">Everybody and Their Motherboard</a> <img decoding="async" class="CToWUd" src="https://mail.google.com/mail/e/1f916" alt="?" data-goomoji="1f916" data-image-whitelisted="" />.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 043 Author Interview: Alexandra Grunberg and &#8220;The Family Recipe&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-alexandra-grunberg-and-the-family-recipe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 043]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19440</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just in time for Halloween, we chat with Issue 043 author Alexandra Grunberg about her&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just in time for Halloween, we chat with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-043/">Issue 043</a> author Alexandra Grunberg about her witchy, magical, and slightly ominous story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-family-recipe/">The Family Recipe</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong><span class="im">LSQ: This story has less of a plot and more of an ambling-through-time arc. What do you like about stories with no overt conflict? What can we get out of them?</span></strong></em></p>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21966 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/antiquariat-1724472_1920-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/antiquariat-1724472_1920-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/antiquariat-1724472_1920-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/antiquariat-1724472_1920-768x508.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/antiquariat-1724472_1920-1536x1017.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/antiquariat-1724472_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Alexandra: After several false starts looking for a plot-like entryway, I decided to shift the focus from one specific character and their more traditional arc to the prop-focused story. The object itself remains, if not static, then constant, as the stories weave through and around it. I think that stories that follow this type of ambling timeline have their own kind of conflict that stands outside the narrative. It never materializes because the characters themselves do not realize what they are dealing with, if there will be repercussions, and how their actions play out in the wider world outside their immediate family’s experiences. I hope that this invites a playful experience for the reader, as they reckon with the family cookbook in a way the characters never realize they should. The ambling storyline then sits parallel to another, much darker story, that forms in the reader’s imagination. As a reader, I enjoy stories that let me act almost as a detective or explorer, taking on an active role when the story has room for various readings and interpretations.<br />
<span class="im"><br />
<em><strong>LSQ: The idea of a family cookbook being passed down, enjoyed, and added to through generations is so wonderful. Where did you get the idea for this story? What made you add in a dash of deviousness? </strong></em></span></div>
<div>Alexandra: I got the idea for the story while cooking with my flatmate. We have very different approaches to recipes – I follow guidelines exactly (I’ve even googled how much a ‘pinch of salt’ actually is) while my flatmate ‘lets the ancestors guide her’ when it comes to measurements and cooking times. It made me think of how personal cooking is and how much it is tied to the methods our families pass down to us, while also reflecting our own personalities through our approach to recipes. I liked to think that there could be that same casual, familial, and fun relationship to magic recipes. The ‘dash of deviousness’ surprised me – I thought I was writing a feel-good family piece. But in exploring the history of the family in relation to the cookbook, I remembered that magic books have their own histories and legends as well.<br />
<span class="im"><br />
<strong><em>LSQ: What was the most enjoyable part about writing this story and why? The most difficult?</em></strong></span></div>
<div>Alexandra: The most enjoyable part about writing this story was reaching the end, discovering for <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21965 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/campfire-1846142_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/campfire-1846142_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/campfire-1846142_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/campfire-1846142_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/campfire-1846142_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/campfire-1846142_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />myself the true ties that connected the family to this book and each other, and how that realization colored all the memories and moments that came before. The most difficult was going back and justifying the ending without (hopefully) making it too obvious and maintaining the dark surprise.<br />
<span class="im"><br />
<strong><em>LSQ: Are there any other projects you&#8217;re currently working on? If so, could you tell us a bit about them?</em></strong></span></div>
<div>Alexandra: I am currently a postgraduate student in the DFA in Creative Writing program at the University of Glasgow. I am working on my dissertation, a novel that is a post apocalyptic retelling of <em>The Merchant of Venice</em>.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 043 Author Interview: Victoria V. and &#8220;Vó Úrsula’s Magical Shop for Soul-Aches&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-victoria-v-and-vo-ursulas-magical-shop-for-soul-aches/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 10:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 043]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s October, it&#8217;s Tuesday, it&#8217;s a great time for a magical author interview! Step into&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s October, it&#8217;s Tuesday, it&#8217;s a great time for a magical author interview! Step into &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/vo-ursulas-magical-shop-for-soul-aches/">Vó Úrsula’s Magical Shop for Soul-Aches</a>&#8221; and enjoy our chat with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-043/">Issue 043</a> author Victoria V.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Beyond the sweet facade of Vó Úrsula&#8217;s house lies a world in turmoil. But instead of focusing on the bad events happening outside, the story takes place solely inside the house. Why did you make this choice?</em></strong></p>
<p>Victoria: It wasn&#8217;t something I had in mind when I began to write the story! I wanted to explore the idea of how important a tight community is during hard times, and I decided to do that by focusing on a small group of characters. It&#8217;s important to read and write about important historical events — and, in today&#8217;s Brazil, more than ever, to remember what happened during the military dictatorship — but I wanted to explore how ordinary lives are affected by them. So the outside world wasn&#8217;t exactly my focus, even if it plays a crucial part in the story.</p>
<p>As the plot began to develop, I noticed that what brought all of these very different people <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21910 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/house-3596198_1920-237x300.jpg" alt="" width="237" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/house-3596198_1920-237x300.jpg 237w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/house-3596198_1920-808x1024.jpg 808w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/house-3596198_1920-768x973.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/house-3596198_1920-1212x1536.jpg 1212w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/house-3596198_1920.jpg 1515w" sizes="(max-width: 237px) 100vw, 237px" />together was the safety and comfort they found in Úrsula&#8217;s figure, in different ways. It was an almost automatic decision for the action to take place inside her house. I&#8217;ve always been drawn to stories in which the setting is, depending on how you see it, a character, so that might have had an influence on how it is presented throughout the story. I also had a lot of fun imagining its details, especially the magical shop.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Vó Úrsula&#8217;s house feels so cozy and peaceful. Where did you find the inspiration for this character and her magical home?</em></strong></p>
<p>Victoria: It came from two places. The first one is the figure of the typical Brazilian grandmother: a kind figure with a big heart who knows how to be stern from time to time, and who brings the family together. They usually have a miraculous recipe or ritual that they swear by, and that&#8217;s where the idea for Vó Úrsula being an unconventional witch came from — I believe all grandmothers are, at some degree, magical.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The second source of ideas was my own family. I didn&#8217;t write the story with my experiences in mind, but I&#8217;m sure that there was a lot of personal input. I&#8217;m lucky enough to be able to spend time with both of my grandmothers, who are strong and loving women, and to have heard their stories as I grew up. The inspiration for Úrsula&#8217;s house certainly came from their apartments,  filled with little secrets and memories. Also, the room for the grandchildren exists, and it had the magical property of fitting nine loud cousins during Christmas gatherings.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Aside from an amazing setting, your characters are all relatable and dynamic. What are your tips for creating characters that feel real?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Victoria: Oh, I&#8217;m so happy to hear that! I don&#8217;t have any specific method I follow to create characters — actually, my creative process consists of messy notebooks, lots of revisions, and ranting to my friends, so I&#8217;m not the best person to give advice. Besides, this was my first published short story, so I&#8217;ve still got a lot to learn, too.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21911 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cat-2742106_1920-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cat-2742106_1920-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cat-2742106_1920-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cat-2742106_1920-768x510.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cat-2742106_1920-1536x1021.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cat-2742106_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I&#8217;ve always been interested in history, and one of my favorite discussions is how easy it is to forget that the major events were lived by common people. One of my favorite writers, Svetlana Aleksiévitch, says that it&#8217;s more difficult to understand a human soul than the &#8220;big history&#8221; itself. Thinking about that changed how I view the world — and, I believe, how I see my characters. Humans are complex! We all have different motivations, contradictions and beliefs: we’re not flat people who have only one purpose. Allowing a little bit of that complexity into the people that move your story is an interesting way to make them feel more real.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong><em>LSQ: Are there any other projects you&#8217;re currently working on? If so, could you tell us a bit about them?</em></strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Victoria: I’m currently working on writing down some ideas, and in exploring different formats to tell stories. For example, I’m a huge fan of reading and writing letters, and I’m rewriting a story that’s told through correspondence. It centers on the themes of memories and exile, and there are ghosts — as a good Brazilian, I can’t resist a good ghostlore. I’ve also got some smaller projects at different stages, but I’m still not sure what I want to do with them. Having my first story published has been a great surprise: I’ve always been very private about my writing, and seeing it out in the world was an amazing experience. I can’t wait to see what comes next!</p>
<p dir="ltr">Also, I’m a blogger for Luna Station Quarterly, so I’m always thinking about themes for <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/freedom-books-flowers-the-moon/">my column</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 043 Author Interview: Chelsea Sutton and &#8220;The Space Beyond Cubicle Twenty-Nine&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-chelsea-sutton-and-the-space-beyond-cubicle-twenty-nine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 043]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s Tuesday, dear readers, and you know what that means! We have a brand new&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s Tuesday, dear readers, and you know what that means! We have a brand new <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-043/">Issue 043</a> author interview for you to devour. Today we&#8217;re talking with Chelsea Sutton about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-space-beyond-cubicle-twenty-nine/">The Space Beyond Cubicle Twenty-Nine</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story has a lot of significant imagery, from the sugarcane to spirals to powdered doughnuts. How did you decide on what imagery to use? Do you have any advice on using imagery effectively?</strong></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chelsea: When I’m writing a story, I always think about ways to engage the senses beyond the visual. What images can also evoke a smell, a sound, a taste or a texture? I’m a playwright as well, and I lean heavily into sound design when I write plays &#8211; partly because sound and music can evoke so much and it saves me time in exposition. With fiction, I think smells and tastes tend <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21342 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/donut-179983_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/donut-179983_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/donut-179983_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/donut-179983_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/donut-179983_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/donut-179983_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />to come through more often and for the same reason. Anything that is going to ground a reader into their bodies and give them a tangible experience of the world is going to be helpful, especially for things that are difficult to describe. A powdered doughnut can sometimes speak to an emotion, energy, or unknowable sadness more easily than all the abstractions a writer can muster. But make your images work for you on at least two levels. Don’t let them hang around, rent free. They have to prove their worth.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best possible thing you can do to improve your imagery is to read and write poetry. I am not a poet. But in college I took a lot of poetry classes. At the time I took them out of curiosity and because there just were not many fiction classes in my department. So I wrote and read a ton of poetry &#8211; and I still run to it when I need to refill my word well. The expanse of worlds a poem can hold in a dozen lines is magic. Each word is especially chosen and placed in precisely the location where it can have the most impact. Fiction writers don’t necessarily have the time to obsess over every single sentence in this way &#8211; but if you can do it for those choice few moments &#8211; you’re golden. </span></p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Even though the world is crumbling and changing dramatically, Lucy still goes to work and buys groceries, living as normal a life as possible. What do you think you would do in a world being taken over by Humans?</em></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chelsea: This is tricky! For Lucy, I think she clings to normalcy for a few reasons. First, I think she has a unique way of processing the world, which allows her to see a kind of inauthenticity that most of the others can’t or are unwilling to see. Second, she’s grieving for the loss of a relationship and people she knows and we tend to like the familiar when something else has been ripped from us. But most importantly, life is still continuing on. She still has to pay rent and eat. She still has to have health insurance and get an oil change. This is because the Human take over is gradual and is wrapped very tightly around a narrative that is being fed to the population. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21344 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-2952779_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-2952779_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-2952779_1920-1024x577.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-2952779_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-2952779_1920-1536x865.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-2952779_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I think we all have an image of who we’d be in an extreme dystopia or apocalypse. When the world as we know it has crumbled, we don’t have the option to choose normal. If there are no rent collectors and no money, then why go to work? But usually that apocalypse is sudden, dramatic, and more like a war &#8211; where you have to react immediately in order to survive. Even <em>The Handmaid’s Tale,</em> while also showing a gradual religious extremism and take over, has a sudden and violent movement to it that pushes it into the actual dystopia phase. But the slow descent into a dictatorship, or, say, a pandemic that doesn’t immediately turn everyone into zombies? I think of that frog-in-boiling-water analogy. We humans are really great at adapting and rationalizing, so when the changes happen in small steps, it’s easy to get lost on the trail and tell ourselves this is how its always been. The frog, however, does actually jump out before being boiled alive (it’s been scientifically proven). Humans though? I’m not so sure.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All that to say, probably we are in some sort of version of this right now, in this moment. So while I’d like to say I’d be stealing fighter jets and flying into the aliens’ giant and obvious laser weapon a la </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Independence Day</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, in reality I’m just trying to survive (because rent is still due), so I’m balancing the normal with the small acts of rebellion and incremental change (protests, voting, wearing a mask, working on codes of conduct and spreadsheet audits for various support systems). You know. The boring stuff.</span></p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: What was the most challenging thing about writing this story and why? What was your favorite part?</em></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chelsea: My first draft of this was far less scifi/fantasy. I wrote the first version of this during a phase when I was convinced anything too “weird” would never get published (partly because I’d been told that over and over by teachers and such). Now I don’t care and have plenty of ready-to-go lectures on why genre fiction is awesome. EVERYTHING I write is genre. Version one didn’t have any aliens at all (it was much more government conspiracy) and Lucy’s general situation was leaner. It was also in first person! So the hardest part was allowing myself to push this more into an alien invasion genre and expanding the character work. The second hardest was just structural &#8211; I rearranged how we learn information about the outside world and the office a million times. My favorite part was the office dynamics &#8211; characters who are so intimate and yet still strangers are wildly fascinating to me. And while every version of Lucy had her drawing in some way, allowing her drawing to span the whole office felt like a piece of the story’s heart that had been missing.</span></p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: What and who are your sources of inspiration?</em></strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-21345 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-rocket-3153987_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-rocket-3153987_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-rocket-3153987_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-rocket-3153987_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-rocket-3153987_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/space-rocket-3153987_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chelsea: When it comes to other writers, the moment I read Kelly Link’s collection </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Magic for Beginners</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, it was like a lightbulb went off in my head. Oh, you can do</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">? That’s what I want to do! So basically all Kelly Link all the time for structure, character, and imagination, and Kurt Vonnegut for language, tone, and humor. But mostly I’m inspired by my fellow writers &#8211; I have a few communities of writers in fiction and in scriptwriting who I talk with, trade writing with, and collaborate with all the time. I’m in the Clarion UCSD class for 2020/21 (we couldn’t go this year because COVID) &#8211; we call ourselves #ClarionGhostClass and we’re in a constant chat, giving and receiving advice, support, recommendations, and feedback. And I found this true with my cohort in my MFA program and other writing groups I’m involved with &#8211; I learn far more from my peers than my teachers. Awesome teachers are precious and wonderful and necessary &#8211; but it’s the people you come up with who will keep you sane, keep you on track, and inspire you. I think this is true for whatever community or career you’re in. When I taught creative writing in my grad program, that was the one last piece of advice I gave them &#8211; find your tribe. If you forget everything else I went over this quarter, just don’t forget that.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 043 Author Interview: Victoria Zelvin and &#8220;Dead Katherine&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-victoria-zelvin-and-dead-katherine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 10:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 043]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How are you liking Issue 043 so far? If you just can&#8217;t get enough of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How are you liking <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-043/">Issue 043</a> so far? If you just can&#8217;t get enough of those stellar stories, then join us as we delve deeper with our author interviews! Victoria Zelvin sits with us today to discuss her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/dead-katherine/">Dead Katherine</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story is a unique blend of post-apocalyptic, Western, and sci-fi. Were these elements difficult to meld? What was your writing process like?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-19865 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pistol-2053092_1920-300x135.jpg" alt="" width="367" height="165" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pistol-2053092_1920-300x135.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pistol-2053092_1920-1024x459.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pistol-2053092_1920-768x344.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pistol-2053092_1920-1536x689.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pistol-2053092_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 367px) 100vw, 367px" />Victoria: One of my favorite parts of the term speculative fiction is how much can fit under the umbrella. Personally, I do not find that blending genres is too terribly difficult, and enjoy the challenge that comes with fitting the pieces together, with genre and character. My writing process for this story started with the idea for the characters, two people sharing one body, and I started to circle out from there. The lone gunslinger type of character naturally evokes a Western, and with things like Westworld in popular culture I have seen more of an understanding that these archetypes can be used across genres. Then that couples with the fact that some of my favorite stories recently have taken an expected genre and set it so far after the &#8220;apocalypse&#8221; that this is the new normal. While I am starting to grow more and more tired of apocalypse, world ending stories, I&#8217;m very fond of stories that take place after the dust has settled and human beings continue on like we always do, for better or for worse.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I had a hunch that the characters sporting &#8220;sunburn&#8221; were actually suffering from radiation poisoning, and was quite pleased when I was right. What advice do you have for effectively using foreshadowing like you did in this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Victoria: Good catch! The idea of radiation poisoning has always been terrifying to me, and something so slow acting works very well to communicate that something is wrong, something is off, before it is actually revealed what &#8212; and that is in this case a damaged alien spaceship. I like to start at the end of my stories, and then work backward from there. I am a very piecemeal drafter, starting in different spots, writing a couple paragraphs or pages, and then going back to connect the dots. I think that doing that helps me figure out what I want to foreshadow, because I have written the end already and can write it into the beginning next. If you&#8217;re a person who drafts from beginning to end, I&#8217;d definitely recommend going back and figuring out what you can pepper in to tease the reader. In my own work, I&#8217;ve liked to try to tell the reader something about how it ends in the first couple pages, if not in the first paragraph.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Who and what are your major sources of inspiration?</strong></em></p>
<p>Victoria: I try to read and watch a bit of everything, though I am clearly a lot more into speculative<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19866 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/fantasy-4704796_1920-300x170.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="170" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/fantasy-4704796_1920-300x170.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/fantasy-4704796_1920-1024x579.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/fantasy-4704796_1920-768x434.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/fantasy-4704796_1920-1536x869.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/fantasy-4704796_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> fiction than anything else. Some of my formative inspiration comes from authors such as Tamora Pierce and Octavia Butler. I also think there&#8217;s a lot that we can learn about storytelling from movies and video games, and I&#8217;ve been very interested in how the latter casts the player as a protagonist, and how the shape of the story changes depending on gameplay choices.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any other projects you&#8217;re currently working on? If so, could you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Victoria: I am currently working on my first novel, a murder mystery set in a world where everyone knows how they&#8217;re going to die from the day they&#8217;re born. I also have a few other short stories out in the world, making the rounds, and if you&#8217;re interested you can check out <a href="http://www.victoriazelvin.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.victoriazelvin.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1598901738082000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFgzNex2Ha1pKU1Kqc9TrBrwZv5Tg">www.victoriazelvin.com</a> for updates as I have them.</p>
<div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 043 Author Interview: Andrea Goyan and &#8220;A Worship&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-andrea-goyan-and-a-worship/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-andrea-goyan-and-a-worship/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 10:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 043]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yes, it&#8217;s true, we have another Issue 043 author interview for you! Join us as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, it&#8217;s true, we have another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-043/">Issue 043</a> author interview for you! Join us as we chat with Andrea Goyan about creepy crawlies and her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/a-worship/">A Worship</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What a fascinatingly creepy story! Where did you get the idea to turn insects into killers of not just crops, but people?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19811 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/brussels-sprouts-3733289_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/brussels-sprouts-3733289_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/brussels-sprouts-3733289_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/brussels-sprouts-3733289_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/brussels-sprouts-3733289_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/brussels-sprouts-3733289_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Andrea: I’d been reading about scientists genetically altering insects for pest management. On the surface, it seemed like the perfect solution to mitigate our overuse of pesticides. Still, I wondered if it would stop there? Insects are excellent vectors, and I figured weaponizing them would be some man’s sick fantasy. The story took off from there.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: A short story doesn’t leave a lot of time to develop a mystery, but you managed it. Do you </strong></em><em><strong>read a lot of mysteries and thrillers? Did you have any particular inspiration for Detective Angie </strong></em><em><strong>Ferguson?</strong></em></p>
<p>Andrea: I’m a very eclectic reader, really, I’m all over the map. I can’t claim to be an avid reader of any one genre, but I love a great page-turning mystery or thriller. Angie Ferguson didn’t come from one particular inspiration. I feel like she’s an amalgamation of many take no prisoner women characters I’ve admired. She’s also a nod to women everywhere who’ve been underestimated. And a warning—<em>Don’t do it!</em></p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: When I think of creepy insects, aphids aren’t the first that spring into my head, but this story </strong></em><em><strong>might change my mind. If you had to rank insects from most menacing to most benign, what </strong></em><em><strong>would top your list?</strong></em></p>
<p>Andrea: I want to say spiders are the most menacing because I don’t like finding them in <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19809 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aphids-756838_1920-300x202.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="202" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aphids-756838_1920-300x202.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aphids-756838_1920-1024x689.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aphids-756838_1920-768x516.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aphids-756838_1920-1536x1033.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/aphids-756838_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />unexpected places, but I appreciate their place in the ecosystem, and technically, they aren’t insects. I’m going to go with mosquitoes because they kill so many people every year. I also recently learned about kissing bugs. They freak me out. They’re like little vampire insects whose parting gift is the Chagas disease. Plus, there’s something about them biting around your eyes and mouth while you’re sleeping that horrifies me. Most benign, I’m choosing butterflies, ladybugs, and dragonflies. I love praying mantises, but they’re certainly menacing to anything small enough for them to catch. Of course, I’m looking at all of this from a human perspective. In reality, we’re a much bigger menace to them. I imagine the insect world has WANTED posters of us everywhere they go.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-andrea-goyan-and-a-worship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 043 Author Interview: D.L. Podlesni and &#8220;For God is in Sleep Also&#8230;&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-043-author-interview-d-l-podlesni-and-for-god-is-in-sleep-also/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 043]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to Tuesday, where we interview an author of our current issue! Today we chat with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Tuesday, where we interview an author of our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-043/">current issue</a>! Today we chat with D.L. Podlesni about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/for-god-is-in-sleep-also-and-dreams-advise/">For God is in Sleep Also, and Dreams Advise</a>.”</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: This is a story with so many layers, I could read it five times and glean something new from it each time. Where did you get the idea for this, and how did you build it up into something so </em></strong><strong><em>complex?</em></strong></p>
<p>D.L.: It started as a nightmare. It’s been banging around my drive since about 2010, with edits and revisions, but the bulk of it was a nightmare. I wrote a collection of magical realist stories based not all that loosely on my hometown in West Virginia in my MFA program, and this one takes place in the next county over. Most West Virginians identify their place of origin by county to outsiders, since there aren’t a terrible lot of cities to speak of.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19757 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/green-5124174_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/green-5124174_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/green-5124174_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/green-5124174_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/green-5124174_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/green-5124174_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Matewan is a real place, in McDowell County, WV, where union leader and scallywag of the people Sid Hatfield really was assassinated in broad daylight by Company thugs, which kicked off the Battle of Blair Mountain, the first time the US government literally bombed its own people to put a miner’s rebellion down in the ‘20s.</p>
<p>This is the world our narrator is living in, that’s been beaten into accepting injustice for, at the time she’s speaking, more than a century. She has this congenital nihilism, even before her father dies so gruesomely, that is sort of endemic to the area.</p>
<p>The Immigrants, and Stella, in particular, represent something new and beautiful&#8211; something hopeful, even, and you see what happens to them&#8230;honestly I struggle with the whole “what does it MEAN?” bit of this story. It’s partly a manifesto on the foolishness of hope from the narrator’s perspective. It’s partly my own struggle trying to shake off that mountain-bred nihilism&#8211;I moved away a long time ago, but that stuff is in the DNA. The immigrants will come back some day, and who will we be then? There’s a glimmer of hope at the end, at least something that feels like hope, and neither of us, the narrator nor myself, trust it entirely. But, it is there.</p>
<p>That said, it may be important to remember it started as a nightmare.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I love your rich descriptions of the Immigrants and the place they came from. What inspired </strong></em><em><strong>you to make them so plant-like?</strong></em></p>
<p>D.L.: If I’m honest, the Immigrants are plant-like because it seemed really cool. I liked the aesthetic&#8211;they are so very unlike the locals in every way. It’s a tiny bit of foreshadowing, too, though. Microscopic, even, to the point that it’s pretty much just for me. It isn’t easy to get plants to grow in soil that’s been wrecked by mining, in low valleys where it’s dark all the time. If you know that, you know the immigrants are doomed from the start.</p>
<p>LSQ: <em><strong>This story’s ending makes me think there could be a lot more to this world. Do you have any </strong></em><em><strong>plans to revisit it?</strong></em></p>
<p>D.L.: This is the revisit!</p>
<p>I wrote a collection of magical realist stories based on my hometown for my MFA thesis. My <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19759 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/succulents-939919_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/succulents-939919_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/succulents-939919_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/succulents-939919_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/succulents-939919_1920-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/succulents-939919_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />cohort was pretty split on some of the stories&#8211;they said it was impossible to tell the era stories were taking place. For some people it was a complaint, others, less so. But I never tried to make those stories unstuck from time; it’s just the nature of cultural poverty. When I wrote this story, I wanted to give it a more specific sense of time, even if it was subtle, like naming the different groups of refugees who had lived in the Immigrants’ houses in the past. “For God is in Sleep…” is me writing a story set in the “future” of the town I’d been writing about for so long. (For what it’s worth, the cohort was less split on this one&#8211;all but about 3 of my friends despised it because it is ‘genre’.)</p>
<p>I want very badly to be done with this world. I am always glad when readers like to visit it, but writing about it is painful. The real life model these stories sprang from is not an easy place to live, and I have not lived there for over 15 years. I wanted “For God is in Sleep” to be a capstone to the whole thing, but I suspect I’ll be back.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
