<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Fun and Games &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/columns/fun-and-games/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:30:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Why the RWA Implosion Is Relevant to ALL Writers</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/why-the-rwa-implosion-is-relevant-to-all-writers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 11:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, Y/N. I’ve got no jokes today. I’m no fun and no games, either. See,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17120 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/jeshoots-com-2vD8lIhdnw-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Hello, Y/N.</p>
<p>I’ve got no jokes today. I’m no fun and no games, either. See, recent events in the Romance Writers of America, an organization I’ve paid dues to, has my smile turned upside down and with d*mn good reason.</p>
<p>If you have not heard the ugly basics of this ongoing scandal/mess, there are a couple of resources to peek at first. Author Clair Ryan <a href="https://www.claireryanauthor.com/blog/2019/12/27/the-implosion-of-the-rwa">composed an excellent article</a> featuring an incredibly useful timeline of events. <a href="https://medium.com/the-aambc-journal/a-tragic-fall-from-grace-rwas-public-implosion-bf9b1f279b6a">Medium’s Phoenix Williams</a> offers her experience and a succinct overview of the trash fire,<a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/pw/by-topic/industry-news/trade-shows-events/article/82100-rwa-cancels-2020-rita-awards.html"> Publishers Weekly</a> covered the cancellation of the RITA awards, <a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/1/10/21055125/rwa-what-happened-resignations-courtney-milan-damon-suede-backstory-2020-ritas-conference">Vox has a piece</a> updated to actually feature content from writers of color, and which displays the offensive, recent, and monstrously tone-deaf Romance Writers Report cover.</p>
<p>It’s a lot to follow. TL:DR of the most micro&#8230;the RWA, an organization meant to unite and support romance writers, has engaged in non-inclusive and unethical practices that are harmful to PoC writers, and underrepresented writers from a variety of communities. The precipitating events centered around the ever-awesome Courtney Milan, a Chinese-American romance author and lawyer, are just the tip of the iceberg.</p>
<p>Why is this relevant to you, dear Y/N? Rampant racism, bigotry, and ethical violations in publication are not new (*cough HUGOS cough*). Romance fiction, though, is a huge industry. It is escapism, when done well; at its best, empowering, inclusive, and inspiring. For scandal, hatred, and breaches of ethics to infest what is supposed to be entertaining and empowering means that, for all of those excluded and harmed, their right to enjoyment, to their own voices, to inclusion in not just publishing but hobby-reading, reviewing, and fun in general is tenuous at best.</p>
<p>I can carry this over to the importance of diversity in fanfic and any other popular media, and will in other posts. For now, I’ll say this: if writers of color, LGBT+ authors, and writers with disabilities cannot find a safe haven in creating and sharing love stories, then there is a serious freaking problem. And there has been for years. Again, this is not new, but it is very loudly, brightly obvious to the publishing, reviewing, and reading world now more than ever after the RWA implosion.</p>
<p>The up-side, if there is one? Maybe someone being stupid enough to go after Courtney Milan (I hate that I even have to do this silver lining crap) will lead to greater transparency within publishing communities, and will boost support and readership for authors of color and underrepresented authors. Maybe the mess that is currently the RWA will be reborn in a better form, or will pave the way for stronger support organizations that are truly inclusive.</p>
<p>RWA’s recent events prove that yes, hand-wringing do-gooders that want everyone to be nice, there is a reason for authors affected by these practices to be angry. Leave the nice to those of us with the privilege to do so. The RWA’s implosion is relevant to all (by which I mean to emphasize traditionally privileged, white) writers because we <i>have </i>to do better. White fragility and professional gripes or jealousies have NO place in the conversation right now. This is not about those of us who have enjoyed privilege throughout our careers or, if hobbyists, our experiences posting and sharing our fics. This is the time for us to listen, learn, and make changes based on the advice and recommendations of those who have been most hurt by <img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17121 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/eric-ward-P6NhhvGIL9k-unsplash-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />scandals like this.</p>
<p>Yes, this is a soap-box moment. A teachable moment. And yes, it is relevant and important to anyone, even those who do not read or write in the romance genre. Where can we start, you might be wondering&#8230;well, it’s actually not that difficult. Support PoC authors by buying, reading, blogging about, featuring their work. Consult sensitivity readers when you write outside of your perspective and demographic. Read blog posts and listen to author talks that address inclusivity, sensitivity, and DEI issues in publishing and writing. And when someone who is NOT you but who has been gaslighted, taken advantage of, been excluded from professional outlets, and so on is talking about their experience, be quiet and LISTEN.</p>
<p>I hope that this series of painful experiences and scandals can help shed light on the pervasiveness of racism, exclusivity, and bigotry, and that this light shines on better practices and opportunities and a future where such implosions are a thing of the past. Till then, Nice White Ladies, we have work to do, so get to it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self Care in the New Year: Back to Life, Back to Reality</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/self-care-in-the-new-year-back-to-life-back-to-reality/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 11:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17017</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well hello again, Y/N⁠—happy 2020! So, I am a Gen-X’er,  hailing from the ancient days&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17018 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/pexels-photo-3496995-300x285.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="285" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/pexels-photo-3496995-300x285.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/pexels-photo-3496995.jpeg 653w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Well hello again, Y/N⁠—happy 2020! So, I am a Gen-X’er,  hailing from the ancient days of cassingles and acid washed, tight-rolled jeans. In 1989, the band Soul II Soul released a song that pops into my head to this very day⁠—&#8221;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TB54dZkzZOY">Back to Life&#8221;</a>. A good beat, smooth af vocals, earworm-worthy in every way.</p>
<p>And now that I’m back to work after the holiday break, the song loops in my head and rings with relevance all these years later. The holidays here in the U.S., for many, are a liminal space. Even if you are working, it’s not the same flavor of &#8220;working&#8221; as other times of year. Projects, workflows, customers, tasks gain a strange mix of urgency and hazy-lazy. I’ve worked a wide variety of jobs over my lifetime: cashier in a variety of retail outlets, barista, legal clerk, temp agencies, teaching, administrative stuff, editing. In every one of these disparate jobs, the Holiday Time Vortex applied. Like the olden dank meme says, I tumble out of them “confused, full of cheese, unsure of the day of the week.”</p>
<p>Then, suddenly, I find myself “back to life, back to reality, back to the here and now.” Work continues apace, sorta. Routines reassert themselves, or I forge new ones. Usually. Sometimes, though, it’s not that easy. Post-holidays malaise can carry into daily life in surprising ways. Like, forgetting to actually cook nourishing food or shop for said food. Staying up till 3 a.m. staring at a screen like I don’t actually have to haul my @ss into the office the next day.</p>
<p>Another extreme of non-routine exists: Resolutions Zealotry. I have plans! I have goals! I have agency! Yes, yes, and heck yeah, you do. But you also have only so much time and energy (by you, I mean me, and anyone else who does this). It’s easy to slump into feeling defeated and unsuccessful when the millions of well-meaning goals we set are left unchecked in those shiny new planners. I have to ask myself, what are some goals I can let go, and which ones can I keep and actually accomplish in a way that alleviates rather than causes stress? For me, meal-planning is a big one this month. Simple meals, allowing myself pre-packaged ingredients but things I will cook, that will not leave me feeling that just-ate-a-box-of-cheezysnacks yuck.</p>
<p>It’s a simple thing, but it supports my health which supports my writing, my life.</p>
<p>So, dear Y/N, what are some small, check-offable goals that will bring you back to the here and now?</p>
<p>Here’s wishing you all a New Year filled with peace, light, and every good thing&#8230;thanks for reading!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holiday Self Care</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/holiday-self-care/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 11:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello again, Y/N! Yeah, I’m sticking with the whole fanfic thing here. So, at least&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16907 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/self-love-3969644_1920-1-288x300.jpg" alt="" width="288" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/self-love-3969644_1920-1-288x300.jpg 288w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/self-love-3969644_1920-1.jpg 318w" sizes="(max-width: 288px) 100vw, 288px" />Hello again, Y/N! Yeah, I’m sticking with the whole fanfic thing here. So, at least here in the U.S., winter holidays are fast upon many of us. Even if you do not celebrate a particular holiday, the trappings are all around: decorations and music in retail outlets, commercials full of red bows and jingling bells, movies and TV shows featuring holiday themes, and even for many folks either extra work time (customer service this time of year is no joke) or less work time than usual due to closures at your places of school/employment.</p>
<p>In other words, we are immersed. This can be a wonderful thing, in many ways—lights, good food, focusing on gifts and gratitude, and so on. For many others, it can be a remarkably stressful time of year. Many people find themselves feeling lonely, especially when comparing themselves against the happy-family-and-friends-perfection they find all over popular media. For those who have experienced trauma, grief, and loss around this time of year, anniversary syndrome can strike hard. For many others, the lack of sun and sometimes cold temps (here in the Northern Hemisphere at least) can result in Seasonal Affective Disorder, or even just winter blahs.</p>
<p>These things, Y/N, are not to be taken lightly. It’s all too easy to skim through your Insta feed or let your eyes glaze over back to back commercials chock full of picture-perfect joy. And yes, these moments of exquisite, sparkling, gift-wrapped happiness can indeed exist. But so can missing family and friends who are not there, dealing with illness or financial troubles, or feeling trapped in family events amongst those who are not accepting or gentle. Most people have some sort of stress that hits with the holidays and we can’t always see this in the perfectly curated social media feeds or too-bright smiles they show the world.</p>
<p>Bearing this in mind, please know that you are NOT alone in feeling alone, stressed, depressed, or any of it. And with this knowledge close to your heart and forefront in your mind, take time for self-care. I’ll repeat this again, Y/N&#8230;the holidays are not all fun and games so yes, TAKE TIME FOR SELF-CARE.</p>
<p>Self-care does not look the same for any two folks, but it can be as simple as treating oneself to nourishing, tasty meals; taking time off work to sleep in or engage in activities that make you smile. It can be volunteering to help those less fortunate (and there are more than enough opportunities to fit a variety of personalities, physical ability, and talents). It can be re-reading that one book that always makes you smile, not taking phone calls from people you know will bring you down, not leaving the house if you’re feeling extra social anxiety, or taking a brisk walk even though there’s four inches of snow on the ground. Nobody knows what caring for yourself looks like better than you, Y/N, and I am giving you a permission slip to take the time you need to be the best possible you this holiday season and always.</p>
<p>Here’s wishing you all peace, joy, and good things now and into the new year!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self-Care for NaNo and Beyond, Part Two</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/self-care-for-nano-and-beyond-part-two/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Editor&#8217;s note: Part 1 of Self Care for NaNoWriMo posted November 8.] Well hello there,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[<em>Editor&#8217;s note: Part 1 of Self Care for NaNoWriMo <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/self-care-for-nano-and-beyond-part-one/">posted November 8</a>.</em>]</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16667 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eye-for-ebony-7EpZ2IMxK7g-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />Well hello there, Wri-mers . . . are you hydrated today? Have you taken a moment to breathe? Yeah? That’s great! You are well on your way to fostering some wonderful habits that you can carry over into your non-NaNo life!</p>
<p>But what’s that you’re saying? You’re creatively blocked? Sick of your story? Sick of spoken and written language altogether?</p>
<p>Ah, yes. Creative burnout is a very real phenomenon and not at all a pleasant one. Good thing I have, thanks to my personal experiences and suggestions from many other creatives I know, come up with some nice little block-breakers and creativity hacks!</p>
<p><b>NaNo Self Care: The Mind Edition</b></p>
<p><b>Here are some simple ways to not just survive NaNo, but to thrive in the process. These items can be done whenever you feel like your writing is stalled, your process is failing, or your mind is just not in the game.</b></p>
<p><b>Change up your scenery or work area. </b>While repetition and routine can work wonders for forming habits, these things can start to feel more like ruts when you are experiencing creative burnout. You can change your routine in a variety of ways: move your computer or notebook into another room; change the decorations on your desk or add some holiday decor, soothing scented candles, or other happy-place items; mix up your mix&#8211;music-wise&#8211;and listen to some new stuff; get out of the house/office/regular writing cave and attend a write-in, find a nook in a public library, write with a partner, or write at a different time of day than usual.</p>
<p><b>Don’t be afraid to suck.</b> Write a note to yourself and post it in your writing area that is a reminder to your writerly soul that IT’S OKAY TO NOT BE PERFECT. It’s okay for a first draft to suck. It’s MORE than okay, in fact . . . it’s normal. If it’s important enough to you, you can sand down the rough places in a later draft. We all go into this knowing that we are not writing our cleanest/best, and keeping that at the top of our thoughts can go a long way in breaking blocks that hold you back from getting out those words and having fun.</p>
<p><b>Talk about it.</b> Speak&#8211;aloud&#8211;to yourself or a friend (or houseplant or pet) about what is frustrating you most. Talk about why you think your piece stinks. Rant about how crappy your <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16668 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/florencia-viadana-1iyGImW84cQ-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />word count has been, or about your insecurities or plot knots or whatever you feel is holding you back. At the end of no more than half an hour, make a plan: how can you move past these frustrations? What can you do to push forward? Articulating both problems and solutions aloud can go a long way in invigorating your process.</p>
<p><b>Remember to play.</b> Set aside an hour in the day where you do nothing but play. Allow yourself the luxury of sitting down and typing nothing but nonsense. Plop your broody MC into a ball pit at Chuck-E-Cheese, scribble whatever random words and phrases pop into your head, make a bullet-point list like this one of all of your MC’s most hated foods, visit a random generator to come up with absurd prompts, take your antagonist to your favorite coffee shop for an interview session, give your broody MC a perky makeover. If you can’t play on the page, step away and watch an episode of the show that inspired your piece in the first place, do some fan-art of your world or characters . . . you get the picture.</p>
<p><b>Remember you’re not alone, then get back in the chair. </b>Step away from your manuscript and visit the NaNo forums/blog/website to see how other people are dealing with their blocks and slogs. Engage, lurk, or whatever serves your process best, but purposely be aware that YOU ARE NOT ALONE in this . . . that the event itself is one big community of people doing the same thing: <em>writing</em>.</p>
<p>You are back in the chair now, write? I mean right?</p>
<p>I hope these lil’ tips and suggestions help you in your quest to crank out those words, and here’s wishing you a most lovely, joyful, and awesome NaNoWriMo 2019!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self-Care for NaNo and Beyond, Part One</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/self-care-for-nano-and-beyond-part-one/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One of the things I really love about the NaNoWriMo forums, website, and blog is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16466 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kaitlyn-baker-vZJdYl5JVXY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="354" height="236" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kaitlyn-baker-vZJdYl5JVXY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kaitlyn-baker-vZJdYl5JVXY-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/kaitlyn-baker-vZJdYl5JVXY-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 354px) 100vw, 354px" />One of the things I really love about the NaNoWriMo forums, website, and blog is that there are oodles of helpful and inspiring posts and tips about cultivating creativity under pressure. The topic of self-care during this high-pressure month is a topic I see pop up time and again, and I never get tired of seeing these posts. Why? Well . . . yes, I’m a grown@ss adult (no, really I am) but sometimes I forget to do the little things that, uh, keep me alive and functioning.</p>
<p>Since I know many of you are already charging toward that 50K goal, I will keep this post short and simple. I should mention here that any of the bullet-points in this post apply not just to NaNoWrimers, but to creative professionals under deadlines, to students facing down the battle that is pre-finals projects, and to people whose lives have suddenly crossed the border into Busytown.</p>
<p>What I’m offering in this post today is a checklist that, optimally, you’ll use 2-3 times within your waking hours. I personally use Google Docs or Sheets so I can check in from my phone, but this would work well printed or integrated with planning apps like Trello. I’ve even known writers to use their fitness trackers to ping them for the goals those particular apps are able to track. Without further ado, here are some things to remember as you wade/march/rocket/waddle into the fray:</p>
<p><b>NaNo Self Care: The Body Edition [<em>editor&#8217;s note: stay tuned for Part 2 later this month!</em>]<br />
</b></p>
<p><b>Here are some simple ways to not just survive NaNo, but to <em>thrive</em> in the process, and keep your body and mind in the game. Note, setting reminders/alarms for the time-based tasks, at least for the first few days, will help form these healthy habits. </b></p>
<p><b>Drink a glass of water hourly. </b>Hydration is <i>everything</i>. Without it, our bodies cannot do what they need to do to heal, process nutrients, allow us to THINK (and therefore, write).</p>
<p><b>Stretch or, if you are physically able to do so, get up at least once an hour. </b>Physical <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16467 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/adeolu-eletu-DqWEAOHsAvc-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/adeolu-eletu-DqWEAOHsAvc-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/adeolu-eletu-DqWEAOHsAvc-unsplash-768x509.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/adeolu-eletu-DqWEAOHsAvc-unsplash-1024x678.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />activity&#8211;even something as simple as lifting your arms, readjusting your posture, or moving your legs where you sit&#8211;can wake up a sleepy writer, succeeding where caffeine fails. Take the bench, coffee&#8211;jazz hands, you’re up!</p>
<p><b>Every half hour, pause and take a few deep breaths.</b> Often when we are in the creative flow, we forget even to blink, and our breathing can be shallow, affecting our oxygen levels. Breathing purposefully can refresh and reorient our systems, allowing for greater mental clarity.</p>
<p><b>Eat regular meals/snacks and stick to your normal meal routine as much as possible. </b>If you can afford/manage quick meals and snacks (frozen meals, groceries delivered, PB&amp;J sammiches, batch meals or snacks like soups that you can freeze or large bowls of popcorn you can portion out), this is ideal. Setting aside a couple of hours a week for meal planning and prep can save you hours in the long run, and give your mind fuel for cranking out those words!</p>
<p><b>Sleep!!!</b> Keeping a regular sleep schedule, as much as possible, will work wonders for your ability to push through on days when you’re about ready to set your manuscript on fire then chuck it into the stratosphere. Even if you are getting less sleep than usual, staying on a schedule or at least allowing dedicated time to rest with purpose can make all the difference when fighting burnout.</p>
<p><b>Engage with others! </b>Yes, this is a physical/body self-care bullet-point. Engagement with other beings, sentient or otherwise, can do wonders for grounding you, bringing you back down to earth. While participating in the chaos of the month can be exciting, speaking to your housemates/SO’s/online friends or petting your kit-cat/doggo/birb/snek animal pals helps you remember that you exist as a corporeal creature, not just a big, word-addled brain. If you are the kind of person who likes hugs and can find them, do it (even hug yourself if you have to)&#8211;nurturing your physical self with the affection of those around is recharging in a way that nothing else is.</p>
<p>So that’s that, folks. Take care of your body, and the mind will thrive. Here’s wishing you all happy writing&#8211;remember, you’ve got this!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yes to NaNo</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/yes-to-nano/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 18:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[November and late fall mean many things to many people. For a subset of writers&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">November and late fall mean many things to many people. For a subset of writers all over the world, November is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">the </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">month of creative abandon, frantic word-count stuffing, gleeful late nights in front of the computer or analogue documentation device (notebook), and spirited write-ins. AKA, </span><a href="https://www.nanowrimo.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NaNoWriMo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, now an institution in the world of creative content generators. It’s a time of <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16410 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/neel-aSPbuSG4rpo-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/neel-aSPbuSG4rpo-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/neel-aSPbuSG4rpo-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/neel-aSPbuSG4rpo-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />year where the opportunity to write, write, and write some more is more than appealing⁠—it’s a celebration of creativity and craft! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Though most of the buzz surrounding NaNoWriMo is positive, there are still those who take issue with the event for one reason or another and fall into the Na-NOPE camp. A lot of these boil down to personal writing style/preferences, and that is legit. I’ve seen comments noting that the projects resulting from such fast-paced writing fall prey to sloppy craft, inconsistencies, and other pitfalls. If you are striking out to create something that is solid right out of the gate, this argument holds water. Some people justifiably don’t approve of the aggressive timeline, noting that it cultivates unhealthy attitudes towards writing and hey, that also makes sense. Not everybody works the same way, and some people buckle under aggressive deadlines in ways that block them from writing altogether⁠—NOT a good thing. Still others (this is the one that actually sticks in my craw) argue that using NaNoWriMo to write fanfic is cheating, as fanfic is &#8220;not real writing.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That last one⁠—that’s where I have to say my piece. If writing a 50K fanfic installment gets you in the writing chair, that’s fantastic! If it means more people are engaging with the community and actively writing, enriching their lives, then I’m all for it. NaNoWriMo is, at its core, an empowering organization that believes (and participates) in outreach and bringing creativity into the world at large. There are self-awarded badges now that show one’s pride in not playing by the traditional NaNo rules (not writing 50K, doing advance prep, etc.). There is even a separate event, </span><a href="https://ywp.nanowrimo.org/pages/camp-nanowrimo"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Camp NaNoWriMo</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, that occurs in April and July and offers a much greater creative flexibility within some standard, set guidelines.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I have never once “won” NaNoWrimo. I have friends who, on the other hand, exceed the 50K by word-slides. I routinely have to set aside such an aggressive deadline for real life/health issues, and so on. But I always and forever have fun. It’s a celebration of what I love doing most, after all! And at the end of the month, even if I have &#8220;lost,&#8221; I have a reminder that setting writing goals is important. It gets a lot of us out of our creative blocks and back into the habit of writing (when possible) every day. So, at least for me, I say YES to NaNo and hope to happily wri the whole mo of November. OK, I’ll show myself out now.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What are you all working on this year? Happy writing to all, whether you participate in NaNoWriMo or not!</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fun and Games: The Spoopy Edition</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/fun-and-games-the-spoopy-edition/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 10:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BOO! Okay, I love October. Beautiful weather, awesome food (stews, cider, the whole cozy kit&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16310 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/20191006_181329-300x283.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="283" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/20191006_181329-300x283.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/20191006_181329-768x723.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/20191006_181329.jpg 772w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />BOO!</p>
<p>Okay, I love October. Beautiful weather, awesome food (stews, cider, the whole cozy kit and caboodle), and yes . . . Halloween! This past year, I’ve been joining friends as we heed the siren call to escape our realities and dive into new worlds through the medium of board games. Tabletop gaming of any kind seems to be thriving these days, if all the game shops and cafes cropping up around the city are any indication. Immersive, tactile, social in a way that is refreshing&#8211;board games have a lot to offer, and it helps that the past years have seen so many wonderfully creative new offerings on the market.</p>
<p>So, what does this have to do with October and the month of creppy/spoopy goodness? I’m glad you allowed me to project that question in your voice, dear reader. With Halloween around the corner, I thought I’d offer a cute lil’ trinity of portable/packable/party games with themes that fit this most haunted of holidays. For eerily atmospheric to downright scary-good, there are quite a few games on the market that could fill an entire evening of candy and games on their own: Mysterium, Betrayal at House on the Hill, the Arkham Horror entries, and so many more. But if you are out and about for your Halloween celebrations, these games are tiny but in the spirit (get it?) of the season and oh so fun.</p>
<p>If you want a game to accommodate a large party, <a href="https://beziergames.com/products/one-night-ultimate-werewolf">One Night Ultimate Werewolf </a>is perfect for any ghoulish game night. A fast-paced game of deception, logic, and chaos, One Night Ultimate Werewolf provides the option to use the associated app in setting up the scenario. The app <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16311 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/20191006_181431-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/20191006_181431-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/20191006_181431-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/20191006_181431-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/20191006_181431.jpg 2016w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />creates atmosphere and immersion, as well as fulfilling the practical role of getting the game going without having to rely on an outside narrator. The setup is simple, too, once you’ve learned the rules&#8211;there are cards, tokens, and the initial introduction via the app or a narrator. Join your friends and work with (or against) them as you save the town (or not) from a looming, lycan menace! As a bonus, there are other entries in the One Night Ultimate series (such as a vampire-themed one), and a variant called Werewords with very different (and still cool) gameplay in the same cutely-creepy world of One Night Ultimate Werewolf!</p>
<p>If you want a . . . wait for it . . . NO BRAINER of a game, <a href="http://www.sjgames.com/dice/zombiedice/">Zombie Dice</a> is your game. The goal is simple: eat brains and un-live to shamble another day. Where One Night Ultimate Werewolf is best with a larger party, Zombie Dice is plenty of fun with just two players, but accommodates more. The challenge is to collect as many brains as you can without rolling the dreaded shotgun dice, which will eventually end your noggin-chomping ways. This is another fast-paced game (games tend to run around 10 minutes or so when I play) with a lightweight form-factor&#8211;a simple little tube of dice/rules that you can chuck into a bag and barely notice. Bonus: you can buy the expansion (a few extra dice) to give yourself yet another . . . this one’s gonna be good . . . SHOT at nomming some brains!</p>
<p>Last, but not least, is <a href="https://www.atlas-games.com/product_tables/AG1350">Gloom</a>. As a writer, I thoroughly enjoyed this one&#8211;you get to be a storyteller in Gloom. In fact, it’s the point. A one-deck card game, Gloom is the most portable but also the most in-depth of my trinity of recs. This game is unique in so many ways: transparent cards that you overlay with others in your hand to keep track of game objective; wonderfully creppy/spoopy, Goreyesque art; the use of storytelling as a game mechanic; and many others. The real twist, though, is that while in most games you strive to keep self and kindred alive, in Gloom, the objective is to kill off the entirety of your miserable, twisted, wretched family in the most gleefully gruesome of ways. Gloom is for 2 to 4 players, and can take an hour or so, so it’s by far the heftiest entry into my list of potent portables. The makers of Gloom also created Chthulhu and Fairy Tales versions of the game that I’m curious to play.</p>
<p>Now I must shamble/lope/ghostily hover away to stuff my face with candy corn, put on some scary music, and enjoy the days leading to Halloween&#8211;I hope you have a frightfully good one!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ao3 Got a Hugo Award and that is RAD</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ao3-got-a-hugo-award-and-that-is-rad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Well hello again, Y/N! I wasn’t planning two back-to-back fanfiction posts, but it’s not just&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16146 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/christian-wiediger-WkfDrhxDMC8-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/christian-wiediger-WkfDrhxDMC8-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/christian-wiediger-WkfDrhxDMC8-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/christian-wiediger-WkfDrhxDMC8-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Well hello again, Y/N! I wasn’t planning two back-to-back fanfiction posts, but it’s not just every day that one of the biggest fanfiction community organizations WINS A HUGO AWARD. That’s right&#8211;Archive of Our Own, known commonly as AO3, received a Hugo for Best Related Work of 2019. As <a href="https://archiveofourown.org/admin_posts/13528">AO3’s official writeup on the event notes</a>, this is a triumph not just for the hard-working creators of this awesome venue and resource, but for all of those who have contributed through time, donations, and reading or writing fanfiction that makes the site so remarkable.</p>
<p>I have to say, I kinda shrieked like a pterodactyl (at least the kind in movies) when I saw the news. My excitement mirrors the thousands? millions? (don’t make me number) of fans whose lives are richer because of fanfiction and the communities it builds. While source material is exactly that&#8211;and the property of its creators&#8211;writers taking their feels to the page to let us exist for just a little while longer in our happy places do so much to enrich the fandom experience. People can band together to (at times) be a powerful force for good, and fandom is no different than any other set of communities in this respect. Some of my first real experiences with truly inclusive writing were pieces by fanfic writers who wanted to see themselves in the worlds they <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16147 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/brooke-cagle-g1Kr4Ozfoac-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/brooke-cagle-g1Kr4Ozfoac-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/brooke-cagle-g1Kr4Ozfoac-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/brooke-cagle-g1Kr4Ozfoac-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />loved. Inclusivity and tolerance in communities still have *so* far to go, but it’s a start. Recognizing Archive of Our Own, the writers who work to create content, and the readers who engage and encourage is a huge win for the fanfic community and fandom generally.</p>
<p>Now, more than ever, the world needs dreamers. We need spaces where we can revel in what brings us joy, and we need to remember that joy is allowed to begin with. That we are not just allowed, but <i>supposed </i>to have fun sometimes. And what better place to squee than in fanfic communities? Fun does not need to be legitimized, and fanfiction is not going anywhere but stamping a big old Hugo on an organization and hub of communities that does so much good in many of our lives feels important. It feels like on some level, the world is recognizing the importance of such communities. That on some level, we are all working together to make our lives better through positive fandom experiences.</p>
<p>Pardon me if I got a little sentimental there. /wipes away tear of glee/</p>
<p>I’ll draw this love letter to AO3 and fanfiction generally to a close by saying again, CONGRATULATIONS, AO3! Congratulations to all who work so hard to make the site thrive, and thank you for making the world a brighter place&#8211;you truly are rad.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Including Inclusivity in Reader-Insert Fanfiction</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/including-inclusivity-in-reader-insert-fanfiction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun and Games]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=15912</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hiya, Y/N! Yes. I just called you, lovely reader, Y/N. Or, Your Name. As in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hiya, Y/N! Yes. I just called you, lovely reader, Y/N. Or, Your Name. As in Your Name in reader-insert fanfiction.</p>
<p>First things first, though⁠—welcome to my new column! <i>Fun and Games</i> will be, truly, as advertised: ramblings about gaming, books, and movies; fan-stuff; occasional reviews; other nerdariffic sundries.</p>
<p>I thought a nice place to start would be a simple guide to inclusivity in reader-insert fanfiction. I won’t go into terms/definitions or anything like that, but those of you who hang out on Tumblr or Ao3 have probably encountered a good amount of reader-insert fics for any number of fandoms. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15963 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/serrah-galos-H6xxqTIHOTM-unsplash-187x300.jpg" alt="" width="187" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/serrah-galos-H6xxqTIHOTM-unsplash-187x300.jpg 187w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/serrah-galos-H6xxqTIHOTM-unsplash-768x1232.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/serrah-galos-H6xxqTIHOTM-unsplash-639x1024.jpg 639w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/serrah-galos-H6xxqTIHOTM-unsplash.jpg 1870w" sizes="(max-width: 187px) 100vw, 187px" />I’ll give those who have not encountered these in the wild a TL:DR version. Reader-insert fanfic exists to allow the reader to imagine they are the protagonist/subject of the narrative, dropping them into the worlds of their favorite movies/shows/books. This is fantastic, fun, and sometimes, completely alienating.</p>
<p>When a reader is hanging out with Steve Rogers and Bucky Barnes; adventuring with Rey, Poe, and Finn; or in the embrace of their favorite character, it’s important to <i>be yourself/see yourself</i>. Meaning, if the writer is adept, you become Y/N, immersed in a world that you love and surrounded by your favorite characters. When the writer has not thought things through, though, a reader drops out of the narrative in an instant⁠—lurching violently from hyperdrive into real space with significant damage and a sense of <i>why in the stars did I go here in the first place???</i></p>
<p>I am a white woman but I am not young or thin so if I am merrily reading along and I notice my “slender body” and “youthful face” reflected in ye olde mirror scene, I’m not Y/N anymore. I’m someone else. If my bff just shook hands with Bucky Barnes and sees her white hand on his arm, that’ll be a NOPE. Full-stop. Her brown fingers against his arm have to be imagined, the scene reset, and BAM, another alienated reader who feels like there is not a safe place for them in such fics. That’s a terrible feeling when one is reading reader-insert fanfiction to escape and be immersed in fun.</p>
<p>I’ve heard a lot of writers complain that there’s no easy way to fix this. I call foul on that. It takes a bit of retraining and thought, but hey, thinking is good. Really, really good⁠—especially when it involves other human beings who deserve respect and inclusion.</p>
<p>A secret, a hint, a piece of advice to reader-insert fic writers far and wide: <b><i>you’re allowed to keep the details vague!</i></b> I’m serious. You can say that Y/N put their hand on Bucky’s arm and it’s even easier than adding details about skin tone, body type, or gender. Instead of blushing pink, <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-15964 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/marion-michele-h9gaTYBxEwA-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/marion-michele-h9gaTYBxEwA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/marion-michele-h9gaTYBxEwA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/marion-michele-h9gaTYBxEwA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Y/N can feel their face heat. Instead of Y/N leaning <em>up</em> to kiss so-and-so (not everybody is smaller than their object of affection), they can lean <i>in </i>to kiss so-and-so, leaving it vague who is taller than the other. If you want to include more degrees of physical ability, you can have Y/N <i>move </i>to stand next to Poe Dameron instead of run, skip, or any of those. Instead of someone’s eyes rounding in surprise, Y/N’s eyes can instead <i>widen </i>in surprise. These are just a few tiny things but if Y/N is blushing pink, chances are, they are white. That by default means that anyone who does not match that physical description is knocked out of the experience, forced back into a world where it’s all about someone else and not them (and totally defeating the purpose of an inclusive reader-insert fic).</p>
<p>I know this is by no means a thorough discussion on the matter, but my hope is that it’s a good place to start! So, Y/N, thank you for reading&#8230;it seriously is awesome of you. And everybody, if you know of any great resources for writing reader-insert fanfic or have tips yourself, feel free to drop a comment! Finally, I’d like to thank my awesome bestie for letting me consult with her on this⁠—you can find her on Tumblr as <a href="https://spinsterlocity.tumblr.com/">@spinsterlocity</a> and on Twitter as <a href="https://twitter.com/Ms_WordNerd">@Ms_WordNerd</a>. Thanks again for reading!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
