<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>An Editor&#8217;s Ephemera &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/an-editors-ephemera/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 02:04:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>On trying to read Frankenstein</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/on-trying-to-read-frankenstein/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ll admit it, on this day of Mary Wollstonecraft Shelley&#8217;s birth, that I have not&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-599958329-1bf5a3d1c2204eddb9ced96f16723860.webp"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-25737" src="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-599958329-1bf5a3d1c2204eddb9ced96f16723860-300x204.webp" alt="" width="300" height="204" srcset="https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-599958329-1bf5a3d1c2204eddb9ced96f16723860-300x204.webp 300w, https://2f5f93.p3cdn2.secureserver.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GettyImages-599958329-1bf5a3d1c2204eddb9ced96f16723860.webp 768w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>I&#8217;ll admit it, on this day of Mary Wollstonecraft Shelley&#8217;s birth, that I have not yet read <em>Frankenstein</em>. It&#8217;s a hole in my education as an author of genre fiction, though I wouldn&#8217;t go so far as to call it a failure. I&#8217;m not done trying, yet! This of course is especially a bit embarrassing seeing as she was featured on <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-023/">the cover of a previous issue of LSQ</a>. Oh my!</p>
<p>In an effort to set things right and with Ms. Shelley&#8217;s birthday fast approaching, I sat down this year to read <em>Frankenstein</em>, settling in with a humble Dover edition I had picked up secondhand. The volume is slim, for all its reputation, and I thought I would slip through those pages with ease. Unfortunately, reading the book is akin to reading Shakespeare or watching a black and white movie, where it takes the mind a little time to adjust to the prose and style.</p>
<p>Sadly, my mind simply isn&#8217;t in the right state to read something so beautifully, but densely, written. However, in giving it a solid try anyway, I did uncover some very useful resources that I&#8217;ll be leaning on when I make my next attempt. I thought I would share them with you all so that you can have a little support as well if you&#8217;ve picked it up, been intimidated by the prose, and subsequently put it down as I have.</p>
<p>First, there are a couple of annotated versions of the text that would be helpful in providing context for the novel, both via footnotes and essays:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25735 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/51P61X0XolL._SX260_-255x300.jpg" alt="" width="255" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/51P61X0XolL._SX260_-255x300.jpg 255w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/51P61X0XolL._SX260_.jpg 260w" sizes="(max-width: 255px) 100vw, 255px" /><em><a href="https://wwnorton.com/books/The-New-Annotated-Frankenstein/">The New Annotated Frankenstein</a></em><br />
&#8220;Featuring over 200 illustrations and nearly 1,000 annotations, this sumptuous volume recaptures Shelley’s early nineteenth-century world with historical precision and imaginative breadth, tracing the social and political roots of the author’s revolutionary brand of Romanticism. Braiding together decades of scholarship with his own keen insights, Klinger recounts <em>Frankenstein</em>’s indelible contributions to the realms of science fiction, feminist theory, and modern intellectual history—not to mention film history and popular culture.&#8221;</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25736 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/collidbooks_covers_0isbn9780262533287type-217x300.jpg" alt="" width="217" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/collidbooks_covers_0isbn9780262533287type-217x300.jpg 217w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/collidbooks_covers_0isbn9780262533287type.jpg 550w" sizes="(max-width: 217px) 100vw, 217px" /></p>
<p><em><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/frankenstein">Frankenstein: Annotated for Scientists, Engineers, and Creators of All Kinds</a></em><br />
&#8220;This edition of <em>Frankenstein</em> pairs the original 1818 version of the manuscript—meticulously line-edited and amended by Charles E. Robinson, one of the world&#8217;s preeminent authorities on the text—with annotations and essays by leading scholars exploring the social and ethical aspects of scientific creativity raised by this remarkable story. The result is a unique and accessible edition of one of the most thought-provoking and influential novels ever written.&#8221;</p>
<p>There&#8217;s also the lightly annotated version that I&#8217;ve been reading as well: <a href="https://store.doverpublications.com/0486282112.html"><em>Frankenstein</em>: Dover Thrift Edition</a></p>
<p>Then there are a few reading guides, meant for students, that may help with parsing the text and understanding what&#8217;s going on.</p>
<p>&#8211; <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/bitesize/topics/z3vjmnb">The BBC&#8217;s GCSE guide to Frankenstein</a><br />
&#8211; <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/326525/frankenstein-by-mary-shelley/9780593203392/readers-guide/">Penguin Random House&#8217;s Frankenstein Reader’s Guide</a> (I still say they missed out by not calling the company Random Penguin, but I digress)<br />
&#8211; <a href="https://www.purdue.edu/convocations/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Frankenstein-study-guide.pdf">The Glencoe Literature Library Study Guide for Frankenstein</a></p>
<p>Finally, I&#8217;ll pass along a few resources that are a little more out of the box. These might help get you in the right mindset and place things in a bit more context for reading the book:</p>
<p>&#8211; <a href="https://ed.ted.com/lessons/everything-you-need-to-know-to-read-mary-shelley-s-frankenstein-iseult-gillespie">Everything you need to know to read &#8220;Frankenstein&#8221;</a> &#8211; TED Ed put together a short video and other resources to guide you through the book.<br />
&#8211; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6JB422UxL5w">Frankenstein by Mary Shelley // Literature in a Nutshell</a> &#8211; Christy Anne Jones sums the book up in a short video. Here be spoilers, if you&#8217;re looking to avoid such things.<br />
&#8211; <a href="https://librivox.org/frankenstein-or-modern-prometheus-by-mary-w-shelley/">Frankenstein, or The Modern Prometheus on Libravox</a> &#8211; a free audio book version for those who might better absorb the language of the book via audio.<br />
&#8211; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frankenstein">Frankenstein on Wikipedia</a> &#8211; for a broad history of the book.</p>
<p>There are numerous other audio recordings, staged plays, etc. available on places like Youtube. Be sure to <a href="https://www.worldcat.org/">check your local library</a> (including <a href="https://www.hoopladigital.com/">Hoopla</a> and <a href="https://www.overdrive.com/apps/libby/">Libby</a>) as well for both print and audio editions. I encourage you to seek out the tools you need to support your reading, no matter the book. I hope this list gives you the hand you (and I) need to enjoy this classic of science fiction literature.</p>
<p>My most sincere apologies to Ms. Shelley. Perhaps next year will be our year. Happy 224th birthday, madame.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Every word counts</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/every-word-counts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 11:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every word you are reading right now has added to my daily word count. Having&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every word you are reading right now has added to my daily word count.</p>
<p>Having a daily word count practice is a new and scary thing for me, something I&#8217;ve been hesitant to start. The last year was rough for the obvious reasons and I haven&#8217;t been writing at all, never mind daily. There was also a less obvious reason that held me back. See, last February I <a href="https://takeonme.xyz/">sent a novel out into the world</a>. I sincerely believe that it was the best thing I&#8217;ve ever written. It took me a year to write it, and then another year and a half to edit it. I didn&#8217;t have any other irons in the fire that whole time, other than <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/silks/">a story for LSQ</a>. I don&#8217;t regret that choice because it was what that particular story required.</p>
<p>I released that book and then lockdown happened and I got sick. My creativity dried up along with a lot of other activities. Like many of you, it was enough to show up for work and take care of myself. Later last year I also started a new job that has me working harder than ever before. There has been no engine, no fuel, for me to write anything but code and Slack messages. At some point in that process, I gave myself permission to stop worrying about it. It&#8217;s not what I wanted, but acknowledging that my creativity wasn&#8217;t available was some of the best self-care I could do and I don&#8217;t regret it.</p>
<p>Of course a small, fragile part of me kept a lookout. I know in my heart I&#8217;m not done with writing, I know there are stories yet to come. Over the course of this year, I&#8217;ve been slowly circling around what it means for me to be a writer. What can I possibly have to say after all that&#8217;s gone on in the world? Much to my pleasant surprise, very recently ideas and thoughts have been surfacing. They&#8217;re small, wee little things that I hold in my mind like baby chicks. They feel like little miracles, as humble as they are, and I&#8217;m doing what I can to protect them from the big, mean world. They&#8217;re especially wonderful because they are not the same old, same old. It seems my mind has returned to the land of Storytelling in ways I wasn&#8217;t expecting.</p>
<p>The first inkling I had that I may return to writing was a spontaneous story I made up about a few people I saw in a parking lot. It was little more than an &#8220;oh, what if&#8221; idea, but it was definitely the start of something. Every time I&#8217;ve gone back to that spot, I&#8217;m reminded of those two people and another little piece of the story formulates in my mind. This is something I haven&#8217;t put down to paper other than a single line of a story hook. Doesn&#8217;t matter, it&#8217;s a seed planted and growing. Conveniently, we&#8217;re in the summer here, when such things can thrive and bear fruit.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-25563" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IVas4u-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IVas4u-300x300.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IVas4u-150x150.png 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IVas4u-550x550.png 550w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IVas4u.png 735w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Next, I worked on a &#8220;playbook&#8221; for a pastoral RPG called <a href="https://www.possumcreekgames.com/wanderhome">Wanderhome</a>. This was nice, very low pressure work. I&#8217;ve been wanting to do some kind of game writing for ages and the gentle setting of Wanderhome was the perfect home for an idea for a character type that I&#8217;ve been carrying around for a while. Writing this was more about ideas and shape and character than traditional storytelling. Happily, this led to a further need to scratch the game-making itch I&#8217;ve carried for years, and I&#8217;m currently in a similar process of designing a humble map-based adventure game. I don&#8217;t know that I&#8217;ll do any &#8220;professional&#8221; work like this, but it&#8217;s a brilliant hobby.</p>
<p><a href="https://itch.io/">Itchi.io</a>, despite being focused on indie video game publishing, has become an interesting little haven for writers of weird RPGs and zinesters. I haven&#8217;t written a zine in many years, but I&#8217;ve never felt like I was &#8220;done&#8221; with that format. I began to wonder what would happen if I combined my love of zines with my love of writing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drabble">drabbles</a>. This thinking has led to a series of zines I&#8217;m now planning. I also get to stretch my design muscles again, which is pure bonus points.</p>
<p>Finally, just a week ago, one of LSQ&#8217;s editors mentioned the <a href="https://mini1000.substack.com/p/coming-soon">miniature 1000 words of summer</a> writing challenge (thank you, Margaret!) and another acquaintance showed me 4thwords.com. I began to wonder, what if I allowed myself to write every day? I&#8217;ve done it in the past for things like <a href="https://nanowrimo.org/">NaNoWriMo</a>, but that level of word count is not sustainable for the long term. I could definitely do 1k words for a week, though. I also remember quite clearly that NaNo brain was really good at turning off my inner editor. Words just flow, and that&#8217;s one of the things that hasn&#8217;t been happening for me for the last year.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-25562 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/s-3-300x188.png" alt="" width="300" height="188" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/s-3-300x188.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/s-3-1024x640.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/s-3-768x480.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/s-3.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><a href="https://4thewords.com/">4thewords</a> is writing, gamified. I know some would roll their eyes at this idea, but I&#8217;ve been using <a href="https://habitica.com/">Habitica</a> for years now to keep my personal life and LSQ on track. The model works for me. I like battling monsters, okay? Frankly, if I&#8217;m self-aware about it, the little dopamine hit I get from defeating the forces of evil with my keyboard fills in the gap that regularly publishing fanfic used to give me. If I want to keep things small, but sustainable, this kind of tool fills the gap when my motivation lags.</p>
<p>When this post goes live, I&#8217;ll be in the midst of that 1k per day sprint. I&#8217;m excited and a little scared, but in that good way that tells me I&#8217;m challenging myself and growing. I also can&#8217;t wait to see what comes out of that work, if there&#8217;s anything that will be worth shaping further. When that&#8217;s all over, the daily 444 word count practice outlined on 4thewords will begin in earnest. How many days can I go? A month, a year? I&#8217;ll let you know when I defeat the boss, or put out another book, whichever comes first.</p>
<p>When I look back at the last four months or so, I can see a steady, organic shift back to my creativity. I did this intentionally, noting when inspiration appeared and nurturing it, but this time I put no pressure on any of it. I allowed it to happen, while holding it gently. Most importantly, it centered around things I love: writing that makes me happy, different mediums, and a sense of playfulness that I haven&#8217;t allowed myself for a long time. I think that regardless of how 2020 went, I was still going to have to go through some of this process, and that&#8217;s okay. I&#8217;m returning with more wisdom about myself and I can better recognize the kind of writing I want to do and maybe even how I want to do it.</p>
<p>I encourage you all to take a brief look at what&#8217;s driving you, regardless of where you&#8217;re using your energy. In your creative work, in the books you read, in any facet of your life that needs a little attention. Look for things you love. There are treasures there, yet to be discovered. Onward! To adventure!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;m finding places to be proud everywhere</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/im-finding-places-to-be-proud-everywhere/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 10:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With this month being Pride, I thought I would talk about a few places where&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With this month being Pride, I thought I would talk about a few places where the LGBTQIA+ community is more welcome than you might think. In some ways, these places are simply part of what I love, but at the same time they&#8217;re ubiquitous, mainstays of American culture. I&#8217;m going to start with a small confession.</p>
<p>Lately, I&#8217;ve gotten into watching WWE professional wrestling. Yes, I am serious. It&#8217;s cheezy and dramatic, in the same way soap operas are cheezy and dramatic. Honestly that&#8217;s part of its charm. So help me I love it.</p>
<p>Isn&#8217;t it violent? Yup, it is, quite so. Isn&#8217;t it all fake? Well, yes and no. There&#8217;s a storyline that is developed and followed, but when one wrestler throws another out of the ring, that&#8217;s still going to hurt whoever is landing on the floor. Sounds kind of bloodthirsty, but the athleticism on display is impressive and everyone knows we&#8217;re here for a good time. It&#8217;s definitely show business, along with a lot of sweat and biceps.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve very quickly grown attached to a couple of wrestlers in particular (Charlotte currently really is the Queen for me), which is part of the fun. You cheer on your favorites and boo the heels (unless they&#8217;re Charlotte and then I&#8217;m cheering anyway).</p>
<p>You may be thinking that wrestling is not a place someone like me would feel comfortable and welcome. I&#8217;m just as surprised as you to say that the opposite is true. I&#8217;ve found in my short stint being a fan of &#8220;sports entertainment&#8221; that the audience is extraordinarily diverse and welcoming.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium" src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/hmg-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/images/wwe-sonya-deville4-1584711167.jpg" width="1200" height="1200" />Pride does not go unnoticed by the WWE, with <a href="https://www.wwe.com/superstars/sonya-deville">Sonya Deville</a> (from my home state!) leading the way as the self-proclaimed &#8220;Pride Fighter&#8221; along with other out wrestlers. Allies have also <a href="https://www.wwe.com/gallery/wwe-superstars-pride-month-photos#fid-40367069">stood up within the organization</a> to let the LGBTQIA+ community know they&#8217;re supported and welcome.</p>
<p>As an aside, the storylines are so much fun and honestly if you enjoy a good ship dynamic trope, you&#8217;ll feel right at home. My particular favorite &#8220;ship&#8221; of the moment is the tag team known as RK-Bro, consisting of RKO and The Original Bro. They are the epitome of &#8220;Oops I accidentally adopted this absolute child&#8221;. So good.</p>
<p>The next place I was very surprised to find a supportive ally is Cracker Barrel. This is a place that my childhood memories and other more recent associations would lead me to believe was a place I should avoid, and I have up until now.</p>
<p>Curiosity about the menu got me looking at their website and lo and behold, they have a robust <a href="https://www.crackerbarrel.com/Diversity-and-Inclusion">Diversity and Inclusion</a> page on their website. This finding is going to have me poking around a lot more &#8220;red letter&#8221; restaurant websites to see what other options might be out there. Local independents are a bit harder to pin down with this kind of thing, but it&#8217;s always nice to find them when they do.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m going to wrap up with a perennial favorite of mine, something that&#8217;s been with me far longer than Cracker Barrel or wrestling. Baseball, while still a fairly gendered sport, has been consistently groundbreaking when it comes to inclusivity. Jackie Robinson broke the color barrier on April 15, 1947, long before much of America was &#8220;ready&#8221; for integration. He started 1st base for the LA Dodgers, the team I now cheer on for 162+ games every year.</p>
<p>Baseball is one of those things that is a perennial comfort and joy for me. I started out watching bits of games as a kid with my grandfather. LSQ Creative Director Tara Lindsey (and one of my dear family) reintroduced baseball to me as an adult and taught me the ins and outs of the game. Through her I learned about the steady pace of the season, the stalwart nature of those nine innings, day after day. For more of the year than not, there is a game on somewhere.</p>
<p>Once again, in baseball as in wrestling, there is a display of athleticism. Beyond that there are lessons in teamwork, discipline, and lessons for life, too. As a hitter, being hugely successful in baseball means you fail two out of three times. There&#8217;s something to be learned from watching players stand up to face that outcome over and over.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/KUwMrOoFIrKi4iFBnD9HC_3FQDs=/1400x1400/filters:format(jpeg)/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/16312671/dodgersmound.jpg" width="1400" height="1400" />The Dodgers in particular have felt welcoming to me because they, and some of their staff, celebrate Pride quite demonstratively. As I write this, the LA logo <a href="https://www.mlb.com/dodgers/tickets/specials/lgbt-night">on the pitcher&#8217;s mound</a> at Dodger Stadium is a rainbow. Billie Jean King and her partner are part owners, and work to expand LGBTQIA+ inclusion in the organization, supported by Magic Johnson (did you know he owns the Dodgers?) who has an openly gay son.</p>
<p>With the way so many countries are treating their queer citizens, I find myself incredibly grateful to be here and now. There is surely still much work to do for everyone to feel safe, pursue happiness how they please and follow their own natures. Still, at the moment, I&#8217;d like to take a small step outside of that work and take a look at where we are and how far things have come. I am taking a little time to wave a pretty, colorful flag, and connect with my community in places I never expected to be able to do so.</p>
<p>Happy Pride!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>December issue delayed, here&#8217;s the details&#8230;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/december-issue-delayed-heres-the-details/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 12:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22296</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Greetings from Luna Station Quarterly HQ! I hope you all are doing well, keeping safe&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Greetings from <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> HQ! I hope you all are doing well, keeping safe and happy.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, this is not my usual Editor&#8217;s Ephemera column. Instead, I have an announcement to make:</p>
<p><strong>The next issue of LSQ is going to be delayed until December 15th. </strong></p>
<p>Some related personal challenges over the last couple of months threw production massively off track. (Thanks, 2020!) Eventually, a logistical wall blocked my path and there was no reasonable way to get the issue out on time. Long-time readers may recall that there have been a handful of other issues in our history that were delayed. Life just gets in the way sometimes. Oh, the life of an indie magazine!</p>
<p>Questions? Let me know and I will be happy to answer them. Otherwise, here’s to getting the issue flightworthy and prepping LSQ for its TWELFTH year. (wow!)</p>
<p>Thanks so much for your patience!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A humble hobby</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/a-humble-hobby/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 10:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last month I talked about Amelia and the idea of hobbies. It might not surprise&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-19432" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/library-425730_640-300x216.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="216" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/library-425730_640-300x216.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/library-425730_640.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Last month I talked about Amelia and the idea of hobbies. It might not surprise you to learn that I consider reading to be one of mine. However, it may be unexpected that the hobby of reading has little to do directly with the website you are currently visiting.</p>
<p>I run LSQ, which requires me to read what we publish. I write stories and novels and essays, all of which means I read for research. My career requires me to read technical articles and my curiosity drives me to read various other kinds of articles.</p>
<p>Much of this reading I enjoy quite thoroughly. Obviously, technical articles are limited in their fun, though they can surprise me from time to time. Yet, what I am taking in isn’t really a hobby. It’s all related to the work I do for LSQ or for my day job or it’s part of keeping my mind active and informed.</p>
<p>That all changes when I sit down to read something I’ve picked for myself for the simple joy of the journey. When that special book whisks me off into its world and time slides by with me barely noticing it, that’s when we’ve hit upon my lifelong _hobby_ of reading.</p>
<p>This reading is for myself and only later may be for others. When I take this time for enrichment, my life feels larger and fuller. The benefits I gain from reading are esoteric and ephemeral, having little to do with productivity or success.</p>
<p>After reading a book that resonates with me, I will carry that experience with me. I may end up writing something of my own, building on that inspiration. If I find the right person, I may recommend a particular book to them and make a connection I might not have otherwise. Both of those clear benefits are still too concrete to explain why I love reading.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-19433" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-ylanite-koppens-810050-1-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-ylanite-koppens-810050-1-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/pexels-ylanite-koppens-810050-1.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Reading relaxes me, it excites me, it deepens my experience of life. I learn new things, regardless of whether the book is fictional or not. I do not go into a book seeking transformation and yet that is exactly what happens, even with a book I don’t enjoy.</p>
<p>These are all reasons we choose these kinds of activities in the first place. Be it woodcarving or collecting Pokemon cards or watching sports doesn’t matter. Call it self-care if you like, for it is a way of taking care of yourself and recharging the batteries. Call it enrichment if you prefer, for it does enrich a give life some meaning and purpose beyond the daily grind.</p>
<p>For myself, I still call reading my favorite hobby. I like the humble term, I think it keeps things in perspective. It prevents any sense of pretense about what I’m doing and helps me keep it loose and fun, leaving the door open for whatever surprise is just around the corner.</p>
<p>I hope you have a hobby too, and that it brings you joy. If you don’t, is there a little space and time in your life for one? If not, may you find one.</p>
<p>Now off you go, I’ve got a page-turner waiting for me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>For the fun of it</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/for-the-fun-of-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 10:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking about Amelia Earhart a lot recently. If I’m honest, it’s not so&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-19222" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/6423929689_50e747983d_o.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="425" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/6423929689_50e747983d_o.jpg 580w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/6423929689_50e747983d_o-300x220.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" />I’ve been thinking about Amelia Earhart a lot recently. If I’m honest, it’s not so much the flesh and blood woman I’ve got rattling around my brain, but the mythic idea of her. I’m not sure if she would appreciate being put on a pedestal, likely not. Yet here I am, placing her there. Better than a pedestal, let’s place her higher, up among the clouds, where she felt most free.</p>
<p>I go out on Sunday mornings to pick up bagels and OJ and bacon for breakfast. Often after that, I take a bit of a drive. The roads are quiet and I find a place to pull off and rest my mind and think. This week, I stopped by the local small airport, found a spot, and watched the planes take off and land.</p>
<p>I grew up around airplanes. My father and his father built one, the Rutan Long-EZ. As a result, many a childhood weekend was spent at the airport. Rhinebeck, NY, Oshkosh, WI, the Smithsonian Air &amp; Space Museum, and other flight and space related sites were places of pilgrimage for my family.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-19223" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/N828HP-300x131.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="131" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/N828HP-300x131.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/N828HP.jpg 705w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Amongst all the various planes and talk of engines and lift there would always be a small display dedicated to the female aviators who were pioneers, not just in the air but in how they got there. Names like Jackie Cochran, Bessie Coleman and Pancho Barnes were presented as sources of inspiration for all the girls in the audience. Which all brings me back around to Amelia and what she means to me.</p>
<p>She’s symbolic of doing something that&#8217;s difficult just because it needs to be done. When asked why she worked hard to break dangerous records, she famously replied, “For the fun of it.”</p>
<p>Fun is something that seems to fall by the wayside far too easily in our society. I see many folks putting pressure on the things they like doing in order to turn them into “side hustles,” and they then become worried about being “productive.”</p>
<p>What ever happened to hobbies? While I would not call what Earhart accomplished a hobby, her pursuit of those records were things she did because she loved doing them. They brought her joy and freedom, first and foremost.</p>
<p>When I think of Amelia, I am reminded that it is good for me to have hobbies and passions that serve no other purpose than my own joy. They are part of a well-rounded, enriched life, something our modern mechanized age was supposed to help us enjoy.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ahmcpxdujv0-2-scaled.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-19228 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ahmcpxdujv0-2-300x225.jpg" alt="orange blue and white yarn" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ahmcpxdujv0-2-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ahmcpxdujv0-2-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ahmcpxdujv0-2-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ahmcpxdujv0-2-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/ahmcpxdujv0-2-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>My hobbies do not make me money. At times, they may even cost a little, no different than going to the movies or entertaining friends. I can pick up and put them down as time and energy allow. They are there solely for me. My writing, a thing I once thought could make me money, has become such a hobby, and this is where Amelia and I find common ground.</p>
<p>I have found freedom in words much as Amelia found freedom in the air. I have no deadlines, no contracts, no editor making suggestions I may or may not agree with. There is just me and the page and whatever story comes into my mind.</p>
<p>For some, the deadlines and editors and such are worth navigating in order to make a living at their craft. There is nothing wrong with that and for some they may even find their own kind of freedom in that work.</p>
<p>For myself, keeping writing as a hobby works for me. It joins the ranks of knitting and bookbinding and needle-felting as one of many things I do in my spare time and as the mood strikes.</p>
<p>I like to think Amelia would approve. Perhaps my next hobby will be building a model of her plane. Perhaps it will be something else entirely. I only know I’ll be doing it for the fun of it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kishōtenketsu: We don’t need your conflict</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/kishotenketsu-we-dont-need-your-conflict/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 11:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“So the Hero has decreed through his mouthpieces the Lawgivers, first, that the proper shape&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>“So the Hero has decreed through his mouthpieces the Lawgivers, first, that the proper shape of the narrative is that of the arrow or spear, starting here and going straight there and THOK! hitting its mark (which drops dead); second, that the central concern of narrative, including the novel, is conflict; and third, that the story isn’t any good if he isn’t in it.“<br />
&#8211; The Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction, Ursula K. Le Guin</p></blockquote>
<p>Conflict, we are told in the West, is the cornerstone of good fiction. If there’s no conflict then there’s no story. Or is there? And what do we mean by conflict? This exploration is personal for me. Having written a few books and with half a lifetime of reading experience under my belt, I am seeking reinvention of myself and my works, uncovering a new way of looking at and creating stories.</p>
<p>Last month I focused on Iyashikei, the Japanese genre of healing stories. This month I’m taking a look at Kishōtenketsu, another Japanese concept that describes a story format that removes the focus on conflict we adhere to in the West.</p>
<p>To clarify, when I’m speaking of conflict, I mean it as defined by <a href="https://stilleatingoranges.tumblr.com/post/25153960313/the-significance-of-plot-without-conflict">Still Eating Oranges</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>In the West, plot is commonly thought to revolve around *conflict*: a confrontation between two or more elements, in which one ultimately dominates the other. The standard three- and five-act plot structures–which permeate Western media–have conflict written into their very foundations. A “problem” appears near the end of the first act; and, in the second act, the conflict generated by this problem takes center stage. Conflict is used to create reader involvement even by many post-modern writers, whose work otherwise defies traditional structure.</p></blockquote>
<p>I first came across Kishōtenketsu when I was seeking ways to explain my recent novel “Take On Me.” As a faithful fantasy/sci-fi writer, tackling a work that was intimately personal and set in the modern reality of 2015 meant I had to adjust some of my thinking about what made a good story. The book is a journey, but nothing explodes along the way. The world is not in danger, the kingdom doesn’t need saving. So what did I just write? I knew for a fact I was not the first person to write like this, as the book’s inspirations showed.</p>
<p>I also knew I had seen explorations of different story forms in film and comic books. Seeing the film “Only Lovers Left Alive” showed me that there were ways to blend the personal and quiet moments in with deep characterization, while the plot fell largely by the wayside. Sure, there is a form of central plot that moves the characters from one place to another, but it almost feels like an afterthought, something to hang the story together rather than its driving force.</p>
<p>In searching for answers, I came across the new-to-me term Kishōtenketsu and a lightbulb went off in my mind. I found a new jumping off point for my writing.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-18948 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/0tb2wnhbx_q-1-225x300.jpg" alt="selective focus photography of purple petaled flowers" width="225" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/0tb2wnhbx_q-1-225x300.jpg 225w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/0tb2wnhbx_q-1-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/0tb2wnhbx_q-1-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/0tb2wnhbx_q-1-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/0tb2wnhbx_q-1-scaled.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" />At its most basic level, Kishōtenketsu is a simple structure of four acts: introduction, development, twist, conclusion. We have a setup, and go deeper with the world and characters, then there’s a seemingly unrelated event that happens, later in the story in the third act, before the conclusion ties that event into the main story and brings it all together.</p>
<p>While this form doesn’t represent what I had written (my book hums along with smaller events turning the story’s direction like a tugboat nudging a freighter) it does give me a new perspective and style to play with in future work.</p>
<p>Kishōtenketsu also connects very nicely to Ursula K Le Guin&#8217;s &#8220;Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction,” which posits that the first tools were not the bow and arrow, but instead the net and sling. We began as gatherers more than hunters and the quieter, seemingly gentler type of story was the tale of the day.</p>
<p>I’ve found myself drawn to write more of this type of tale, meditative and simple where “nothing much happens” but we gain a deep sense of place and people. It has basically given me permission to write from what my heart tells me rather than some perception of what a story structure is “supposed to” look like.</p>
<p>Combining Kishōtenketsu with Iyashikei opens a world of gentle storytelling that can provide true comfort to myself as the writer as well as to any potential readers. I feel a bit like I’ve discovered a new mountain and come home all at the same time. That freedom is powerful and makes me want to write even more, a feeling that is never in great supply.</p>
<p>If you’re curious to learn more about Kishōtenketsu, I have a few examples for you to check out. All of them do have some minor conflicts or perhaps even tense moments or a little violence. Yet, these elements are not core to the story, they are simply things that happen in the course of the telling. They show that breaking down the expected forms of Western storytelling don’t have to make for boring stories, just different pacing and different feelings. In fact, in a lot of ways, these examples feel more like real life than their more traditional counterparts.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ycOKvWrwYFo">Only Lovers Left Alive</a> &#8211; a film by Jim Jarmusch about vampires that&#8217;s really more about music and time and maybe a little about fungi.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32802595-record-of-a-spaceborn-few">Record of a Spaceborn Few</a> &#8211; Becky Chambers’s next volume in her Wayfinder series that moves along at its own steady pace.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20170404-station-eleven">Station Eleven</a> &#8211; a post-apocalyptic novel by Emily St. John Mandel that crosses between two timelines but is more about Shakespeare and art than it is about the apocalypse.</p>
<p>And a few resources for learning more:</p>
<p><a href="https://stilleatingoranges.tumblr.com/post/25153960313/the-significance-of-plot-without-conflict">The significance of plot without conflict &#8211; still eating oranges</a></p>
<p>Is conflict necessary?: Kishōtenketsu and the conflict-less plot – Words like trees.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kish%C5%8Dtenketsu">Kishōtenketsu &#8211; Wikipedia</a></p>
<p><a href="https://mythicscribes.com/plot/kishotenketsu/">Kishōtenketsu for Beginners – An Introduction to Four Act Story Structure</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.academia.edu/17313163/The_Carrier_Bag_Theory_of_Fiction_-_Ursula_K._Le_Guin">The Carrier Bag Theory of Fiction &#8211; Ursula K. Le Guin | Fiori Vonière &#8211; Academia.edu</a></p>
<p><a href="https://theoutline.com/post/7886/ursula-le-guin-carrier-bag-theory">We should all be reading more Ursula Le Guin | The Outline</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iyashikei: We can take care of each other</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/iyashikei-we-can-take-care-of-each-other/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/iyashikei-we-can-take-care-of-each-other/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 10:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It was tricky to find my topic this month. I knew I wanted to write&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-18072 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/stone-tower-3280617_640-233x300.jpg" alt="" width="233" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/stone-tower-3280617_640-233x300.jpg 233w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/stone-tower-3280617_640.jpg 497w" sizes="(max-width: 233px) 100vw, 233px" />It was tricky to find my topic this month. I knew I wanted to write something that felt meaningful and fully fleshed out. Many things I considered writing about just felt hollow until a magical thread of synergy wove through my thoughts over the last week.</p>
<p>It began with <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2020/may/09/the-real-lord-of-the-flies-what-happened-when-six-boys-were-shipwrecked-for-15-months?CMP=twt_books_b-gdnbooks">an article that has been floating around recently</a> which tells the story of a group of boys who were shipwrecked in the 1960s. Rather than becoming a real-life “Lord of the Flies”, the boys took care of each other, organized themselves, and survived through their trials to be rescued.</p>
<p>This article reminded me of <a href="https://boingboing.net/2020/01/14/people-are-good.html">one I read earlier in the year</a> regarding a new study that disproves the “bystander effect.” It’s long been thought that if you are in trouble out in the world, then you’re on your own because others will not step in to help. Analysis of CCTV footage shows that on the contrary, 9 times out of 10, bystanders do step in to help when someone is in danger.</p>
<p>In pondering this, I began to reflect on how these assumptions of the cruelty of the world, the uncaring nature of the strangers around us, has penetrated our literature. “Man vs Something” is the root of all stories and we’re constantly “fighting” for something, we’re “at war” with the world around us and that’s just the way things are. Or is it? Are these the only kinds of stories that can be told? Is there a more caring, gentler response that can still make powerful changes? Are there other ways of telling stories?</p>
<p>The other day someone asked a question of the collective internet (as folks are wont to do): Does the West even make “healing stories”?</p>
<p>The question caught me by surprise. As someone who runs a <a href="https://selfcare.tech/">directory of self-care</a> resources and has often sought out media that soothes, the idea of healing stories is right up my alley.</p>
<p>There is, I have learned, a genre of fiction in Japan called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iyashikei">Iyashikei</a> which, thank you Wikipedia, is: “a sub-genre of slice of life, portraying characters living out peaceful lives in calming environments, and is intended to have a healing effect on the audience.”</p>
<p>Sign. Me. Up.</p>
<p>I started research and it was one of the most gentle internet rabbit holes I’ve had the pleasure of traversing. I’m still lost in it even as I write this. Allow me to share a bit of what I found.</p>
<p>In practice, these stories are truly meant to shift the reader&#8217;s mood and induce a state of calm or relaxation, much like a massage. There are numerous manga and anime works in this genre (yes, links below!) which is awesome, but what of Western literature and media? Because it may be difficult to find these works in English, do we have anything here that might fall under this category?</p>
<p>After some thinking and digging, I have found a few things in my own collections that I feel sum up what these stories are meant to do for us all.</p>
<p>The first thing that came to mind is <a href="https://truluv.ai/selfcare/">Tru Luv&#8217;s &#8220;Self Care&#8221;</a> app. Part soothing companion, part journal, part tarot deck, part meditation app, etc. etc. this “game” was intentionally created by Brie Code and her team to help calm and sooth its users. It’s a video game for people who don’t like “video games.”<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright size-medium" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/56630642e4b0288a6978c18b/1526294685327-RNTKPO4QH8AI9JV3MWET/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kAuezfUMkoIaQx238rC9rkl7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0mjTXrniUQ13tHDa-GTGS03S4ydqMFj5L7XDQE8O4IXKU3pht5-FXH-v-FD8dbeLvg/SelfCare-Main.png" width="1000" height="1337" /></p>
<p>A few more games also fit this mold. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_Crossing">Animal Crossing</a> is a classic, as is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neko_Atsume">Neko Atsume</a>. Unsurprisingly, both are made by Japanese companies. I’ll also throw <a href="https://www.stardewvalley.net/">Stardew Valley</a> into the pot. I haven’t played too many simulation games but of what I have played I find Stardew to be the most relaxing with a quiet, soothing charm.</p>
<p>In literature, I found myself looking towards books aimed at younger readers. Diana Wynne Jones’s trilogy <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Howl%27s_Moving_Castle">following the adventures of Sophie and Howl</a> have conflict in them, but they also have plenty of fun and adventure make for a gentle read.</p>
<p>Even more so is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_Waiting">Castle Waiting</a>, a comic book by Linda Medley. With very mild conflicts and a heart-warming cast of characters, the two volumes simmer along like a pot over a cozy fire.</p>
<p>What these books and games have shown me quite clearly is that there is room in the Western canon for stories that don’t just drop our protagonists from one dangerous or wrenching situation to the next. Characters don’t always have to be in danger or heartbroken to be fully-formed.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-medium" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/hostedimages/1380363624i/715098.png" width="448" height="233" />To be honest, this was a relief to discover because my own writing often falls under this umbrella. My books and stories meander, they move through the world like a cat with a full belly seeking a sunny patch of rug. As many of us know, finding representation out in the world can be an empowering experience. I feel I have permission now to write with even more freedom, which for me means more healing, more quiet, more gentle self-discovery.</p>
<p>Needless to say, at a time like this, discovering this genre is lovely. It’s something we can enjoy for its own sake and carry with us when things are hard. I hope you take some time to explore the links I’ve included in this post. May they inspire, heal and bring you a little peace in the days to come. And if you have any stories you know and love that fit the bill, please do send them my way!</p>
<p><strong>Resources:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/27756619">Ambient Literature and the Aesthetics of Calm</a></li>
<li><a href="https://amynotdorft.com/2016/10/17/iyashikei-and-worlds-that-heal/">Iyashikei and Worlds That Heal</a></li>
<li><a href="https://screentherapyblog.wordpress.com/2018/03/13/iyashikei/">Iyashikei: Japan’s Genre of “Healing Games”</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.ranker.com/list/best-iyashikei-anime/anna-lindwasser">The 15 Best Iyashikei Anime That Will Lift Your Spirits</a></li>
<li><a href="https://floatingintobliss.wordpress.com/2017/05/27/iyashikei-the-genre-of-healing-an-attempt-at-a-definition/">Iyashikei: The Genre of Healing – An Attempt at a Definition</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/iyashikei-we-can-take-care-of-each-other/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Problem of Input and Output</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-problem-of-input-and-output/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 18:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’ll be honest, I’m not watching the news right now. I get a daily digest&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ll be honest, I’m not watching the news right now. I get a daily digest of headlines and that keeps me up to date as much as I can handle. I pick up a thing or two from my personal network, but otherwise I’ve closed down the media fire hose. It’s vital for me to take a break from all that because what I take in is going to greatly affect what I put out.</p>
<p>As a creative person, I’m doing my best to keep good, authentic work flowing, which is important to my own mind and heart. Of course others may read my stories in the days to come, but at the point of creation, I’m not thinking about an audience.</p>
<p>So, what do I mean when I’m talking about input and output?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17815 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/inputoutput-300x300.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/inputoutput-300x300.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/inputoutput-150x150.jpg 150w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/inputoutput.jpg 474w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />I follow <a href="https://austinkleon.com/">Austin Kleon’s</a> newsletter, which often leads to his blog posts. He’s written on the topic of input and output multiple times (links below). It’s important to him, and it’s become important to me.</p>
<p>In one of his posts, he recounts that Jim Jarmusch talks a lot about “Strummer’s Law,” four simple words he learned from his friend Joe Strummer: <em>“No input, no output.”</em></p>
<p>For most of us, our input is going to be reflected in our output. First of all that makes taking time to absorb new things important. Reading, listening to music, watching films, taking in work outside your own medium or field, whatever it is that engages your imagination, gets your mind excited (or calms it, that choice is yours!) will lead to new output.</p>
<p>Whatever you are taking in is going to get processed through your thoughts and experiences and come out in your work. If you’re not taking anything in, it’s going to be much harder to get anything out. Even something we perceive as crappy can be motivating in an “I can do better than that” kind of way.</p>
<p>Of course the problem isn’t just for traditionally creative work. I come across the same problem in my programming work. If I’m not reading articles and essays that help me think about my work differently or learning new techniques that help me improve my skills, it’s much harder to muster the inspiration to write about that work and to actually write the code itself.</p>
<p>We’re often evaluated on our output, how productive we are, and the quality of that work. We are held accountable for that by our bosses, audience, and others, including ourselves.</p>
<p>Whatever reason you are responsible some kind of output, maintaining that is not going to magically happen out of the ether. It requires input, mostly good, with a little crappy on the side for perspective (or fun, depending on your mood). However, unlike with your boss or audience, no one is going to call you out on whether you’re taking in anything useful. The question of what is useful is up to you as well.</p>
<p>For me, realizing that without a steady flow of input I struggle with output (if I’m not reading, I’m probably not writing) was vital to my creativity. I started paying more attention to when I went into a reading slump and how that affected my ability to write in a satisfying way. Of course, I could push through without that inspiration but it got much, much harder. It’s much easier, and more pleasurable, to read and listen to music, etc., and find inspiration in the works of others. This is not just true now, when the world has gone off the rails. This was just as true last year and the year before and will be true next year, too.</p>
<p>I also started paying closer attention to what I was taking in and exactly how it affected me. Reading too much of the news made me feel very negative about the world. I understand the importance of keeping up to some degree, but our brains weren&#8217;t built to process everything that&#8217;s thrown at us in the &#8220;Internet Age&#8221;. I put boundaries in place that I loosen and tighten as needed. I notice how much taking walks and checking in with the weather and the trees makes me feel open. I notice what kind of music excites me and what kind of films lift my heart. After some time taking that all in and pondering it, it all feeds back into my work. I can&#8217;t have output without input.</p>
<p>The next time you are struggling with trying to put some kind of work down on the page (whatever form that page takes), I encourage you to take a step back and see what you&#8217;ve been taking in lately. Despite whatever you may be going through, I hope that you all try to pay a little more attention to your input in general. I hope it helps your output, when the time comes to create something new. I also hope it helps your mind and heart to find a little bit of peace.</p>
<p><a href="https://austinkleon.com/2019/12/19/your-output-depends-on-your-input/">Your output depends on your input &#8211; Austin Kleon</a><br />
<a href="https://austinkleon.com/2015/11/12/problems-of-output-are-problems-of-input/">Problems of output are problems of input &#8211; Austin Kleon</a><br />
<a href="https://austinkleon.com/2019/06/19/no-input-no-output/">No input, no output &#8211; Austin Kleon</a><br />
<a href="https://austinkleon.com/2019/01/22/if-you-want-to-be-a-writer-you-have-to-be-a-reader-first/">If you want to be a writer, you have to be a reader first &#8211; Austin Kleon</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keeping Calm and Carrying On</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/keeping-calm-and-carrying-on/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jennifer Lyn Parsons]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 10:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[An Editor's Ephemera]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17584</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, dear readers! It&#8217;s me, JP, your friendly neighborhood editor-in-chief. I wanted to use my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17591 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jamez-picard-hgFddoULkHs-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jamez-picard-hgFddoULkHs-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jamez-picard-hgFddoULkHs-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jamez-picard-hgFddoULkHs-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jamez-picard-hgFddoULkHs-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/jamez-picard-hgFddoULkHs-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Hello, dear readers! It&#8217;s me, JP, your friendly neighborhood editor-in-chief.</p>
<p>I wanted to use my column this month to reach out and say hello. There are a lot of these virtual check-ins going on right now. We&#8217;re all like a bunch of conures, sounding off to make sure we&#8217;re heard, that we&#8217;re still here, still around.</p>
<p>LSQ, as always, is here to stay. We&#8217;re going to keep going and hopefully provide a bit of a reprieve for your minds and hearts. This has always been part of our mission statement, to be the uplift we want to see in the world.</p>
<p>While I know it&#8217;s hard to stay off the news right now, I encourage you to take a break now and then. To put the phone down and pick up a book. To read or watch something that lets you rest for a little while. There are plenty of suggestions in our blog archives!</p>
<p>We here at LSQ can&#8217;t fix everything, but as a community we can work to deepen our connections and check in with those near and far. In our Slack group, I&#8217;m seeing folks check in more, sharing bits of news, and just engaging with each other in such kind ways. It&#8217;s heartening to see.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re also here to provide a guidepost to navigate by in the form of stories. The tales in our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-041/">issues</a> are ready to enchant you, make you think, laugh, and enjoy a moment or two of respite in the midst of this new normal.</p>
<p>I hope that when I see you again next month we&#8217;ll have happier things to talk about. Until then, I hope you all stay safe and healthy. I hope you all keep writing and reading and sharing great stories. Be well, and remember to be kind to one another.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
