<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-ongoing-exorcism-of-the-demon-hetpat/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 21:33:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Write Like You&#8217;re Running Out of Time (Because You&#8217;re 30 Now)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/write-like-youre-running-out-of-time-because-youre-30-now/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/write-like-youre-running-out-of-time-because-youre-30-now/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annacatalano]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 12:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To everyone still reading this blog in the new year, happy 2021! Welcome back to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">To everyone still reading this blog in the new year, happy 2021! Welcome back to my ongoing midlife crisis, where I&#8217;m pleased to announce that despite my best efforts I still remain solidly On My Bullshit.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As the year of 2020 drew to a close, so did the flower of my youth&#8230; (I turned 30, okay, allow an old woman her theatrics.) More than ever, I found myself staring down the astronomical list of projects I still&#8211;STILL&#8211;haven&#8217;t finished, darkened by the increasing tint of the impending void hurtling faster and faster towards me to swallow me up.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22722" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22722" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22722" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-4331973_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-4331973_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-4331973_1920-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-4331973_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-4331973_1920-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-4331973_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22722" class="wp-caption-text">When will my reflection show&#8230; the old woman I am inside</figcaption></figure>
<p dir="ltr">Granted, I hadn&#8217;t seriously decided to pursue authorship as my career until about eight years ago (for a long time I was convinced I would be an actor), but even then I had always imagined 30 being the age of True Adulthood&#8211;when you finally have all your shit together and are Living Your Best Life Now. Nearly every day on Twitter you see more and more authors in their early or mid-twenties debuting their first novel, even getting signed for multiple other books within months of the debut. Authors like Tomi Adeyemi have made it big with a signed trilogy (and now a movie deal) even before 25, while I&#8217;m over here agonizing over a single chapter and generally wondering how on earth I am considered a real adult person now.</p>
<p dir="ltr">YOU MISSED YOUR WINDOW! HetPat, the physical manifestation of my anxiety, swaggers on over uninvited, dressed to the nines as the Grim Reaper, no doubt impatient for me to shuffle off this mortal coil. MAYBE YOU COULD HAVE BEEN PUBLISHED BY NOW IF YOU HADN&#8217;T WASTED SO MUCH TIME! IF YOU&#8217;D TRIED HARDER! YOU SAID YOU WANTED TO BE SUCCESSFUL WHILE YOU&#8217;RE STILL YOUNG AND HEALTHY ENOUGH TO ENJOY IT! WELL TOO LATE NOW, THE YOUTHS ARE PASSING YOU UP AND YOU ONLY HAVE A FEW SHORT DECADES LEFT TO DO EVERYTHING YOU WANT TO DO, AND THAT&#8217;S IF YOU&#8217;RE LUCKY!</p>
<p dir="ltr">Okay first of all, calling them &#8220;youths&#8221; makes you sound like a dime-store Chicago gangster.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Second&#8211;yeah let&#8217;s not pretend like I don&#8217;t have major FOMO every time a young, scrappy, and hungry author debuts at the age where I was only just deciding to take my writing seriously. I look at these young, talented, beautiful people and every cell in my body is like, &#8220;Your biological clock is ticking, time to pop out that book baby already. Loser.&#8221;</p>
<figure id="attachment_22723" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22723" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22723" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/home-office-4994104_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/home-office-4994104_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/home-office-4994104_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/home-office-4994104_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/home-office-4994104_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/home-office-4994104_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22723" class="wp-caption-text">Found footage of an up and coming young novelist writing their first bestseller.</figcaption></figure>
<p dir="ltr">It&#8217;s times like these that I must once again force myself (sometimes physically) to reread<a href="https://bookriot.com/women-authors-who-debuted-at-35-or-older/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://bookriot.com/women-authors-who-debuted-at-35-or-older/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1610757928091000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEe0OFOWovIMRlFxIsRLMbXdmU6wQ"> articles</a> that remind me of wildly successful authors (specifically women) who debuted after they turned 30. It&#8217;s enough of an uphill battle for women constantly fighting society&#8217;s heinous and nonsensical idea that once you hit 30, you may as well pack it up because you&#8217;re as good as dead. And when you add the hurdles of publishing to the mix? No wonder HetPat has a literal smorgasbord of insecurities to feed on with every passing day.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/why-30-under-30-lists-mis_n_4791178" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.huffpost.com/entry/why-30-under-30-lists-mis_n_4791178&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1610757928091000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG-UJWVgGEt2umf6RFgm-JowV3gCw">Society’s obsession with youth</a>&#8211;especially as it pertains to women/people of color/any disenfranchised group&#8211;is nothing but a way to uphold white supremacy and eugenic ideals, not to mention a way to control the bodies of those people.</p>
<figure id="attachment_22725" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-22725" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-22725 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-5883625_1920-300x167.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="167" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-5883625_1920-300x167.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-5883625_1920-1024x569.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-5883625_1920-768x427.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-5883625_1920-1536x854.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/woman-5883625_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-22725" class="wp-caption-text">GEDDIT, GRANDMA</figcaption></figure>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;">And if we don’t fit that mold, if we don’t “succeed” during that very specific and arbitrary time frame, we’re conditioned to feel like we’re failures.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I guess the thing to remember (I say, as a total hypocrite who struggles to believe this) is that there IS no window for &#8220;making it.&#8221; Obviously, yes, I would very much prefer to have more of my life ahead of me than behind me when it comes to having time to write and publish everything I want to. And no, I&#8217;m not getting any younger as I sit here, spinning in panic circles and avoiding the pressure of making myself New Year&#8217;s writing goals.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But if there’s a reminder that I really need stapled to my forehead (or a water gun to nab HetPat with), it’s why I write in the first place&#8211;it’s (technically) not for the fame or money or renown (because HA, like THAT’LL ever happen), it’s to share stories. It’s about the impact I might leave on the world, the people I might help, the ideas I might explore.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Because at the end of the day, HetPat only cares about power: who has it, and who can’t have it. Time isn’t real, and no one will care how old you were when you wrote the story that’s getting them through a hard time. We’re all fighting the same powers that try and tell us what we’re worthy of, or what we do or don’t deserve (LIKE HETPAT)&#8211;unfortunately, that obstacle won&#8217;t go away anytime soon.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Anyway, that’s enough out of Grandma&#8211;y’all eat your veggies, smash the patriarchy, and write your damn book. I’m tired and old and I’m gonna go take a midday nap before getting back to work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/write-like-youre-running-out-of-time-because-youre-30-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yule Never Guess What I Accomplished This Year (Not Much)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/yule-never-guess-what-i-accomplished-this-year-not-much/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annacatalano]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 11:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22528</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Okay nobody panic, but it looks like we made it to the end of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Okay nobody panic, but it looks like we made it to the end of the year. It&#8217;s wildly unclear how it&#8217;s already December when I&#8217;m pretty sure March was ten minutes ago, but hey. Time isn&#8217;t real. Normally, this would be the time that I would start drafting up some awesome New Year&#8217;s resolutions, psyching myself up to be productive.</p>
<p dir="ltr">That being said&#8230; it&#8217;s hard not to keep looking back at all the resolutions I had originally made for 2020 that flew right out the window:</p>
<p dir="ltr">Start learning sign language. Finish a full first draft of any WIP. Revise the first book of my fantasy trilogy and make it ready to query by the end of the year. Launch my author website. Get another short story published.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Ah, past Anna, you sweet summer child. End of the entire year, and where do we stand?</p>
<p dir="ltr">YOU FAILED <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/whoa-were-halfway-there-through-nanowrimo/">NANOWRIMO</a> JUST LIKE I SAID YOU WOULD! HetPat, as an end of the year treat, crawls out of the garbage disposal covered in coffee grounds and slurping loudly on eggnog. YOU DIDN’T FINISH THE FIRST DRAFT OF ANY OF YOUR PROJECTS! YOU DIDN’T SEND OUT ANY STORIES TO GET PUBLISHED&#8211;YOU DIDN’T EVEN WRITE ONE THIS WHOLE YEAR! YOU HAVEN’T EVEN TOUCHED YOUR WEBSITE YET!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22529 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gull-2166711_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gull-2166711_1920-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gull-2166711_1920-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gull-2166711_1920-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gull-2166711_1920-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/gull-2166711_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">I mean, yes you’re right, but you don’t have to be so rude about it. <em>Back in the sink, demon</em>!</p>
<p dir="ltr">So how do I measure success in objectively one of the hardest years I&#8217;ve ever lived through?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Here&#8217;s a quick recap of the last ten months.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I began the ongoing battle against the anxiety demon <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/hetpat-the-anxiety-demon-an-unfortunate-introduction/">HetPat</a> who lives in my head and tells me I&#8217;m not good enough.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I began looking more critically at the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/ive-got-white-in-my-ledger-and-id-like-to-wipe-it-out/">diversity and implicit biases in my past writing a</a>nd vowed to work to remedy those issues in the future.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I took refuge in <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-i-wrote-it/">fanfiction</a> to reinvigorate my love of writing that has been on the fritz this year.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And to be fair, there were things I accomplished this year that just aren&#8217;t writing-related. I moved into my first apartment on my own. I bought my first car. I started going to therapy, got an anxiety diagnosis, and started my journey on medication. And while the writing-writing has been kind of a bust, I did actually revamp three novel outlines into something way stronger and exciting, so that when I eventually get back to those projects, they will be another step closer to achieving their True Form.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And even since beginning to draft this blog post, I have been struck by the lightning of a new book idea&#8211;something fun and indulgent and <em>definitely</em> not inspired by all of the fanfic I&#8217;ve been reading this year. Yes, I still have a billion other projects that I should be working on that I want to be working on. Yes, I am easily distracted by shiny new book ideas and yes, I likely bounce around so much because I&#8217;m intimidated by the commitment of Finishing a Project.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But after the creative struggle that was this year, I deserve to catch a break.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I guess I can&#8217;t make promises, even to myself, about what I want to accomplish next year. The exorcism of HetPat, as this blog column suggests, is ongoing, which means I will need to keep smacking him when he shows up now and then to discourage me.</p>
<p dir="ltr">See you all in the new year, where I inevitably come up with more new and exciting excuses to not get anything done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whoa, We&#8217;re Halfway There (Through NaNoWriMo)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/whoa-were-halfway-there-through-nanowrimo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annacatalano]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=22143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the time you read this, I’m probably dead… tired… and probably crying&#8211;from amazing success&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">By the time you read this, I’m probably dead… tired… and probably crying&#8211;from amazing success or devastating failure, but in either case I’m definitely crying.</p>
<p dir="ltr">We’re past the halfway point of November, and you’re probably wondering, after my lofty promises, how NaNoWriMo is going. You wouldn’t be alone&#8211;all my friends, their encouraging, expectant faces shining through the Zoom screen&#8211;also anxiously await to hear all about my progress.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I consider lying&#8211;oh my gosh you guys, we are kicking so much butt, I might just finish this book early, the writing is so so good and coming so so easy…</p>
<p dir="ltr">But my face would give it away&#8211;I’ve always been an open book… unlike this book. That I’m trying to write. That has never <em>felt</em> more closed.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So yeah&#8211;I’m 6,000 words behind.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22146 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/frantic-typing-300x219.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="219" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/frantic-typing-300x219.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/frantic-typing-1024x748.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/frantic-typing-768x561.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/frantic-typing-1536x1121.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/frantic-typing.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">WELL YEAH, WHAT DID YOU THINK WAS GONNA HAPPEN?! HetPat, always one for Opinions, waltzes into my headspace like he owns the place, sipping a cup of smoking hot turd. THERE WAS AN ELECTION THE WHOLE FIRST WEEK AND YOUR MENTAL HEALTH IS ALL OVER THE PLACE AND REMEMBER HOW YOU’VE BARELY WRITTEN AT ALL THIS YEAR&#8211;AND YOU THOUGHT YOU COULD MAGICALLY WRITE 50,000 WORDS IN ONE MONTH?! WHAT WERE YOU THINKING!</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>But&#8211;you’re the one who told me to do it!</em> I want to scream at him. <em>You literally argued in our last <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/nano-is-the-hour-of-our-discontent/">post</a> that I had no good reason to NOT do it, since I have all my projects outlined! This is your fault!</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">HetPat simply cackles&#8211;his work here is done. And yes, I do feel like an entire clown for choosing the one November that was an election year in the middle of a pandemic to get back into NaNoWriMo, that one’s on me.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Because I promised public accountability in this challenge: there have been at least three days in which not a single word was written (which is how I fell so far behind). But I guess I should also mention that on all other days, I’ve written&#8230;something. More often than not it was way less words than was my daily goal, but&#8230;<em>something</em>. Which I suppose I should commend myself for, as the whole “writing every day” thing has been&#8230;NOT a thing this entire calendar year.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It’s just so hard to not compare myself to other writers, who are conquering this challenge far easier, cranking out words by the thousands every day while I’m struggling to get through even a hundred at a time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22144 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/writers-block-300x259.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="259" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/writers-block-300x259.jpeg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/writers-block.jpeg 499w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">There’s still some time left in the month for the end-of-NaNo-writing-frenzy, so perhaps a cozy, seasonal miracle will happen.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I’m running on the fumes of exhaustion, the buzz of the first night’s excitement tapped out. But it’s probably to be expected that the second half of a race is bound to be harder than the first.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Here’s what I have to keep reminding myself (and HetPat): contrary to the competitive nature of this challenge, this <em>isn’t</em> actually a race&#8211;it’s a journey (yes I did throw up in my mouth a little but it’s true.) Yes, I want to win/succeed at hitting my word goal, and yes, I desperately want to stick it to HetPat, proving that I can do something that I put my mind to. But forward progress is forward progress, and by the end of November, this book will be closer to being done than it was at the start.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-22145 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/hurry-up-2785528_1280-300x271.png" alt="" width="300" height="271" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/hurry-up-2785528_1280-300x271.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/hurry-up-2785528_1280-1024x925.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/hurry-up-2785528_1280-768x694.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/hurry-up-2785528_1280.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">So we press onward.</p>
<p dir="ltr">We’re getting through this if I have to scream and cry all the way to the finish line.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NaNo is the Hour of Our Discontent</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/nano-is-the-hour-of-our-discontent/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/nano-is-the-hour-of-our-discontent/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annacatalano]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 10:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=20274</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s October, which means we have officially entered spoopy month&#8211;time for scary movies, pumpkin spice&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="m-7873797581703072010" class="mail-message expanded">
<div class="mail-message-header spacer">It’s October, which means we have officially entered spoopy month&#8211;time for scary movies, pumpkin spice lattes, and dressing up in the comfort of your own home because there’s still a pandemic on and we’re not going to any parties anytime soon, <i>right</i> <i>Karen</i>?!</div>
<div class="mail-message-content collapsible zoom-normal mail-show-images ">
<div class="clear">
<div dir="ltr">
<p>But for writers, it’s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=npHj0-yszuI" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v%3DnpHj0-yszuI&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1602564081305000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFQeTWnwKw3ByOFnq22nX55LsnxCg">Preptober</a>, which precedes NaNoWriMo, which, if I can speak for myself, is 200% scarier than Halloween.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1102" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1102" style="width: 270px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci6.googleusercontent.com/proxy/94E8O1rxENZGCDtxBtYIyvAgyFEB4iMOkp63CqNWO3D9n8ua1_n_TlqjdcQfuUgKwiNatnhW7OxjucrsEXe2Lwn1jddfoNd5i_UEVka4hi1HZ_qtY-SkzkUa7O2-IquCk6TrqbO8DnmUzNwK1VF4Eseh0vYl1sQ=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/screaming-146426_1280-270x300.png" alt="" width="270" height="300" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1102" class="wp-caption-text">Me, taking one look at the daunting challenge ahead</figcaption></figure>
<p>For those unfamiliar, <a href="https://nanowrimo.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://nanowrimo.org/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1602564081305000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHJAwLCdOj99zfjoKPLP_Or4bZ5HA">NaNoWriMo</a> (a catchy abbreviation for National Novel Writing Month, which is November) is an annual event and competition in which writers strive to write a complete novel (or the equivalent of 50,000 words) in a mere month. If this sounds like a fun, amazing time, I’m very happy for you and also where do you get your enthusiasm from, can I have some, please?</p>
<p>If this sounds like a rollercoaster of high emotion and stress, you have come to the write (heh) place.</p>
<p>I participated, unofficially, in NaNo way back in the good ol’ simpler days of 2013. I won&#8211;I met the goal of starting and finishing a whole ass book&#8211;with a modern-day reimagining of <i>The Hobbit </i>as a spy thriller (was it cool? Yes. Was the execution good? Absolutely not. Am I ever going to rewrite this project to salvage it? I have six million other things to do first, but boy would it be nice at some point.)</p>
<figure id="attachment_1107" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1107" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/XkNP1nMv-V4F5hF6dC5WnRT8bsSppFpowhO0XDRKEMKlXRibBAzTL-CUZUa7RRK_ZhGwZ3wyX6w2hvHXohjker85LA-6jtp8J2jvAWePFCmQcEI4eB7ZxlBqZIjTRcUSGaecd5k4Euq4a0w-lzxKZtPnK5Q=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/books-1245690_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1107" class="wp-caption-text">So&#8230;many words&#8230;that I have to write&#8230;</figcaption></figure>
<p>I have not attempted NaNo since then, for various reasons involving the lack of personal motivation, declining mental health, as well as the fact that up until recently I worked in retail, where October through December is literally the busiest time of the year with no days off. But every year, like clockwork, as I hear about people getting hype about NaNo as we approach November, I get serious FOMO. More than once, I made it a New Year&#8217;s resolution to participate this year for sure, OK, I <i>promise</i>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1103" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1103" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/RfuyiM7IK40qiK5VjryQtdh3UZ9NvPq7QPKUATLjDZ0jCOel9-yity2j4iuFkSb7YhVPM7UliGMIszSVPvZzzWSVBVNsQG93_wN_TNu9AlenIRIm813bv9MHhdkdeE9CVGl0wZ3v1PtGAPVDj2epxupEgcU=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/woman-3711719_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1103" class="wp-caption-text">Staring down at the people getting their lives together and doing NaNoWriMo like god I wish that were me</figcaption></figure>
<p>2020 has very manifestly NOT been the year for me being my most productive self. And yet, again, like clockwork, people are out here prepping their manuscripts and filming vlogs and engaging in the writing community with other authors excited for this challenge… and like a glutton for punishment, I’m back to considering doing it.</p>
<p>YOU HAVE NO EXCUSE! <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/hetpat-the-anxiety-demon-an-unfortunate-introduction/">HetPat</a> perches on the edge of my mind-palace desk like a haggard demon cat, armed as always with a Mary Poppins bag full of insults and insecurities. YOU ALREADY HAVE COMPLETED OUTLINES FOR ALL YOUR PROJECTS! YOU HAVE MORNINGS BEFORE WORK THAT YOU CAN USE TO WRITE INSTEAD OF SLEEPING IN LIKE YOU DO EVERY DAY! YOU HAVE WEEKENDS YOU COULD USE TO WRITE INSTEAD OF DOING NOTHING LIKE YOU DO EVERY DAY!</p>
<p>Touché, you slimy little piece of garbage.</p>
<p>It’s true that I have no shortage of projects to choose from, and yeah, technically if I truly committed to this endeavor I <em>do</em> have the time where I could make it happen. But my brain is so fundamentally binary that I never see my own progress&#8211;if I don’t start a thing and then finish it and have a completed end product in my hands, I see it as an abject failure. If I don’t succeed at writing a whole novel in November, it doesn’t matter the work I put into it, if I don’t “win” and finish it in time, I consider it a complete wash.</p>
<p>Contrary to HetPat’s claim that WHAT’S THE POINT OF DOING SOMETHING IF YOU’RE NOT GOING TO FINISH IT AND WIN, I have been informed that this might, <em>perhaps</em>, be untrue.</p>
<p>Some writers thrive under strict deadlines, like the ones NaNoWriMo imposes. Others flourish on their own timeline, refusing to be held to outside constraints. I have been both of these people over the years, as I’ve struggled with finding the Writing Process That Works For Me. Don’t know if I’ve found it yet, it’s been a whole wild trial and error journey.</p>
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/tGocODX7i0ILxHft46hAn3lWgbeViMS3fiFagKCph1eTzkL5YhpkJqgJ42N1IzhAvYucGC0zzEzNgxd1w4HFAmOfrN4PouuNUodba-krlNSGmfYJDEPrcmMQf51Asc9RbgCLy8BOuT7ZhZBI5D1JW6gfYU77=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/laptop-3087585_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Bold of you to assume I can stick to self-imposed deadlines</figcaption></figure>
<p style="text-align: left">I <i>do</i> have a consistent work schedule now though, which I didn’t used to have. So it <i>is</i> fully within my power to plan my days accordingly to make time to Write One of My Books (<em>But Which One?</em>)</p>
<p>Should it be the project that’s objectively closer to being coherently done and plotted out? Should it be the one I’m most excited to see as a finished product? Should it be the one I consider to be the most <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/dessert-first-making-writing-indulgent-again/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://2f5.f93.mwp.accessdomain.com/dessert-first-making-writing-indulgent-again/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1602564081305000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHk4cijkj420YAVY6-AwvK-GTF-nQ">marketable</a>?</p>
<p>Maybe by even putting this suggestion out into the universe I will convince myself to follow through with this challenge. Maybe just the act of publishing this post will motivate me to do this if only under the threat of public shaming.</p>
<p>&#8230;I feel like I’ve inadvertently committed myself to doing it now. Oops.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1105" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1105" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/s8s65jy0xzGNKHFlr-QYHOEv_XqalqSM4sfkerB2f1D1Rnkjx5vGLaTSUo6xeg3M-dKeCo4j5lfBIs1HibnVgf6NFpkltw-raRNWf9I6uX7zc27tM9s0Xc5odd3v454quKRARLR_Mfnz1eQc7527XGmMrQ=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/raven-988226_1920-300x194.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="194" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1105" class="wp-caption-text">Quoth the raven: write some more</figcaption></figure>
<p>But hey, even if I “fail” the challenge, maybe someone reading this blog and following my journey will get something out of it, even if it’s a What NOT to Do During NaNoWriMo. #Education.</p>
<p>Because that’s what’s so great about the writing community&#8211;sure, we encourage and lift each other up in our successes, but there’s also plenty of support to go around for the failures.</p>
<p>So let’s drown HetPat out in a chorus of #NaNoFail, and #ITooAmAFraud, and #What’sImportantIsYouHadFunKiddo.</p>
<p>After all, perhaps the real NaNoWriMo is the friends we make along the way.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="mail-message-footer spacer collapsible"></div>
</div>
<div id="conversation-footer" class="spacer"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/nano-is-the-hour-of-our-discontent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ace: The Final Frontier</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ace-the-final-frontier/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annacatalano]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 10:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19780</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the midst of a creative dry spell and general despair, I recently took a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="m4212786557713266968" class="mail-message expanded">
<div class="mail-message-header spacer">In the midst of a creative dry spell and general despair, I recently took a desperate jaunt down to fanfic land, and in one of my last <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-i-wrote-it/">posts</a> I discussed how my dabble into <em>Star Trek: Deep Space Nine</em> fic helped me (momentarily) out of the writing slump I had found myself in.</div>
<div class="mail-message-content collapsible zoom-normal mail-show-images ">
<div class="clear">
<div dir="ltr">
<p>But for every solution, a new problem inevitably arises, and I discovered something as I journeyed farther into my self-indulgent Quark/Odo fanfic. All I wanted was to write some good old-fashioned alien sex… but what am I supposed to do when one of those aliens happens to be <a href="https://www.thetrevorproject.org/trvr_support_center/asexual/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.thetrevorproject.org/trvr_support_center/asexual/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1601058621328000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE96gy6W6Pkbv678Gy4WfDXQsjGJA">asexual</a>?</p>
<p>I had written the pining, the buildup, the crackling romantic tension. All that was left was to deliver on the sex&#8211;the part I’m usually excited to get to. And… I hit a wall.</p>
<figure style="width: 213px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/mh-_JOLalplHj_Z8Iybq1gQu9rxhJNCd1wnVLF7c7zz1DgFZm6hflSHfWenQorhes2N0Tt5pe9XOABaAoKQY3mKpN9yI1Xx8fjfiOujP-AxEXUajlc8ptH4xXysRVg=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/lust.png" alt="" width="213" height="291" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Kate Beaton, Hark! A Vagrant</figcaption></figure>
<p>Okay, what’s the problem <em>now</em>? This was like 90% of my motivation for writing this scene in the first place and I get to the grand finale and I <em>freeze</em>? What’s the <em>deal</em>, man?</p>
<p>And I realized that I was struggling to write a sex scene between a character who is sexual and comfortable in his body and with physical intimacy, and a character who is very clearly coded (subtextually and through his own dialogue) as asexual in canon.</p>
<p>And therein lies the rub, really. For reference, for anyone who hasn’t watched the show, Quark (a snarky Ferengi bartender with a heart of gold) and Odo (a shapeshifter working as the chief of security who has it out for Quark) have a show-long, bantery, enemies-to-friends-to-they-could’ve-been-lovers if the showrunners had taken one very tiny extra step in that direction because they were honestly THERE.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1094" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1094" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/RsQ_glDJw0-gdsJvi4RU7JNH47Ho1KamFLaOloFn9hMVOlKzlDP-Da1tV92W4mJ5hkRa3Da-E_wLfDF32XBONaxjWqlcGDTKoVPo7_AnsYxVmctM56k2SnASka7c2ligU7veZn78wXaRTuw2qVISkoE19xeuGrJr48jpAYtPnEw=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Quark_and_Odo_on_the_Promenade-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1094" class="wp-caption-text">Stand even closer, I dare ya</figcaption></figure>
<p>Odo says early on that he has never understood non-shapeshifters’ penchant for coupling, and let me tell you I did a double-take. It’s rare if ever that I encounter any explicitly asexual characters in media, and when I do they tend to be robots, aliens, or sociopaths (which is a whole other issue that we will address in a later post.) But this character was layered and gruffly lovable, with a tragic backstory I deeply empathized with, and I felt very suddenly SEEN.</p>
<p>His slow-burn romance (because that’s what it was) with Quark was one of my favorite things to see develop over the course of the show&#8211;up until the showrunners decided that it was very important that Odo, who had explicitly voiced having no interest in sex, have sex and then immediately decide that it was great, and he was wrong this whole time, and let’s do some deeply out-of-character leering at people whose asses we want to tap now.</p>
<p>If I had a dollar for every time an ace character was introduced only to be forced into a <a href="https://feminisminindia.com/2019/10/25/things-keep-mind-writing-asexual-characters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://feminisminindia.com/2019/10/25/things-keep-mind-writing-asexual-characters/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1601058621328000&amp;usg=AFQjCNH2q_ebAlW_qp7Z9jDK50ZWGNdJsA">“cure” narrative</a>…</p>
<p>And obviously there is nuance here&#8211;sexuality is often fluid, and confusing, and can change with a person’s growth throughout their life. And for goodness sake, even under the asexual umbrella, there are many aces who do still have sex for a myriad of personal reasons, and this is nuance that I believe should be explored and talked about without having to fit into a very Specific Box that is most palatable for mainstream’s understanding of this identity.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter" src="https://ci3.googleusercontent.com/proxy/4oVSw7sK4etP4gjJj3v2Uzh36U9QrJ5DE7VrueI5588tRVw626qzH5r9b-v6d80NE2dDPvIB5zcj5ja0x8nVZ1UpYRSMFC5S7k_ZqB6JT8sU8J0bBBq3NHpQvrXRF-jI9D7Ka7_OUXYXoy_V5v7G_ZS6AvrEwF3XKlTzTv4oTIAC71LLCJHL6YoLJ57Zb5NVv5Q=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/asexual-pride-flag-waving-vector-600w-1227293473-249x300.jpg" alt="" width="249" height="300" /></p>
<p>BUT TO BE FAIR, HOW WOULD YOU KNOW? a familiar voice grates, and hoo boy, looks like it’s time for HetPat’s unasked-for opinion again. He rolls gratuitously onto the scene with his lewd and uneducated commentary, waving a Straight Pride flag. IF THE MAJORITY OF PEOPLE HAVE SEX AND LIKE IT THEN MAYBE YOU’RE THE ONE WHO’S WRONG! ASEXUALITY DOESN’T EXIST&#8211;THERE’S JUST PEOPLE WHO ARE SCARED, OR CHILDISH, OR JUST DON’T KNOW ANY BETTER! OF COURSE THEY NEED TO BE FIXED&#8211;YOU SAID YOURSELF YOU ENJOY READING AND WRITING SEX SCENES, HOW DO YOU EXPECT TO DO THAT IF YOU DON’T JUST ACCEPT THAT SEX IS THE NATURAL, LOGICAL, HUMAN CONSUMMATION OF LOVE?</p>
<p>Okay, even if we ignore everything <em>blatantly</em> wrong with what this gremlin’s ignorantly spouting, that’s the thing&#8211;sex and romance, while sometimes related, are not intrinsically correlated. In <em>DS9</em>, Odo never expresses any aversion to romantic love, or companionship&#8211;in fact, he privately indulges in reading cheesy romance novels.</p>
<figure style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci6.googleusercontent.com/proxy/YeorREXxZC7zuWl1e2iXZfCYrSCRv1Cy_2wbhUvJ3yHoO361o6OMcnIErKBXu_kimu_7uv9w9vhAf3L_F9MjURKFg3vUBs53sRj3dPWEFw_dN22AJQVWwOk2UQj9rPoMGkNT8Ht4S9cTJQ9nfjkN2lnPUVj84xvlYLg4bOo1SkIEDKjHTw=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Odo_and_Quark_in_crashed_Rio_Grande-300x230.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="230" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">An iconic episode for an iconic alien couple</figcaption></figure>
<p>An asexual icon, to be sure, but not an <a href="http://wiki.asexuality.org/Aromantic" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://wiki.asexuality.org/Aromantic&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1601058621328000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFUaMUNJptRVMMa6vZtbz2ncesRXQ">aromantic</a> one.</p>
<p>See, that’s what I need to incorporate in this torrid fanfic I’m composing when I should be doing other things. There’s no reason to believe that someone like Odo wouldn’t, when given the opportunity to engage sexually with a beloved partner, put aside his own lack of desires in an effort to see that partner satisfied.</p>
<p>Odo from <em>DS9</em> is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stone_butch" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stone_butch&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1601058621328000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHnUBbuGMrDeMOO3Rh7v5n7_3x73Q">stone butch</a>, tell the geek boys I said what I said.</p>
<p>So why not <em>use</em> that nuance? The scene I want so desperately to write can still exist, just maybe not in the way it might for two <a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Allosexual" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term%3DAllosexual&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1601058621328000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFcoVFAaYnMgY-EWvcnrkjExY8d9A">allosexual</a> individuals. And this is something the characters could mention, and explore, and communicate about (you know, like a healthy relationship dynamic.)</p>
<p>This, of course, works out fine because these are already existing characters in a fictional world that we’re free to speculate about. What remains a struggle for another day is what happens when these characters are my own creation&#8211;like, for example, the two asexual characters I’ve decided to pair up in a romantic relationship in my WIP novel.</p>
<p>What does it say that I, an asexual writer striving for better representation, still want them to smooch and stuff? Does that make me a hypocrite? A fraud? A lying liar who lies?</p>
<p>Bet you ten bucks that HetPat says DUH.</p>
<p>Tune in next time when we do our best to figure this out, one insecurity-gremlin at a time.</p>
<p>But for now, I have more procrastinating to do.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="conversation-footer" class="spacer"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dessert First: Making Writing Indulgent Again</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dessert-first-making-writing-indulgent-again/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dessert-first-making-writing-indulgent-again/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annacatalano]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 10:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19335</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It’s finally happened, friends&#8211;after years and years of market saturation and subsequent radio silence&#8211;vampires have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s finally happened, friends&#8211;after years and years of market saturation and subsequent radio silence&#8211;vampires have <em>officially</em> reentered the publishing sphere and I quite literally could not be more excited, oh my </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">GOD</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, my time has COME.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This means that after considerable time away, I can </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">finally</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> drag my vampire novel work-in-progress kicking and screaming back out into daylight (vampire pun not intended).</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gay vampires! Blood and guts! Delicious sexual tension! Apocalyptic stakes! (vampire pun not intended again, okay, I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">swear</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">).</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_19349" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19349" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-19349 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/rainbow-2796595_1920-300x200.png" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/rainbow-2796595_1920-300x200.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/rainbow-2796595_1920-1024x683.png 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/rainbow-2796595_1920-768x512.png 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/rainbow-2796595_1920-1536x1024.png 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/rainbow-2796595_1920.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19349" class="wp-caption-text">Tonally this is not where the novel is, but thematically it Is Image by Alexis Hunter from Pixabay</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I even had a super productive brainstorming session, the likes of which I haven’t experienced in months, in which I had several breakthroughs regarding the (previously) extremely vague second half of this novel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">See here’s the thing you should know about me as a writer&#8211;I don’t care that much for plot. At least, I don’t when I have to write it myself&#8211;I have been known to enjoy many a plot, in my day, when someone </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">else</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> has to do the hard work to do worldbuilding and take the story from point A to B.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But when I have to do it </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">myself</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, when the onus of scraping together a coherent narrative with plot beats and escalating action and intriguing twists falls on my easily bored shoulders?</span></p>
<p>Thanks but no thanks.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Left to my own devices, I would much rather revel all day in the formation of my characters, ideally constructing ways in which I can make them talk about their feelings and then enthusiastically smooch each other. For </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">reasons</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_19350" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19350" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-19350 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hands-437968_1920-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hands-437968_1920-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hands-437968_1920-1024x678.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hands-437968_1920-768x508.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hands-437968_1920-1536x1017.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/hands-437968_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19350" class="wp-caption-text">It&#8217;s all about the YEARNING Image by Tu Anh from Pixabay</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, I have been &#8220;informed&#8221; that that is not, in fact, enough to get me through a whole-ass novel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">THAT’S THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN TRYING TO GET PUBLISHED TRADITIONALLY AND JUST WRITING FANFICTION, INNIT? <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/hetpat-the-anxiety-demon-an-unfortunate-introduction/">HetPat</a>&#8211;who has turned British all of a sudden, perhaps shapeshifting into Ricky Gervais for the purpose of this argument&#8211;slimes his way onto the scene, a writing rulebook in his slimy hands, ready to beat me over the head with it. THERE ARE RULES YOU HAVE TO FOLLOW IF YOU WANT TO DO THIS PROFESSIONALLY! AND ONE OF THE RULES IS THAT YOU HAVE TO HAVE A PLOT! A STORY! NOT JUST 300 PAGES OF SELF-INDULGENT SMOOCHY NONSENSE WHERE IT DOESN’T BELONG!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve been doing good worldbuilding, and have a pretty solid working outline with plot beats and story craft galore. And yet, as I gaze down upon my plot-heavy monstrosity with a romantic sideplot if you squint, all I can think of is how </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">bored</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I am. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How I</span>’m slogging my way through necessary exposition and getting us from point A to point B. How I want nothing more than to abandon the #Plot in favor of just having romantic drama and the payoff of sexual tension between my leads.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Skip the meat and vegetables and go straight to dessert.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_19351" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19351" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-19351 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cake-1746435_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cake-1746435_1920-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cake-1746435_1920-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cake-1746435_1920-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cake-1746435_1920-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/cake-1746435_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19351" class="wp-caption-text">Until my book makes me feel the way eating chocolate cake does, it is not done Image by MikesPhotos from Pixabay</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I cut HetPat off at the pass&#8211;</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I understand that I have to write a book with a plot, okay? I know I have to keep the publishing world’s expectations in mind if I want to query this at some point. But here’s the thing&#8211;didn’t someone once say that in writing, you should write what you want to read? Well, if I was reading this book&#8211;not writing it&#8211;I would want way more romance. And for goodness sake, my characters are <strong>vampires</strong> and yet there is a distinct lack of self-indulgent vampire sexiness that would be befitting of my brand, like what the <strong>heck</strong>.</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most fun I have reading is when I’m reading self-indulgent sexy fanfiction&#8211;I should be writing more of that, if that’s what I enjoy.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">BUT THEN YOU SHOULD JUST WRITE FANFICTION! YOU CAN DO THAT IF YOU WANT BUT YOU HAVE TO FOLLOW THE RULES IF YOU WANT TO WRITE FOR A REAL AUDIENCE IN THE REAL WORLD! YOU’RE CREATING A WORLD FROM SCRATCH, YOU HAVE TO MAKE THE WORLDBUILDING COME FIRST! YOU CAN’T COAST OFF ANYONE ELSE’S EXISTING WORK! THESE ARE THE CHOICES YOU HAVE TO MAKE&#8211;A MAINSTREAM, PUBLISHABLE STORY OR A SELF-INDULGENT FANSERVICE EXTRAVAGANZA, YOU CAN’T HAVE BOTH!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I guess there </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">is</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> something to be said for writing specifically with the intent to publish (versus only writing for yourself). But I can’t just forsake one for the other. I need to find a middle ground that will satisfy my schmoopy, trope-loving heart as well as the part wanting to write a good story from a craft perspective so that I can pitch this book.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_19352" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19352" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-19352 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/relaxing-1979674_1920-300x205.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="205" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/relaxing-1979674_1920-300x205.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/relaxing-1979674_1920-1024x701.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/relaxing-1979674_1920-768x526.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/relaxing-1979674_1920-1536x1052.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/relaxing-1979674_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19352" class="wp-caption-text">Apparently taking time to relax does wonders for creativity, who knew Image by Jill Wellington from Pixabay</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But there’s </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">vampires</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and</span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> love triangles</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">betrayal</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and I am underutilizing their vampyness in their own story and that just will not do.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Plenty of authors have spoken up on Twitter about how their most elaborate, plot-twisty, worldbuildy novel is not necessarily their biggest hit&#8211;<a href="https://www.lapl.org/collections-resources/blogs/lapl/interview-author-ve-schwab">V.E. Schwab</a> has said repeatedly that </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vicious</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> was likely so widely loved </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">because</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it was the project she just allowed herself to get carried away in, writing something she thought only she would enjoy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clearly, readers can smell books written full of passion coming a mile away, and apparently they eat it up? Because you can tell when an author is having a good time writing something and when they’re not?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Writing is hard enough on the best of days, so gosh dang it I am gonna be here for a good time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the trade off is between writing something I enjoy&#8211;even if it’s fanservice for myself&#8211;and writing something dry and uninspired that technically checks the boxes of what Publishing Wants… then I’m gonna go with the tropey, juicy, indulgent vampire book of my dreams, and HetPat can crawl back into the shadows and suck it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And yes, that vampire pun WAS intended. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dessert-first-making-writing-indulgent-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s the End of the World (As I Wrote It)</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-i-wrote-it/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-i-wrote-it/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annacatalano]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=19098</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Confession time: I think I’ve forgotten how to write. That’s the only explanation&#8211;it’s been months now and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="m6204901143133305124" class="mail-message ">
<div class="mail-message-header spacer">Confession time: I think I’ve forgotten how to write.</div>
</div>
<div id="m1113183268882299937" class="mail-message expanded">
<div class="mail-message-content collapsible zoom-normal mail-show-images ">
<div class="clear">
<div dir="ltr">
<p>That’s the only explanation&#8211;it’s been <i>months</i> now and every semblance of creativity, of craft, of intimate emotional engagement with my characters, has up and abandoned me.</p>
<p>Little-Timmy-is-trapped-down-a-well level of abandoned.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter" src="https://ci6.googleusercontent.com/proxy/6SAblCT03xBdrtTAKMfooBhToN3liFnCcEelz7b4KAjOx3SAUNiauslNWRX7HR2E7jCe-YLYMb2ym6VgG_nSjPKgPMTnqbWK_meq1xe_6gllfcv0WWsYEhiMgSlSnX_tSpTLFCSP6g7Vt-XXPotDUcMr=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/guy-2609240_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="&quot;Image" /></p>
<p>It’s not like it’s a mystery, it might have something to do with the overwhelming external stimuli that’s making the ability to focus on writing all but impossible. Obviously, we are all Going Through It at the moment. And normally, I eventually make it out of these dry spells&#8211;but what if this time is different?</p>
<p>I’ve had multiple false starts on the countless projects that are on hiatus and to no avail&#8211;the characters, so present and vibrant in my head and heart, have all simultaneously lost their voices.</p>
<p>Realistic dialogue that humans would say? Gone with the wind.</p>
<p>Ability to imagine literally any scene that’s not a blank white room? A distant memory.</p>
<p>The mere <i>concept</i> of constructing a sentence&#8211;have I ever even <i>seen</i> a sentence before?!</p>
<p>I’m hit with the horrible realization that maybe writing isn’t like riding a bike. Maybe it’s like speaking a different language&#8211;if you don’t use it, you lose it.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1081" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1081" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/jaXzEbw0IAFhV6fGZOQgMS8R90zbs0y1qkryqDGeu2rZjZ74REyXhxC17rKR99kIKU5LiGGKrYAoFu-wYEjDPO_-e-gXzBxA2PItt0sKa1AOKWJTB4YgqKysxWrwp3hZqQrWUtKP=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/cow-300x252.jpeg" alt="https://www.memedroid.com/memes/tag/looking+into+the+distance" width="300" height="252" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1081" class="wp-caption-text">(broken recorder version of &#8220;My Heart Will Go On&#8221; playing in the distance <a href="https://www.memedroid.com/memes/tag/looking+into+the+distance%5B/caption%5D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.memedroid.com/memes/tag/looking%2Binto%2Bthe%2Bdistance%255B/caption%255D&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1594530766588000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGA6FxvemFBCWwzs1ueDsQIlgqlfQ">https://www.memedroid.com/memes/tag/looking+into+the+distance</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>IF YOU DON’T GET IT BACK SOON, IT’LL BE GONE FOREVER! <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/hetpat-the-anxiety-demon-an-unfortunate-introduction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://2f5.f93.mwp.accessdomain.com/hetpat-the-anxiety-demon-an-unfortunate-introduction/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1594530766588000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGJOFYcTExwuHsmbEsdkkZ5oPmFKg">HetPat,</a> the evil Keebler Elf himself, crawls, steaming and stinking in his three-piece suit, out of the toxic hellhole of my mind, voice harsh and grating. YOU SHOULD’VE ENJOYED LAST SUMMER’S PRODUCTIVITY WHILE YOU HAD IT BECAUSE THAT WILL NEVER HAPPEN AGAIN! REMEMBER BEING A FUNCTIONAL HUMAN AND A PRODUCTIVE MEMBER OF SOCIETY?!</p>
<p><i>I’m a published author, </i>I try and tell him, my voice small and wavering. <i>I have short stories in literary magazines. I signed a book deal. People I trust have told me that I’m a good writer. </i></p>
<p>IF YOU WERE A REAL WRITER, YOU COULD GET BACK INTO IT! HetPat slithers atop my computer keyboard like a disgruntled, demonic cat craving attention. YOU WOULDN&#8217;T JUST FORGET HOW TO WRITE AFTER SOME TIME AWAY! MAYBE YOU&#8217;RE NOT AS GOOD AS YOU THOUGHT YOU WERE&#8211;THEY&#8217;RE PROBABLY LYING TO YOU ANYWAY TO MAKE YOU FEEL BETTER ABOUT BEING A LAZY, UNQUALIFIED, UNTALENTED WASTE OF SPACE! HOW CAN YOU CALL YOURSELF A WRITER WHEN YOU CAN&#8217;T EVEN REMEMBER HOW TO WRITE CHARACTERS THAT CAME FROM YOUR OWN HEAD?! SAD!</p>
<p>But the act of writing has become like pulling teeth, a chore. The words are staring menacingly at me from where I last left off. The detailed outline I made tells me specifically what needs to be done in this scene but sits in passive-aggressive judgment in one of my dozen open tabs, long neglected. The passion I, objectively, <i>know</i> I have for these stories feels like a far off dream, a hot cup of tea that’s been so long forgotten it’s become an iced chai.</p>
<p>Surely I should remember how to write characters that originated in my own head&#8211;surely I’m the only one who <i>can</i>.</p>
<p>And <i>yet</i>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1083" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1083" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/oCWJB9z1WO7ABOvyz3_IKStCPumfjXsYLSK2CYmcSP1iKiZbq2xMA4DvMLMJFl3tyWXjBhm8qRgSFCFPCE6duMrcQJCk1s2NDZYuE4Kv8ss_y4jYjD6IgTYpcuEy3Jh1ztwWV2zx=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/rose-300x136.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="136" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1083" class="wp-caption-text">I would try begging, but I think my characters can probably smell desperation <a href="https://memegenerator.net/Rose-Titanic-Come-Back/caption%5B/caption%5D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://memegenerator.net/Rose-Titanic-Come-Back/caption%255B/caption%255D&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1594530766588000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGLxoX1baK_kp9TFYADgKRi66MOsg">https://memegenerator.net/Rose-Titanic-Come-Back/caption</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>The desire to write is there, but if the motivation doesn’t return, or the ability to even half-ass a rough draft just to have <i>something</i> on the page, if the creative well in my brain has been shut off never to return&#8211;what do I <em>do?</em> I don&#8217;t have a backup plan, no other career opportunities, no marketable skills outside of the writing that I <i>used</i> to be able to do (I have the receipts from old stories&#8211;supposedly, <i>apparently</i>, at some <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/cry-sanctuary/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://2f5.f93.mwp.accessdomain.com/story/cry-sanctuary/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1594530766588000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGZriT2hb2Ll1SoRABK5vlgTLSG5w">point</a>, I <a href="https://www.planetscumm.space/shop/planet-scumm-issue-8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.planetscumm.space/shop/planet-scumm-issue-8&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1594530766588000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGpJg0JEWsarATrra80f9nWIV045w"><i>was</i></a> able to do <a href="https://www.planetscumm.space/living-through-sci-fi/how-to-write-during-the-apocalypse" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.planetscumm.space/living-through-sci-fi/how-to-write-during-the-apocalypse&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1594530766588000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG7Hwm8nzT-UvE8xAaOMUp1k0GdIg">this</a>.)</p>
<p>To HetPat’s chagrin, I’ve done the only thing I can think of in these trying times.</p>
<p>I’ve gone back to my roots, following the only lingering bit of enthusiasm and motivation left in my husk of a body and written a short little fanfiction about an uptight Chief of Security and a snarky bartender (<i>Star Trek: DS9</i>, thank you for your service.)</p>
<figure id="attachment_1082" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1082" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/fS70aRrxVZSfuY0g9gTkNle8xcrJZEuqpa3TKNNn8u_iORro5S_7iY4dYeiRek_dBnCi_tF-ejSCsPzqY-Kgu98D29Tt-ATAP4dvBxMhR59MUQp4PWpjQhr6--Gj9fnKPhnTI-llyA=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/quodo-300x229.png" alt="" width="300" height="229" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1082" class="wp-caption-text">What can I say, your honor, they are in love <a href="http://www.letswatchstartrek.com/2013/05/08/ds9-profit-and-loss/picture-9-145/%5B/caption%5D" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.letswatchstartrek.com/2013/05/08/ds9-profit-and-loss/picture-9-145/%255B/caption%255D&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1594530766588000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHiZbhQpNhW8AJ5HUiqqZa2-pzcHg">http://www.letswatchstartrek.com/2013/05/08/ds9-profit-and-loss/picture-9-145/</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>That’s where my emotional engagement lies at the moment, and maybe&#8211;just maybe&#8211;it could be the cathartic, stepping stone towards the realm of remembering how to tell stories.</p>
<p>I wrote 4,500 words over the course of two days, which for me is practically an entire novel at this point.</p>
<p>I guess there’s something to be said for self-indulgent, homoerotic fanservice written as a desperate, last-ditch effort to prove to myself that I can still write.</p>
<p>There’s no telling if I’ve toggled the switch back on or not&#8211;I haven’t braved a look back on any of my abandoned projects yet, because I’m terrified of the wall still standing as impenetrable as it was before.</p>
<p>And no, HetPat, I know what you’re going to say, and maybe this <i>was</i> a waste of time as I write something that ISN’T one of the six million actual projects that I’m trying to finish.</p>
<p>He won’t let me stay here forever, in this tiny oasis in the middle of a god-forsaken barren wasteland where creativity comes to die. At some point, when I regain my strength and will to live, I will need to push forward and make it out of the desert.</p>
<p>If there IS a way out.</p>
<figure id="attachment_19100" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-19100" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-19100 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/maze-1804499_1920-300x160.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="160" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/maze-1804499_1920-300x160.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/maze-1804499_1920-1024x546.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/maze-1804499_1920-768x410.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/maze-1804499_1920-1536x819.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/maze-1804499_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-19100" class="wp-caption-text">The write is dark, and full of terrors Image by Arek Socha from Pixabay</figcaption></figure>
<p>But if this is the end for me, if the writing gene has really faffed off for the foreseeable future, then so help me I’m taking this entire <a href="https://www.google.com/imgres?imgurl=https://66.media.tumblr.com/8699f5b43ad586ab4325282acc01bcb8/tumblr_pv1bsxhgX01yp8zpjo1_r1_500.gifv&amp;imgrefurl=https://www.tumblr.com/tagged/quark%252Fodo&amp;tbnid=UliejPwzEK0hSM&amp;vet=1&amp;docid=e8AWo2u1Mrc1YM&amp;w=416&amp;h=206&amp;itg=1&amp;q=quark+and+odo+kiss&amp;hl=en&amp;source=sh/x/im#h=206&amp;imgdii=UliejPwzEK0hSM&amp;vet=1&amp;w=416" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/imgres?imgurl%3Dhttps://66.media.tumblr.com/8699f5b43ad586ab4325282acc01bcb8/tumblr_pv1bsxhgX01yp8zpjo1_r1_500.gifv%26imgrefurl%3Dhttps://www.tumblr.com/tagged/quark%25252Fodo%26tbnid%3DUliejPwzEK0hSM%26vet%3D1%26docid%3De8AWo2u1Mrc1YM%26w%3D416%26h%3D206%26itg%3D1%26q%3Dquark%2Band%2Bodo%2Bkiss%26hl%3Den%26source%3Dsh/x/im%23h%3D206%26imgdii%3DUliejPwzEK0hSM%26vet%3D1%26w%3D416&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1594531534262000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFbDtXQL3jAzwPhjkVxpdhPOTZy4g">Quark/Odo</a> fanfic with me, cackling all the way down.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="clear">
<div dir="ltr"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/its-the-end-of-the-world-as-i-wrote-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We Need to Talk About Katniss</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/we-need-to-talk-about-katniss/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annacatalano]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 10:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“When might young readers of color realize that the characters I am rooting for are&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="m-3817946980322757042" class="mail-message ">
<div class="mail-message-header spacer" style="text-align: center;">“When might young readers of color realize that <i>the characters I am rooting for are not positioned like me in the real world, and the characters that are positioned like me are not the team to root fo</i>r?”</div>
</div>
<div id="m-4039643208617149742" class="mail-message expanded">
<div class="mail-message-content collapsible zoom-normal mail-show-images ">
<div class="clear">
<div dir="ltr">
<p style="text-align: center;">&#8211;Dr. Ebony Elizabeth Thomas, <i>The Dark Fantastic</i></p>
<p><b><i>Content warning: mentions of racial violence and police brutality</i></b></p>
<p>Thousands of <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/los-angeles-police-department-budget-cuts-defund-lapd-eric-garcetti-press-conference-a9549001.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/los-angeles-police-department-budget-cuts-defund-lapd-eric-garcetti-press-conference-a9549001.html&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGtiO8UWZmtywz2uPL3Pl5OGDU_LA">people</a> marching in the streets for a week straight. <a href="https://www.prisonpolicy.org/blog/2020/06/05/policekillings/?fbclid=IwAR0bHf8Vi-2EYjZMmrEeT5avZ5A_inuQoOUAyY909PsJKOEXIneS7Vn0wDA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.prisonpolicy.org/blog/2020/06/05/policekillings/?fbclid%3DIwAR0bHf8Vi-2EYjZMmrEeT5avZ5A_inuQoOUAyY909PsJKOEXIneS7Vn0wDA&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGJzCvWbAaUcALQh_bcDfExsVfAHw">Police officers</a>&#8211;sworn to be peacekeepers&#8211;attacking and murdering in full view of cameras, with little to no legal repercussions. Fires and looting and the tearing down of Confederate statues hundreds of years late.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1074" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1074" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci6.googleusercontent.com/proxy/B4msSo0KLusdOqx2aqhxTVmVzPjs-k3JC5Ls-8hHY5nxye0XElE1A3G71-NDHKeXgUcGf7qmOd-3EEdlDT5aR4JH8G8PasWxRqnaEypUUtzAuXWAdCbqTQSYSHCihI3V4Psl2iirN7_48eDVwu5YveNFthucQQ=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/protest-4499802_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1074" class="wp-caption-text">Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/PlanetMallika-2152290/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=4499802" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/users/PlanetMallika-2152290/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D4499802&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGV-zTjJyQgqDMO1TlhYTuqu6J3Ww">PlanetMallika</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=4499802" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D4499802&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGPe7KdbNkLdcBcVIwDAtjzpbSiiw">Pixabay</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Millennials&#8211;and indeed anyone who has ever watched a movie&#8211;have realized pretty quick that real life is mimicking fiction right about now. Stories involving overthrowing tyrannical governments like <i>The Hunger Games</i>, or <i>Star Wars</i>, or even <i>Harry Potter</i> are all starting to feel eerily familiar. In fiction, it’s always easy to see who the heroes are&#8211;Katniss Everdeen…Luke Skywalker…Harry Potter. They’re the ones storming the castle, or leading the battle, or any other dramatic throw-down involving explosions and the glory of victory.</p>
<p>It’s been super easy for white people to look at these stories about underdogs fighting the system and go, <i>oh</i> <i>wow&#8211;a story about me and my struggles!</i> Which… sure, us white people have plenty of struggles&#8211;I mean, sometimes Target doesn&#8217;t have that strappy sundress in the size we need. The line at the DMV (pre-plague) is obnoxiously long. And sometimes&#8211;<i>sometimes</i>&#8211;the local organic market is completely out of kale. Quelle horreur.</p>
<p>Of course, this is not to say that white people have never had <i>personal</i> problems to deal with&#8211;but they’ve never been SYSTEMIC.</p>
<p>We have been conditioned to only see ourselves as the heroes in stories, even if the narrative itself doesn’t actually support <a href="http://www.lib.latrobe.edu.au/ojs/index.php/tlg/article/view/97/82%26lt%3B" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.lib.latrobe.edu.au/ojs/index.php/tlg/article/view/97/82%2526lt%253B&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF87eMvgDFfP_sVOj0iKWg00NrOsw">this</a>.</p>
<p>This is something that author Dr. Ebony Elizabeth Thomas talks about in her book <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/42129087-the-dark-fantastic" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/42129087-the-dark-fantastic&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFgfgbodpGj2RBi9X8qv59AOzybgg"><i>The Dark Fantastic: Race and the Imagination from Harry Potter to the Hunger Games.</i></a> After reading this work over the weekend, it has come to my attention that, fellow white people&#8211;we need to talk about Katniss.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1070" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1070" style="width: 209px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci6.googleusercontent.com/proxy/vzya-Jr3rkOLbmsVNauUs1khoV-u7iYTtq7zsXivelp-C_GNoBHaaMDd_y5gVOQQ21q4phy433uUFuTQC83bAgJTuQKw7RFucgN_8K4l3etCAjX22RXGgyjPKK32TAm_lkuss2WeVEFULERk0JQZCwNv2Bg=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-dark-fantastic-209x300.jpg" alt="" width="209" height="300" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1070" class="wp-caption-text"><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07JJGGZVG/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1&lt;/dd&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07JJGGZVG/ref%3Ddp-kindle-redirect?_encoding%3DUTF8%26btkr%3D1%5B/caption%5D&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEzQmaCxS-rhGiTvxglOZjhV7PHZA">https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07JJGGZVG/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;btkr=1</a></figcaption></figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="conversation-footer" class="spacer">
<p>The hero of the iconic YA series <i>The Hunger Games, </i>right? The Mockingjay, right? The leader of a revolution that ultimately dismantles an oppressive, tyrannical government, right?</p>
<p>Of <i>course</i> we want to relate to her. Of <i>course</i> we want to see ourselves as this headstrong, authentic girl fighting for justice in an unjust system. We can all clearly see that the Capitol (and the series antagonist President Snow) are morally corrupt, the system broken, benefiting only the privileged elite who are spared the violence of the Games. It’s exciting&#8211;inspiring, even&#8211;to see Katniss heroically lead the underdogs to climactic, cinematic victory.</p>
<p>But here’s the thing, fellow white people&#8211;we are not Katniss.</p>
<p>At best, we are the Capitol. At worst, we are President Snow himself.</p>
<p>Especially when we look at <i>The Hunger Games</i> film adaptation, where a white actress was cast as Katniss (who is <i>repeatedly</i> described as dark in comparison to her fair mother and sister) and the majority of the impoverished District 12 citizens are, for some reason, also white, it begs the question&#8211;exactly what conversation are we having about race here?</p>
<p>In <i>The Dark Fantastic,</i> Thomas mentions Rue, the young black girl who was murdered in the arena and whose death propels Katniss towards the heroism of becoming the Mockingjay, the symbol of rebellion against the Capitol. Thomas, as well as the Tumblr sources that she cites, assert that “the revolution really doesn’t start with Katniss. It starts with <i>Rue</i>.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_1071" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1071" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/WicthYTL6CFd8-89hh9hfce2hnKfBsYCNubw4Zx_2SXZYt6Qpw4yyCVFhvLgPZlYCeJ5aSjkGY4SES-b3HAYWBrdej_uydJWJP2z1Fm4lbWr-mmmvfLAzdFBAXpkHtkfadpFUeQ_45WL_I_iaC_AjIwzeXP7_5blU27573BK=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/the-hunger-games-811955_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1071" class="wp-caption-text">Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/Marco-willy-1078561/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=811955" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/users/Marco-willy-1078561/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D811955&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFAD5LdXmoz-hXjSPQIFQcQZs_0Ww">Marco-willy</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=811955" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D811955&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF7fWzfC1bDxcpij2go2JQt18wdcg">Pixabay</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>And it <i>does</i> start with Rue&#8211;when the innocent black child dies, the mantle of savior is picked up by the white (or read-as-white) hero, the one the audience is meant to identify with. The story then shifts its focus to Katniss, whose sympathetic reaction to Rue’s death inspires the (white) Districts to begin rioting against the Capitol.</p>
<p>Wow, white people taking it upon themselves to violently and dramatically act out under the guise of wanting justice for a murdered black person when really just wanting an excuse to cause a ruckus because it’s a fun break from the status quo? Preposterous, THAT would NEVER happen in real life.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci6.googleusercontent.com/proxy/QCs2Tf6GNrgOndAf-vhx_ORkyRZ21ydXqncnjT48lsbrQZ91zH0nYyucRfhqWl4IUj85T1dVnfUJliD3BzTqtW0-rmp75XmfpqsYiYG8GHoVdCuFboyGAyTGNQsmHrN-EKuKvIZPdAcfg4dku71efimU1q0reTa_SYlKeDhBZsO0c_XHhx1oV9vFJLo7=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Eugene-riot-Eugene-Police-Dept.-530-860x588-300x205.jpg" alt="https://ktvz.com/news/oregon-northwest/2020/05/30/eugene-protest-turns-violent-rioters-destroy-several-businesses/" width="300" height="205" /> <a href="https://ktvz.com/news/oregon-northwest/2020/05/30/eugene-protest-turns-violent-rioters-destroy-several-businesses/[/caption]">https://ktvz.com/news/oregon-northwest/2020/05/30/eugene-protest-turns-violent-rioters-destroy-several-businesses/[/caption]</a>[/caption]It’s become obvious how we, as white consumers of stories of rebellion, have fully misunderstood and appropriated this particular struggle.Breaking free from oppression is a struggle that we have never and will never experience&#8211;and yet, it’s the kind of story that we keep coming back to in our books and movies and D&amp;D fantasies.</p>
<p>So how can we train ourselves to de-center ourselves from the narrative? To step back and allow ourselves to become supporting characters, background players, characters that exist to serve the narrative of others, instead of the other way around?</p>
<p>The first step is to understand that this is <i>real</i>. What is happening outside our window is not fantasy, not fiction, not a chance for us to play-act revolution like it’s a LARP-ing convention.</p>
<p>The second is to acknowledge and respect our place as extras in this narrative, using the resources available to us to uplift the voices of black communities <a href="https://www.charisbooksandmore.com/understanding-and-dismantling-racism-booklist-white-readers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.charisbooksandmore.com/understanding-and-dismantling-racism-booklist-white-readers&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHYm75W-o_gMVHiX5O8CuH7dcVRdw">instead</a>.</p>
<p>The third is to put our money (and time) where our mouths are&#8211;crack open that <a href="https://www.nylon.com/life/black-people-with-disabilities-donations-resources?fbclid=IwAR2DZ69XqR71_xHCIC2zu29r4Sg8MLkVrMEWynLt68uss-SEEalqDZqbdCg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.nylon.com/life/black-people-with-disabilities-donations-resources?fbclid%3DIwAR2DZ69XqR71_xHCIC2zu29r4Sg8MLkVrMEWynLt68uss-SEEalqDZqbdCg&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF3KkXtA5ZgxP_-pxGJLxg00G45iQ">wallet</a>, expedite that carpal tunnel by signing <a href="https://twitter.com/danielsleftoe/status/1269447624957890561" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://twitter.com/danielsleftoe/status/1269447624957890561&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313236000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHd375-Zozg3ErxSi8GYJ3arYj2ZA">petitions</a> and writing <a href="https://sayitagain.carrd.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://sayitagain.carrd.co/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313237000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHmERTzb-5n_g8CGTa-8DRV6xX2qA">emails</a>, educate our fellow <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/booksblog/2020/jun/03/do-the-work-an-anti-racist-reading-list-layla-f-saad?fbclid=IwAR0K06fqd6wiPHjbQJlJXLLYhD0AoCASLEyjf1KsNOP-mJnNIIhjn0AXet0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.theguardian.com/books/booksblog/2020/jun/03/do-the-work-an-anti-racist-reading-list-layla-f-saad?fbclid%3DIwAR0K06fqd6wiPHjbQJlJXLLYhD0AoCASLEyjf1KsNOP-mJnNIIhjn0AXet0&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313237000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEET8p1Me7dRkzTAHScgb9qOLtxag">white</a> people when possible (mayhaps through an overly preachy blog post) and sit down and shut the fuck up the rest of the time.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/BalVXIUb5WmvQiPJrSOJr9-n1qrbpfckSDwQuoT5Fnf1bIs1Vvz05AisSfvqEKwXdB2ASy_VD6eC_wyqVrh9108WnaLi1m177qtA6JMGFFIWuc3DhZZTtbo6710rIESIihPW1WVr6C-9rwOqkgiGUywUUwnX_7QJTbgOldahjhtC=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/black-lives-matter-1011597_1920-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" />Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/bmartinseattle-208305/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=1011597" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/users/bmartinseattle-208305/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D1011597&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313237000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHPWWS6oPYfJTDNXhjMkDqjRIel_g">Betty Martin</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=1011597" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D1011597&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1591812313237000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGWsA_EwMkmZE3WpiJjhI6mKXwFtQ">Pixabay</a></p>
<p>The longstanding white supremacy involved in nearly 100% of the stories we were exposed to growing up has provided us with delusions of heroism, with fantasies of glorious rebellions that were Definitely Meant For Us Because Isn’t Everything. But the biases of publishing have failed us, just as it’s failed the black voices that have fought to have their stories heard.</p>
<p>Black lives matter. Not just in fiction, where black kids should be able to see themselves represented and allow themselves the beauty of imagination and magic that white kids have had handed to them. But they matter <i>here</i>, in reality, where a revolution is forming, where those leading the charge are those that fiction has not allowed in this role.</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t get cookies for doing this. We don’t get to make this story about us, heroically stepping aside for the black people to take center stage. Contrary to the content of this entire blog post, this is not.</p>
<p>About.</p>
<p>Us.</p>
<p>So we need to show up. Shut up. And don’t take selfies.</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;ve Got White in My Ledger&#8211;and I&#8217;d Like to Wipe it Out</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ive-got-white-in-my-ledger-and-id-like-to-wipe-it-out/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ive-got-white-in-my-ledger-and-id-like-to-wipe-it-out/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annacatalano]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 10:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=18106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There are six hundred projects I should be working on, and I’m doing exactly none&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="m-3817946980322757042" class="mail-message expanded">
<div class="mail-message-header spacer"></div>
<div class="mail-message-content collapsible zoom-normal mail-show-images ">
<div class="clear">
<div dir="ltr">
<p>There are six hundred projects I should be working on, and I’m doing exactly none of them. Instead, I’ve chosen to procrastinate by focusing on the Pandora’s box opened in my last <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/male-as-default-getting-better-at-writing-women-when-you-are-a-women/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://2f5.f93.mwp.accessdomain.com/male-as-default-getting-better-at-writing-women-when-you-are-a-women/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912884000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHea8JxD-ZCafVhCrx9lMSIPbBygg">blog post</a>&#8211;where I discovered a truly shocking lack of female characters in my writing.</p>
<p>Never one to procrastinate halfway, I decide to delve deeper into my writing history to see what other blind spots have surely developed over the years. Perhaps a quick jaunt down Memory Lane would lend insight as to just how deep my inherent biases go.</p>
<p>Because there’s no way <i>this</i> goes wrong.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1056" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1056" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci3.googleusercontent.com/proxy/wHB3lnoUNOo7uGgu77Y_nL0diZx8CF-lcEX7lOR33dTWjxfVSrR8e-C7i2MBbTbVLIYHNIDqM0RkfKJDjJ8M8kRoFHu83hLD8p3qjoVjcVcbPHUQw8JHD6uDKNDxNQ_eY9kvHYSyssdSoqhfziyKe1dcr9NIbzM=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/directory-281478_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1056" class="wp-caption-text">Come with me, and you&#8217;ll be, in a world of pure indoctrination Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/geralt-9301/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=281478" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/users/geralt-9301/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D281478&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912884000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHNnMSFFQViDH_A7wMFspMg1BAmKQ">Gerd Altmann</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=281478" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D281478&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912884000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGTVshNbgVr6OoIsTTOvyiPESB6iw">Pixabay</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Making elaborate lists is one of my favorite things to do, especially when procrastinating, so I open up approximately forty tabs (rip my laptop CPU) containing every story/novel/anything project finished, started, or just brainstormed, then scoot on over to Google Sheets to make an organized, color-coded ledger.</p>
<p>I want to cover as many bases as possible&#8211;if I’m gonna drag myself on the internet for the sake of education, let’s not cut any corners. This time I’m not just looking at female characters represented, but at white characters vs non-white ones, degrees of ableness, and the spectrum of gender identity and sexual orientation. This is an experiment, and I want the largest possible sample size, so I’m including every character I’ve ever written.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1058" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1058" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/blYuoeTYAkzua_oBUGlSbQuBFJVzL_34ERGyYmV6_rHDz8OS7dOwruefgqtFsfwQ6ZhzemT8s2vlCNciSZVLM71GKhQ6hmJMqwQBjUGX_YOYRMU3UxdCLtPsV0iHnn-Ag-hx5VaTQiPW-7p6BrH7BHTi_d9Usg8CFf4BpoaIzLf147p64Ti9Enm8R0D8Es26AMkWrDNr1flRgD8RixD5PQ=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/strict-female-teacher-with-book-pointing-at-scribbled-3771074-300x192.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="192" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1058" class="wp-caption-text">This is what organization looks like, trust me, I&#8217;m a professional Photo by Andrea Piacquadio from Pexels</figcaption></figure>
<p>A half an hour later and, reader, the results were…harrowing.</p>
<p>While as an upside there was a 49:9 ratio of queer characters to straight ones, there was still a <i>significant</i> absence of inclusion on the disability/neurodivergence/non-white/female characters front.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1057" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1057" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci6.googleusercontent.com/proxy/DVohUorSI8KS0-hnPzUELAqpATpX8vbOu7hpiWsuNfMSTUvVzvQ5kw3mZrLXji_LvN2IC25QSAcjCvx9KfUpqBOa5gbMQRMxR29-ClCqGvFMUv-2bSPUnncxvmXF5l7agNWa5O9U7z4kmWrp6amQxyVCQ7tyqyA=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/ecstatic-2821540_1920-300x300.png" alt="" width="300" height="300" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1057" class="wp-caption-text">A candid shot of me, gaping in horror at the lack of diversity that my hands hath wrought Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/mohamed_hassan-5229782/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=2821540" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/users/mohamed_hassan-5229782/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D2821540&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912884000&amp;usg=AFQjCNG1DBx1gcg1JhIxEcAu02B95DQUrg">mohamed Hassan</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=2821540" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D2821540&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912884000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHQKZ-h5UAC78dsBOEp_2UsTirqqQ">Pixabay</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Which I guess makes sense, considering that I grew up exclusively around white people (with the brewing internalized misogyny still piping hot on the stove). Everywhere I looked, there was a certain image of what I believed the world to look like at that time, and that image was not very, shall we say, colorful.</p>
<p>But that isn’t the reality of how the world looks to me anymore. Which makes the existence of so many instances of subliminal heteronormativity and white supremacy so totally unacceptable at this juncture.</p>
<p><i>Speaking of the devil&#8211;</i></p>
<p>IT’S JUST WRITING WHAT YOU KNOW! Like a Kraken summoned from the deep, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/hetpat-the-anxiety-demon-an-unfortunate-introduction/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://2f5.f93.mwp.accessdomain.com/hetpat-the-anxiety-demon-an-unfortunate-introduction/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912884000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFQSUx15Zw7Eiy3COFe6N3JNZ0VYg">HetPat</a> crawls his way out of my mind swamp to share his unsolicited two-cents. WE ALREADY AGREED THAT THAT’S WHAT’S EASIEST FOR WRITING! YOU’RE WHITE, SO YOU KNOW YOU CAN WRITE THAT! IF TRYING TO WRITE CHARACTERS OF COLOR CAUSES ANXIETY THEN ALL THE MORE REASON TO NOT DO IT! THEN YOU DON’T HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT MESSING IT UP! YOU WON&#8217;T BE ABLE TO FOCUS IF YOU&#8217;RE STRESSED, SO DON&#8217;T FRET ABOUT IT! JUST DO WHAT COMES NATURALLY AND EVERYTHING WILL BE FINE!</p>
<p>As if Mr. Personification of the Patriarchy and My Anxiety has ever cared about my well-being in literally any capacity.</p>
<p>Here’s the thing&#8211;I don’t need an imaginary demon in my head to tell me that it’s easier to write characters who look like me, with similar life experiences. That’s 100% the reason why my subconscious falls back on what’s safe, and comfortable, and familiar.</p>
<p>But that doesn’t make it a good reason&#8211;especially considering how hard I’ve worked to avoid slipping back into those bad habits.</p>
<p>Making a fairly comprehensive ledger lampshading the diversity I’ve included in my writing and seeing (in full color-coded glory) where, specifically, the problem areas lie, has been a concrete step towards holding myself accountable in avoiding white-able-male-centric narratives.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1053" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1053" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci5.googleusercontent.com/proxy/5SO_aPGg7X5DtgDzTSuvJwpXwrldezv1TdIP_Wjr5MpHRqV_a17hZjdqyM3o7lPhmuAaZz8F_vSLW41QQ57eA7A2_eNwrzVTwCGATR_KfeyTkUYa-EhX6Bwcsm_3w6DKYcpgVNMPoD9Sm9JaoglRZvIA968=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/adult-1851571_1920-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1053" class="wp-caption-text">Behold, a whiteable man, able to white perfectly on command Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/Pexels-2286921/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=1851571" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/users/Pexels-2286921/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D1851571&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912884000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE5OqagTmTSN_CXjdn6-46ZorAFtQ">Pexels</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=1851571" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D1851571&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912884000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFsm2Ix41cIClUWDSrgJsFus8_BCw">Pixabay</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>Honestly, when divided by project and exact numbers, it’s not quite as dire as it seems on the surface&#8211;the most egregious lack of diversity appears in the first novel series that I began working on back in 2011, where all 7/7 characters that I wrote were all male and white.</p>
<p>I know this isn&#8217;t diversity bingo, or Pokemon Go&#8211;gotta catch &#8217;em all&#8211;because obviously the solution is not a forced diversity checklist when crafting characters. But in follow-up projects, particularly recent ones, the casts are significantly more balanced in terms of male vs female and white vs non-white characters.</p>
<p>Which I suppose is encouraging, because that means that even if I continue to overthink my entire process&#8211;with HetPat throwing up barriers faster than I can tear them down&#8211;progress is slowly but surely coming along.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1060" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1060" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://ci3.googleusercontent.com/proxy/rL5Y0YeYkeb9fmoBZnOejOJfIgecZts8kXcLJU_N7m5WWHJbyvgVnSKzcKPnKK_Q-wV1jlaULM8m7_ZCXQ5rhLGAsHmcAXWiwZ5Pmik1976Rk1g0a78yWYKxLTW-SIfi7vBig1D8aSvjs76iaFn5FkPx_Vgl=s0-d-e1-ft#http://lunastationpress.com/submissions/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/success-479568_1920-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1060" class="wp-caption-text">Image by <a href="https://pixabay.com/users/geralt-9301/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=479568" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/users/geralt-9301/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D479568&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912885000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEfCO0csxSWMf3YLdgIXN-XMmYfXg">Gerd Altmann</a> from <a href="https://pixabay.com/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=479568" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pixabay.com/?utm_source%3Dlink-attribution%26utm_medium%3Dreferral%26utm_campaign%3Dimage%26utm_content%3D479568&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912885000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEKQAkliUlJZdAo4pMmJnxoy43vNg">Pixabay</a></figcaption></figure>
<p>And as for messing it up&#8211;of <i>course</i> I’m more hyper-aware now that every inclusion of a marginalized identity (especially one that is not my own) is a slippery slope of an opportunity to accidentally cause harm. But at least there’s an abundance of <a href="https://writingwithcolor.tumblr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://writingwithcolor.tumblr.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1589845912885000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFWWA3YDGvTf-DFtpTBfc3HVp3ocA">resources </a>out there to help avoid this as much as possible&#8211;and obviously, surrounding myself with people who embody the diverseness of the world has been essential in looking inward and going <i>hey, look at what you’ve missed out on!</i></p>
<p>HetPat is a chaotic, wildly unhelpful presence in nearly every aspect of my life, but maybe there is something to be said for the anxiety surrounding my desire to portray diversity in fiction. But the answer is not to fall back into false safety by not attempting it, or to allow myself to be incapacitated by the fear of getting it wrong. I didn’t make it this far just to keep painting inaccurate pictures of the world when I know now how much variety exists around and in me.</p>
<p>I’ve been so much happier since figuring out that the world is not nearly as <i>blah</i> as I was meant to believe.</p>
<p>I guess sometimes all you need is an Excel spreadsheet to help make sense of the world.</p>
<p>Or, at the very least, help get your head out of your own ass.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/ive-got-white-in-my-ledger-and-id-like-to-wipe-it-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Male as Default—Getting Better at Writing Women When You ARE a Women</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/male-as-default-getting-better-at-writing-women-when-you-are-a-women/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/male-as-default-getting-better-at-writing-women-when-you-are-a-women/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[annacatalano]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 10:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Ongoing Exorcism of the Demon HetPat]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My work-in-progress is the first book of a fantasy series that I&#8217;ve been grappling with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17927 aligncenter" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/unnamed-300x186.png" alt="" width="300" height="186" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/unnamed-300x186.png 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/unnamed.png 512w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />My work-in-progress is the first book of a fantasy series that I&#8217;ve been grappling with for close to six long and arduous years. It features an ensemble, queer cast of various ethnicities and degrees of ableness having magical, morally questionable adventures with plenty of romantic tension and intrigue befitting my Brand. It was my first foray into writing novels independently, and I was far enough into my twenties and my quest to be Woke that I was sufficiently optimistic about my efforts to incorporate more diversity in my work.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">On approximately the fifty-millionth time staring at the first couple of god-forsaken chapters of said novel, I suddenly realized something that, in hindsight, should&#8217;ve been obvious.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">There were. Entirely. Too many men.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_17930" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17930" style="width: 200px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-17930" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/eye-15699_1920-200x300-1.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17930" class="wp-caption-text">Searching for the female representation in my novel</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Queer men of varying backgrounds. But still men. And hardly any women. In my book that I was aiming to be diverse.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">So. I realized that the only way forward was to change the gender of one of my leads. The trouble with this brilliant solution was that my brain was suddenly eating itself in the struggle to adjust to the change.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">My history with writing male vs female characters has been a roller coaster ever since I was a wee, squishy cheeked bab just starting out on my writing journey. During my elementary and middle school years, I wrote plenty of women&#8211;though they were inauthentic and problematic caricatures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">But then, somewhere in the realm of high school heading into college&#8230;I very suddenly stopped creative writing, and didn&#8217;t pick it up again until midway through college. And by then, most of the characters I wrote were overwhelmingly male.</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400">Why did this happen?</span></i></p>
<figure id="attachment_17931" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17931" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-17931" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/adult-1854191_1920-300x200-1.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17931" class="wp-caption-text">Behold, a diversity</figcaption></figure>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/hetpat-the-anxiety-demon-an-unfortunate-introduction/"><span style="font-weight: 400">HetPat</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400">&#8211;the anxiety demon and resident paragon of the patriarchy who lives in my head and likes to shout at me&#8211;has some ideas.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">MALE CHARACTERS ARE MORE INTERESTING AND DYNAMIC AND MULTIFACETED THAN WOMEN! AND THEY&#8217;LL BE EASIER TO WRITE! YOU&#8217;VE BEEN DOING JUST FINE WITH THE MEN UNTIL NOW! IF IT AIN&#8217;T BROKE, DON&#8217;T FIX IT!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">And there&#8217;s the shameful bit&#8211;I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">do</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> prefer writing male characters. I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">do</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> find it easier. I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">do</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> find them easier to connect with. I feel like, deep down, there&#8217;s a reason why, consciously or not, most characters are male as the default before I have to go out of my way to change that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">So&#8230; mayhaps it IS broke.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Maybe it&#8217;s just an ingrained assumption, or something I heard once, but I keep coming back to this idea that writing women should, by all reason, come naturally to me, a woman.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">But if you think about it&#8211;why </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">would</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> it? Why would it come naturally to me to write a woman when I can&#8217;t even be sure how much of my own identity was predetermined for me? How much is manufactured and how much is authentic? How am I supposed to even tell the difference?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">At the end of the day, it&#8217;s not so much about writing what I know&#8211;it&#8217;s far more accurate to say that I&#8217;ve been writing what I&#8217;ve read. Case in point&#8211;Harry Potter notwithstanding&#8211;the vast majority of authors on my bookshelf growing up were male. And indeed&#8211;Harry Potter </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">with</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400">standing&#8211;even the books written by women tended to focus on male protagonists. So in terms of a guidebook on How to Write Women Good, I didn&#8217;t exactly have much to go on during my formative years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">So back to my work-in-progress, and my newly appointed female character. She&#8217;s a warrior, a physically strong and skilled fighter. Her body is covered in scars from her time in battle, her motivations revolving around her loyalty to her family and sense of justice&#8211;all of which are attributes still left over from her original iteration.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">AND YOU KNOW THAT READERS ARE GOING TO EXPECT SOME SEXUAL ABUSE IN HER BACKSTORY NOW, DON&#8217;T YOU? EVEN IF YOU DON&#8217;T WRITE IT, THEY&#8217;LL THINK IT&#8211;OOH, LIKE A PAVOLOVIAN RESPONSE!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">More on </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">that</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> in a future post, as I keep fighting the knee-jerk idea that women&#8217;s backstories need to involve abuse to be valid. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">I don&#8217;t even want to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400">disclose</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400"> the amount of time spent suddenly wondering if I had to totally rewrite my character’s backstory, now that she&#8217;s a woman. And this isn&#8217;t the first or last time this has happened&#8211;I once spent the better part of two hours brainstorming a female, genderbent retelling of a literary classic and found myself furious at how I was completely unable to think of a motive for her, as I was convinced that it had to be different from when she was a man.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">As if her woman-ness is something that now needs to be the main element in her story.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_17932" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-17932" style="width: 300px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-17932 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/makeup-brush-1761648_1920-300x200-1.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-17932" class="wp-caption-text">Get those women some makeup, women love makeup</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">This internalized misogyny still creeps in unannounced from time to time, with HetPat hollering wildly in the background, a hypersexist PowerPoint presentation at the ready. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Maybe that&#8217;s what&#8217;s so frustrating&#8211;that it&#8217;s so easy to recognize the shortcomings and pitfalls of men trying to write female characters and failing to capture nuance, but it&#8217;s harder to recognize (or indeed, remedy) in female writers&#8230;in ourselves.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">And though I know this will be an ongoing struggle for me going forward in my writing, I guess that being aware of my own shortcomings and harmful fallbacks is a step in the right direction.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400">Maybe then I can write an ensemble fantasy&#8211;a genre that should be unfettered by modern biases&#8211;where I can imagine that someone like me exists. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/male-as-default-getting-better-at-writing-women-when-you-are-a-women/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
