<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 036 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-036/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:11:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 036 Author Interview: Mariah Montoya and &#8220;Death&#8217;s Armchair by the Sea&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-036-author-interview-mariah-montoya-and-deaths-armchair-by-the-sea-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 11:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 036]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re back with another Issue 036 author interview. This week we&#8217;ve chatted with Mariah Montoya&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/leonardo-yip-1015708-unsplash.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12879 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/leonardo-yip-1015708-unsplash-240x300.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="300" /></a>We&#8217;re back with another <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-036/">Issue 036</a> author interview. This week we&#8217;ve chatted with Mariah Montoya about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/deaths-armchair-by-the-sea/">Death&#8217;s Armchair by the Sea</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: How did you decide on the different, nontraditional forms Death took on throughout the story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mariah: Whenever death is personified, it always seems to be a ghostly male figure with a black hood. I was bored with this. I’m always interested in seeing women representations of traditionally male roles, and Death seemed like an intriguing female character to start with.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Living to 105 out of sheer willpower is quite a task. What inspired you to create a character like Matilda?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mariah: I’ve heard some extraordinary stories about people whose mindsets kept them going even when deterioration or death seemed physically inevitable. I think the mind is capable of so many things. Also, my narrator needed to witness someone clinging to life with every fiber of her being in order to appreciate just how beautiful and fragile life is.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There are countless takes on what happens after we die. How did you come up with the concept of dutiful grim reapers who gently take souls to a motherly Death?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mariah: I had some family members on the verge of death – after writing this story, they did end up passing – and I wanted to envision more than just a light for them. A sweet embrace and gentle arms to carry them onward felt right.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the hardest part about writing this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mariah: I was advised to reduce the number of characters (specifically to combine the characters of Matilda and Layla) so that readers would not get so confused or overwhelmed with the number of names and souls in such a short story. But the more I started to revise, the more I realized it didn’t feel right. I was not trying to explore the relationship between my narrator, a “runner” for Death, and a lone human. I simply wanted to explore what death might be like if people embraced it rather than feared it, and for this exploration, I needed a handful of different scenarios. It was hard to show how the accumulation of these souls, not just one stubborn woman, touched and changed my narrator.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></p>
<p>Mariah: I am indeed working on another project right now, a cohesive collection of fairy tale retellings set in a world where technology, myth, and magic intertwine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 036 Author Interview: Sarah McGill and &#8220;Down Among the Fireweed&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-036-author-interview-sarah-mcgill-and-down-among-the-fireweed-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 036]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Issue 036, the Crones issue, is up and out and walking around with thirteen&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/olenka-kotyk-75067-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12805 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/olenka-kotyk-75067-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-036/">Issue 036</a>, the Crones issue, is up and out and walking around with thirteen speculative fiction stories by women authors in its guts. Do go check it out, and pay close attention to Sarah McGill&#8217;s story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/down-among-the-fireweed/">Down Among the Fireweed</a>,&#8221; the subject of our interview today:</p>
<p><span class="im"><em><strong>LSQ: The style of this piece reads almost like a long poem. Is this the sort of style you usually write in? What do you like about it?</strong></em></span></p>
<p>Sarah: To write a story about a Jack o’ Lantern-type character, meeting the devil on the crossroads, and bad bargains, I needed a style that I hadn’t written in before. I wanted something that read like an old English ballad. When I read <a href="http://greergilman.com/ashes.html">Greer Gilman&#8217;s <em>Cloud and Ashes</em></a>, which passes between prose and iambic pentameter – she describes it as “dissolved pentameter, half water and half ice” – I was completely taken by it. I love lush, almost impossible styles and Gilman’s is mythic, rooted, and ruddy. The rhymes and cadence give her stories an archaic, spell-like quality, which greatly influenced how I approached telling “Down Among the Fireweed.” If anyone’s telling this story, it’s Tom Scratch and this is how he’d tell it – with a focus on words, winter, and liminality.<br />
<span class="im"><br />
<em><strong>LSQ: This issue’s theme is “crones.” Is there anything in particular that drew you to this topic?</strong></em></span></p>
<p>Sarah: To me, the style of this story demanded bargains, cold roads at night, and crones. While Marjorie physically fills the role of &#8216;crone&#8217;, what’s more crone-ish about the story is the way it feels. This story is about death, witchcraft, isolation, and those who wait on dark forest paths. It&#8217;s also about people with the wisdom and experience to accept their mistakes and those who do not.  The idea of cronehood loomed over the story and worked its way in like hoarfrost in the earth.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story? What was the hardest part?</strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: The rhyming was both the hardest and my favorite part. This is not a straightforward style and sometimes I had to choose <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/colton-sturgeon-1142896-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12806 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/colton-sturgeon-1142896-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>between imagery and clarity. I especially spent a lot of time reworking dialogue where I needed to convey a specific idea, retain the cadence, and end with a specific rhyme.</p>
<p>But I love what the rhymes allow me to convey. Each character has a rhyme: Tom&#8217;s is &#8216;scratch,&#8217; Marjorie&#8217;s &#8216;weave,&#8217; and Jack struggles to hold onto any particular rhyme, although he relies mostly on &#8216;chain.&#8217; Characters use rhymes to control the conversation and as soon as a character uses another character’s rhyme, they’ve given in. Tom Scratch is a trickster and all about bargains and words, so the moment another character uses his rhyme, they’re in a lot of trouble. And since this story is all about words, Tom is always in control because this is his element. Jack&#8217;s rhyme is not nearly as strong and he lacks control all the way through. The rhymes also allowed me to surround a character with a set of words – like in film how characters are given musical themes that morph and break and reassemble. Marjorie in particular has a lot of lovely, witchy words &#8211; cleave, leave, deceive, sheaves.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any writers who have influenced your work?</strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: Greer Gilman, without who’s work I never would have found the right style and imagery for this story. Catherynne Valente, who’s work showed me how in fantasy an author can take an insubstantial idea – like the fear of death, the cyclical nature of time, and comfort – and crystallize them into physical objects or phenomena that can be touched and explored. And I would be remiss if I didn’t also name Rachel Swirsky, Sofia Samatar, Anne Carson, and Margo Lanagan.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 036 Author Interview: Stuti Telidevara and &#8220;The Last Evening at Prosperity&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-036-author-interview-stuti-telidevara-and-the-last-evening-at-prosperity-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 21:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 036]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Issue 036 continues to rock and roll. We&#8217;re excited to share with you today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/ibrahim-rifath-787042-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12744 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/ibrahim-rifath-787042-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>Our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-036/">Issue 036</a> continues to rock and roll. We&#8217;re excited to share with you today a chat we had with author Stuti Telidevara about her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-last-evening-at-prosperity/">The Last Evening at Prosperity.</a>&#8221;</p>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The world you’ve crafted is full of magic but unfolds through context clues rather than being overly explained. What are the benefits of this kind of world building? Do you have any world building tips to share?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Stuti: I actually prefer to read . . . let&#8217;s call it implicit world building? I think that allows the reader to pick up details on their own. When I read stories and settings like that, it makes me feel like the author isn&#8217;t underestimating my intelligence. It also makes more sense that when you&#8217;re in a character&#8217;s head — even if it&#8217;s limited rather than deep POV — that the character wouldn&#8217;t be spelling out every facet of their own world in their narration. I actually think of it as the same way I&#8217;d think of writing about my own culture. If your audience was people unfamiliar with the culture, then you might have to explain <em>everything</em>. If your audience was exclusively people familiar with it, then you would explain very little. Implicit world building sits somewhere in the middle, where you can let some things just sit in the text without pointing them out, but you do give the reader the context they need. Then over the course of your story or novel, it&#8217;s like you&#8217;re pulling the reader closer into the fictional culture or world.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I&#8217;m still working on perfecting this in my own writing, but I think the most important thing is to resist the urge every author has to include and explain every world building detail in the text itself. Sometimes not remarking on a detail has the effect of making it seem normal to the narrator, and so that implies it&#8217;s normal to the setting. I have an example within &#8220;The Last Evening&#8221; that I had to stop myself from emphasizing: in the very beginning of the story, Jaya wraps a towel around her waist, and that was very intentional, suggesting how her culture thinks about bodies and especially women&#8217;s bodies. I have an outtakes document that describes every food at every stage of the Prosperity process, and its significance. Only with world building do I take the &#8220;less is more&#8221; approach; if my writer friends tell me they don&#8217;t understand something or need more information, <i>then</i> I&#8217;ll add it in during revision.</div>
<div></div>
<div>This story is very much inspired by Indian history and early British rule in India, when the East India Company was consolidating territories and spreading its way through the land by treaty rather than war. (Well, at first.) So there are some references to that end — the shah, the company, little tidbits that people familiar with Indian history will pick up — but again, I had to make sure that I wasn&#8217;t shouting about it into the reader&#8217;s ear, so to speak.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What made you decide to make Jaya, an older woman, be the protagonist of this story rather than someone younger like Bo?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Stuti: Part of this is going to be a bad answer. Jaya popped into my head because I was thinking specifically of the &#8220;Crones&#8221; theme for this issue! I find that characters come to me not fully formed, but carrying some essence that I want to expand on. My main characters tend not to be the spunky, confident type — at least, not at the start of the story. So I knew the narrator for this story was someone who was uncertain, caught between passivity and action, and Jaya was that character from the get go. I don&#8217;t think I could write from Bo&#8217;s perspective without sounding totally hokey and one-dimensional.</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong><em>LSQ:</em> Where do you see these characters going after the conclusion? Will we be seeing more of them in the future, do you think?</strong></div>
<div></div>
<div>Stuti: You know the sense that wars tilt one way and then the next? This is definitely the bit where the invaders have the advantage, so while I don&#8217;t have a sense of what <i>exactly</i> happens, it probably doesn&#8217;t end too well for the townspeople. Which feels so bad to say, I grew really attached to Jaya and Kiren! But I am playing around with another idea set in the same world. I know that the story will take place physically far away, but I haven&#8217;t figured out the timeline yet, so there might be a rebellious fire-wielder cameo . . .</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: If you were capable of small-magic, what would it be?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Stuti: I have taken multiple personality questions to see what element I&#8217;d be most comfortable in, and the answers were <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cristian-newman-43777-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12745 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cristian-newman-43777-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a>tragically inconclusive. But I think I&#8217;d have a very practical, unmagical small-magic, which would be good for my ego. I&#8217;m great with names and faces, so maybe that&#8217;s my small-magic.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Stuti: Figuring out the story&#8217;s overall direction, really. I didn&#8217;t know how it would end when I started it, which is rare for me. And I pieced together the setting while I drafted, too — I&#8217;m a very visual writer, so I need to have a concrete vision for my setting. I fiddled around on <a href="https://pin.it/kiqjgzszkkqyz3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://pin.it/kiqjgzszkkqyz3&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1543852578118000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE8KxIuVXqNm6CHDxCERUGWWMcQcQ">Pinterest</a> for an obscene amount of time. (I discovered in the process that it&#8217;s <i>so</i> hard to find the right images of older brown women. That was not surprising, but pretty upsetting.) I also did some (very casual) research about the progress of colonialism in India, which is always interesting — and devastating — to read about.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 036 Author Interview: Maya Dworsky and &#8220;Bog Witch&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-036-author-interview-maya-dworsky-and-bog-witch-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 036]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We love our Issue 036 stories so much, we could go on about them forever.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We love our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-036/">Issue 036</a> stories so much, we could go on about them forever. But we&#8217;d prefer to let our authors do that themselves! Today we continue our interviews with Maya Dworsky, about her reality-shaping story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/bog-witch/">Bog Witch</a>&#8220;:</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/nathan-dumlao-1183239-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12684 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/nathan-dumlao-1183239-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>LSQ: This is such a timely story, what with the whisper network of women actively rejecting their patriarchy. Did this idea come to you recently, or is it something that’s been brewing for a long time?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Maya: Cue Feminist Rant a.k.a. You Brought This on Yourselves&#8230;</p>
<p dir="ltr">To me, the Bog Witch is about ideology more than anything else. Ideology is like the eucalyptus tree; it grows stronger by poisoning the ground around it so nothing else can grow. It has previously been acknowledged (most often condescendingly) by powerful men that while they allegedly decide where society is headed, it is often women who get us there. That is to say, while men and their institutions make the rules, so to speak, women are given the choice of whether or not to pass them on to the next generation. So, we get the future, while they get Now.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It’s been Now for a really long time. In fact, it kind of seems like it’s always Now.</p>
<p dir="ltr">By promising us an inevitable transformation option we are lulled into a complacency that successfully obscures our possibilities right here, in this neverending present. What Taterra, my bog witch, succeeds in doing is changing the present, as well as the future of her little mudball moon by using the same subversive tactic naively offered to her by the patriarchy — imagination. Taterra doesn’t just imagine a future, she helps other women imagine that their present is different. That their present is changeable. That Now is what you make of it.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: What inspired you to have an older protagonist, a “bog witch,” rather than someone younger?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Maya: I’ve always enjoyed playing with the ‘witch’ trope and its natural overlap with the scientist, almost as much as I liked the idea of my magical prophecy-born prince being the result of an experiment conducted by a social scientist from a different world. The combination of a young protagonist plus an older magical mentor is a staple of both fantasy and Sci Fi works, so I figured I could not only subvert the traditional gender of the pair but also reverse whose perspective it might be told from.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: If you could magically believe something into existence, what would that be?</strong></em></p>
<div>Maya: Right this moment? Ice cream. Any other day it’d be World Peace, but you caught me at a weird time.</div>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The ending of this story does not have finality. What do you see Dr. Taterra Myshtaq and Prince Bartholomew getting up to in the future?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Maya: Okay, you got me. Both Taterra and Prince Bartholomew hail from a much longer work of mine — specifically a series titled “The HuMan Prince” in which their world of Yereyoch is menaced not only by Bartholomew’s father, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/robson-hatsukami-morgan-134754-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignright wp-image-12685 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/robson-hatsukami-morgan-134754-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>the king of Hu, but also by Charles Lioness, Taterra’s former lover and, technically, the owner of the former prison moon. Needless to say that adventure, romance, and general questing ensues. While the story is told from multiple perspectives, Taterra’s has always been a particularly fun one from which to write.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Maya: Like most writers I have a few balls in the air at all times. I am currently seeking publication for a YA novel titled Clothilde, which takes place a long time from now in the Historical City State of Jerusalem. Beneath the city, in the Well of Souls, the last prophet of Earth leaves a message for Lyla Shavit, a draft-dodging, hard-drinking, saxophone-playing high-school dropout. There’s telepathy, space monks, depressing Middle Eastern geopolitics and all that jazz.</p>
<p dir="ltr">My true love, however, is middle-grade, and I am currently working on a children’s book called Passover Knight in which a Jewish eighth-grader chooses to become a knight. There are dragons, princesses, and AP Bio pop-quizzes, as well as lessons to be learned about friendship, courage, and toxic masculinity. There’s also a talking horse named Stasheff who has a lot of opinions about Science Fiction tropes.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Then of course there’s that pesky dissertation…..</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 036 Author Interview: Laura Duerr and &#8220;Transcripts of Tapes. . . &#8220;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-036-author-interview-laura-duerr-and-transcripts-of-tapes-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 036]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you still savoring our Issue 036??? We certainly are &#8212; it is delicious. Which&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/justin-greene-137326-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12671 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/justin-greene-137326-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Are you still savoring our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-036/">Issue 036</a>??? We certainly are &#8212; it is <em>delicious</em>. Which is one main reason we&#8217;re here today to share with you all our recent chat with Issue 036 author Laura Duerr about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/transcripts-of-tapes-found-near-the-depot-06-45/">Transcripts of Tapes Found Near the Depot, 06-45</a>.&#8221; Please go enjoy Laura&#8217;s story and our interview below!</p>
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The structure of this story would make for an excellent podcast. Is that something you have, or would ever, consider?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>Laura: I have actually had two stories come to life as podcasts. It&#8217;s a much different experience as an author to hear your words, rather than just read them &#8211; it was a little nerve-racking, to be honest! But it&#8217;s incredible to hear how a narrator interprets the phrasing, the voice, etc., and I&#8217;d absolutely love to hear Linda&#8217;s voice out loud.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: An old woman keeping a farm by herself isn’t exactly the quintessential face of an apocalypse survivor. Where did you get the idea for your protagonist?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>
<div>Laura: Linda and her farm come from many different sources. I&#8217;ve spent a lot of time driving through the Willamette Valley and out to the Oregon coast, and I always wondered about the lives of the people who work on the farms and vineyards I&#8217;d pass by. Linda talks very much like a Portland-area woman I used to work with &#8211; no one messed with her, and it was always entertaining to overhear her profanity-laced phone calls. As for Linda&#8217;s age, I get a little tired of teenage protagonists (despite working on a book about one myself), and after seeing the clan of biker grandmas in &#8220;Mad Max: Fury Road,&#8221; I never got over the idea of tough-as-nails old ladies bucking expectations. I also have to give credit to Grandma Ben from the &#8220;Bone&#8221; comics and Judi Dench&#8217;s M in the Bond movies.</div>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">But even more important than her toughness is Linda’s capacity for kindness. She’s absolutely entitled to keep her flourishing little farm a secret, but instead she goes through a lot of effort to share her resources with others who might need them. Even though it puts her at risk &#8211; and people do actually try to take advantage of her generosity, in the form of the gang members attacking her farm &#8211; it never occurs to her to not try to build this community. I hope people see that when they read the story: we all need to get there together.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: “They never wanted to change.” That line, as well as Linda’s remarks about how one woman’s eco-friendly efforts were nothing compared to the carbon footprint of corporations, really hit home. What can we, the regular folks, do in the face of such an imminent climate crisis?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>
<div>Laura: Call your representatives. Write to your representatives. Tweet your representatives. Send balloons to your <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/christopher-windus-87387-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12672 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/christopher-windus-87387-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>representatives. Okay, not the last one, but seriously, our elected officials are the ones who have the power to enact the changes our world needs. On the other hand, don&#8217;t give up on the little things you&#8217;re doing to help. Those matter, too, and no one should feel useless or ineffective for doing them! What I&#8217;ve had to do is come to terms with the fact that I can&#8217;t save the world alone (I know, right?) and that the best I can do is to give my time or resources to those in a position to do the world-saving, whether that&#8217;s candidates or nonprofits, while also recognizing that the little things I do still have value. Every reusable bag and thermos counts &#8211; but yeah, find and contact your representatives.</div>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Just when all hope seems to be lost for Linda, it rains. Why is the promise of hope so important in post-apocalyptic stories?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>
<div>Laura: The promise of hope is important in everything. There&#8217;s a line in <em>The Rewind Files</em> by Claire Willett that goes, &#8220;Why do we do what we do if not for the belief that the future can be changed?&#8221; Our own world can look pretty post-apocalyptic at times, with climate crises, refugees fleeing wars and corruption, and poverty and oppression in our own cities. If we don&#8217;t have hope in our own lives, we&#8217;ll burn out. What I love most about science fiction, including the post-apocalyptic genre, is its ability to tell us truths through a different lens, and the truth I try to tell in all of my stories, even and perhaps especially the post-apocalyptic ones, is about hope. We can have all the grit in the world, but if we don’t have an image of hope before us as a goal, we’ll run out of strength.</div>
</div>
<div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<p><em><strong><span class="im">LSQ: </span>What was your favorite part about writing this story?</strong></em></p>
<div dir="auto">Laura: The structure was really fun to play with. Originally I had sound effects and notes like [unintelligible] to emphasize that these are, as the title says, transcripts, but I ended up liking the immediacy of Linda’s story in the form it’s published. The reader is freer to guess on when these tapes were actually found and transcribed, and by whom. The ending of <em>The Handmaid’s Tale</em> (spoiler alert?) does something similar, revealing that the whole story was found via tapes, but the story itself doesn’t give any clue that Offred’s experience isn’t happening in real time. The reader doesn’t get any kind of catharsis from the fact that Gilead no longer exists because Offred’s fate remains unknown. Ultimately Linda’s fate is unknown, too, but I think it’s easier in this iteration of the story to imagine her finding a happy ending.</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 036 Author Interview: Leonie Skye and &#8220;Francie&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-036-author-interview-leonie-skye-and-francie-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 11:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 036]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rejoice, dear readers, it&#8217;s our first author interview of 2019! Issue 036 has been out&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rejoice, dear readers, it&#8217;s our first author interview of 2019! <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-036/">Issue 036</a> has been out for about a month now, and it still has thirteen amazing crone-themed stories for your eyeballs. Why not try Leonie Skye&#8217;s &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/francie/">Francie</a>,&#8221; and then follow up here for her answers to our burning questions.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The concept of the American Dame and grown women buying and pampering their mini-me dolls made me think a bit of the American Girl franchise. Was any inspiration gathered from this source?</strong></em></p>
<p>Leonie: Yes, definitely in terms of the all-encompassing nature of the services and themes and stories provided in that retail setting. I’ve probably only been in one of those stores once. I have a-four-year old daughter who was recently given an American Girl doll. She immediately stripped it and gave all the clothes and accessories to her stuffed pig who can more or less fit in them. The doll has been lying bereft and almost naked for weeks in a corner <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/adult-art-blue-312591.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12495 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/adult-art-blue-312591-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>where my daughter left her. I’ve always been sort of curious about human-doll interactions, so I’m waiting to see if my daughter rediscovers the doll. I tried to imagine what such a retail situation would look like for older women. It wouldn’t be necessarily what older women want, but what the market wants them to want.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The extremely life-like description and personality of Francie made me feel a bit concerned that she&#8217;d turn evil. . . perhaps I&#8217;ve been burned by the likes of the </strong></em><strong>Child&#8217;s Play</strong><em><strong> movies. A practically living and benevolent doll—where did this idea come from?</strong></em></p>
<p>Leonie: I had been reflecting a lot on the experiences of women at mid-life because that’s where I am right now. There aren’t a ton of pop cultural guides for women in mid- life in the form of movies or TV that feel authentic to me. It’s a time of change, obviously. One day I had this overwhelming urge to sort of&#8230; it’s hard to explain, but I guess take control of myself as a child would take control of a doll, experimenting with it, dressing it, taking it out on adventures, giving it different identities each day.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: On the topic of life-like dolls, exactly how life-like is Francie? Dose she eat? How organic is she? Or are these details better left to the reader&#8217;s imagination?</strong></em></p>
<p>Leonie: I’d like to leave that to the reader’s imagination. But it’s interesting, I’ve had other reviewers want to know exactly how she functions. Is it magic? Is she a robot, some kind of A.I.? Practical functioning didn’t occur to me while I was writing it.</p>
<p><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/baby-child-concrete-floor-207923.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12496 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/baby-child-concrete-floor-207923-300x209.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="209" /></a>LSQ: The concept of dolls as having a role greater than a plaything is certainly explored in this story. Can you comment on that?</strong></em></p>
<p>Leonie: Dolls have lots of different roles in different societies. They can be doubles, constructed to attract bad luck and thereby keep it away from the owner. They can have religious uses. And they can be involved in children’s development. I don’t know that Francie isn’t a plaything. Adults like to think they aren’t playing, but you could probably argue for a theory about human life and development that says that all we’re doing is playing up until the day we die.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Do you think there would be a market for the American Dame in our current universe?</strong></em></p>
<p>Leonie: I fear that there might be.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging aspect about writing this story and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Leonie: Actually, I wrote this really fast. It’s probably the fastest a story has ever flowed out of me. I don’t know why. But I suppose whenever a story involves the death of a loved one, or two deaths in this case, it can be stressful.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Leonie: I’m in a novel-writing workshop right now trying to wrestle a novel into publishable shape. It’s an epic secondary world fantasy about a fraudulent deity, a young woman sold by her family to blindly enable a takeover of her own culture. It’s about how she figures this out, all the terrible things that have been done in her name, and what she does about it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 036 Author Interview: Regina Higgins and &#8220;Wise Woman&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-036-author-interview-regina-higgins-and-wise-woman-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 036]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tired of Issue 036 yet? Neither are we! Here&#8217;s another interview with one of our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tired of <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-036/">Issue 036</a> yet? Neither are we! Here&#8217;s another interview with one of our lovely authors, Regina Higgins, about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/wise-woman/">Wise Woman</a>.&#8221; Be sure to give it a read before moving on to the Q&amp;A.</p>
<div><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/lucky-machine-999956_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12358 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/lucky-machine-999956_1920-225x300.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a>LSQ: Let’s start with the obvious: Mildred is awesome! What was your inspiration behind her character? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Regina: I love Mildred, too! She’s every older woman in our lives who’s incredibly gifted and generous with those gifts. We all know them, don’t we?</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The trial scene holds tension, as it could lead to Mildred’s demise, but there’s also an element of humor brought by the young Councilman that makes it seem a bit farcical. What were your thoughts when writing this scene? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Regina: I thought there’s always someone—no matter what the situation—who thinks it’s all about him. And it’s usually “him.”  Head-smacking stupid. But, invariably, it becomes part of whatever’s happening.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The story opens in first person perspective, but switches to third person for the rest of the story. Is there a perspective you prefer, or one you find has particular benefits over the other?  </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Regina: I love including many perspectives in a story. All perspectives have particular benefits, and switching from one to another enriches a story. I love reading stories with different perspectives. Kate Atkinson (<em>Life After Life</em>) is a genius at multiple perspectives. She’s one of my favorite writers.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The setting seems to be a women-focused world, yet Agnes easily betrays Mildred. Do you think the world of this story, and our own world, can ever truly achieve solidarity among women? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Regina: The setting is a very small woman-focused community in a man-focused world. We’ve got plenty of those communities. And none is perfect, because people aren’t perfect. I wouldn’t say Agnes “easily” betrays Mildred.  Agnes—and everyone else—has known for a long time that she’s far below Mildred in magical abilities. I imagine this is a continual gall to Agnes. And then when Agnes thinks she sees evidence of Mildred cheating, it’s too much for her.  She makes her accusation. But when Agnes is convinced she’s been mistaken, she withdraws the charge of cheating, and she’s contrite. Still, it didn’t have to be this way. If Agnes had asked Mildred for help with her magic, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cup-829527_1920.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12359 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/cup-829527_1920-300x201.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="201" /></a>Mildred, being Mildred, would have supported and taught her beautifully. But Agnes doesn’t ask for help. She just stews by herself and bubbles over with spite. So the potential for solidarity is there, but Agnes can’t reach out and be part of it. Maybe her experience of the trial will change her for the better.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Regina: I’m working on a novel featuring a young woman in the American West in the late nineteenth century. She’s so tough, Billy the Kid is <i>her </i>side-kick.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 036 Author Interview: Anna Catalano and &#8220;Cry Sanctuary&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-036-author-interview-anna-catalano-and-cry-sanctuary-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 11:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 036]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Issue 036 is out and lovely and we&#8217;re here today to share a chat we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/helena-lopes-459331-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12331 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/helena-lopes-459331-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-036/">Issue 036</a> is out and lovely and we&#8217;re here today to share a chat we had with Issue 036 author Anna Catalano about her story &#8220;Cry Sanctuary.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The ability to make things disappear/reappear at will is a skill I think a lot of people would covet, but then likely use for selfish reasons. In your story, the characters use these powers for good. What made you marry this concept with this character type? What does this say about Reina, Ethan, and Nua?</strong></em></p>
<div>Anna: The twist that each of the characters developed magic powers was actually something that wasn&#8217;t intended from the start. It was only when I was envisioning the final confrontation at the end that I had the image of Reina kind of zapping Josiah out of existence. From there, everything clicked into place for the other characters as well, and it became clear that each of their particular abilities corresponded with the specific kind of abuse they had suffered.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Over the course of the story, the characters&#8217; powers are used for good in the sense that they served to keep their little found-family together. For me, it was important to show that these characters needed each other. As for the future, who&#8217;s to say how their abilities are used—I didn&#8217;t want to take any particular stance that any survivors of abuse will either A) always be kind and selfless and sit on a morally pure pedestal or B) lash out and continue the cycle of violence. I can&#8217;t speak for other situations (as everyone, real or fictional, is different), or how these characters will behave in the future. But for right now, it was their priority to help whomever they could.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: There is a lot of tough subject matter in this story. What was the most challenging part of this story to write and why? What was the most enjoyable aspect? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Anna: The most challenging part of writing this story was the portrayal of abuse, and wanting to make sure I didn&#8217;t unintentionally misrepresent or treat that theme lightly. The writing process was heavy and emotionally draining, but it was a story that I knew I wanted to tell. But through that, what I found most enjoyable was seeing each individual magic ability manifest in the story, as well as the chemistry between the main gang when they&#8217;re talking and bantering among themselves.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: How much about the background of these characters, especially Tuppy, do you know? What was the final straw that made Tuppy leave her home situation? </strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Anna: I know the vague basics about the background of the supporting cast, though I know the most about <span id="m_-3121834159176184149:d4.1">Tuppy</span> as of right now. In regards to what made her decide to finally leave, I don&#8217;t necessarily think it was any one particular incident. We know that fairly recently Josiah lashed out violently and bruised her arm, but based on the time it would&#8217;ve taken for <span id="m_-3121834159176184149:d4.2">Tuppy</span> to build up a secret stash of escape money, she was likely considering all the details of a possible escape for maybe a couple of months before the story begins. I believe that at this point in her narrative, anything could have been the straw that broke the camel&#8217;s back—she&#8217;d spent so many years with this building and building inside her, and I personally think it took some time for her to even realize just how bad the situation had become.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: This story breathes a hopeful tone into some dire situations. How do you think readers can take your story and apply it to similar situations they may know about or identify with?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Anna: With a story with subject matter as heavy as this, I did want to leave it on a hopeful note, especially since none of the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/joshua-newton-275881-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12332 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/joshua-newton-275881-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a>characters have to struggle alone anymore. Since I&#8217;ve never personally experienced anything close to what these characters have, I don&#8217;t feel like I&#8217;m in a position to give much advice to people who might be struggling with similar situations in the real world. But if there&#8217;s anything that I had hoped might be a take-away from this story is that you are not alone. There are others who are dealing with the same (or similar) things, and there is only strength in asking for or accepting help.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Do you know from where your characters received their powers or do you prefer to leave this a mystery, even to yourself?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Anna: I always intended the characters&#8217; powers to be magical realism, as I have no idea how they would have originated, especially in ways that are so personal and specific for each character. In my opinion, the origin of the abilities is not particularly the point, but I definitely understand if anyone feels like speculating on that just for fun!</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Anna: This past year, my main project has been working on the second draft and revision of a fantasy novel. The story follows a diverse group of misfits who must band together to save a cursed prince from a fate worse than death. There&#8217;s magic, snarky characters with gray morality, and a whole lot of angst. I also have several other fantasy novels in the works, some new short stories, and a few experimental projects that I&#8217;m not sure the genre of yet. While I enjoy toying with different genres and not committing to one specific one, all my stories feature diverse casts, existential philosophical questions, and a hint of romance.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 036 Author Interview: Elizabeth Hinckley and &#8220;Butterflies&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-036-author-interview-elizabeth-hinckley-and-butterflies-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 036]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thirteen stories, thirteen authors, and we have interviews with each and every one! Let&#8217;s continue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thirteen stories, thirteen authors, and we have interviews with each and every one! Let&#8217;s continue the fun today with Elizabeth Hinckley as she answers our questions about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/butterflies/">Butterflies</a>&#8221; which can be found in <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-036/">Issue 036</a>.</p>
<p><em><strong><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/karina-vorozheeva-666315-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12298 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/karina-vorozheeva-666315-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>LSQ: Your story contains beautiful but tragic descriptions about the demise of our pollinators and the impact that has on the ecology and, ultimately, on us. Do you have a background or interest in entomology or climate change? Did you have to do research in order to write this piece?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I’m actually a naturalist and environmental educator, so the environmental and science stuff is already part of my knowledge base. But I always like to do research on even the smallest factual aspects of my fiction because, aside from the imaginative or speculative aspects of a story, I feel a responsibility to represent things accurately. For example, we might take for granted that roads are always driveable, but if you consider that in a forest, a dead tree falls down from time to time, then you must consider that they sometimes fall on a road and there must be someone there to clear it. If you never think about trees, and you never think about road workers, then the apocalypse is going to be extra hard on you. So I researched strange things like what happens to infrastructure, pandemics, and the tech we might be likely to have a few decades from now, as well as just fact-checking my ecological details.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The topic of technology is touched on early in your story, as the narrator grows up and her parents impart a limited allowance of its use. How does this translate into your own view of the ubiquitous nature of smart phones, etc., in our current daily lives?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I accept technology as part of our lives and am grateful for the many ways it has helped society.  Thanks to technology, I didn’t die from a disease I never got because of a vaccine, and I can watch eagles raise a brood on a webcam.  But like many advances before our current ones, technologies are only as good or bad as the intentions behind them. It raises questions about our reliance on things we don’t need, but that’s an old story, the same as TV or conveniences people have invented in the past, and people adapt and eventually make their choices on it.  What really concerns me is social media and too much interconnectivity—it’s very addictive, it erodes privacy and civil discourse, and puts a lot of power in the hands of, well, anyone who wants to exploit people’s desires and tendencies. There are lots of people with vested interests in your attention and consumer dollars working very hard to make sure you keep clicking.  I don’t think it’s particularly healthy, especially in a world where people have more knowledge at their fingertips than at any other time, but can’t tell a squirrel from a chipmunk and are afraid to go outside. (Those are real life examples.) For myself, I don’t use social media and since I started drastically limiting my time spent online, I feel like my life opened up so much more.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There&#8217;s a moment in the story where the narrator remarks on the unexpectedly non-violent meetings of Others compared to what is typically portrayed in other post-apocalyptic stories. I found this refreshing and unique as a reader (and a bit meta!). What made you choose this &#8220;friendlier&#8221; version?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I’m so glad you liked that—I really wanted to do something different there that rang true and wasn’t just wishful thinking.  Part of fiction’s job is to examine the human condition, and stories that deal with violent or depressing reactions of people to terrible situations reflect possibilities that can and do happen.  Those explorations are valid. But I also feel that there’s a possibility that people who are frightened, humbled, or suffering can go the opposite way. Tragedy can uncover the best in people. I saw it with my own eyes in Hurricane Sandy. There are individuals and even entire cultures who can and do make a choice to come together and protect each other when times are tough.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: How closely do you identify with Lucy? What was it like to narrate the story from her eyes?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: It was important for me that Lucy was a good scientist—rational, intelligent, and self sufficient—to endow her with credibility. Passion inspires devotion, but credibility inspires respect. Compared to Lucy, I am more openly heart-centered and intuitive, where she is pragmatic and reserved. I mean, I’ve earned my own intellectual chops and achievements too, which is how I’m able to understand her, but I think that she is definitely more introverted. Like a<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/elijah-o-donnell-715864-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12299 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/elijah-o-donnell-715864-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a> lot of bright  people, she has less patience for people in general, who don’t see things as quickly as she does. She also has passion that bubbles up, and uncovering the depths of her emotions rounded her into a more whole and balanced person.  There’s a worthwhile journey in revealing those things, rather than just displaying them outright. I feel almost like I could see her heart better than she would be able to herself, at least in her younger and middle years. She embodies the things I cultivate in myself—credibility as well as passion—just in different recipes.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Have you written other post-apocalyptic or &#8220;cli-fi&#8221; stories? What made you choose this sub-genre? Were there any authors or books in these sub-genres that you used for inspiration?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I’m a little embarrassed to say I had to find out what Cli-Fi is, but now that I know, I’m glad that there are other people writing on these kinds of themes.  So I didn’t choose this sub-genre so much as I chose the story I had to tell right now. The inspiration came on me powerfully and and I <i>had</i> to put it down—which is usually why I write about a particular idea in the first place. This story came to me as an exploration of love and grief at what I know about things happening to the natural world—and to us.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></p>
<p>Elizabeth: I’ve been working on my second novel for a while. It’s inspired by anthropology, spirit, and the otherness of the outsider. I really loved my first novel, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29081999-david-a-rat?ac=1&amp;from_search=true"><i>David, A Rat</i></a>, because it flowed out of my heart so easily. This one scares me a bit because sometimes I don’t know my new characters yet the way I knew David—I knew him as well as a real person. That tells me to wait and learn about who they are, what they want, and what they need to say and do, so it’s probably going to take a while. I’m also working on a natural reference book that combines scientific and spiritual study of the natural world—animals, plants, habitats, and the like. I’m a STEM advocate interested in science and critical thinking, as well as a person who values the intuitive and spiritual connection with the natural world. Science and spirit are often seen as opposites, but I think they are just different ways of exploring the world. And short stories and essays tend to pop up and feverishly push my larger projects out of the way—&#8221;Butterflies&#8221; was one of those.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 036 Author Interview: Artyv K and &#8220;A Handful of Mud&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-036-author-interview-artyv-k-and-a-handful-of-mud-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 036]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We have 13 speculative fiction short stories by women authors in Issue 036 so that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/kyle-ellefson-196125-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12301 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/kyle-ellefson-196125-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a>We have 13 speculative fiction short stories by women authors in <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-036/">Issue 036</a> so that means 13 author interviews! Here&#8217;s one with Artyv K about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/a-handful-of-mud/">A Handful of Mud.</a>&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The relationships both daughters have with their grandmother are very different, presumably based on their age. Can you speak to the complex relationship between Dana and her grandmother?</strong></em></p>
<p>Artyv: They do have an interesting dynamic. Mtra, the younger of the sisters, is the blank canvas. The one who is impressionable, the dreamy child both the grandmother and elder sister are trying so hard to persuade over to their side. On the other hand, the reason why Dana and her grandmother have a more complex relationship is because these are two central figures who act outside the norm of their expected roles. Dana serves as the voice of the critic, the Freudian <em>super ego</em> to the grandmother’s <em>id</em>. She is level headed for her age, a devil’s advocate and more measured in how she navigates changes in her young life while her grandmother, the <em>mipaati</em>, remains impulsive and reckless, not exactly the sort of role model Dana wants to emulate. I was trying to create a subversion in the archetypes of the ‘Old Woman’ and the ‘Child’.</p>
<p><em><strong>L</strong><strong>SQ: The grandmother is described as a hoarder. Do you think in a way she is trying to hang onto the past?</strong></em></p>
<p>Artyv: That’s true. The children have no memories of the past. But their grandmother does, and she remembers the past so intimately. She misses it and wants to turn back time to how things used to be: clean, unpolluted and most importantly, free. A time when humankind could plant a seed and have the luxury to watch it grow before their very eyes. A time when their food didn’t descend from the unknown and they had the choice to eat what they liked. As I understand, there are two kinds of hoarders— the thrifty, practical kind and then, there are ones who attach sentiment to objects, trying to draw out the length of memories. Dana’s grandmother would be the latter kind. Her clothes, her motley of hoarded trinkets and even her grudge are all a physical manifestation of her longing for the old days.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The symbolism of the mud &#8212; its many uses and possibilities &#8212; and the choice to use it to grow a seed is rich in your piece. Why did you choose mud? Where did this idea come from?</strong></em></p>
<p>Artyv: I was pottering about my plants one day. Quite literally. I was shifting them about, changing their pots and weeding <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/markus-spiske-502390-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12302 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/markus-spiske-502390-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>out the grass that had found their way in. In the beginning, I tried to use a spade to uproot them but noticed how the edge was cutting off some delicate roots. So, in the end, I decided to use my hand to scoop the plants out. There is something oddly edifying about holding mud in your hand. Mud gets so little credit despite being a life giver.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: It&#8217;s impossible as a reader to not get swept up in the grandmother&#8217;s excitement and ambitiousness regarding her germinating seed. How were you able to maintain the momentum and suspense in this story? What was the most challenging aspect of it to write and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Artyv: One way to maintain the momentum is to leave out details and exposition, which take away from the crux of the theme. Instead, the focus was solely on character personalities, conversation dynamics, events, and their repercussions. The most challenging aspect in writing ‘A Handful of Mud’ was to set this story in a place which is close to my heart and my home, and then to walk the line between capturing the uniqueness of the culture and to somehow keep it universally relatable.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The ending, of course, could have gone a hundred different ways. What made you choose this particular ending? Mtra&#8217;s observation in the last line gives a bit of dark humor and some levity, as younger children&#8217;s honest observations often do. Did you have this line planned out all along, or did it appear along the way?</strong></em></p>
<p>Artyv: Dashing of naïve dreams seemed to me the only way to go. Inevitably, it’s one of those harsh realities of life and a part of growing up. I was very particular about Mtra having the last say, and I especially wanted her to have that last line, because she is my blank canvas. Her judgement serves as an honest conclusion, and it also takes the story away from the two characters who inhabit a great part of it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
