<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lale Davidson &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/author/lale-davidson/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:18:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cosmic Cat</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/cosmic-cat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lale Davidson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Literary Fantastic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Science fiction appeals to creatures of all kinds. Daisy, an American Bobtail mixed breed cat,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p>Science fiction appeals to creatures of all kinds. Daisy, an American Bobtail mixed breed cat, watches the opening of season three of <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt3230854/"><em>The Expanse</em></a><em>, </em>based on the novels by James S. A. Corey about a future where few have the privilege to still live on Earth, and where most of the population mines for water in an orbiting dust belt. Daisy is one of the smartest cats I&#8217;ve ever had the pleasure to live with, so if she likes something, you should pay attention.</p>
<p><iframe title="Cosmic Cat" width="730" height="411" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7KvkNclNXa4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>I adopted Daisy from the local animal shelter when she was still nursing kittens. She was a teen mother. When not stalking birds and other unsuspecting prey, she follows me around the house indoors and out, jumping into the middle of whatever I&#8217;m doing and tilting her head quizzically as if to say, &#8220;Whatcha doing, Hooman?&#8221; She&#8217;s the only cat I know who can purr and growl simultaneously. She can be a bit of a bitch, which only intensifies her allure. She occasionally watches TV but has discerning tastes. It seems to run in the family, because her son, Merlin, who was adopted by a friend, also tries to catch the pictures. Cats were one of the few creatures H.P. Lovecraft loved, and he portrayed them as the walkers between worlds.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strong Female Protagonists</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/strong-female-protagonists/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lale Davidson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 11:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Literary Fantastic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More than ever before, badass female protagonists populate book and screen.  From Lara Croft, to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than ever before, badass female protagonists populate book and screen.  From Lara Croft, to Black Widow, to Katniss Everdeen, they kick butt. In America, the message seems to be that true power is only gained by brute force and coercion, so women can only be powerful if they are young, beautiful, and fight like a man.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.kijjohnson.com/">Kij Johnson</a>’s poetic <a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9780765391414"><i>The Dream-Quest of Vellitt Boe </i></a>shows female power in a refreshingly different way<i>. </i>It’s not every day that you read a sci-fi adventure novel with a sixty-something-year-old female protagonist. Vellitt Boe is <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/johannes-plenio-782754-unsplash.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11954 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/johannes-plenio-782754-unsplash-300x195.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="195" /></a>quiet, careful, and wise—and her body aches after a long hike. Nevertheless, her goal is achieved, and her strength is expressed in her mentorship of a younger woman. That which has been stereotyped as feminine weakness is revealed in this novella as revolutionary power.</p>
<p>In the mystery genre, there is slim precedence for elderly protagonists whose only weapon in the apprehension of criminals is intelligence. Take <i>Murder, She Wrote</i> on TV and Agatha Christie’s <i>Miss Marple</i> series.  However, I can’t think of a single elderly female protagonist out for adventure in science fiction. Let me know if you can.</p>
<p>Johnson, who was born in 1950 and is a professor at the University of Kansas, explains in an interview for <a href="https://geeksguideshow.com/2016/08/14/ggg217-kij-johnson/"><i>The Geeks Guide to the Galaxy</i></a> that this novella was written in response to  H. P. Lovecraft’s <i>The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath, </i>which has no women in it at all. She asked herself, “What happens to [the male fictional] world if I put females in it? Does it break it?”</p>
<p>Some of my students didn’t want to read the book, fearing an angry feminist critique of Lovecraft and all men, but what we found, instead, was a gentle assertion of female-centered conflict and a main character who uses other forms of power: intelligence, kindness, and patience.</p>
<p>The premise of the novella is that a gifted female college student in Dreamland has thrown away her future to run off with a man to the waking world. Because the education of women is threatened in this male-dominated world, her teacher Vellitt Boe and her Dean determine she must be retrieved before it causes a scandal and the college is shut down. When the Dean proposes to send a man who has the advantage of being both young and—well—a man, Vellitt Boe convinces the Dean that her own knowledge and her power of persuasion are more important to the success of the mission than physical prowess: “We need her to <i>listen</i>, to understand what is at risk…”</p>
<p>The plot thickens when Vellitt discovers that the girl is the granddaughter of a god. The gods in this Lovecraft’s Dreamland are cruel, petty, and beyond random. If he discovers she is gone, he might raze the entire city in which the college resides.</p>
<p>Though she has to use a machete once or twice, it is primarily the power of patience, wit, clear sight, and compassion that save Vellitt from the murderous shantak birds and ghasts. In a feat reminiscent of the Greek myth of Psyche with the ants helping to complete her insurmountable tasks, Vellitt’s tears when she is trapped are tracked abroad by millipedes, and this draws to her rescue a monster gug whom she saved when it was an infant. Thus, Velitt’s compassion in the past bears fruit in the form of an enormous life-saving gug.</p>
<p>If great power comes in subtle forms, so does great danger. In the climax before she breaks into the waking world, Vellitt’s greatest obstacle is not Dreamland’s violence, but doubt, which arrives in the form of a violet-eyed god who tells her that her city, Ulthar, has already been destroyed and her quest failed. Again, Vellitt’s power is not brutal <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/drop-the-label-movement-668213-unsplash.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-12555 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/drop-the-label-movement-668213-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>strength, but strength of character as well as reason: “You cannot stop me,” she tells the god. “If you could, I would be dead already…and if Ulthar were truly destroyed, you would have brought me visions and shown me relics.  You are just a shadow here. You have no power”.</p>
<p>Turning yet another stereotype on its head, Clarie Jurat, the object of Vellitt’s quest, has already fallen out of love with the man she followed to the waking world by the time Vellitt catches up to her. Clarie has discovered on her own that she really didn’t crave the man’s love but rather the expansive world to which he belongs. Women have historically been associated with the unconscious and intuitive – i.e. the Dreamworld, whereas men represent the active, external world, so Clarie’s realization of her own true intent – her desire to leave the interior realm of the unconscious and live abroad in the active realm shows a woman in true possession of her power.</p>
<p>Johnson continues to highlight a subtler form of power in the last turn of the plot. Vellitt convinces Clarie to return not by forceful argument but by providing Clarie with the facts and then just…waiting. Awfully passive for a heroine. However, her waiting is really trust of her student’s higher nature. Rather than coercing, she respects the independence and intelligence of her student. This form of power is based on mutual respect, and has a revolutionary effect.</p>
<p>When Clarie realizes that the fate of an entire city rests on her decision, she vows to return. Not just another woman sacrificing herself for others, Clarie vows she will change Dreamland and fight the capricious cruelty of the gods: “I have seen a world without gods, and it’s better…I will return and fix our world…I am one of them. I can do it.&#8221; “Do you doubt me?” she asks Vellitt. “No,” Vellitt says. “No.” Transcendently, Clarie laughs and “for a moment it seemed as though the little house was filled with thunder and the earth beneath them shuddered”.</p>
<p>Thus, Kij Johnson’s feminist approach doesn’t tear down Lovecraft’s world, but augments it by adding women to it. While she points to how women are ignored and disapproved of in a man’s world, her protagonist shows how women are powerful on their own terms.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">References</span>:</p>
<p>“Interview: Kij Johnson.” <i>Geeks Guide to the Galaxy</i> with David Barr Kirtley. <i>Lightspeed Magazine</i>. January 2017 (Issue 80). <a href="http://www.lightspeedmagazine.com/authors/geeks-guide-to-the-galaxy/">http://www.lightspeedmagazine.com/authors/geeks-guide-to-the-galaxy/</a></p>
<p>Johnson, Kij. <i>The Dream-Quest of Vellitt Boe</i>. A Tor.com Book Published by Tom Dhoerty Associates, LLC. 2016.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When the Quickening Quacks</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/when-the-quickening-quacks/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/when-the-quickening-quacks/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lale Davidson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Literary Fantastic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=12259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early in the morning, a chickadee sings outside my window, two notes: B flat to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/peter-lewis-491699-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-12260 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/peter-lewis-491699-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>Early in the morning, a chickadee sings outside my window, two notes: B flat to A flat. I don’t hear an answering call, and eventually, it moves down the street, the call getting fainter and fainter until it’s gone.</p>
<p>At some point, we all ask ourselves, why keep writing? When it’s going well, it can unravel problems, provide essential witness, and deliver a glow like nothing else. However, when it’s not going well, when the river has run dry, forcing ourselves to write feels like self-flagellation.</p>
<p>Why keep sending out our work? With so many amazing writers already out there, does the world REALLY need another one? Why not do what Emily Dickinson did, tie up our work with beautiful bits of ribbon, and hide it in a trunk?</p>
<p>Two quotes help in this situation, one from Mahatma Gandhi:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Whatever you do may seem insignificant, but it is very important that you do it.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The other comes from <a href="http://www.marthagraham.org/">Martha Graham</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>“There is a vitality, a life force, a quickening that is translated through you into action, and because there is only one of you in all time, this expression is unique. If you block it, it will never exist through any other medium and will be lost.”</p></blockquote>
<p>We write because it’s what our minds and hearts do, and to stifle the voice, to refuse to answer the call, is to be less than we were born to be.</p>
<p>Sometimes, though, when the quickening is just quacking, it’s okay to lay down that pen, and put aside that computer.</p>
<p>Roseann Bane, in her book <i><a href="https://baneofyourresistance.com/around-the-writers-block-book/">Around the Writers Block</a>,</i> reminds us that we go through of phases of writing, and in some phases, we aren’t writing at all, but gestating a new piece deep underground in that wordless place, or we are hibernating, while our creative stores are replenished. That’s when reading is a great thing to do.</p>
<p>The world of small presses and literary journals paints a very different picture of America than the one you find on TV &#8212; an America of intelligent, creative, and deeply caring people.</p>
<p>Birds sing to find their mates, wolves howl to find their pack, and we write and send out our work to find our tribe. In the process, we discover new voices, new species, new tribes we didn&#8217;t know we were already a part of.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/when-the-quickening-quacks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unraveling Lovecraft’s Dream-Quest</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/unraveling-lovecrafts-dream-quest/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lale Davidson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 11:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Literary Fantastic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11952</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Does an overtly racist writer deserve the energy it takes to write about them? I’m&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/johannes-plenio-782754-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11954 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/johannes-plenio-782754-unsplash-300x195.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="195" /></a>Does an overtly racist writer deserve the energy it takes to write about them? I’m not sure. However, Kij Johnson’s <i>The Dream-Quest of Vellitt Boe</i>, based on Lovecraft’s <i>The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath,</i> obliged me to read him. Turns out, her interest in Lovecraft is timely, so this month, I’ll focus on Lovecraft, and next month I’ll focus on Nebula and Hugo award winning <a href="http://www.kijjohnson.com/">Kij Johnson</a>.</p>
<p>Lovecraft’s style in <i>The Dream-Quest</i> is annoying and boring. His prose is crammed with value-laden adjectives like<i> terrible, shocking, frightful</i>; his characters are flat and don’t evolve; there’s little dialogue, and there’s a lot of summarized action. Finally, he favors pretentiously and anachronistically twisted syntax.</p>
<p>Yet, when I enter Lovecraft’s land of “dream,” I feel like a person wading through a bog, sliding my foot along a hidden rail of oddly compelling, incomprehensible sense. His more polished stories remind me of Jorge Luis Borges.</p>
<p>The basic plot of <i>Dream-Quest </i>is that Randolph Carter (Lovecraft’s avatar) visits the land of “dream” and sees a “glorious” sunset city that fills him with “the pain of lost things and the maddening need to place [them] again.&#8221;</p>
<p>He prays to the gods of Kadath to go there, but they don’t answer him. He determines to go Kadath, “where no man has gone before,” to speak to its gods in person. What ensues are rambling encounters with Ghouls, Night-gaunts, Zoogs, and Gugs with no apparent progression.</p>
<p>Western Kentucky University scholar <a href="https://www.wku.edu/fsa/staff/tim_evans">Timothy Evans</a> asserts Lovecraft’s antiquarian travel writing is key to understanding his fiction. He idealized his white, New England heritage, and he despaired of science, industrialization, and modernism. He loved America’s colonial landscapes, seeing them as the “real America” (forget the indigenous). His greatest horror was immigration and “miscegenation.&#8221;</p>
<p>Alan Moore corroborates this in <i>The New Annotated H.P. Lovecraft</i>, where he urges us to see Lovecraft as a “barometer . . . of the fears . . . of the white, middle-class, heterosexual, Protestant-descended males” who were threatened by “the shifting power relationships . . . of the modern world.”</p>
<p>Sound familiar? Trump would seem to be a dumber, barely literate version of Lovecraft, engaging in absurd antics as he tries to rectify a nostalgic vision of “the great white America,” while populating the White House with Ghouls, Zoogs and Thugs. But I digress.</p>
<p>Evans asserts that while Lovecraft’s travel writing explores the light side of his antiquarianism, his fiction explores the dark side, which, in my estimation, might partially redeem his fiction.</p>
<p>Certainly, <i>Dream-Quest </i>is rife with bucolic landscapes rendered in misty-eyed wonder. The rejection of obsessive <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/katie-moum-446408-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11955 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/katie-moum-446408-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>antiquarianism is evident when Randolph Carter encounters King Kuranes, who has dreamed up a replica of old Cornwall. His warning that life in his fulfilled dream is actually unfulfilling suggests that Lovecraft – at least unconsciously—thought the same.</p>
<p>The fact that Randolph encounters ugly and dangerous creatures who kidnap, drug, and almost kill him supports Evans’ assertion of the dark side of antiquarianism, as does Randolph’s interview with the “crawling chaos” Nyarlathotep, at the end of the novel.</p>
<p>Nyarlathotep informs him (spoiler alert) that the city he seeks has always been his for the taking, for it is made of his childhood memories of New England. The gods of unknown Kadath have been hanging out there and that’s why they didn’t let him reclaim it. All he has to do is ride on a “monstrous” bird, alight among the gods, and remind them how beautiful their own Kadath is, thereby inducing them to leave his city.</p>
<p>It appears to be a trick when the bird flies him into chaos where he’ll certainly go mad.</p>
<p>The duality of cats and Ghouls, the only friendly creatures in the land of “dream,” who save his life, is yet more evidence of Evans’ assertion.</p>
<p>When I opened the window to let in my own cat, she paused on the threshold, the perfect embodiment of duality. Cats are wild but domestic, cuddly by day, killer by night, and they always pause on the threshold. In short, they make the perfect guides between worlds, thus serving as a touchstone for reality. A fan of cats, Lovecraft depicts them thus in many stories.</p>
<p>Dogs are also dualistic creatures, wild and tame, happy, silly human companions who nevertheless eat carrion and feces. So, too, Ghouls, described as having dog-like faces, “glibber” and “meep” rather adorably, considering they are cannibalistic zombies.</p>
<p>If we view both Randolph and King Kurane as monological, the fact that dualist Ghouls and cats save Randolph suggests Lovecraft sees resolution in the dualism. One more point for Evans.</p>
<p>Here’s where Evan’s interpretation ceases to work, though. Randolph, in the midst of being driven into madness, suddenly remembers he’s dreaming and can simply jump off the bird. Inexplicably&#8211;yet somehow consequently&#8211;the cosmos dies and is reborn.</p>
<p>Then two conflicting things happen: on the one hand, <i>maybe</i> the dream world becomes real (italics mine):</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;There was <i>a firmament</i> again…for through the unknown ultimate cycle had lived a thought and a vision of a dreamer’s boyhood, and now there were <i>re-made a waking world </i>and an old cherished <i>city to body</i> to justify these things…</p>
<p>&#8220;Randolf Carter had indeed descended at last the wide marmoreal flights to his marvelous city, for he was come again to the fair New England world that wrought him.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>On the other hand, he simply wakes up:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Randolph Carter leaped shoutingly awake within his Boston room…and <i>infinities away,</i> past the Gate of Deeper Slumber…the crawling chaos Nyarlathotep…taunted insolently the mild gods of earth whom he had snatched abruptly from their scented revels in the marvelous city.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>I must admit, I like the way Lovecraft’s prose deconstructs itself here, delivering and un-delivering a resolution at the same time by moving the dream into the real world, but characterizing the dream world as simultaneously “infinities away.” Jacques Derrida could have a field day.</p>
<p>Far from being a rejection of antiquarianism, the ending of <i>Dream-Quest</i> suggests that if you pursue your dream with the right consciousness and a few friends in the unconscious, you can turn fantasy into reality, and it’s worth a brush with death.</p>
<p>The contradictory and inscrutable ending makes it impossible to ascertain just exactly what the story means, which is perhaps the point of all stories, but most certainly this one.</p>
<p>That’s why, against all intention, I ended up liking it and look forward to rereading Kij Johnson’s <i>Dream-Quest of Vellit Boe </i>with it in mind.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">References</span>:</p>
<ol>
<li>Evans, Timothy H. “Tradition and Illusion: Antiquarianism, Tourism, and Horror in H. P. Lovecraft.” <i>Extrapolation</i>. Vol. 45, No. 3. by the University of Texas at Brownsville and Texas Southmost College. 2004.</li>
<li>Johnson, Kij. <i>The Dream-Quest of Vellitt Boe</i>. Tor.com. 2016.</li>
<li>Klinger, Leslie S. “Forward.” <i>The New Annotated H.P. Lovecraft</i>. Ed. Leslie S. Klinger. Liveright Publishing Corporation. 2014</li>
<li>Lovecraft, H.P. <i>The Dream-Quest of Unknown Kadath. </i>A Del Ray Book. Ballentine. 1990.</li>
<li>Moore, Alan. “Introduction.” <i>The New Annotated H.P. Lovecraft</i>. Ed. Leslie S. Klinger. Liveright Publishing Corporation. 2014</li>
<li>Rottensteiner, Franz. “Lovecraft as Philosopher.” <i>Science Fiction Studies,</i> March 1992, Vol. 19, p117-121.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;The Potbellied Virgin&#8221; by Alicia Yánez Cossío</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-potbellied-virgin-by-alicia-yanez-cossio/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lale Davidson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 10:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Literary Fantastic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11723</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One interesting characteristic of Latin American magic realism is that it often rejects the European&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/chandler-hilken-633198-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11725 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/chandler-hilken-633198-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>One interesting characteristic of Latin American magic realism is that it often rejects the European and North American literary legacy of unified narratives. Unified narratives can sometimes unintentionally promote the hegemony of one class and culture. <i>The Potbellied Virgin</i>, written by Ecuador’s Alicia Yánez Cossío in 1985 and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Potbellied-Virgin-American-Literature-Translation/dp/0292714106">translated into English</a> in 2006, is an interesting example of a communal narrative. The reading experience is fascinating though disorienting for a mind trained in North America or Europe.</p>
<p>Although <a href="https://ecuadorfiction.com/alicia-yanez-cossio">Alicia Yánez Cossío</a> is one of the better-known authors in Ecuador, only two of her books have been translated into English and she is virtually unknown in the United States. <i>The Potbellied Virgin </i>provides a social history of Ecuador between 1900 and 1970, blending voices of the indigenous, the Catholic Church, descendants of the ruling Spanish aristocracy, Marxist revolutionaries, and the military.</p>
<p>The plot revolves around a wooden statue of the Virgin Mary that is cared for by members of Ecuador’s white aristocracy, the Benavides family, specifically the women. Years ago, the Benavides came to the region and simply stole the land from the Pandos family, who were Mestizo landowners. The Mestizos were descendants of European conquerors who were born in South America and with whom some of the indigenous had married.</p>
<p>When the white Benavides laid claim to those lands, the Pando clan sued, but, in the words of the group narrative, “justice is slow and lazy when the rich man fights the poor”. Somewhere along the line, the Virgin statue becomes “pregnant.” The Pandos believe that the deed to their land and the proof of their ownership is being hidden on the Virgin’s dress, hence the belly. A series of military coups and Marxist revolutions ensue as the statue of the Virgin is bandied about amidst both carnage and humorous chaos, resulting in the spontaneous abortion of the deeds.</p>
<p><em>Y</em>anéz Cossío uses four devices supplant the unified narrative. First, she makes copious use of proverbs. Second, she slides the point of view seamlessly from the main characters to people in the crowd, often with few identifying taglines, gestures, or facial expressions. Third, she uses long plot digressions about things which have nothing to do with the main characters, but which sometimes reveal the animism of the indigenous culture or a bit of social history, a device often evident in García Márquez’s <em>One Hundred Years of Solitude</em>. And fourth, she uses humor<em>. </em></p>
<p>The fourth device is evident throughout the novel but mostly at the end, during a brutal yet comical military coup. Professor of comparative literature and writer Kenneth Wishina, quoting narrative theorist Mikhail Bakhtin, writes that the “absolute monoglossic unity” of narratives “can be destroyed by laughter which is rarely present in the majority of Ecuadorian Historical novels” but which is a “dominant motif” in Yanéz Cossío’s work.</p>
<p>Though people often hate &#8220;spoilers,&#8221; it will increase your enjoyment of this disorienting narrative to know that <i>The Potbellied Virgin</i> ends when one the Benavides’ female descendants runs off with one of the young Pandos who has become a communist, leaving his elderly relatives to sit in the village square as they have spent most of their life doing, unwittingly smoking the scraps of their land deeds, which are blowing about the streets after the coup. Thus the town will find liberty only in the intermarriage of their disparate voices and outlooks.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Sources</span>:</p>
<ol>
<li>Cossío, Alicia Yánez. <em>The Potbellied</em> Virgin. Translated by Amalia Gladhart University of Texas Press. 2006</li>
<li>Wishnia, Kenneth. <em>Twentieth Century Ecuadorian Narrative: New Readings in the Context of the Americas</em>. Bucknell University Press. 1999.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Not to Hook &#8216;Em</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/how-not-to-hook-em/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lale Davidson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 10:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Literary Fantastic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=11117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At a GrubStreet Muse and the Marketplace Writers Conference, I workshopped my novel query “pitch”&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/mathieu-le-roux-705336-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-11329 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/mathieu-le-roux-705336-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>At a GrubStreet <a href="https://museandthemarketplace.com/">Muse and the Marketplace Writers Conference</a>, I workshopped my novel query “pitch” with a goateed and bespectacled editor from Scribner:</p>
<p>“After her mother spontaneously combusted on the <i>Altiplano</i> between Bolivia and Chile, Fallon struggles to grasp reality. Fifteen years later, her brother, who is bi-polar…”</p>
<p>He sighed audibly and wrinkled his nose under his black-rimmed spectacles. “Your pitch is too plotty. As an editor of literary fiction, I’m less interested in plot and more interested in language and style. What are your &#8216;comparables&#8217;?”</p>
<p>That’s shop talk for authors you might compare yourself to.</p>
<p>I suggested magical realists like <a href="http://www.flammableskirt.com/about/">Aimee Bender</a> and <a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/authors/70463/karen-russell">Karen Russell</a>. That was strike two.</p>
<p>“People in the publishing industry don’t call Karen Russell’s or Aimee Bender’s writing magical realism.”</p>
<p>“What would you call it?” I asked.</p>
<p>He thought for a moment. “I’d call it literary fiction that pushes the boundaries of reality.”</p>
<p>OK, I admit it. I was discouraged. I was hoping people would say, “Wow, fascinating, send it to me.”</p>
<p>Part way through the happy hour, we were supposed to mingle. He introduced me to an editor from William Morrow, and she agreed with his assessment. She said, &#8220;spontaneous combustion&#8221; raised so many questions about whether I was joking, talking about reality, or using a metaphor, that she couldn’t listen to the rest of the pitch. She thought I should simply say, “After the mysterious death of her mother . . .”</p>
<p>My friends all groaned when I related this. They love my opening line.</p>
<p>Later, at the GrubStreet Manuscript Mart, where agents and editors read the first twenty pages of your manuscript and comment, Laura Biagi from the Jean V. Naggar Agency had a problem with my opening lines. She thought I should start with something less confusing, or go into more detail about the combustion, or start in real time in the present with the main character and give us enough about her that we start to really care about her.</p>
<p>I told her my opening lines were making a bow to the opening lines of Gabriel Garcia Marquez&#8217; novel, <i>One Hundred Years of Solitude, </i>“Many years later, as he faced the firing squad, Colonel Aureliano Buendía was to remember that distant afternoon <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/kyle-glenn-686350-unsplash1.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-11330 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/kyle-glenn-686350-unsplash1-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>when his father took him to discover ice.” She pointed out that his novel then goes into that scene of the discovery of ice, whereas my first paragraph starts in the past, brings us too briefly to the pub and then goes the previous day. Too much too fast.</p>
<p>Peter Blackstone from Grove also agreed that my first paragraph was front-loading the novel too much.</p>
<p>So, I learned a valuable lesson. Start your query and your novel with a hook, but don’t give people whiplash.</p>
<p>A friend of mine who works for GrubStreet said, &#8220;You&#8217;ve also learned that the big publishers aren&#8217;t adventurous. They say they want something different, but not that different. After all, it has to be something that 100,000 people would like.” He had personally given up on them and only deals with small presses. I’m soon to follow.</p>
<p>I’d love to end this post telling you they were all wrong, and I published the novel as it was and lived happily ever after. Alas, I’m still revising. Just for yucks, though, I’ll leave with my before and after. Judge for yourself.</p>
<p><strong>Before</strong>:</p>
<blockquote><p>After her mother spontaneously combusted on the altiplano between Chile and Bolivia, Fallon turned her head, saw herself reflected, beautiful and male, in the face of her older brother Ovid and fell in love. Fifteen years later, navigating her way across the crowded floor of the North Star Pub to serve drinks to tourists and Wall Street brokers, she was still struggling to disentangle herself from both events.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>After</strong>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The road before them dissolved into two sets of tire tracks pressed deeply in the sand, one going to the left and one to the right. The American family of five looked through the front windshield at the greatest expanse of nothingness they had ever seen. Sands every shade from silver to lead stretched in all directions and would have gone on eternally had not snow-capped volcanoes pricked the horizon. Their conical perfection burned the sky, too harsh for reality, too exact for dreams. The tracks represented not so much a choice, as the utter impossibility of choice, rational or otherwise.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Does Fantasy Dodge or Enhance Reality?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/does-fantasy-dodge-or-enhance-reality/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lale Davidson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 10:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Literary Fantastic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lately, I’ve been writing and reading realistic stories with a hint of guilt. Why guilt,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jeremy-bishop-556948-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10865 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/jeremy-bishop-556948-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>Lately, I’ve been writing and reading realistic stories with a hint of guilt. Why guilt, you may ask?</p>
<p>Because I’ve been a staunch defender of the literary merit of fantasy, sci-fi, and magic realism, and because my turn to realism in middle age is accompanied by a bit of skepticism about the paranormal and a bit of boredom with its fiction, even as these genres are gaining status in the publishing world and as writers are beginning to blur genres with greater effect and fewer apologies.</p>
<p>In a recent interview with the <em>New York Times Book Review</em>, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/21/books/review/samantha-hunt-by-the-book.html">Samantha Hunt</a> said:</p>
<blockquote><p>“’Magic’ is a tricky word. It separates the unexplainable from our daily experience. Yet eyeballs, snowflakes, quantum physics and birth (along with many other things), are magical and habitual. I prefer the word ‘science.’ I like to write about wonder found in the ordinary.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Basically, she’s saying reality is so amazing that she uses the concept of magic to call attention<br />
to it. That’s sort of what I do—use magic to externalize emotional, psychological, physical, and<br />
spiritual truths – make metaphor materially (or at least verbally) manifest.</p>
<p>But while I agree with Hunt that molecular structure is wonder-inducing, calling into question,<br />
as it does, the nature of solidity, I disagree that science equals the magic or the miraculous. The<br />
words “magic,” “supernatural” and “miraculous” specifically mean that which is beyond nature<br />
– that which has no rational explanation.</p>
<p>So why do we keep using it in fiction if what we are really talking about is our perception of<br />
reality? Why, in the wonderful featured story, “<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-thing-in-the-walls-wants-your-small-change/">The Thing In the Walls Wants Your Small</a><br />
Change,” does author Virginia M Mohlere use the tiny dragon to symbolize the main character’s<br />
need to let her own inner monster out to fight the very real monster of her abusive, alcoholic<br />
mother? Why didn’t she just write a realistic story about that? Wouldn’t that be more complex to<br />
have the character fight her own battle, thus inviting the question of whether it’s right to fight<br />
violence with violence?</p>
<p>I don’t know if I can answer that question, but I’ll try: the tiny dragon is a more delightful, more<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/daria-tumanova-310162-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10866 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/daria-tumanova-310162-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a><br />
beautiful, more loving solution to rancid reality. The dragon is allowed to be an animal. It’s right<br />
and correct for the dragon to bite and scratch the mother—because it is acting in accordance with its true nature, whereas it would be wrong for the narrator to do that, because humans are supposed transcend their basic nature, to transcend violence. The dragon construct, therefore, allows us to have both. It allows us to deal with a heavy subject in a light way. But, at the risk of offending, I wonder when approaching my own writing on this score, if I’m dodging the difficult. If one goes much further down this road one might conclude, as some do, that all of fiction is a contrivance, and that only “real stories” are worth reading. Is there something wrong with relying on a construct? Is a construct the same as a contrivance?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ursulakleguin.com/MenuContentsList.html">Ursula Le Guin</a>, in her essay, “The Critics, The Monsters and the Fantasists,” would object to this<br />
line of questioning. She says, to assert that fantasy is mere metaphor or allegory is to reduce it<br />
and negate its primary power, which is to point us outside the box of quotidian life, which she<br />
sees, I think, as an inherently good activity because it opens us up to tolerance for difference<br />
and to imagining a better life.</p>
<p>Of course, we all know how subjective reality can be. And we’ve all heard the adage that fiction<br />
(good fiction anyway) is truer than truth.</p>
<p>I remain conflicted and curious about this issue, and ultimately, I think the world takes all kind<br />
of fiction and needs all kinds. After all, there isn’t just one version of a willow; there are thousands, and<br />
new ones crossbreeding every day.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Nature Makes Magic Real</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/how-nature-makes-magic-real/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lale Davidson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Literary Fantastic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10620</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a hemlock grove atop a snowy mountain, silence blooms. Minutely needled branches quiver. Water&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>In a hemlock grove atop a snowy mountain, silence blooms. Minutely needled branches quiver. Water drips from a crotch of snow between crossed logs into a black pool. More silence.  Nothing is as beautiful as this. No poem, no words, no sculpture, no painting. Nothing human-made can approach this three dimensional physical plane, where the points of depth and dimension are plotted by each hemlock needle.</div>
<div>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/deglee-degi-400520-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10621 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/deglee-degi-400520-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>Don’t listen to the theorists who have traveled so far from the physical that their heads float like balloons above their bodies, attached only by a tiny string. They have tried to convince us that reality is perception, that we shape what we see with our language, and therefore can never truly see the world as it is.</p>
<p>We know better. If you stop, breathe and look, you will see.</p>
<p>They got it backwards. We are part of nature. The landscape shaped us, shaped the brains that made the language. Landscape shaped our stories. The fallen logs beside the still water tossed up the elves. The creek burbled fairy laughter, the snow-covered boulder created Hansel and Gretel’s frosted house impossibly far from the path of human treading. When you hear a woman screaming in the forest and follow the sound into the mouth of a mountain lion, a thousand myths are born. The seal’s soft round eyes created the selkies who shed their skins and became us. The change of seasons, the unceasing variety of bird call and flower petals commanded our tongues to shape new sounds. The order of the needles divided our sounds into segments, giving birth to language.  And now, when we go back to the source, the land speaks us, and we call it magic.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Difference Between Magic Realism and Fantasy</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-difference-between-magic-realism-and-fantasy/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-difference-between-magic-realism-and-fantasy/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lale Davidson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 10:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Literary Fantastic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=10355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’re reading about dragons, chances are, you’re reading fantasy. But if you’re reading about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/jr-korpa-529181-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10356 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/jr-korpa-529181-unsplash-206x300.jpg" alt="" width="206" height="300" /></a>If you’re reading about dragons, chances are, you’re reading fantasy. But if you’re reading about women ascending bodily to heaven, you’re probably reading magic realism.</p>
<p>Confused? You’re not alone. The most common definition of fantasy is “literature in which magical things occur” or, as the <a href="https://www.uv.es/fores/The_Routledge_Dictionary_of_Literary_Terms.pdf"><i>Routledge Dictionary of Literary Terms</i></a> defines it, &#8220;literature which creates its own coherently organized worlds and myths.&#8221;</p>
<p>Of course, magical things happen in both fantasy and magic realism, so that doesn’t help us. I’ve heard people say that the big difference is that in fantasy, the characters are amazed, stunned, and shocked by the magical events, as when the glass suddenly disappears at the zoo in <em>Harry Potter</em>, and everyone screams. In magic realism, by contrast, the characters react to the magical as though it is ordinary.</p>
<p>Complicating both these definitions is the fact that the concept of reality is culturally defined. Orthodox Christians consider God and the Bible real. Atheists consider both fantasy. Roman mythology was at one time considered real; now the word <em>myth</em> is synonymous with <em>lie</em>. Native American writers such as <a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poets/leslie-marmon-silko">Leslie Marmon Silko</a> write about things that most Caucasian Americans would call unreal, but which are very real to her.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.theparisreview.org/interviews/3196/gabriel-garcia-marquez-the-art-of-fiction-no-69-gabriel-garcia-marquez">Gabriel García Márquez</a>, the king of magic realism and author of the Nobel Prize winning <i>100 Years of Solitude</i>, said, “Fantasy has nothing to do with the reality of the world we live in; it is purely fantastic invention, an inspiration, and certainly a diversion ill-advised in the arts.”</p>
<p>However, anyone who has heard a woman screaming in the forest and followed the sound into the mouth of a mountain lion will find the origins of fantasy very real. The flicker we all get in the peripheral vision, and secrets our parents tried to keep but which we all  felt, is where ghosts come from. The amygdala is a crude but lightning fast instrument. So I have to respectfully disagree with the king.</p>
<p>I think the best way to consider the difference between fantasy and reality is to consider its impact on the <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/rob-potter-398564-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-10357 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/rob-potter-398564-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a>reader. Tsvetan Todorov, a literary theorist famous for his treatment of the fantastic, said that magic realism disrupts the reader’s sense of reality whereas fantasy creates another completely enclosed reality. Whereas fantasy “imposes absolute closure” and “implies complicity on the part of the readers,” the literary fantastic seeks reader hesitancy.” The story begins in the “real world” and when something unreal happens and the reader is never sure if the cause is supernatural or natural, such as a psychotic break or a drug induced hallucination.</p>
<p>According to this definition, Henry James’ <i>The Turn of the Screw</i> is an example of the literary fantastic: did the governess see a ghost or hallucinate it? Did the ghost kill the boy, or did she scare him to death? The movie <i>Pan’s Labyrinth </i>is likewise an example: is she alive or dead at the end? Did imagination save her or kill her?</p>
<p>However, this definition doesn’t work for the poster child of magic realism, <i>100 Years of Solitude</i>. No one doubts that Remedios the Beauty ascended bodily to heaven and that a man’s blood flowed out the front door, down the block, turned left and went into his mother’s house. As Lucy Armitt says in her book, <i>Fantasy Fiction: An Introduction, </i>there are no “competing readings of the text&#8230; revolving around two choices, the psychological or the supernatural.”</p>
<p>However, you do feel ill at ease in Jorge Luis Borge’s short stories.  In “The Garden of Forking Paths,” you aren’t even sure that anything magical happens, it’s just an incredible coincidence that a spy randomly walks into the house of a man who has been studying his ancestor’s life work. Is Borges just a bad writer, you find yourself wondering. Is this even a story?</p>
<p>That’s why you also need this other defining characteristic of magic realism to understand it. Jon Evans says magic realism “draws from the well” of political disruption, violence and chaos, where the “surreal becomes normal and the insane becomes rational.”</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/tiko-giorgadze-262541-unsplash.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-10358 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/tiko-giorgadze-262541-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Magic realism is often the intersection of culturally competing definitions of reality and that creates an inherent tension. In the case of <i>100 Years</i>, it’s the intersection of indigenous and Catholic culture. This is the kind of tension you find in Toni Morrison’s <i>Beloved</i> (the tension between White and Black culture) and Leslie Marmon Silko’s <i>Ceremony </i>(the tension between Native American and White culture), even Karen Russel’s story, “Reeling for the Empire,” about Japanese women sold into slavery and turned into human silk worms by poisoned tea.</p>
<p>I’m not sure how I explain why I would put Aimee Bender and Amber Sparks in the category of magic realism rather than fantasy, especially as Bender has representatives of both in the same collection. Perhaps it comes down to a third distinguishing characteristic.</p>
<p>In fantasy, the magic is orderly and even predictable: rules apply. In contrast &#8211;and this is why I prefer it&#8211;mystery lies at its heart of magic realism. We don’t really know <em>why</em> the tigers come out of the forests with split skins, patiently waiting to be sewn back together by two sisters in Aimee Bender’s “Tiger Mending,” but the trope shimmers in our minds like an image on water: hard to grasp, unforgettable, and necessary.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">References</span></p>
<p>Armitt, Lucie. <i>Fantasy Fiction: An Introduction</i>. New York: Continuum International Publishing Group, 2005.</p>
<p>Bender, Aimee. <i>The Color Master. </i>New York: Doubleday, 2013.</p>
<p>Childs, Peter and Roger Fowler. <i>Routledge Dictionary of Literary Terms</i>.  Routledge, Taylor and Francis Group, 2006.</p>
<p>Evans, Jon. “Magic Realism: Not Fantasy. Sorry.” <i>Tor.com</i>. Tor Books. 23 October 2008. Web. 12 March 2014.</p>
<p>Kroeber, Karl. <i>Romantic Fantasy and Science Fiction.</i> New Haven: Yale University Press, 1988.</p>
<p>Le Guin, Ursula K. “The Critics, The Monsters and the Fantasists.” <i>The Secret History of Fantasy. </i>Ed. Peter S. Beagle. San Francisco: Tachyan Publications, 2010. 355-366.</p>
<p><i>Pan’s Labyrinth.</i> Dir. Guillermo del Toro. Perf. <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm1419440/?ref_=tt_ov_st">Ivana Baquero</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0317725/?ref_=tt_ov_st">Ariadna Gil</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0530365/?ref_=tt_ov_st">Sergi López</a>. Warner Brothers, 2006. Film.</p>
<p>Russell, Karen. <i>Vampires in the Lemon Grove</i>. New York: Knopf, 2013.</p>
<p>“Thursday, March 6, 2014.” <i>The Writer’s Almanac with Garrison Keillor. </i>American Public Media, 6 March, 2014. Web. March 12, 2014.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/the-difference-between-magic-realism-and-fantasy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
