<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Option Clauses: Pros and Cons	</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/option-clauses-pros-and-cons/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/option-clauses-pros-and-cons/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:12:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: An Interview with Literary Agent Jacqui Lipton, by Heather Stigall, and a Critique Giveaway! &#124; EasternPennPoints		</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/option-clauses-pros-and-cons/#comment-2114</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[An Interview with Literary Agent Jacqui Lipton, by Heather Stigall, and a Critique Giveaway! &#124; EasternPennPoints]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=25253#comment-2114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] Jacqui:&#160;Generally, we try to work with reputable, established publishers, so there shouldn’t be too many red flags in the sense of things that are inappropriate or unprofessional in a contract. However, there are of course things we always try to fight for on behalf of our clients, including making sure we’re not giving away rights that could be exploited elsewhere in a more lucrative way. For example, many publishers do not necessarily focus on exploiting film/TV rights, and those can often be exploited more effectively outside the original contract. The same goes for a number of other sub rights like foreign and translation rights. If the publisher wants to take more sub rights, our aim is to make sure they compensate the author accordingly. Additionally, it’s generally important to understand the scope of option and noncompete clauses and to limit them as effectively as possible so they won’t hinder the author’s future work—I’ve written a number of blog posts on these issues that I can share during the webinar. You’ll find some of them at&#160;https://lunastationquarterly.com/tag/non-compete/, https://lunastationquarterly.com/option-and-non-compete-clauses/,&#160;and https://lunastationquarterly.com/option-clauses-pros-and-cons/. [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] Jacqui:&nbsp;Generally, we try to work with reputable, established publishers, so there shouldn’t be too many red flags in the sense of things that are inappropriate or unprofessional in a contract. However, there are of course things we always try to fight for on behalf of our clients, including making sure we’re not giving away rights that could be exploited elsewhere in a more lucrative way. For example, many publishers do not necessarily focus on exploiting film/TV rights, and those can often be exploited more effectively outside the original contract. The same goes for a number of other sub rights like foreign and translation rights. If the publisher wants to take more sub rights, our aim is to make sure they compensate the author accordingly. Additionally, it’s generally important to understand the scope of option and noncompete clauses and to limit them as effectively as possible so they won’t hinder the author’s future work—I’ve written a number of blog posts on these issues that I can share during the webinar. You’ll find some of them at&nbsp;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/tag/non-compete/" rel="ugc">https://lunastationquarterly.com/tag/non-compete/</a>, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/option-and-non-compete-clauses/,&nbsp;and" rel="ugc">https://lunastationquarterly.com/option-and-non-compete-clauses/,&nbsp;and</a> <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/option-clauses-pros-and-cons/" rel="ugc">https://lunastationquarterly.com/option-clauses-pros-and-cons/</a>. [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
