<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/rwx-readwriteexplicate/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 18:27:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Writing Resolutions for 2017</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/writing-resolutions-for-2017/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 17:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7780</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This time of year, writers who blog tend to lay out their plans for the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This time of year, writers who blog tend to lay out their plans for the next twelve months: writing projects, submission goals, directions for their craft, whose work they plan to read, and so on. And so I too am using this time to consider my writing in the coming year. But not, in the way that I have done so before.</p>
<p>In light of the recent US elections, I&#8217;m faced with far different writing goals this year. The sort of SF I write and prefer to read—social with a focus on feminist and humanist concerns—is more urgently needed as part of a larger conversation about our culture. That said, do I read more? Absolutely. Do I blog more about this? I should. Do I write more social SF?</p>
<p>There&#8217;s where the problem lies for me. Since November, I&#8217;ve spent more time writing letters to elected officials, calling out problematic appointments and voicing my opinions on proposed legislation that promises to strip the hard-won rights of fellow citizens. And what I&#8217;ve written about to local, state, and national officials is not even a small fraction of what I find appalling among these proposals.</p>
<p>Writing letters takes resources that I would have otherwise used writing fiction and poems. But at present, the letters are more urgent than either of those. So I write more letters, stamp them, and send them on their way.</p>
<p>And yet, I circle around to the stories, the poems. So many writers, readers, publishers, and editors have reminded us lately that we should not stop writing stories that should be told. These stories are needed as part of the narrative that we as a society have constructed about ourselves. We can&#8217;t let the overriding story become what those who have power would have it be.</p>
<p>So here&#8217;s my writing resolution for 2017: find balance. Write to those in power when I can, but remember the power of story. Quite often, the fiction comes from asking questions about the implications of policy as proposed. For example, what happens if access to birth control is all but blocked? What happens if voting rights are further threatened? What happens if large corporations are allowed to control environmental and labor policies?</p>
<p>Either way, in letters and in stories, I&#8217;ll be saying the same thing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Author Websites: Some Concerns Regarding Websites for Women Who Write</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/author-websites-some-concerns-regarding-websites-for-women-who-write/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 17:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just about all the articles, blog posts, and books you can find on author self-promotion&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><!-- @page { margin: 0.79in } P { margin-bottom: 0.08in } --></p>
<p>Just about all the articles, blog posts, and books you can find on author self-promotion will contain this bit of advice: you need a website. Nothing fancy, just a website with a list of works, a bio, maybe a blog, maybe a picture. But you need a website.</p>
<p>As a relatively new SF author—I can&#8217;t say young, and really, I&#8217;m returning to publishing in the last couple years after a decade away—I&#8217;m at the point where I&#8217;d like to follow this advice. I have a number of poems and stories published and forthcoming, and I blog here and elsewhere. Most advice is for authors marketing books, but I don&#8217;t have a book out yet (Working on it. Or them, really. Still in draft form, alas.). That said, these articles (etc.) on self-promotion also encourage you to set up a website (and accompanying social media presences) before publication, so it would be a useful exercise for me regardless.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/index.png"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7669 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/index.png" alt="index" width="266" height="190" /></a>So, what&#8217;s the first step? Not registering a domain, nor choosing a hosting service. Not determining whether I&#8217;d like to use a blogging platform such as WordPress, nor hiring a designer for a banner. Not deciding whether to blog, nor what I should write about, aside from writing. It&#8217;s not drafting a biographical sketch, nor determining how much of my personal life I should include in it. No, the first step, I&#8217;d argue, is going through the advice and questioning how, or whether I should, follow it in light of the fact that I&#8217;m a woman.</p>
<p>What does this have to with anything? Just about everything you could put on an author website falls into the category of double-standards. The most obvious example of this is the author photo. If I were a man, I&#8217;d have a more limited set of decisions to make. Maybe, for example, what to wear or where to take the picture.<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/15-0623-Double-Standards.png"><img decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-7670 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/15-0623-Double-Standards-300x208.png" alt="15-0623-double-standards" width="300" height="208" /></a></p>
<p>The author picture isn&#8217;t so simple for me, though. Take makeup, for one. I don&#8217;t usually wear it; in fact, I can&#8217;t remember the last time I did. Do I do so for the sake of the picture? Do I forgo it since I don&#8217;t wear it? Should I do so, I risk the possibility of criticism for presenting myself in a way I don&#8217;t usually appear, for buying into some (male-driven?) notion of what I should look like, for thinking that I should do so to appear more “professional” (whatever that means). If I don&#8217;t, I risk criticism for trying to appear, perhaps, as if I were distancing myself from women who do wear it, or as if I were wanting to present a less feminine image.</p>
<p>Over the next couple blog posts, I&#8217;ll take apart some of the more commonly recommended elements of author websites and walked through my decisions about them. I&#8217;d also like to examine why we expect author websites to have these elements, and what that implies about our expectations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Herland: Feminist Utopias, Women-Only Spaces, and the Men Who Want to Conquer Them, Part 2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/herland-feminist-utopias-women-only-spaces-and-the-men-who-want-to-conquer-them-part-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 16:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In my post from July, I discussed the three archetypes that the three men who&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/CharlottePerkinsGilman_Herland.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7326 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/CharlottePerkinsGilman_Herland-201x300.jpg" alt="charlotteperkinsgilman_herland" width="201" height="300" /></a>In my <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/herland-feminist-utopias-women-only-spaces-and-the-men-who-want-to-conquer-them-part-1/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post </a>from July, I discussed the three archetypes that the three men who entered Herland exemplified: the philanderer, the woman-worshiper, and the observer. In this post, I&#8217;ll draw parallels between those three types and the reasons men often give for wanting to enter women-only spaces. Again, in this post, I do want to be careful to note that “women-only” is often used as a term for spaces for not only women but also for those who are trans women and non-binary as well. To clarify, I&#8217;m using the term “women-only” to signify those spaces set aside for those who don&#8217;t identify exclusively as cisgender men.</p>
<p>As an organizer of and participant in women-only groups, I&#8217;ve seen a number of men try to infiltrate the safe spaces we attempt to provide. Each man has his own reason, but roughly, we can group them in the same way that Charlotte Perkins Gilman characterizes the men who enter Herland (Terry Nicholson, Jeff Margrave, and Vandyck Jennings). Terry, the Philanderer, wants the women to love him; Jeff, the Woman-Worshiper, wants to adore them; and Van, the Observer, wants to learn more about them. Though some motivations may seem more noble than the others, all are problematic. And they all point to a couple of very disturbing conclusions.</p>
<p><b>The Philanderer: Where Else Will I Meet Women?</b></p>
<p>We&#8217;ll start with the obvious one first. The Philanderer wants to meet women, because, naturally, they all want to meet him. Don&#8217;t they? Of course they do. And he&#8217;s going to want to charm his was in as a favor to all us ladies.</p>
<p>Though, really, it&#8217;s the case that women-only spaces just look like the best or only option for finding us.</p>
<p>Often, the men who use this reason to justify entering women-only spaces are part of the larger communities to which the women-only spaces belong. That said, the reasons they can&#8217;t meet women in these larger groups are the very reasons that women need their own spaces. Maybe they don&#8217;t feel welcome in the first place. Maybe they&#8217;re spoken over, dismissed, or outright harassed. And maybe they&#8217;ve been the target of too many philanderers in the larger community to feel comfortable.</p>
<p><b>The Woman-Worshiper: Can&#8217;t I Just Enjoy Women&#8217;s Company?</b></p>
<p>While it&#8217;s easy to see why philanderers harm communities that want to welcome more women, it&#8217;s not as obvious to see why those who just want to enjoy the company of women—often without any of the romantic or prurient intent of the philanderer—would be harmful as well.</p>
<p>I think this is about being a good ally. Good allies work alongside, not simply on behalf of—the difference being in one&#8217;s presumed relationship with the group one allies oneself with. Jeff adores women, to the point of annoying even Van: “Jeff idealized women in the best Southern style. He was full of chivalry and sentiment, and all that. […] But I got out of patience with Jeff, too. He had such rose-colored halos on his womenfolks.” He can&#8217;t see women as equals, but only as inferiors to be protected.</p>
<p>Should the woman-worshiper respect women-only spaces, then he&#8217;d subvert his own desires to spend time with the women in those spaces and instead work toward being a better ally. Which, in the context of larger communities, means honoring the need for the women-only spaces while making the larger communities better places for women to participate in. If an ally wants to enjoy women&#8217;s company, he should make them feel more welcome as the equal participants they are.</p>
<p><b>The Observer: What Do Women Really Want?</b></p>
<p>Another reason I&#8217;ve heard for men wanting to enter women-only spaces is that they want to find out what we want, what makes us tick. Again this is a case of attempted alliance gone awry. Instead of wanting to protect “weak but virtuous” women, these men want to find out what makes us “tick” in order to better help us and the communities we belong to as a whole.</p>
<p>Except women aren&#8217;t extraterrestrial beings. We&#8217;re part of the same societies as men, subject to the same cultural forces as men. By viewing women as so dramatically different from men, the observer reinforces the cis-man as norm that makes women feel alienated, though we&#8217;re not alien.</p>
<p>Often, I&#8217;ve heard men want to attend women-only groups to hear what we think about feminism, for example. While it&#8217;s commendable that these men want to know more about this subject, their insistence places the burden of education on the women in these groups. That burden does not belong on the participants in women-only spaces.</p>
<p>And again, I think this is a matter of being a good ally. If men in the larger groups want to know more about feminism, for example, they could invite a speaker or panel from the subgroup to talk to the larger group instead of entering the women-only space. This has the double benefit of both honoring boundaries as well as getting the message about feminist issues out to not only observers, but woman-worshipers and philanderers as well.</p>
<p><b>It&#8217;s Not Fair. It&#8217;s Not. Let Us In!</b></p>
<p>One problematic upshot is that a number of men, including those who don&#8217;t necessarily fall into one of these three broad groups, protest having an exclusive group. I grappled with this myself in recommending women-only spaces in larger groups I&#8217;ve been in. Is it fair to exclude men from these spaces? I can answer yes because of the pervasiveness of the problems these spaces try to address.</p>
<p>The purpose of a safe space is not to detract from the larger group, but instead to allow those within the safe space to find support where they may be undervalued in the larger group, even when that undervaluing is not consciously done.</p>
<p>By and large, the vast majority of men in the larger communities to which the women-only spaces I&#8217;ve participated in have been good allies. They do value women as equals. Being a good ally does mean speaking out when it&#8217;s appropriate (while not acting the role of the white knight) and listening and directing others to listen when it&#8217;s appropriate to do that. And respecting safe spaces is an important part of that.</p>
<p>We can hope that one day, the need for woman-only spaces will become rarer and rarer, as society progresses. We won&#8217;t evolve exactly along the lines Gilman suggests, given the complexity of the problems she tackles and what we know about gender now, but we can take from her utopia some hope that we can address these issues and make positive steps now and in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dr. Sabrina Starnaman Q&#038;A: Creating and Teaching SF as Literature Classes, Part 2</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dr-sabrina-starnaman-qa-creating-and-teaching-sf-as-literature-classes-part-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 15:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently, I interviewed Dr. Sabrina Starnaman, Clinical Assistant Professor of Literary Studies at The University of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<p>Recently, I interviewed Dr.<a href="http://sabrinastarnaman.com/"> Sabrina Starnaman</a>, Clinical Assistant Professor of <a href="https://www.utdallas.edu/ah/programs/literature/">Literary Studies at The University of Texas at Dallas</a>, who teaches science fiction and fantasy as literature courses.  Some of the classes she has taught include “The Hero’s Journey,” “LeGuin and Butler,” and “Cyborgs and Robots.”  Her research foci include American literature written by and about women, and representations of bodies, specifically representations of gender and disability.  This is the second half of the Q&amp;A; the first half can be found in my April 2016 post <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/dr-sabrina-starnaman-qa-creating-and-teaching-sf-as-literature-classes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<p><b>rwx: </b>What role does your own research play in the content of the class?</p>
<p><b>Dr. Starnaman: </b>It&#8217;s really interesting because I did not start out as a science fiction and fantasy reader. My interest and my research is originally in late nineteenth century American women&#8217;s fiction, particularly women who moved to the city or women in cities. My research is interested in questions of gender, class, race, labor, sexuality, ethnicity, immigration, and those sorts of things. Those are central themes in the stories I work on; they&#8217;re central themes in the research questions that I engage. And so when I was initially asked to teach science fiction and fantasy lit—being asked to teach classes outside your area of research is a common thing in education—I immediately had to start reading. But I thought long and hard about how would I teach this class because it was not my primary research area. So what I decided was that race, gender, sexuality—all these things—would actually be the foundation of the class, and it&#8217;s just the texts that changed. That&#8217;s something I bring into it.</p>
<p>And then of course wherever possible I try to bring in books from the late nineteenth century because I think it&#8217;s very easy for us to believe—or at least it&#8217;s easy for a lot of students now—they&#8217;re inundated with YA fantasy and science fiction books. They&#8217;re inundated with these blockbuster movies. And I think it&#8217;s important for them to see that this has a long history. And the fact that I also believe that science fiction is a genre of social protest. So to bring in a story from the 1880s about women&#8217;s suffrage and women&#8217;s rights is to show them that science fiction has always been a genre of social protest. And so that&#8217;s assuredly one way that my research runs through the class.</p>
<p>Another way is that because I work on a lot of nineteenth century women writers, I&#8217;m very invested in the recovery of women writers and seeing books get back into publication that weren&#8217;t in publication. I really believe that the act of requiring books for class is an act of social justice. Who you put on your syllabus and who the students have to buy sends a larger message to publishers. I work very hard to make sure that my students are buying books by women and books by people of color. For this semester, I have my courses subtitled “The Hero&#8217;s Journey,” and they have an anthology—a really well edited anthology by David Hartwell called <i><a href="https://tachyonpublications.com/product/the-sword-sorcery-anthology/">Sword and Sorcery</a>—</i>and then they had to buy <i>Epic of </i><i>Gilgamesh</i>, and every other book they are buying are either by women or people of color. I think that&#8217;s really important, and in fact, one of the books that we are reading for the semester is essentially out of print. We bought every single copy there was in the American book market for the book. My hope is that it sends a message to the publisher that this book is worth going back into print. So that&#8217;s another way in which the commitments of my personal research get written into a syllabus and written into the books that we buy and that we discuss.</p>
<p>But like I said, I don&#8217;t know that the students actually find it remotely radical anymore. They just think it makes sense that they&#8217;re reading all these books that have diversity in them.</p>
<p><b>rwx:</b> So, progress?</p>
<p><b>Dr. Starnaman: </b>Yes. One hopes.</p>
<p><b>rwx:</b> What has surprised you most about the way the class has evolved?</p>
<p><b>Dr. Starnaman: </b>That&#8217;s a really great question. It&#8217;s funny because I took over this class from a male science fiction author and editor, and he had a huge following. He had an enormous knowledge of the history of science fiction and fantasy as a publishing field and as a literary genre. He did a lot of lecturing—he taught most of his class through lecture. And so when I took over the class, there were a lot of surprised, perhaps even disappointed, students because they weren&#8217;t going to get what they had expected. Many of them had already taken his class before, and they were looking forward to taking it again. And so in the beginning I think that there was a little bit more resistance.</p>
<p>One of the things that I’ve seen is that more students in my class are out as gay, more students in class are trans*. I had believed that maybe the number of women in my class had changed over the semesters. In fact every other year I teach a class where all we do is read Ursula LeGuin and Octavia Butler. And I thought that would probably skew the course toward more women. This past year just out of curiosity I went back, and I looked at all of my classes from the last years. I counted how many men and how many women were in class, and it hasn&#8217;t changed at all. So I still have two-thirds men and one-third women, and that surprised me. Maybe I’m becoming more aware of trans* students in my class or maybe my class is clearly a safe space that students who are gay [or transgender] can talk about their own experience. [I hear students] say, &#8220;this moment in this book really speaks volumes to the experience of coming out to your parents.&#8221;  So maybe that has been something that has evolved, and students know that it&#8217;s a safe space, and so this becomes something that&#8217;s expected in my classes. But just the breakdown of men and women, just sheer numbers has not changed, and that has really surprised me.</p>
<p>Teaching a science fiction and fantasy course is not like teaching any other course. This is something that surprised me, as I have learned more about what it means to teach science fiction and fantasy. If you&#8217;re teaching American Realism and Naturalism, the students come to the class, and they might know a little bit about what they remember from high school, but by and large, you&#8217;re introducing them to something they don&#8217;t know and whatever they do know, you&#8217;re teaching them as the course evolves. In a literature of science fiction or literature of fantasy class, often sixty of my eighty to ninety students are people who love science fiction love fantasy, and have read enormous amount, have played thousands of hours of video games in the genre, have watched hundreds of films or televisions shows in the genre. Something I was totally unprepared for in the beginning was the encyclopedic knowledge some students have. I imagine if you teach paleontology, it&#8217;s the same way, you have these kids who&#8217;ve been studying dinosaurs since they were little. But I’ve had to change the way I teach in some ways because I have to honor the fact that many of the students in class have this incredible knowledge.</p>
<p>Another issue is that a lot of the literature students in my class don&#8217;t have any background in science fiction and fantasy, and so they walk into this class expecting it to be like every other lit class they&#8217;ve been in, which is that people are pretty much on the same footing in terms of their literary knowledge with the exception of one or two outliers. But then they walk into a room and there&#8217;s sixty people who are using references and know things and can reference details about the author and other books they&#8217;ve written. I’ve learned right from the beginning to address this because it scares the lit students. They think “what am I getting myself into? I didn&#8217;t know I had to have all this pre-knowledge for this class.” And so I work hard to say, &#8220;a lot of the people who have knowledge about the genre don&#8217;t have a lot of skills about talking about it critically and all you advanced lit students have a lot of skills for talking about it critically. Its&#8217; okay, lit people, don&#8217;t be worried. In a few weeks you&#8217;ll have some texts under your belt, and you&#8217;ll be able to participate from your strengths and the things you&#8217;ve learned.&#8221;</p>
<p>Teaching science fiction and fantasy lit classes, especially at a place like UT Dallas which has this huge Arts and Technology program dedicated to gaming and sound design which is often related to gaming, is I think a different experience than if I was teaching it at a small liberal arts college where my students would be literature or history majors. That&#8217;s another way in which I’ve evolved to understand the class, and it&#8217;s a way in which I evolved to teach the class to reassure everybody that&#8217;s it&#8217;s going to be okay, that we&#8217;re all going to get through this, and that I evolved the course so that some students can learn the skills they don&#8217;t have and some students can learn the genre that they don&#8217;t know. By a third of the way through the class we&#8217;re all together in our movement toward our final sophisticated discussions and final projects or final analytical papers.</p>
<p><b>rwx:</b> If you could recommend to the blog readers one novel or anthology that you&#8217;ve taught, what would you suggest?</p>
<p><b>Dr. Starnaman: </b>Oh, that&#8217;s the hardest question. I have become a total fan of the work of <a href="https://www.panmacmillan.com/authors/china-mieville">China Miéville</a> in the course of teaching this class. Every book he writes while they are all speculative fiction, they are always in a different genre, so one is steampunk—his Bas Lag series, the first one <i>Perdido Street Station</i> is a steampunk novel. The next book in the series, <i>The Scar</i>, is a high-seas adventure but also in the same world. And the third in the series, <i>Iron Council,</i> is a western, even though it&#8217;s still in the same world. I recommend anything by him. I also often teach his book<i> Kraken</i>, which is about a squid cult and different god cults in London in the end of days. There are a number of reasons why I think his books are worth reading. One is that they&#8217;re so rich with allusions to other literature and other media, for instance, as he was raised playing Dungeons and Dragons and watching <i>Star Trek</i>, so that can also been seen though these books. He&#8217;s also is a readers&#8217; writer&#8211;he has read so much and that is evident in his work. I think it&#8217;s great for students to see the purpose of learning literature is to participate in the conversation. His books are a conversation across time and across different forms of media. If you don&#8217;t know the allusions, that&#8217;s fine, they&#8217;re interesting books nevertheless, but I think they&#8217;re a great read and they&#8217;re a great teach in that sense.</p>
<p>Also his books do something that I enjoy seeing in books and I enjoy teaching in class. You don&#8217;t just read the book from the beginning to the end because the way the story builds, as you move forward through the book you&#8217;re also reinterpreting what you&#8217;ve already read. That is a process that those of us who love literature know about, reading in both directions at the same time and then the joy of rereading his books when you teach them.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div> I&#8217;m currently in love with the book that we just read this week which is N.K. Jemison&#8217;s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19161852-the-fifth-season"><i>The Fifth Season.</i> </a>I also recommend that—it&#8217;s a book that can be read in both directions at the same time. And so in class when I explained this to the students and we did a close reading of the first page, I had students put their heads in their hands and say this page is so much more devastating now that I’ve read the entire book. This experience of rereading the first page for them in class was perhaps for some of them their first experience of coming to a rereading or re-understating of a book after you&#8217;ve finished it. And seeing it as an organic, evolving experience. I recommend China Miéville for all those reasons. I have to say that I was very impressed with N.K. Jemison&#8217;s novel that we just read.</div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<p>I think that the question of one is really hard thing for me to answer. I would also like to say that I think that <a href="http://www.theodoresturgeontrust.com/">Theodore Sturgeon</a> is the best writer that most people haven&#8217;t read. He&#8217;s long gone now, but he was a writer&#8217;s writer, and he was an influence on so many other writers. And every time I teach either one of his stories, like “Thunder and Roses” or I teach his novel <i>More Than Human</i>, it is a transformative experience for students. If I could bring back an author into the public consciousness, and of course there would be thousands of people who would say “What? No! Theodore Sturgeon is amazing! Of course he doesn’t need to be brought back.” But in terms of an author that a lot of everyday readers don&#8217;t know, he&#8217;s one that I wish that more literary scholars knew about, I wish that more readers had an opportunity to read. But that&#8217;s my job to bring him to everybody.</p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Herland: Feminist Utopias, Women-Only Spaces, and the Men Who Want to Conquer Them, Part 1</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/herland-feminist-utopias-women-only-spaces-and-the-men-who-want-to-conquer-them-part-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 16:08:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Among the problems of aging utopian novels is the fact that many of the ideas&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Among the problems of aging utopian novels is the fact that many of the ideas these perfect societies are founded upon become outdated and, sadly, obscure the lessons present-day readers can take from them. Such is the case with Charlotte Perkins Gilman&#8217;s 1915 novel <i>Herland</i>, in which three male explorers from the US attempt to breach the tantalizing land of all women they hear about from their local South American guides. While it&#8217;s easy to dismiss the novel for its reliance on a strict gender binary—among other problematic ideas—<i>Herland</i> also offers us a way of thinking about twenty-first century safe spaces for women.</p>
<p>As a woman who has participated in groups designated women-only, I&#8217;ve seen numerous attempts by cis-men to “invade” these safe spaces. (These groups are welcoming to self-identified women as well as non-binary identifying people, thus getting around the strict divide in the novel. I&#8217;m using the term “women-only,” but it should be read as inclusive of everyone except cis-men.) Although it may seem obvious why the men would do so, I think it may be helpful to examine their motives a bit closer. If we know why someone acts as they do, then we may have a better chance—I can hope—of stopping their harmful behavior. Given that the explorers are so archetypal (the philanderer, the woman-worshiper, and the observer), they provide us a way of looking at some of the possible motives for men to want to infiltrate women-only spaces.</p>
<p><b>Too Tempting to Ignore: The Land of Women and Girls</b></p>
<p>In the novel, three friends—Terry Nicholson, Jeff Margrave, and Vandyck Jennings—undertake an expedition to South America, during which they hear of a secluded land of all women and girls. No men, their guides tell them, have ever returned from this land. Their interest piqued, Terry, Jeff, and Van decide to return to the area later after their initial expedition has been completed so that they may claim sole glory of discovering this women-only country.</p>
<p>Their motivations for doing so differ quite significantly. Though, as the narrator Van claims, all three were “interested in science,” scientific discovery had little to do with their desire to see—and stake their claims to—“Herland.” The personality of each man drives the action of the story, and it also gives us an insight into present-day parallels.</p>
<p><b>The Philanderer: (Pretty) Women as Objects to Conquer and Seduce</b></p>
<p>Van describes Terry as a philanderer. He says of his college friend:</p>
<blockquote><p>“He was a man&#8217;s man, very much so, generous and brave and clever; but I don&#8217;t think any of us in college days was quite pleased to have him with our sisters. We weren&#8217;t very stringent, heavens no! But Terry was &#8216;the limit.&#8217; [ . . . ] But barring a possible exception in favor of a not impossible wife, or of his mother, or, of course, the fair relatives of his friends, Terry&#8217;s idea seemed to be that pretty women were just so much game and homely ones not worth considering.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Terry&#8217;s intentions are quite clear. He intends to use the expedition into Herland as a sort of hunt for fair young things to seduce.</p>
<p>Further, Terry demonstrates his static idea of “womanhood”, as he bristles most at the attempts of his Herland tutor to teach him about their civilization. When he does later pursue and marry Alima, his desire to control her demonstrates that he does not see her as a full partner. Rather, he is unable to get past his own notions of what a woman should be in order to understand her and her wishes.</p>
<p><b>The Woman-Worshiper: Women as Angels to Adore</b></p>
<p>Jeff, on the other hand, “idealized women in the best Southern style. He was full of chivalry and sentiment, and all that.” Van concludes that Jeff is unable to view women as full persons, with the necessary agency to build the sort of civilization Herland possesses. While he eagerly learns from his tutor, he, like Terry, does not accept the full humanity of the women.</p>
<p>Instead, he sees the women as “angels,” an idea that Jeff clung to and as such “tried to force it on us—with varying effect. He so worshipped [his wife] Celis, and not only Celis, but what she represented.” The women of Herland represented, to Jeff, the best of what a woman could be. Which is not the same as the best that a person could be—again, the possibility for equal partnership is lost.</p>
<p><b>The Observer: Women as Objects for Scientific Study</b></p>
<p>Van, the sociologist, fancies himself the most objective of the three, though even he too has much to learn from the women of Herland. Over the course of the novel, he does change. While he is among the women of this utopia, he realizes the “painful defects” of America which he&#8217;d previously not thought about, intentionally or not. He most fully accepts the tutoring they offer, and he is most willing to acknowledge the fact that the American society as he came from has stunted women&#8217;s growth.</p>
<p>That said, his relationship with his Herland wife, Ellador, is hardly fully satisfactory for him. He can respect her for her curiosity, her intelligence, and her willingness to act upon both, but he can&#8217;t fully accept her disinterest in marital relations outside the act leading to conception. He does, however, agree to be patient in this, and  he&#8217;s at least more willing than Terry or Jeff to see his wife as a full partner, not just a means to an end.</p>
<p><b>Men in Women-Only Spaces: What Can We Learn?<br />
</b></p>
<p>So, what does all this breaking down into archetypes do for present-day women who want to protect women-only spaces? Over the years, I&#8217;ve seen a number of cis-men asking to attend—or asserting their right to attend—meetings in these spaces. While I don&#8217;t think the motives break down in the fixed, discrete ways we see in <i>Herland</i>, I do think they provide us a starting point to explore why men want to join in.</p>
<p>In an upcoming post, I&#8217;ll examine some common reasons men give for wanting to “explore” women-only spaces in light of these types. In doing so, I hope, we can both more effectively maintain these safe spaces as well as work toward changing the attitudes in larger society that necessitate them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Princes, Princesses, and Parenting</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/princes-princesses-and-parenting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 16:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While reading Sheila Finch&#8217;s Myths, Metaphors, and Science Fiction, I ran across a passage that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While reading Sheila Finch&#8217;s <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Myths-Metaphors-Science-Fiction-Sheila/dp/161976055X"><i>Myths, Metaphors, and Science Fiction</i></a>, I ran across a passage that gave me, as a parent, pause:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;In later centuries, we seem to have watered down the messages [of fairy tales], especially in the post-Disney world, but the continuing popularity, even into our scientific age, of what might otherwise be considered mere nursery tales tells us that at least some of the original serious intention seems to be getting through” (p. 65).</p></blockquote>
<p>Two phrases here struck me: the “post-Disney world” and “original serious intention” of the tales.</p>
<p>Let me step back here a moment. I&#8217;ve been intentionally vague in these posts about the fact that my now-toddler is a boy. In a cultural moment when we&#8217;re expected to have “gender reveal” parties with cakes or confetti-filled balloons or dove releases that announce the baby&#8217;s gender by being pink or blue accordingly, I wanted to get away from what other people seem to insist is The Most Important Thing about my child. Believe me, it isn&#8217;t. It&#8217;s his curiosity, his laugh, his delight at discovering new things. It&#8217;s the fact that he enjoys spicy food and dancing (like me) and that he needs to know how everything is put together (like his dad). If he were a girl, none of that would change.</p>
<p>And yet, when I found out that my second child, due in October, is a girl, I made that list of things I won&#8217;t allow her to do. Top among these: no princess anything, ever.</p>
<p>Which, I realized shortly after, was a double-standard. If my son wants to pretend to be a prince (or a princess), why not? I&#8217;ll just tell him about the problems of monarchies, especially those that drain the resources from the people. If my son wants to watch a Disney princess movie, sure, go ahead! I&#8217;ll just use it as a teaching moment.</p>
<p>So why not let my daughter do the same?</p>
<p>I&#8217;m probably among the last of the last Gen-Xers to have children. Which means that the last (non-Pixar) Disney movies I saw were <i>The Little Mermaid</i> and <i>Beauty and the Beast</i>, and those only because I was watching them with younger family members. Perhaps princess movies have moved on from the “story ends when prince marries the lucky girl” trope. Regardless, these older movies and related non-Disney films remain popular, so I doubt I can shield my children from them entirely. In fact, I know I can&#8217;t. So what to do?</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/727ae250-8c5c-4313-b447-fa271ffcee4a.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-6714" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/727ae250-8c5c-4313-b447-fa271ffcee4a.jpg" alt="727ae250-8c5c-4313-b447-fa271ffcee4a" width="800" height="360" /></a></p>
<p>Rather than keep my son and daughter away from princess culture, I&#8217;m going to keep in mind the “original serious intention” of fairy tales, including those that glorify romantic partnerships over everything else. There are lessons to be learned, and if my children enjoy the stories, we can use them to talk about, say, good decisions and bad decisions, and about accepting the consequences of breaking rules. We can use them to talk about how some rules are outdated and should be broken. We can use them to talk about how there&#8217;s more to life than romantic partnerships.</p>
<p>And I think I need to remind myself that these pink-and-sparkly versions of fairy tales are most folks&#8217; first exposure to the broader category of fantasy and its umbrella, speculative fiction. If my children are hooked on the stories and want to read more, then shouldn&#8217;t I encourage that? There are so many good middle-grade and YA speculative stories that turn the tropes I worry about on their heads—it should be my job to steer my children toward those stories as well as to discuss what&#8217;s troubling about mainstream depictions of the “princess marries her true love” tales.</p>
<p>So, if my daughter wants to wear pink and pretend she&#8217;s a princess, I&#8217;ll let her. I&#8217;ll also remind both my children that no one&#8217;s story ends just because they win their true love.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mosquitoes, Science, and Science Fiction: Who&#8217;s Going to Save Us From What Comes Next?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/mosquitoes-science-and-science-fiction-whos-going-to-save-us-from-what-comes-next/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 15:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6470</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Late spring in North Texas brings with it warmer nights, more thunderstorms, and, alas, mosquitoes.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Late spring in North Texas brings with it warmer nights, more thunderstorms, and, alas, mosquitoes. Many, many mosquitoes. Some bite during the day, others bite at dawn and dusk. We all cover up in long sleeves and douse ourselves in whatever promises to keep the critters from feasting on us, but the welts show up just the same.</p>
<p>Given the continued threat in the area of mosquito-borne diseases such as West Nile, St. Louis encephalitis, dengue, and chikungunya, and the possibility of Zika, we&#8217;re on even higher alert. Most of these diseases can be deadly, and Zika&#8217;s correlation with microcephaly makes it doubly dangerous. We have repellants that work, and most cities around here spray regularly for mosquitoes. But we have to ask ourselves, is it enough?</p>
<p>One solution that looks promising has already been implemented in Brazil, where the outbreak has already caused significant harm. Earlier this year, <a href="http://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2016/01/26/464464459/genetically-modified-mosquitoes-join-the-fight-to-stop-zika-virus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NPR </a>reported on Oxitech, a British company that released genetically-modified male mosquitoes whose offspring die before adulthood. This has led to a reduction in the population of the mosquitoes that carry the Zika virus. If it worked in Brazil, why not bring the solution here?</p>
<p>In a phrase: genetically modified organisms, or GMOs. To many, the phrase evokes associations with scary possibilities, but studies point to the general safety of GMOs. According to an article in <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2016/feb/16/who-paves-way-for-use-of-genetically-modified-mosquitoes-to-combat-zika" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><i>The Guardian</i></a>, the World Health Organization encouraged the use of GMO mosquitoes to combat the virus, though more research is needed. In this situation, the benefits outweigh the known risks.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/index.png"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6477 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/index.png" alt="index" width="177" height="284" /></a>So what does this have to do with science fiction? I think the way this story is unfolding bears examination. Recently, I read <a href="http://nancykress.com/">Nancy Kress</a>&#8216; Nebula Award winning novella <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13163688-after-the-fall-before-the-fall-during-the-fall"><i>After the Fall, Before the Fall, During the Fall</i></a>, and I think it provides a useful metaphor for the way lay people see technology. In the novella, life on earth has been all but destroyed, and only a handful of people remain in the protective Shell, a habitat provided to them by aliens they call the Tesslies. The people suspect the Tesslies destroyed most life on earth and are now keeping them in the Shell and providing them with technology to live and to regenerate the human population for devious purposes. But in fact Earth, in essence, destroyed life to save itself. The Tesslies saved those whom they could, and sheltered them until the environment was suitable for human life again.</p>
<p>We see the Tesslies through fifteen-year old Pete&#8217;s eyes as a sort of “black box”: he doesn’t know if the metal outer casing of the one Tesslie he encounters houses a robot or a living being. His life, and that of all of those in the Shell, is hardly a happy one; it&#8217;s one of monotony and hardship, and he lacks true companionship. All of this, he thinks, is the fault of the Tesslies. Thoughts of revenge consume him until he learns the truth about the Tesslies&#8217; intentions. They do far more good than harm, even if they are, to him and the other people, unknowable.</p>
<p>While aliens are not going to come down and exterminate all mosquitoes from Earth—though we can hope, can&#8217;t we?—we can take a lesson from Kress&#8217; story. Time is short, mosquitoes are here, and they may begin to carry Zika in the U.S. before we know it. The GMO technology exists for combating the <em>Aedes aegypti</em> mosquito. Now, we just need to find a way to tell the story of the GMO mosquitoes that pushes people past their beliefs that it will cause more harm than good.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dr. Sabrina Starnaman Q&#038;A: Creating and Teaching SF as Literature Classes</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/dr-sabrina-starnaman-qa-creating-and-teaching-sf-as-literature-classes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6348</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently, I interviewed Dr. Sabrina Starnaman, Clinical Assistant Professor of Literary Studies at The University of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>Recently, I interviewed Dr.<a href="http://sabrinastarnaman.com/"> Sabrina Starnaman</a>, Clinical Assistant Professor of <a href="https://www.utdallas.edu/ah/programs/literature/">Literary Studies at The University of Texas at Dallas</a>, who teaches science fiction and fantasy as literature courses.  Some of the classes she has taught include &#8220;The Hero’s Journey,&#8221; &#8220;LeGuin and Butler,&#8221; and &#8220;Cyborgs and Robots.&#8221;  Her research focuses include American literature written by and about women, and representations of bodies, specifically representations of gender and disability.  This is the first half of the Q&amp;A.  Next month, we&#8217;ll conclude the conversation with Dr. Starnaman with questions about her research as it relates to SF, how the classes have evolved, and a few recommended readings.</div>
<div>
<p><b>rwx:</b> Your class changes every semester. Why new texts and themes every semester?</p>
<p><b>Dr. Starnaman: </b>That&#8217;s a actually a really good question. The courses I teach—they&#8217;re literature of science fiction and literature of fantasy—are courses the students can take more than one time. They can take them twice, as long as the topics are different. I like to have at least a couple of versions of each course in rotation so that students can take it more than one time.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s good for me in a couple of ways. One, it&#8217;s great because having repeat students means that they already have some of the critical and theoretical materials mastered. Also, it means that they have a background in texts. So for example this semester, this past week, we read N.K. Jemison&#8217;s <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19161852-the-fifth-season"><i>The Fifth Season</i></a>, her book that came out in August 2015. And Jemison states that her two main influences were Ursula K. LeGuin and Octavia Butler. Because my students take my class more than once, I have a whole bunch of students in class who took my Octavia Butler and Ursula LeGuin course last semester. <span style="color: #000000;">In a </span>sense<span style="color: #000000;"> it is</span> self-serving<span style="color: #000000;">&#8212;</span>I get the pleasure of teaching students that have already read books I think are important.</p>
<p>And then the last reason is because I am hopelessly curious and therefore I am always interested in designing something new and something that piques my interest and satisfies my own curiosity.</p>
<p><b>rwx:</b> How do you go about selecting texts for the class? Do you have students read theory as well as short stories and novels?</p>
<p><b>Dr. Starnaman: </b><span style="color: #000000;">Man</span>y of my classes are thematic. For instance, I&#8217;m getting ready to teach a Science Fiction course about Robots and Cyborgs <span style="color: #000000;">in the fall. I </span><span style="color: #000000;">am</span> actually not terribly interested in robots or cyborgs; however, I am interested in the questions that robots and cyborgs raise. <span style="color: #000000;">F</span>or instance, what makes us human? How do we evolve as a people in changing culture? I look for texts that allow us to engage with those questions. I also look for texts that will allow me to scaffold the discussion, starting at a basic level.</p>
<p>To begin, the students read a rather direct story and we discuss the issues it raises. And then we can work toward more sophisticated and demanding stories, and more sophisticated and demanding questions. For example, in the Robots and Cyborgs class, I start with “<a href="http://digital.library.upenn.edu/women/fuller/arena/order.html">A Wife Manufactured to Order</a>,” which was written in the late 19<sup>th</sup> century and isn&#8217;t particularly well known. It&#8217;s a story about a man whose girlfriend is a suffragette, and he is annoyed with the demands that his girlfriend&#8217;s political involvement place on him. He commissions a animatronic wife made out of wax and she ends up not being everything he hoped that she would be. It&#8217;s a fembot story, our first fembot story in a series of fembot stories. We read <a href="http://my.fit.edu/~rosiene/delrey.pdf">“<span lang="en">Helen O&#8217;Loy</span>”</a>, by Lester del Rey which is a canonical fembot story; then we watch <i><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52350.The_Stepford_Wives">The Stepford Wives</a>.</i> In this way we move through a series of fembot stories and they allow us to talk about gender, women&#8217;s roles, and how women&#8217;s bodies are portrayed in texts. And then we move on to another set of stories about robots as laborers, so we have a series of books in which we discuss a scaffolding set of questions about labor and power.</p>
<p>Usually the last story I teach in that class, Pat Cadigan&#8217;s “The Girl Thing Who Went Out for Sushi,” is also a labor story, but it also can be a book about choosing to change our bodies completely. &#8220;Girl Thing&#8221; is a story about people working in outer space. The workers change their human bodies into entities that are like underwater sea creatures because that works the best for weightless environment. The story focuses on one young woman who goes through this transformation. By the time we get to the end of the semester, the students will say things like “this is a story about being transgender,” and they will be able to take a lot of the ideas we&#8217;ve been working on all semester and apply them to this story in a more sophisticated way.<i><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Ss-mad-max-fury-road-103k.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-6371" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Ss-mad-max-fury-road-103k-681x1024.jpg" alt="Ss-mad-max-fury-road-103k" width="400" height="602" /></a></i></p>
<p>In terms of reading theory at the undergraduate level, sometimes we read snippets and excerpts of critical theory. My students are more often than not non-literature majors. So we often have to start with questions like how do you bring questions of labor justice to a book? How do you bring questions about gender normativity to a book? The students are introduced to theory through short lectures or short passages, like a passage about Freud&#8217;s uncanny, and we&#8217;ll read that in class and discuss it. At the graduate level, we most assuredly read critical theory.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m teaching a new class right now called “The Hero&#8217;s Journey”—and we start with Joseph Campbell, though we do some Ring Theory and other theoretical understandings about how heroic fantasy stories are structured. But I started my class—my class is also two-thirds men—with classic hero tales with male characters. We started with <i>Star Wars</i> and then we went to <i>Gilgamesh </i>and then we did Howard&#8217;s Conan and Moorcock&#8217;s Elric stories. And then I introduced C.L. Moore&#8217;s Jirel of Joiry, who is a female character written at the same time as Conan.</p>
<p>Two weeks ago where we were going to discuss two stories about sword wielding heroines and Furiosa from <i>Mad Max: Fury Road—</i>a gun-wielding heroine. I was prepared to talk about female heroes who don&#8217;t behave in a gender normative manner, but the students had so little problem with that aspect of the stories that we ended up talking about how Ring Composition is evident in <i>Fury Road.</i> At the end of class a young woman came up and asked me “Can you tell me what you had <i>intended</i> today&#8217;s class to be about?” She had figured it out on her own that there was a point to the stories and movie, that we hadn&#8217;t discussed. I was so impressed that she had figured that out, and I said “Well, today was supposed to be the day when everybody got comfortable with the idea that there are female heroines who carry swords and use guns and are tough in a very physical way but are also still women. But no one seems to be having a problem with it.” My plan had been to tackle the tough issue that not all heroes are straight men&#8211;we had reached that point in the semester where from here on out many of our characters are queer, and women and trans*&#8211;but they just didn&#8217;t seem to need any introduction to that issue.</p>
<p>And then for this week, we read a story with a queer relationship in it and a trans* character in it, and they didn&#8217;t even mention it. It wasn&#8217;t as if they didn&#8217;t mention it because they didn&#8217;t notice it. I think they didn&#8217;t mention it because it didn&#8217;t strike them as unusual. And so I&#8217;m not sure if I&#8217;m simply attracting different students now, if I have simply had so many students in my classes that my student body is coming already educated, or if the students themselves have simply evolved to be far more savvy about issues of gender, race, class, sexuality, that sort of thing.</p>
<p>A student announced in class that the trans* character in Jemison&#8217;s book was the first trans* character he&#8217;d ever encountered in a book for school. This experience, he told the class, made him very happy.</p>
<p><b>rwx:</b> This is a literature class, but so much of speculative fiction falls outside the traditional words-on-a-page text. Do you incorporate other media in your classes?</p>
<p><b><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/index-2.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6370 size-full" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/index-2.jpg" alt="index" width="191" height="264" /></a>Dr. Starnaman: </b>Absolutely. This semester we watched <i>Star Wars</i>, and in fact, we started with Joseph Campbell and then <i>Star Wars</i> as a baby step into the larger question of the narrative structure of the Hero&#8217;s Journey. Part of the reason I did that was because almost all the students had seen <i>Star Wars</i> before. Therefore, it was pretty easy for the students to apply Campbell&#8217;s monomyth structure to a text they found familiar.</p>
<p>But then we took the Ring Cycle, which was novel to my students—it&#8217;s not necessarily in terms of the study of literature, but for my students, the Ring Cycle was novel—and used it to do an analysis of <i>Mad Max: Fury Road.</i></p>
<p>In my Robots and Cyborgs class, I definitely will bring in some episodes of <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2085059/"><i>Black Mirror</i></a>, which is a BBC Channel 4 production. It is an incredibly smart television show that looks critically at living in a digital age.</p>
<p>Because so many of my students are avid gamers and are studying game design at UTD, I&#8217;ve had learn a bit about video games. Sometimes we discuss the relationship between game narrative and fiction. Recently, I asked my students to think about how a text could be adapted for the video game medium. We&#8217;d just read N.K. Jemison&#8217;s <i>The Fifth Season</i>, and the structure of the point of view characters is very complex. I asked the students to think about how you would make the book into a game and maintain the complex narrative structure&#8211;to meet the narrative goal of the book. The discussion was incredibly interesting. We had a vibrant discussion about how Jemison constructed the book to elicit a particular experience for the reader, and then how one might construct a digital interface that would engage the reader/player in a similar process.</p>
<p>Not only do we use other media we also talk about the relationship between different narrative modes and science fiction canon. For instance, anyone who wants to work on robots in fiction, gaming, or film should know Isaac Asimov&#8217;s Robot stories. They are the foundation of the robot genre in America.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Poetry Month: One More Way to Celebrate</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/national-poetry-month-one-more-way-to-celebrate/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 16:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here in the US, the Academy of American Poets recognizes April as National Poetry Month,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here in the US, the Academy of American Poets recognizes April as <a href="https://www.poets.org/national-poetry-month/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">National Poetry Month</a>, a time to highlight the importance of poetry in the public sphere and to support the writing, reading, and teaching of poetry. The AAP suggests <a href="https://www.poets.org/national-poetry-month/30-ways-celebrate-national-poetry-month" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">thirty ways to celebrate</a> National Poetry Month, which includes reading poems and reading about poetry among other great ways to enjoy poems privately and publicly.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/TLTNPM.png" rel="attachment wp-att-6223"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-6223 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/TLTNPM-300x142.png" alt="TLTNPM" width="300" height="142" /></a>As March ends, I&#8217;d like to offer a thirty-first suggestion: find a poem for the month and make it yours.</p>
<p>This seems counter to the idea of celebrating poetry in general at first, I know, since it would be more in the spirit of the month to set aside time in April to read whole anthologies, collections, journal issues, and so on. And I do think we should do that too—not only in April but year-round. Poetry is deceptive in its length, however. We read through poems, perhaps pausing a bit over words here and there to savor them. Most often, after these short visits, we breathe out then we&#8217;re on to the next one. Which is a shame, really. By the nature of the genre, well constructed, beautifully crafted poems won&#8217;t reveal everything on first readings. We need to come back to them to really know them, to be moved as far as we can by what the poet has created.</p>
<p>So I&#8217;d like to recommend that you pick a poem for April and get to know it. The poem can be an old favorite or a new find, speculative or traditional in genre, free verse or formal. An epic poem might work, but for the sort of activity I&#8217;m suggesting, a shorter lyric poem would be better: a sonnet, an ode, an elegy, or whatever strikes you.</p>
<p>Read the poem on the first, then put it away for a day or two. Come back to the poem and reread it. Consider how the second, third, fourth, and so on, readings differ from the first. Though you know the ending of the poem, and it may not surprise you on rereading, does it still satisfy you?</p>
<p>Each time you revisit the poem, read it in different modes. Read silently the first time, then aloud the next. Read the poem aloud by yourself once, then read it aloud to a friend or family member. Read it (if it&#8217;s appropriate to do so) to a child. How do your listeners react? Poetry is conversation: it speaks to each of us in different ways.</p>
<p>Read the poem at different times of day. We&#8217;re different in the morning from the people we are midday and the people we are just before we fall asleep at night. How does your perception of the poem change when you are (hopefully) refreshed from a good night&#8217;s sleep? In the middle of a busy day? Preparing to go out for an evening? Or curled up on the couch at the end of a long day?</p>
<p>Listen for the music in the poem. Don&#8217;t scan for meter—that can be counterproductive to your enjoyment of the poem. Remember, this is an act of acquainting yourself with something beautiful or compelling or shocking or consoling or maybe all of these things. It&#8217;s not an academic exercise. Just listen to the music, the way you&#8217;d listen to a familiar song. What do you hear? How does it affect how you perceive the content of the poem?</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t try to memorize the poem. Instead, notice which phrases and lines stay with you and which ones slip away from your thoughts between readings. You may have the poem memorized at the end of the month regardless. Again, this is not an academic exercise. Think of it as more of a walk through a park. You don&#8217;t need to write every tree, every swing set, every light pole, and so on to your mental map of the place to get a good feel for where you are. You just need to stay on the given path and enjoy.</p>
<p>And at the end of the month, ask yourself how you&#8217;ve changed as an audience for the poem. I hope you&#8217;ll end up with not only a deeper appreciation for the poem, but also a deeper appreciation for yourself as a reader.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gender, Names, and Publishing Under Initials</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/gender-names-and-publishing-under-initials/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[T.D. Walker]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 16:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[rwx: Read/Write/eXplicate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a recent post on her website, Mary Robinette Kowal noted that the percentage of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a recent <a href="http://maryrobinettekowal.com/journal/women-sff-survey/">post </a>on her website, Mary Robinette Kowal noted that the percentage of SFF books available for purchase at airport bookstores that were written by women and non-binary authors was alarmingly small in comparison to those written by men. Her explanation of her methodology struck me: “If I couldn’t tell and/or didn’t know, because the author used initials or a gender neutral name, I counted them as male. The reason I did this, instead of leaving them out, is because I was looking at the perception of gender rather than actual gender.” Though I don&#8217;t have a book out, I do have poems and essays published online and in print journals, and I&#8217;ve always published under my initials.</p>
<p>And so I asked myself, am I part of the problem?</p>
<p>So, first, a little history. When I began submitting poems in the early 2000s, I hesitated before typing my full first name on the top left of my poems. My impulse wasn&#8217;t to obscure my gender; in fact, the creative writing faculties at the universities I attended were pretty balanced with regard to gender. The professor who was my mentor and thesis director at my master&#8217;s program is a woman. And I never found the academic literary poetry scene to be nearly as unfriendly to non-men as the SFF scene can be (that&#8217;s not to say there wasn&#8217;t discrimination against women, only that I didn&#8217;t experience it first-hand. In fact, I know now that problematic behavior occurred, but it wasn&#8217;t on my radar at the time).</p>
<p>The problem wasn&#8217;t that I wanted to hide my gender. I wanted, rather, to hide my little-girl name. My first name, the one on my birth certificate, the one that has wafted around me my whole life like the scent of pink cupcakes, is a nickname. It&#8217;s a name that points to the fact that yes, she&#8217;s that ditzy blonde girl from Texas who has lots of spunk to make up for her lack of smarts but hey, hey, it&#8217;s okay, &#8217;cause the boys all love her anyway. It&#8217;s a name that wears ribbons in its hair, cut off jean shorts, and drives a truck. It&#8217;s a name that wears too much eye makeup and is always, always sincere.</p>
<p>My name—or the common perception of my name—is pretty much the antithesis of who I am.</p>
<p>I may be from Texas, but I have about as much spunk as a dead armadillo. The last time I wore hair ribbons, I was probably eight years old. I can&#8217;t tell you the last time I wore makeup. I&#8217;m not blonde (anymore). I&#8217;ve never driven a truck. I am not my first name.</p>
<p>So I used my initials in order to appear more professional, especially since my poems have a southern aesthetic and often explore women&#8217;s lives. I didn&#8217;t think much at the time when I received mail addressed to “Mr. Walker.” I didn&#8217;t correct this error. But I was pretty clear in my bios about using “she” and “her.” When I began writing again a few years ago after a too long hiatus, I submitted under my initials again. The solution to my name problem worked before, so why not use it again? I wanted that sense of continuity—I wasn&#8217;t completely new to the publishing world.</p>
<p>That said, I wonder now if there wasn&#8217;t a better solution to the problem that I should have used when I was first starting out. The names for which my first name is a nickname for don&#8217;t have the same problem as the nickname itself. I could have used one of those. Maybe I should have worked to reclaim my name from its image. The few women I&#8217;ve met who share my name didn&#8217;t strike me as particularly girly. Or I could have used my middle name. I&#8217;d gone by my middle name briefly in college, but several people knew my first name, and they used both. If my first name alone is a pink frosted cupcake, then both together is that frosted cupcake with a good shake of sprinkles on top. So I dropped my middle name along with my accent.</p>
<p>Regardless of what I could have done, I don&#8217;t plan on publishing under a different name now. I&#8217;m T.D. Walker. I&#8217;m a woman. I&#8217;m not interested in hiding that fact. But that I have obscured my gender makes me part of the problem.</p>
<p>So I&#8217;ll keep saying it. I&#8217;m T.D. Walker. I&#8217;m a woman. And I hope that repeating that fact in bios, essays, blog posts, etc. will mean that in some small way, I can be part of the solution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
