<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 040 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-040/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 04:39:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 040 Author Interview: Allyson Shaw and &#8220;Gald&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-040-author-interview-allyson-shaw-and-gald/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 11:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 040]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17364</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to our chat with Issue 040 author Allyson Shaw where we discuss her short&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to our chat with<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-040/"> Issue 040</a> author Allyson Shaw where we discuss her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/gald/">Gald</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: There’s a rich backstory here that’s not overly explained, but rather hinted at through the narrator. What would you say are the pros and cons of letting readers fill in the blanks when it comes to world building?</strong></em></p>
<p>Allyson: Genre has such transportive powers. As readers we can be immersed in strange new places. I love the sensation of wonder I get from reading invented worlds, and I trust readers will be great lone travelers in these worlds I build. As a writer I wonder how much of a tour guide I need to be. Will the reader be able to travel lightly and happily with what I give them? “Gald” started out much longer, and kept ballooning out with each draft so that it seemed to want to be a novel. I finally edited it down so that it would flow and be contained as a shorter piece, hoping that the reader would be familiar enough with dystopian tropes that they could come along.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your use of foreshadowing is the best I’ve read in awhile! Do you have any tips for effective foreshadowing?</strong></em></p>
<p>Allyson: Thank you! I used to think fiction was a dance of veils—that you dazzle the reader with hints and hopes and finally show them some sort of heart or truth. But I no longer like that metaphor, preferring instead to think of foreshadowing as breadcrumbs through a forest. I love <img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17365 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/lukasz-szmigiel-jFCViYFYcus-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/lukasz-szmigiel-jFCViYFYcus-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/lukasz-szmigiel-jFCViYFYcus-unsplash-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/lukasz-szmigiel-jFCViYFYcus-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/lukasz-szmigiel-jFCViYFYcus-unsplash-1536x1023.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/lukasz-szmigiel-jFCViYFYcus-unsplash-2048x1364.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />that in fairy tales this is often done in threes, so that the reader is already doing a kind of adding up as the story progresses. Writing and reading is a process of discovery, so the crumbs—repeated narrative detail—stay in my mind and hopefully that of the reader. They will add up, creating momentum and the summation will feel inevitable.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: If you had a potion that could transform you into something, what would you want that to be?</strong></em></p>
<p>Allyson: Great question! It’s a hard one. The stories in this issue of <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> have inspired possibilities in my mind. I love that so many of the stories show women creating something in friendship and collaboration, kind of like <em>LSQ</em> itself, but I digress! I have multiple disabling chronic illnesses (I’m also a metalsmith so it perhaps comes with the territory of being a smith, who were often disabled in myth). I thought wouldn’t it be great to have a potion that cured me? I’d love a potion that would let me read faster. Surely that wouldn’t upset the order of the universe too much, right?</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></p>
<p>Allyson: I am traveling around Scotland researching, documenting and writing up field notes about the many memorials to women murdered during the witch trials in Scotland. Thousands were killed, and their deaths mark the landscape in every town and village, if you know how to look. This writing is an act of witness and remembrance for me and, I hope, for my readers. I regularly post short pieces based on my field notes to my Patreon. (<a href="https://www.patreon.com/Allysonshaw" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.patreon.com/Allysonshaw&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1582550569464000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFxW-1adgcUi0TYWYbj9Zr1APho4w">http://www.patreon.com/<wbr />Allysonshaw</a>). I am developing this project into a longer work as well, which I hope to be a book.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 040 Author Interview: Laura J. Campbell and &#8220;Slipping Through the Stars&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-040-author-interview-laura-j-campbell-and-slipping-through-the-stars/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 11:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 040]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear readers! Grab a cup of your favorite drink and sit down and enjoy our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17322 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/david-menidrey-zpUsOQzByFg-unsplash-300x169.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="169" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/david-menidrey-zpUsOQzByFg-unsplash-300x169.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/david-menidrey-zpUsOQzByFg-unsplash-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/david-menidrey-zpUsOQzByFg-unsplash-768x432.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/david-menidrey-zpUsOQzByFg-unsplash-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/david-menidrey-zpUsOQzByFg-unsplash-2048x1152.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Dear readers! Grab a cup of your favorite drink and sit down and enjoy our chat with Issue 040 author Laura J. Campbell about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/slipping-through-the-stars/">Slipping Through the Stars</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What made you go for a political domination angle rather than the more typical hostile alien takeover angle that stories focused on human space exploration tend to go with?</strong></em></p>
<p>Laura: I think that when we enter space – colonization, distant exploration – we’ll take our human condition with us. The concept of how we will handle our own drama on an intergalactic scale fascinates me. It is a projection of our current world; yes, there are hostile threats from afar, but the politics and power plays of the neighborhood are more immediate. I simply projected that onto an intergalactic stage.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Your characters are all very focused on their roles, but they still read as people who are unique and likable. How do you pull this off?</strong></em></p>
<p>Laura: Living in Houston I am very much surrounded by people like this. Houston is a vibrantly diverse city; it is also a highly technical city. The city has one of the world’s foremost medical centers, NASA, and is an international hub for the energy industry and law. Many of my friends and colleagues are involved in space exploration, surgery, highly specialized areas of law, or the energy sector – all have to be extremely focused on their roles. Yet when you get to know people, they are multifaceted (even quirky). The professional careers are in juxtaposition with musical side-gigs, painting, culinary pursuits, sports, and other activities. So that concept of extreme focus in balance with a personal life comes naturally.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Mary Osprey is such an awesome character with huge potential for more <img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17321 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bryan-goff-f7YQo-eYHdM-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bryan-goff-f7YQo-eYHdM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bryan-goff-f7YQo-eYHdM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bryan-goff-f7YQo-eYHdM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bryan-goff-f7YQo-eYHdM-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bryan-goff-f7YQo-eYHdM-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />adventures. Do you have any future plans for her, or more stories set in this world in general?</strong></em></p>
<p>Laura: Absolutely. The Earth Secret Service and the Mars Colony have taken on a life of their own. As for Dr. Osprey, I can’t imagine Queen Rigel not providing plenty of opportunities for future adventures. <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any writers who have influenced your work?</strong></em></p>
<p>Laura: Definitely Edgar Allen Poe – his works were read to me as a child. Also Kipling, Dickens. I have to give a shout-out to Mary Shelley &#8211; I think that by writing <em>Frankenstein; or, The Modern Prometheus,</em> she opened the door for women writing in horror and science fiction. Likewise Dorothy L. Sayers and Dame Agatha Mary Clarissa Christie, Lady Mallowan, DBE, who opened up the world of mystery. And the Brontë sisters, who wove wonderful dark worlds. In the modern era, I think films also have an influence – John Carpenter and Alfred Hitchcock, for example. I tend to not rely upon shock or graphical detail – I try to intentionally leave shadows for the reader to fill with their own wonder or dread.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 040 Author Interview: Emilee Martell and &#8220;Nora&#8217;s Potion Jar&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-040-author-interview-emilee-martell-and-noras-potion-jar/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 11:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 040]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello, dear readers, and welcome to our latest chat with an Issue 040 author. Today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello, dear readers, and welcome to our latest chat with an Issue 040 author. Today we talk with Emilee Martell about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/noras-potion-jar/">Nora&#8217;s Potion Jar</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This issue’s theme is “potions and poisons.” What drew you to this theme, and why choose a little girl as a protagonist?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emilee: I was drawn to this issue&#8217;s theme because it seemed to lend itself so well to fantasy, a genre that I wanted to explore more in my short stories. I actually first wrote a story that focused on the &#8220;poison&#8221; part of the theme, which predictably ended up full of murder and mayhem. I decided it wasn&#8217;t a good fit for <em>Luna Station,</em> though. I tried to write a new story on theme, but kept hitting a wall. Finally, a certain Tumblr post reminded me of a great way to tie in the &#8220;potion&#8221; <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17249 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/jonas-weckschmied-N_UwPdUs7E-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/jonas-weckschmied-N_UwPdUs7E-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/jonas-weckschmied-N_UwPdUs7E-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/jonas-weckschmied-N_UwPdUs7E-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/jonas-weckschmied-N_UwPdUs7E-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/jonas-weckschmied-N_UwPdUs7E-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />theme: the near-universal experience of going out into the yard as a five-year-old to concoct a magic brew out of whatever happened to be laying out in the grass. The reversal from a dark murder story to a lighthearted child&#8217;s fantasy turned out to be just what I needed.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What are the challenges in writing a story about a child without it turning too childish for an adult audience?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emilee: I&#8217;ll admit I was anxious about this! There&#8217;s certainly still a campy, warm-and-fuzzy, &#8220;the magic was inside you all along!&#8221; element to the story. But I tried to make that feel genuine, like a special moment in Nora&#8217;s life, instead of a tired trope. Overall, I wanted to write the way a child thinks: straightforward and laser-focused &#8211; at least when they&#8217;ve given themselves a job. It doesn&#8217;t occur to Nora that this anything other than serious business.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any writers who have influenced your work?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emilee: For this story in particular, I actually thought a lot about Calvin and Hobbes, which was a great favorite of mine growing up, and its creator, Bill Watterson. Like Nora, Calvin has fantastical adventures that, for him, are just part of his everyday life. I read somewhere that the magic of Calvin and Hobbes came from Watterson&#8217;s utter commitment to the world he crafted in this comic; the characters never break the fourth wall, never speculate about why they do what they do. Watterson never blinks. That was what I was trying to replicate in &#8220;Nora&#8217;s Potion Jar&#8221;: a kind of colorful whimsy that&#8217;s only prevented from being cutesy by the fact that to the protagonist, it&#8217;s pretty mundane.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</strong></em></p>
<p>Emilee: I always have a long list of projects! Right now, I&#8217;m trying to find a home for the above-mentioned murder story, and finish a very strange nonfiction piece about how Asian raccoon dogs nearly became an invasive species in the American Midwest. But I&#8217;ve had to put my short fiction on the back burner for the moment: I&#8217;m in Pitch Wars and madly revising an adult sci-fi novel through February. It&#8217;s about a social worker, a gang lord, and a government agent uncovering magic and corruption in a high-tech city, and needless to say, it is not nearly as lighthearted as &#8220;Nora&#8217;s Potion Jar&#8221; &#8211; though it has its moments!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 040 Author Interview: Nicole  Lungerhausen and &#8220;Tell Me Something Good&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-040-author-interview-nicole-lungerhausen-and-tell-me-something-good/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 11:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 040]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to our chat with Nicole Lungerhausen, Issue 040 author of the short story &#8220;Tell&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to our chat with Nicole Lungerhausen, Issue 040 author of the short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/tell-me-something-good/">Tell Me Something Good</a>&#8220;!</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: There are plenty of stories about men having doubts about fatherhood when their wives are pregnant, but yours has a woman in that role. What made you decide to take this road less traveled?</b></em></p>
<p>Nicole: I wish I could say that I made a conscious decision from the start to take the road less traveled. It probably would’ve taken me a lot less time and fewer drafts to write the story if I had! But as with most things I write, I didn’t really decide what kind of story “Tell Me Something Good” was going to be, so much as have Naomi and Jenn, the main characters, show up on my right brain doorstep and say, “Hey, you don’t know us but we’re here to visit. And we’re going to stay awhile because we’ve got some things to say.”</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17188 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bruce-christianson-XyZxxJI8g30-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bruce-christianson-XyZxxJI8g30-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bruce-christianson-XyZxxJI8g30-unsplash-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bruce-christianson-XyZxxJI8g30-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bruce-christianson-XyZxxJI8g30-unsplash-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/bruce-christianson-XyZxxJI8g30-unsplash-2048x1368.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Although Naomi and Jenn arrived together, Naomi was the point of view character from the beginning. I was really interested in her perspective because she is so directionless and seems to carry a lot of unacknowledged fear. On one hand, this makes total sense because she’s recently gotten out of prison and is trying to put her life back together. But the way Naomi exists in the world also comes from getting the message from her parents in her youth that what she wants is unacceptable. For her, it’s easier to live without thinking about her own wants at all.</p>
<p>Then enters Jenn, who is so driven, clear, and ambitious about what she wants to do with her life, and Naomi falls under the spell of all that charisma and buoyant energy. I wanted to explore how and why a person will go along with the desires of the person they love and not question whether they share those same desires until it’s too late. Putting Naomi right into the thick of big life stuff with marriage, pregnancy, and impending motherhood seemed like a good way to go about that exploration.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: What makes Dream Awake daydreams different from regular daydreams?</b></em></p>
<p>Nicole: I imagined Dream Awake as making regular daydreams into more immersive full-sensory experiences. I know when I daydream, sight and sound are most prominent and I experience the other senses far less or not at all. With Dream Awake, all the senses are involved: sight, sound, taste, touch, smell. While I envisioned Dream Awake as allowing the user to be more directed about what they want to experience, it is definitely not a perfect VR nanotech drug. In Naomi’s case, her use of Dream Awake somewhat backfires because the drug ends up manifesting the desires of her unconscious mind, rather than the good life with Jenn she believes she wants.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: What do you think you would see if you did Dream Awake?</b></em></p>
<p>Nicole: Oooh, that’s a good question. It stumped me for a bit. . .</p>
<p>The smart-ass answer, courtesy of that sublime 80s movie <i>Real Genius, </i>is that I’d see myself standing in sort of sun-god robes on a pyramid with a thousand naked people screaming and throwing little pickles at me.</p>
<p>The real answer is far more mundane. If I did Dream Awake, I’d want to see an event I’ve already experienced in my life. Like the last time I snorkeled at the Waipio tidepools on the Big Island of Hawaii before they were wiped out by the Kilauea eruption in 2018. Or my first bite of this white chocolate mousse they served at my grandparents 30th anniversary wedding party when I was seven years old; it’s my first food memory and I’d love to experience it again.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: What was the most challenging part of this story to write and why? What was the most enjoyable and why?</b></em></p>
<p>Nicole: The toughest part for me was figuring out Naomi’s journey. In the first draft of the story, I had Naomi and Jenn doing Dream Awake together in their apartment. Jenn was in the process of trying to get pregnant and the big secret that was revealed during the couple’s Dream Awake experience was that Naomi had been in prison. And that was pretty much the end of the story.</p>
<p>When my critique group looked at this first draft, they were kind but also put my feet to the fire and said, in the nicest way possible,  “Is this <i>really</i> what the story is about? We think you can do better.”</p>
<p>All told, I did about 20 drafts of this story, and it was only when I got up around draft #14 or #15 that I finally figured out Naomi’s journey. And that was thanks to a revision exercise in this terrific writing book called <i>Naming the World</i>. The exercise asks you to incorporate a gift into the next draft of a story lacking adequate conflict. When I revised the story based on this prompt, a bunch of things fell into place. Like the fact that being in prison isn’t the secret Naomi is keeping from Jenn; it’s that she has major doubts about becoming a mother and being part of a family. And also that Jenn should be pregnant at the start of the story so as to give Naomi’s quest greater urgency.</p>
<p>One of the most enjoyable parts of writing this story was fleshing out the relationship between <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17187 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/sharon-mccutcheon-bLYDlu0rC20-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/sharon-mccutcheon-bLYDlu0rC20-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/sharon-mccutcheon-bLYDlu0rC20-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/sharon-mccutcheon-bLYDlu0rC20-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/sharon-mccutcheon-bLYDlu0rC20-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/sharon-mccutcheon-bLYDlu0rC20-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Naomi and Jenn. I love how they interact together and play off each other, the sense of humor they share, the love they have for each other, even in the midst of struggle. Me and my husband are very much a classic “opposites attract” couple, so I had a good time writing a same-sex couple who have a similar dynamic.</p>
<p>I also enjoyed writing the scene between Naomi and her father. I hadn’t included any scenes with her parents in the early drafts. But once I got a better handle on Naomi’s journey, I wondered if it would make sense to include a scene between her and her parents. I drafted it, figuring at the very least I’d get some useful back story out of it. The scene ended up being so easy to write &#8211; what you see in the finished story is very close to that first draft – and fit so well within the story. This was an unexpected treat, considering all the other scenes in the story were much harder for me to get right!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 040 Author Interview: Sarah McGill and &#8220;Bone to Bleeding Bone&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-040-author-interview-sarah-mcgill-and-bone-to-bleeding-bone/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 040]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re very excited to share with you all a recent chat we had with Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17133 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/camilo-jimenez-OermHGSUzhI-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/camilo-jimenez-OermHGSUzhI-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/camilo-jimenez-OermHGSUzhI-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/camilo-jimenez-OermHGSUzhI-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/camilo-jimenez-OermHGSUzhI-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/camilo-jimenez-OermHGSUzhI-unsplash-1366x2048.jpg 1366w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/camilo-jimenez-OermHGSUzhI-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />We&#8217;re very excited to share with you all a recent chat we had with Issue 040 author Sarah McGill about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/bone-to-bleeding-bone/">Bone to Bleeding Bone</a>&#8220;!</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story takes the wicked stepsister trope and turns it on its head. What was your inspiration behind this? </strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: This is a story about two sisters forced into the roles of wickedness and kindness. The step-sister story is such a natural way into that because the characters are already cast in those roles. It’s also a story about two sisters who are deeply uncomfortable with the parts they have to play and yet never get to learn that they could be something other than just wicked or kind. They attempt to find solace in the opposite of what they are, but in the end both roles are too narrow and constricting to make them happy. Turning the archetypes on their heads was a way to call attention to those roles and indicate their fabricated nature right at the beginning.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The imagery in this story, from ruby-studded smiles to monstrous pearl children, are all very striking. Where do you get the ideas for these images?</strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: The story was originally based on &#8220;Diamonds and Toads&#8221;, a fairy tale where a good sister is gifted the ability to spit diamonds and jewels while the bad sister is punished with spitting toads <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17134 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/priscilla-du-preez-CoqJGsFVJtM-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/priscilla-du-preez-CoqJGsFVJtM-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/priscilla-du-preez-CoqJGsFVJtM-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/priscilla-du-preez-CoqJGsFVJtM-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/priscilla-du-preez-CoqJGsFVJtM-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/priscilla-du-preez-CoqJGsFVJtM-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />and snakes. As lovely as spitting diamonds and jewels is meant to be, there’s an inherently visceral quality to anything that comes out of our mouths. I wanted to explore how the characters’ identities grow from and into these jewels. The sisters use the pearls to put on façades of both monstrousness and beauty in an attempt to garner affection and love, especially from each other. Yet the step-sister grows into her own monstrous façade and births monsters of her own.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was your favorite part about writing this story and why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Sarah: My stories often begin with a specific image and for this one the first image was the tree growing out of the step-sister’s chest. I’m very taken by hearts-that-are-not-hearts and spinning reality past its natural conclusion, so I loved the idea of Nourie replacing her step-sister’s heart with an apple, which then grows into a tree. Exploring that imagery, the idea of rootedness and interconnectedness, and – let’s be honest – the gore of it was a great deal of fun.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 040 Author Interview: Rebecca Bennett and &#8220;The Remains of Prophecy&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-040-author-interview-rebecca-bennett-and-the-remains-of-prophecy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 11:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 040]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=17064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome back, dear readers! Today we chat with Issue 040 author Rebecca Bennett about her&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back, dear readers! Today we chat with <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-040/">Issue 040</a> author Rebecca Bennett about her story story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-remains-of-prophecy/">The Remains of Prophecy</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: Most of this story unfolds through the narrator and Mirwalda’s meeting, yet their discussion keeps propelling us through the story. What are your tips for action-driving dialogue?</b></em></p>
<p>Rebecca: Less is always more! My original draft was a wall of text of all the information that I wanted the two characters to convey. As I kept editing the story, that wall of text would start to crumble. There&#8217;s a saying that the best version of your story is half the size of the original draft. I think that&#8217;s true for dialogue as well. Getting a sense of your characters, specifically any quirks to a character&#8217;s speaking voice, really helps to distinguish the two voices and changes the conversation&#8217;s pace.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: I loved the lines about magic belonging to women. Why do you think this theme is so powerful?</b></em></p>
<p>Rebecca: Women reclaiming power is a feminist theme that has always been reshaping fantasy <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-17065 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/julia-caesar-3VmiRM4vW2Y-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/julia-caesar-3VmiRM4vW2Y-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/julia-caesar-3VmiRM4vW2Y-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/julia-caesar-3VmiRM4vW2Y-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/julia-caesar-3VmiRM4vW2Y-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/julia-caesar-3VmiRM4vW2Y-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />and science fiction tropes. For me, magic has always been female. I read about the Salem witch trials far too young and, even then, it was clear it was a persecution of women, not witches.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What was your inspiration for this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Rebecca: I&#8217;ve always loved <em>The Wild Swans</em> by Hans Christian Anderson and all the different versions. I&#8217;ve read so many stories about the seventh son or daughter being a tragic figure. Tragedy doesn&#8217;t exist in a vacuum and I loved the idea of expanding the mythology of it.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: Are you working on anything else at the moment? If so, can you tell us a bit about your other projects?</b></em></p>
<p>Rebecca: I’m working on a novella about a crime-solving robot ghost in space. It’s ridiculous and I love it. Beyond that I’m riding that submission train, throwing edited stories out the window at each stop, hoping for a lovely red-lipsticked dame to throw a kiss my way&#8211;or just see a murder on the passing train&#8212;I’m not picky.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 040 Author Interview: Shana Ross and &#8220;Not Fade Away&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-040-author-interview-shana-ross-and-not-fade-away/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 11:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 040]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hello and welcome to our fireside chat with Issue 040 author (and LSQ editor) Shana&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-17010 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/katherine-hanlon-mod2s3-qFOc-unsplash-1024x663.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="473" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/katherine-hanlon-mod2s3-qFOc-unsplash-1024x663.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/katherine-hanlon-mod2s3-qFOc-unsplash-300x194.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/katherine-hanlon-mod2s3-qFOc-unsplash-768x497.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/katherine-hanlon-mod2s3-qFOc-unsplash-1536x994.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/katherine-hanlon-mod2s3-qFOc-unsplash-2048x1325.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />Hello and welcome to our fireside chat with Issue 040 author (and <em>LSQ</em> editor) <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/lsq-author/shana-ross/">Shana Ross</a>. Shana takes us behind the scenes of her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/not-fade-away/">Not Fade Away</a>.&#8221; Enjoy!</p>
<div dir="ltr">
<div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Modern, feminist, business-owning witches! This must have been a blast to write. What was your inspiration for this plot, setting, and cast of characters?</strong> </em></div>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>Shana: This is the first story set in what I hope will be a world worth visiting over and over again.  I&#8217;ve been dreaming about these middle aged witches for a while. I adore all the magical schools that others have created but I wonder what would happen if it weren&#8217;t children and teenagers learning to wield and control their powers, but someone a little more like me, who has a lot of life experience to reckon with, even before we get to magic. Not yet wise crones, but definitely not kids. That&#8217;s a world I want to hang out in.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The friendship between Gabby and Natalie is endearing and their dialogue gives the reader further clues into Gabby&#8217;s character. Tell us more about Gabby &#8212; her insecurities, how she views her life, profession, Natalie, and her clients. What does Gabby&#8217;s future hold?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Shana: Gabby is someone whose story, I hope, resonates with many readers. We are all doing our best, with more power and talent than we fully appreciate, and insecurities leaking out when we least expect it. Gabby just happens to be dealing with magical ethics instead of standard office politics or PTA shenanigans. Luckily, she&#8217;s got her best friend to process everything with.</div>
<div></div>
<div>As far as what her future might hold, I think she&#8217;s got a lot to wrestle with &#8211; even a witch can&#8217;t manage to change the world singlehandedly . . . or can she? She can change the course of individual lives dramatically. Is that enough? Can she change history? Is she willing to risk it?  She can&#8217;t be the first witch with a social conscience. But she&#8217;s also not sure how to start testing the limits of her powers.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The ending was totally unexpected and yet felt right. As a reader, I understood at a deeper level what the client wanted. Don&#8217;t we all at some point? Did you know that&#8217;s how the story was going to end before you wrote it, or was this an ending that the characters created for themselves while you were writing it?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Shana: In January of 2018, my book club (hi ladies!) read <a href="https://nationalpost.com/entertainment/books/marian-engels-bear-reviewed-the-best-canadian-novel-of-all-time"><em>The Bear</em>, by Marian Engel</a>.  Reasonable people can debate whether or not it&#8217;s speculative fiction, and I don&#8217;t want to spoil it, other than to say that I&#8217;ve been obsessed with bears ever since. It&#8217;s a bit of a collective inspiration at this point &#8211; a bear is full of raw and lethal power, and more than a bit unpredictable . . . like women, especially those who are caged, one way or another, before finding <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-17011 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/halanna-halila-uDPHdMyckmc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/halanna-halila-uDPHdMyckmc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/halanna-halila-uDPHdMyckmc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/halanna-halila-uDPHdMyckmc-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/halanna-halila-uDPHdMyckmc-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/halanna-halila-uDPHdMyckmc-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />their voice and needs and strength. I think we&#8217;re all negotiating a relationship with some kind of metaphorical bear &#8211; unless we&#8217;re wrestling with a literal one.</div>
<div></div>
<div>All that was bubbling in my heart as I was writing, but honestly, this ending was written to give myself hope. I have friends who teeter dangerously towards believing the world would be better without them, or that erasure would be a relief. I have dear friends who are so frantic in their day to day that I worry they&#8217;ve got similar seeds inside, waiting for a chance to take root. It terrifies and saddens me. I wanted to remind myself that people will surprise you if you give them the chance, and there are plenty of us just waiting to transform ourselves into majestic creatures who deserve your awe and fear.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: OK, big question here: can you speak to the overarching meaning between the ending and the title and why/how modern women are being pulled in these directions?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Shana: I think I alluded to this when talking about the ending, but I think one of the things that terrifies me most about romanticizing the idea that you could just fade away into a blissful non-existence that&#8217;s all soft light and no demands a la the Heaven that Buffy was ripped out of is that I understand it. I hate it and it&#8217;s wrong and awful, but I know why it&#8217;s attractive. On every level, the modern world demands so much from us &#8211; we&#8217;re still fighting SO MANY of the same gendered socialization and roles and toxic social structures that our mothers and grandmothers had to, still, but now we also get to perform them on social media, 24/7, now with push notifications of all your failures. I know we&#8217;ve come a long way, but being a woman is exhausting. But I hope someone someday reads this and remembers that there&#8217;s a better option . . . not to get punny, but I think the status quo is unbearable. It&#8217;s just that &#8220;unbearable&#8221; doesn&#8217;t mean &#8220;game over, I quit&#8221; &#8211; it can also mean &#8220;this is the last straw, hold my latte while I roll up my sleeves so I can fight and not stop until everything is shredded.&#8221; Choose to be a bear.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us about any of them?</strong> </em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Shana: I&#8217;m very new to writing. Started in 2018. That means I&#8217;m still in that entry level phase (which I may or may not ever grow out of) where I&#8217;m working on a dozen different things at the same time. You can catch more of my short work at Bowery Gothic and Big Echo, with hopefully more speculative fiction to follow in different flavors as I find my voice. I&#8217;m hoping to come back to Natalie and Gabby sooner rather than later. And I&#8217;m working on a poetry manuscript &#8211; tentatively titled &#8220;Exit, Pursued.&#8221; The Shakespeareans will get that joke. I&#8217;m all about the bears these days. Find me on twitter @shanakatzross to get all the updates!</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 040 Author Interview: Tolu Senok and &#8220;Silent Lullaby&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-040-author-interview-tolu-senok-and-silent-lullaby/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 040]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to another Issue 040 author interview! Today we sit down with Tolu Senok. Continue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16973 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eberhard-grossgasteiger-cdc35Juktik-unsplash-683x1024.jpg" alt="" width="683" height="1024" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eberhard-grossgasteiger-cdc35Juktik-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eberhard-grossgasteiger-cdc35Juktik-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eberhard-grossgasteiger-cdc35Juktik-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eberhard-grossgasteiger-cdc35Juktik-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eberhard-grossgasteiger-cdc35Juktik-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/eberhard-grossgasteiger-cdc35Juktik-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" />Welcome to another Issue 040 author interview! Today we sit down with Tolu Senok. Continue below for her insight into her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/silent-lullaby/">Silent Lullaby</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The theme of a mother&#8217;s undying love courses through the entire story, and ending it with hope anew&#8211;much needed good feels in here! Tell us, what was your inspiration for this tale? How did it feel to write something with so much love in it?</strong></em></p>
<p>Tolu: Originally I wrote an entire paragraph here about how I had no clue where the idea for this story came from, and how it had just popped into my head when I started writing and I decided to run with it. While this is true, I remember now that shortly after I’d had this idea, I realized it reminded me of a fairy tale by Hans Christian Andersen called <em>The Story of a Mother</em>. It’s about a mother who tries to find her sick child after Death takes them away. The ending is quite sad, but it also reflects the theme of self-sacrifice that is present throughout the story. Also the story takes place in winter, which is quite the coincidence considering it had been a while since I’d last read it at the time and I didn’t remember this at all. But anyway, I think if there’s anything that could count as inspiration for <em>Silent Lullaby</em> as a whole, it would be this. That being said, when it comes to the actual potion, the source of the idea behind it is still a mystery.</p>
<p>The idea for the setting most likely came from, believe it or not, the cover art of <em>Luna Station Quarterly</em> Issue 038, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-038-release-and-cover-artist-interview-meet-caitlyn-kurilich/"><em>The Ranger</em> by Caitlyn Kurilich</a>. Issue 038 was the latest issue when I first discovered LSQ. I <em>adore </em>this cover. The warm colors, the detail, the sense of adventure, I love it all. Kurilich became my new favorite artist thanks to it and her art style. I believe <em>The Ranger</em> must have, at least subconsciously, made me really want to write something set in the mountains.</p>
<p>The healing pool was inspired by <a href="http://dragone.com/en/shows/la-perle"><em>La Perle</em></a>, Dubai’s first permanent <em>Cirque du Soleil</em>-style show. I’ve seen it twice and it’s fantastic! In the middle of the stage is this big, circular pool, and during the show the performers would suddenly climb out of it, or dive in and never come back up. It captured my imagination (as did the rest of the show) and it’s where I got the idea that the healing pool should be very deep and mysterious. In my mind it looks just like the pool I saw there.</p>
<p><em>Silent Lullaby </em>is an emotional story, and I was certainly swept up in those emotions while writing the first draft. It was really moving to see the care the woman showed to her child in the midst of hardship. The story isn’t just about a mother’s love for her child, though; it’s also about one’s love for their mother, and how much a mother can influence someone throughout their lives. I know mother-child relationships can be complex and not always positive, but I still found it comforting to remember the true strength and devotion of a mother’s heart. The love I felt from this story had this warmth to it that even the cold setting couldn’t touch. To be able to write about something so powerful, yet so gentle and pure… it felt good. It felt really good.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The stark imagery of the cold mountains, the river, the witch and her wolves, the magical hare &#8212; what were the challenges of creating this world? What parts did you enjoy the most?</strong></em></p>
<p>Tolu: The biggest challenge was definitely portraying the setting with some level of accuracy. I’m generally not the biggest fan of reading “cold” stories, that is, stories that predominantly take <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-16974 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/peter-hall-U4HgoD5mc50-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/peter-hall-U4HgoD5mc50-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/peter-hall-U4HgoD5mc50-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/peter-hall-U4HgoD5mc50-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/peter-hall-U4HgoD5mc50-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/peter-hall-U4HgoD5mc50-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />place in very icy/snowy climates. There’s nothing inherently wrong with them, it’s just that the constant chill gets to me, if that makes sense. Also having spent most of my life in the Middle East, I have never been up a snowy mountain or indeed had much experience with snow in general. But a mother going into the mountains was the idea I had, so that’s what I went with. However, I didn’t realize until later drafts that I hadn’t done nearly as much research on this setting as I should have. In my defense, I didn’t have much time. I only started writing this story about a week before the submission deadline (since before then I didn’t know <em>LSQ</em> existed), so I was mainly focused on getting the first draft down and editing the prose. But later on I started worrying about all sorts of things, from what types of snow there would be to whether wolves could live that high up to how close the mountains would be to the village to even whether bear pelts could rot! There was a lot of frantic Googling involved at this stage, but I still ended up being insecure about the more “realistic” details even after sending in the story. For a while I wondered if I’d really managed to get the setting “right” at all.</p>
<p>Related to all this was figuring out where in the world the story was set. I’d imagined the village being in some sort of valley, but I wasn’t sure which mountain range was most similar to what I had in mind. My first thought was the Swiss Alps, and while that is what I settled on eventually I think it’s more likely the village and the mountains are someplace entirely fictional, especially considering I didn’t create anything with any specific mythology in mind.</p>
<p>What I enjoyed the most was coming up with the various beings that live in the mountains. I really loved having that chance to be imaginative and see what I could come up with. But by far the creation I’m most proud of is the hare. Its appearance is just such a gorgeous, striking image to me, and it seems so mysterious too, like it has its own life beyond the story. It didn’t take long for me to fall in love with it.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: What other fairy tales do you love and draw inspiration from? Can you name some authors who inspire you and tell us why?</strong></em></p>
<p>Tolu: My all-time favorite fairy tales have to be the works of Hans Christian Andersen. Some of my favorites by him include <em>Wild Swans</em>, <em>What the Moon Saw</em>, <em>The Little Mermaid</em>, <em>The Snow Queen </em>and <em>Psyche</em>. <em>Psyche </em>in particular is one that (once again subconsciously) inspired another fairy tale of mine called <em>The Artist and the Angel</em>. It’s the first fairy tale I ever wrote, and the one I’m most proud of.</p>
<p>My absolute favorite author as a child, and the one who made me decide to become a writer, was Jacqueline Wilson. She mostly writes realistic fiction about children, usually girls, dealing with various family and social issues. However, the theme in her books that inspired me the most was the power of imagination. Despite the difficulties her characters go through in their everyday lives they always have their imaginations and their dreams to act as their safe haven and keep them going. It’s an idea I hold close to my heart to this day.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: </strong></em><em><strong>Are you working on any other writing projects at the moment? If so, can you tell us about any of them?</strong></em></p>
<p>Tolu: I currently have a sci-fi novel in the works, though progress on it has been rather limited as of late. It’s called <em>The I in the Box </em>and is about an amnesiac who has to escape a video game so his player characters can reclaim their lives. It was my 2018 NaNoWriMo project but since then I’ve changed a lot of things about the story and trying to start over on it has been difficult. Recently I received some feedback on a short story I’ve been working on for a long time (another fairy tale) and plan on editing it again. I should probably start a new short story as well though, if anything to prove to myself that fairy tales aren’t the only thing I can write.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 040 Author Interview: Isabel Cañas and &#8220;The Kingdom of the Butterflies&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-040-author-interview-isabel-canas-and-the-kingdom-of-the-butterflies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 040]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16735</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear readers! We&#8217;re pleased as punch to share with you another chat we recently had&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear readers! We&#8217;re pleased as punch to share with you another chat we recently had with one of our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-040/">Issue 040</a> authors. Please enjoy Isabel Cañas&#8217;s insight into her short story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-kingdom-of-the-butterflies/">The Kingdom of the Butterflies</a>&#8221; today!</p>
<p><em><b><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16952 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beth-ireland-ixZqFkb-iPY-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beth-ireland-ixZqFkb-iPY-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beth-ireland-ixZqFkb-iPY-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beth-ireland-ixZqFkb-iPY-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beth-ireland-ixZqFkb-iPY-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/beth-ireland-ixZqFkb-iPY-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />LSQ: Your story carries with it beautiful images of Latin American mythology. Is your particular story about Rosa and Elvira a retelling of a known myth, your own creation, or a mix of both?</b></em></p>
<p>Isabel: It’s a mongrel of myth and my own creation! Whenever I am short on ideas or inspiration, I often turn to fairy tales or myths that are familiar to Western/Anglo-American readers, break them apart, and stitch them back together with fabric woven from my own background, my doctoral research, and dreams.</p>
<p>Sharp-eyed readers might notice echoes of Greek myth in “The Kingdom of the Butterflies”: the seed of the story sprang from a desire to retell the myth of Arachne, in which a boastful mortal weaver challenges the Greek goddess Athena to a contest. TL;DR, she loses, of course, and is turned into a spider as punishment for her hubris. I also drew on Aztec mythology. Mayahuel, Tezcatlipoca, et al., are familiar faces from the post-Classical Aztec pantheon.</p>
<p>Then, I spun many of the aspects of Elvira and Rosa’s half-afterlife from my own imagination. For example, the weaving of souls and the casting of <i>aguamiel </i>(“honey water,” a liquid from the <i>maguey</i> agave plant that was fermented into alcoholic <i>pulque</i> in Mexico from pre-Columbian times through the nineteenth century) in the role of ambrosia, are my invention.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: Although sisters, there are strong differences between Rosa and Elvira. Does Rosa&#8217;s bitterness only come from her recollection of their past, or is there more to it than that? Why won&#8217;t she enjoy the beauty of the monarchs with Elvira?</b></em></p>
<p>Isabel: Elvira and Rosa’s different reactions to their surroundings and their predicament is based on the way my older sister and I have different experiences recalling episodes from our childhood. My older sister is very much a Rosa, and I an Elvira. For example, when we <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16953 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/andrew-coelho-aL7SA1ASVdQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/andrew-coelho-aL7SA1ASVdQ-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/andrew-coelho-aL7SA1ASVdQ-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/andrew-coelho-aL7SA1ASVdQ-unsplash-768x513.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/andrew-coelho-aL7SA1ASVdQ-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/andrew-coelho-aL7SA1ASVdQ-unsplash-2048x1367.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />remember visiting La Reserva de la Biósfera Santuario Mariposa Monarca in Michoacán, México, as children, she has grim memories of looking at the dead monarcas on the forest floor and thinking about mortality, whereas my memories are dominated by a sense of wonder, of looking up at the thousands of butterflies that covered the trees and thickened the air.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: Tell us more about the symbolism of monarchs in this culture.</b></em></p>
<p>Isabel: Their presence in the story primarily draws on my childhood memories of visiting a monarch butterfly sanctuary!</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: What was the most challenging part of this story to write and why? What is your favorite part about it? What made you want to write this story?</b></em></p>
<p>Isabel: Frankly, the whole thing was challenging to write. First, it was the first #ownvoices short story I had ever written (and my first ever published!). Second, it was the first story I wrote while at Clarion West, and I had little idea of what kind of feedback to expect from the 17 other writers in the summer workshop.</p>
<p>Third, it was late June 2018, and the news was dominated by heartbreaking reports of Latin American refugees and asylum-seekers in detention centers on the border. To make a very long and emotionally-fraught story short, I felt—and often still feel—helpless against the rising tides of White nationalism in this country. I chose to write this story, and I will continue to write stories like it, because I believe that embracing and celebrating Latinx culture in today’s political atmosphere is an act of resistance.</p>
<p><em><b>LSQ: Are you working on any other writing projects right now? If so, can you tell us a bit about any of them?</b></em></p>
<p>Isabel: I have another #ownvoices short story forthcoming from Pseudopod that plays with the legend of la Llorona. It’s called “Silver as the Devil’s Necklace,” and is due to be published in fall 2020.</p>
<p>Though I adore short stories, I am primarily a fledgling YA novelist. My current project is an homage to Shirley Jackson’s<i> The Haunting of Hill House</i> set in rural México in the aftermath of the War of Independence. Think very haunted <i>haciendas</i>, stubborn heroines, and witches where you least expect them… it’s been a joy to write!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 040 Author Interview: Angela Boswell and &#8220;Cleaning House&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-040-author-interview-angela-boswell-and-cleaning-house/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Anna O'Brien]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 040]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=16743</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to an LSQ current issue author interview! (LSQCIAI for short. Just kidding. That looks&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-16855 size-large" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/matt-hardy-6ArTTluciuA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="487" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/matt-hardy-6ArTTluciuA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/matt-hardy-6ArTTluciuA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/matt-hardy-6ArTTluciuA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/matt-hardy-6ArTTluciuA-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/matt-hardy-6ArTTluciuA-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 730px) 100vw, 730px" />Welcome to an <em>LSQ</em> current issue author interview! (LSQCIAI for short. Just kidding. That looks atrocious.) Each week, we release a chat we&#8217;ve had with an Issue 040 author. This week we&#8217;re happy to share an interview with Angela Boswell about her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/cleaning-house/">Cleaning House</a>.&#8221;</p>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: The story starts with an apology, but as the tale continues, we realize the narrator isn&#8217;t apologizing for the loss of her grandmother. What does this apology (and the narrator&#8217;s previous actions to warrant the apology) say about her character and who she is?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Angela: She&#8217;s entered into a world she doesn&#8217;t understand, both in terms of mythology and intimacy.  But she learns to understand at least part of it.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Tell us more about the concept of soul tea &#8212; where did this idea come from? What kind of creature is Maris truly?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Angela: I wrote a couple of different versions of this story, inspired by a <em>Tears for Fears</em> b-side called &#8220;Sea Song,&#8221; where the singer is talking to some sort of mer-person drinking buddy about how they&#8217;re kindred spirits even though they&#8217;re totally different.  Later, I came across what I thought must have been the inspiration for the song, a folktale about a man and his drinking buddy, a merrow who subsists on the souls of shipwrecked sailors, which he catches in lobster cages.  When I wrote another version of the story, I had Maris do something similar, only Maris made tea from the souls.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Maris isn&#8217;t a merrow or a human, but is more like the person described in the song.  Someone utterly alien, but at the same time so familiar that you could swear you&#8217;ve always known each other.  The name Maris means &#8220;from the sea.&#8221;</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Through the story, we realize along with the narrator how the grandmother&#8217;s life was enriched by Maris, and then we learn specifically more about Maris&#8211;it seems like a natural process as told from the first person point of view. Was there ever any doubt in how you <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-16856 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/allie-smith-HGdTI0d7PVE-unsplash-300x203.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="203" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/allie-smith-HGdTI0d7PVE-unsplash-300x203.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/allie-smith-HGdTI0d7PVE-unsplash-1024x693.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/allie-smith-HGdTI0d7PVE-unsplash-768x520.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/allie-smith-HGdTI0d7PVE-unsplash-1536x1039.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/allie-smith-HGdTI0d7PVE-unsplash-2048x1386.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />were going to narrate this piece?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Angela: It was always in first person, but the earlier version switched partway through to become a sort of second person POV talking to Maris.  This was too jarring, so I decided that it needed to be clear that the narrator was talking to another character from the beginning.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: What was the most challenging part of the story to write and why? What&#8217;s your favorite part?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Angela: The ending, because I didn&#8217;t really have one for a long time.  I knew that something came between Lottie and Maris, but I wasn&#8217;t sure what.  I think my favorite part is their meeting.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
