<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Pen Across the Pond &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/the-pen-across-the-pond/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 16:10:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Filk – science fiction music?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/filk-science-fiction-music/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Judith Field]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 12:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Pen Across the Pond]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=9110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A topic I was asked to consider blogging about was science fiction poetry. I confess&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A topic I was asked to consider blogging about was science fiction poetry. I confess that this isn’t something I’m familiar with, except for the rather florid output of <a href="//www.poemhunter.com/howard-phillips-lovecraft/">HP Lovecraft</a>. Science fiction music is a different matter. It occurred to me that there are many songs fitting the theme: David Bowie’s “Space Oddity”, Elton John’s “Rocket Man”, and let’s not forget “Hawkwind” with Silver Machine, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MYVx178VlZ8">Quark Strangeness and Charm</a> (one of my &#8217;70s favorites) and more. And that’s just the stuff I used to listen to in the &#8217;70s.</p>
<p>Wondering about the music of today led me to think about filk. It began in the USA in the &#8217;50s and the name comes from a misprint of the word “folk”. It used to be performed at science fiction conventions, but now it has gatherings of its own. Although it’s sometimes described as science fiction folk music, that falls short of the full range of music that&#8217;s considered filk.</p>
<p>Filk isn’t that easy to define. It can be thought of as music with a science fiction or fantasy theme, but not always. It can be music in the folk style, but not always. A filk song can be a parody or a pastiche, but it doesn’t have to be funny. There are filk rock bands​, indie band​s​, and even choir​s​​. Although there is plenty of guitar-accompanied ​music, singing can be <em>a capella</em>, or accompanied by piano, strings, brass, percussion, and even ther​e​min.</p>
<p>Filk is more a mindset than a musical genre, but even that doesn’t really help, because not everything written by a filker is filk. To try to get my head around it a bit more, I chatted with Mich Sampson (keyboard) and Marilisa Valtazanou (guitar), <span style="line-height: 1.5;">who perform as the singer-songwriter folk duo </span><a style="line-height: 1.5;" href="http://www.playingrapunzel.com/">Playing Rapunzel</a><span style="line-height: 1.5;">, and include filk songs in their repertoire.</span></p>
<p>Mich has been involved in filk sinc<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/RapunzelLaugh-1.jpg"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9115 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/RapunzelLaugh-1-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>e about 2000, when she heard about it at science fiction conventions but hadn’t heard any. She went to a music meet: “I discovered there a warm and funny group of people who made inspiring music about books and TV series that I loved.”</p>
<p>For Marilisa, it&#8217;s all about the community because ​science fiction​ ​and fantasy are not necessarily her genres of choice. “In 2001 I moved to the UK, and at university I made friends with a second generation filker. He dragged me along to a convention and I never left.”</p>
<p>Fundamental to filk culture is the concept of the filk community: you become part of it by coming to a filk circle. According to Mich, the key to trying to define filk is a performer’s involvement in the community: it’s music created by someone who has identified as filk (which rules out David, Elton, and Hawkwind). “There’s no hard and fast definition,” she says, “and no filk police saying what&#8217;s allowed to be called filk and what is not.” For someone who is part of the community, it’s a matter of personal interpretation whether the music they perform is filk or not. Some people sing non-filk songs at a filk circle. The question really is whether the community would appreciate it or find it meaningful.</p>
<p>Filk doesn’t always have a subject, although the majority of filk songs fit that definition. There are also songs about science, computers, cats, ​historical events, ​myths and legends, fairy tales, ​and about other filkers. They&#8217;re not always in the folk style, although this is the most prevalent. In its early days, a lot of filk songs were new words set to existing folk tunes but these days, many more songs are created with original music than are parodies.</p>
<p>As illustration, Mich told me about this award winning filk <a href="http://www.ovff.org/pegasus/songs/child-of-the-library.html">song</a>, with no speculative elements. It appeals to me because it speaks of the importance of libraries. It is a politically left-leaning song than what you might expect to hear at a folk club: “The only &#8216;filk&#8217; elements are that filkers love books, most of them are left or liberal and that the creators sing it at filk circles.”</p>
<p>Filk has established communities in the USA, Canada, UK, and Germany with an emerging one in Sweden. Mich and Marilisa were delighted when FilkContinental, the main annual German filk convention, invited Playing Rapunzel to be guests of honor this year. As well as performing at the convention and running workshops, being an attentive and supportive participant is key, and accomplished by encouraging others to sing, accompanying others, making friendships, and helping to create the warm atmosphere that they experienced when they first arrived in filk.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/DSC00889s.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-9116 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/DSC00889s-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Mich and Marilisa recommend filk conventions where there are &#8220;lots of concerts of wonderful music, interesting workshops, and (perhaps most importantly) filk circles where anyone and everyone can sing, regardless of ability. Some would say that&#8217;s the best thing about filk music &#8211; new and shy people writing or sharing beautiful music to a fantastically supportive community.&#8221; <a href="https://www.facebook.com/playingrapunzel/​">Playing Rapunzel</a>’s new album &#8216;Hanging by a Hair&#8217; is available to listen to and buy on <a href="https://playingrapunzel.bandcamp.com/album/hanging-by-a-hair">Bandcamp</a>.</p>
<p>For readers in the UK, or who are planning to head this way, the next UK filk convention, &#8216;<a href="http://www.contabile.org.uk/enharmonicon/">Enharmonicon</a>&#8216; and is on 2-4 February 2018. Updates on UK filk music can usually be found <a href="http://www.filk.co.uk/">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Big Eyes You&#8217;ve Got</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/what-big-eyes-youve-got/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Judith Field]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 12:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Pen Across the Pond]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It often seems as though older women in fantasy stories and, particularly, western fairy tales,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It often seems as though older women in fantasy stories and, particularly, western fairy tales, fit into one of two character types: either the fairy godmother (for example in <em>Cinderella</em> and too many other examples to list) or the evil witch (such as in <em>Sleeping Beauty</em>, where the wicked fairy takes on the appearance of an old woman, spinning). There seems to have been an assumption over the ages that when a woman becomes old, she also gains wisdom. This has been warped into the character of the evil, ugly witch. For example, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/baba-yaga/">Baba Yaga</a>, the witch in Russian folklore, is predatory in some stories but in others, she is a helper. But, in spite of her powers, she is always described as hideous. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/cristian-newman-63291.jpg"><img decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-8853 " src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/cristian-newman-63291-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="238" height="359" /></a></p>
<p>Older women are often depicted as grandmothers, white haired, bent and ancient, even though many of today’s grandmothers (and I should know, I’m one) are (we hope) nowhere near their twilight years. This character archetype is often not a proactive one. In <em>Red Riding Hood</em>, Granny is bedridden and frail and the wolf uses her to deceive and entrap the heroine. In the <a href="https://www.tor.com/2017/02/02/fairy-tales-little-red-riding-hood/">original version by Perrault</a> she dies. In other versions, for example by the Brothers Grimm, a woodman kills the wolf and cuts Red and Grandma, alive, from its stomach. It’s refreshing to find an empowered (although younger) female in James Thurber’s 1939 parody of this <a href="http://web.nchu.edu.tw/pweb/users/fionaliu/lesson/5198.htm">story</a> in <em>Fables For Our Times</em>, in which Red Riding Hood shoots the wolf-as-Grandma (with the moral ‘It is not so easy to fool little girls nowadays as it used to be’). Dahl also parodied it in <em>Revolting Rhymes</em> (see above link).</p>
<p>Sometime older women characters are called Granny even when they’re not, such as Terry Pratchett’s hard-headed, stern, but infinitely wise witch Granny Weatherwax, who is in fact unmarried and childless. Her place is one of the respected and admired older woman. Other witches in his books have honorific titles like Old Mother, Nanny, and Goody.</p>
<p>There are others in Pratchett&#8217;s works besides the witches. They usually appear in the more stand alone stories, like <em>Reaper Man</em> which has a feisty old lady, and there are the heads of the Seamstresses (for which those unfamiliar with the great Sir Terry should read prostitutes) Guild and of the Beggars Guild. In his <em>Watch</em> series, there’s Lady Sybil, not in her twenties when she first appears, who has carved out a career breeding dragons and who marries the anti-hero. He falls for her; she doesn’t set out to “catch him”.</p>
<p>Actually, I think having a main character that is “older”, however you might define it, is rare, whether they’re male or female. I deliberately tried to go against that when I started writing my stories about two older ghost busters. You can find some of them <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Book-Judith-Sixteen-Tales-Wonder-ebook/dp/B00MRPKZZ6/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1511604318&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=The+Book+of+Judith%3A+Sixteen+Tales+of+Life%2C+Wonder%2C+and+Magic">here</a>. It all started with a “boy fancies girl next door” theme, but they both were aged in their early sixties. Now, though, I realize I’m the age they were at the start of the series, and if anyone calls me elderly I’ll turn them into a frog. <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/jack-hamilton-271069.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="right-image alignright wp-image-8852 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/jack-hamilton-271069-300x234.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="234" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whatever it is, they&#8217;re against it</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/whatever-it-is-theyre-against-it/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Judith Field]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 16:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Pen Across the Pond]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=8244</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I’m doing a creative writing Masters. When I tell people, they usually ask me why.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a class="left-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/groucho.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignleft wp-image-8245" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/groucho.jpg" alt="" width="185" height="140" /></a>I’m doing a creative writing Masters. When I tell people, they usually ask me why.  Some say that the tutors must be failed writers – that it’s a matter of &#8220;those who can’t, teach&#8221;. They tell me about a fool and her money, that creative writing isn’t a serious discipline. To be thought of as someone following a discipline that doesn’t matter, as someone taking a course out of pure indulgence, can be discouraging. My first qualification was in STEM. That’s productive, but that shouldn’t be the only reason for study – it’s good to do for its own sake.</p>
<p>Some people think that creative writing can’t be taught – that you can either write, or  you can’t.  I think that’s to do with the idea that writing is effortless, even though we know it isn’t. It involves skill, and that can be tapped into, and improved.</p>
<p>For many writing students, signing up to these courses is also about taking ourselves seriously as writers. But to pay all this money just for a confidence boost? There’s more to it than that. It’s  important to have spaces where writers work in a community of other engaged, serious writers. Writing can be lonely, and being a part of a supportive community is one of the greatest things about studying writing and the benefits of the writing degree.  I&#8217;ve learned that writing is a process, which gets better the more it takes place</p>
<p>The skills for writing well can be taught. But as well, it’s a matter of practice. Write, write and write again. Over time, many people can learn to write well. But, in a way, the people who say you can either do it, or you can’t, also have a point. Some great writers are born. What is &#8216;great&#8217;? General opinion? Book sales? Number of books written? Perhaps, after all considerations, greatness something we know when we see it, but we just can&#8217;t define it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Year thoughts</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/new-year-thoughts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Judith Field]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 17:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Pen Across the Pond]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The festive season is over.  But spare a thought for the people who were parted&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The festive season is over.  But spare a thought for the people who were parted from their loved ones over the holiday period, and who instead had to spend it with their families. We like to play parlour games, like “guess when the bin men are coming” and “spot the frozen kitchen water pipe”.  I’d tried talking to our recalcitrant pipe, like Moses was meant to have done with the rock in the desert to get water to come out and, if I could have worked out which it was, I’d have hit it instead like Moses actually did. Thank goodness ours survived freezing and thawing and we didn’t come down to find a natural spring in the kitchen when the temperature picked up.</p>
<p>Now we’re into a new year, and I’m with Mark Twain. Now is the accepted time to make your regular annual good resolutions. Next week you can begin paving hell with them as usual. But this year it’s going to be easy to stick to mine, which is not to make any. As I’ve singularly failed over the years to become fabulously rich, to write a novel or tidy the office, these days I just stick to things that don’t take any kind of heroic effort to achieve.</p>
<p>But at my age, losing weight isn’t one of those, and I’ve been trying to find some quick fixes to get rid of the seasonal kilos (converting them to metric makes them sound less). And there have been some pretty daft suggestions published recently. Dieting has become a national obsession and it seems we&#8217;re increasingly willing to put our faith in celebrity would-be gurus rather than common sense, in the battle against the bulge and in the drive to eat healthily.</p>
<p>There are all sorts of silly things said about how the body works. For example, whatever we eat or take, our immune systems can’t be ‘boosted’. As long as we are generally fit and well, the immune system is more than capable of fighting disease. I read of someone who sprinkles charcoal over her meals “to absorb all the bad, damaging stuff in the body”.  Although charcoal does absorb toxic chemicals &#8211; when it’s used in gas masks and in sewage treatment &#8211; the waste products that our cells produce aren’t harmful, and they are removed by our kidneys and liver. And, bad luck, charcoal’s no help if you’ve overdone the festive booze since it doesn’t bind with alcohol at all.</p>
<p>Really, it’s as simple as eating less and exercising more: there are no shortcuts. Even low to moderate exercise is meant to help prevent the milder forms of cognitive decline in older age.</p>
<p>I wrote some time ago about swimming, but it’s such a palaver going round there, getting changed, showering, dressing, drying hair&#8230;what about jogging, for me? Unfortunately, I mostly jog to the kitchen. And here’s the worst thing about working and writing from home. Nibbling and grazing is yet more things that stops me from writing. At least when I go to the library the temptation’s not there. Except it is – part of my ritual now includes special “writing sweets”. They don’t crunch and, provided I don’t rustle the papers, nobody can object. Wouldn’t it be great if someone made sweets with story ideas on the inside of each wrapper? Move over, fortune cookies. Send them my way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thief of Joy</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/thief-of-joy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Judith Field]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Pen Across the Pond]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=7495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Do you find writing easy? Do you sit down at your computer, or pick up&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you find writing easy? Do you sit down at your computer, or pick up your pen, and find the words just flow? I can think of about two stories I&#8217;ve written where that happened, stories which almost seemed to write themselves, but otherwise it’s one hard slog.</p>
<p>My day job and demanding family mean that I don’t have that much time to write. So, when I do manage it, it’s discouraging to find it just won’t come. I’m not one of those writers who can sit down for ten minutes here and there. It takes time for me to get into it and, once I do, I like to get my teeth into it.</p>
<p><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/poison-envy-3.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="left-image alignleft wp-image-7577 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/poison-envy-3-300x297.jpg" alt="poison-envy-3" width="300" height="297" /></a>When I hear about my friends’ successes, I want to be happy for them. But instead, I feel envy. And I feel bad about it. I try telling myself, <em>well what do you expect? They have more time than you do, and more support.</em> And then I feel bad about my own shortcomings as a writer.</p>
<p>If you believe that you are not worthy of what they have, or that – as in my case when I feel like this &#8211; you are incapable of ever deserving it then you are likely to resent the other person even more. Feeling envy can produce shame – what sort of a person wouldn’t rejoice in their friends’ success?</p>
<p>In <em>Othello</em>, the evil Iago plants doubts in Othello&#8217;s mind about his wife&#8217;s faithfulness, while advising him, &#8220;O, beware, my lord, of jealousy! It is the green-eyed monster which doth mock  The meat it feeds on.&#8221; (<em>Othello</em>, Act 3, Scene 3). So here we have jealousy, making fun of the people it devours. Many people use the words jealousy and envy interchangeably. Indeed, there’s the expression “green with envy”, bringing us back to the conceptual metaphor of a destructive emotion as monster.</p>
<p>Theodore Roosevelt said “Comparison is the thief of joy”. Proverbs 14:30 says “A heart at peace gives life to the body, but envy rots the bones”. It’s true that envy can be an ugly emotion. Apparently, it activates a region of the brain involved in processing physical pain. It tells you that someone has something that you want for yourself that you currently believe you lack.</p>
<p>There are different ways to respond to this emotional response to someone or something you want. There is something called helpful envy, which motivates us to work harder to achieve our goals. If you believe that you are worthy of it, you can construct a strategy for gaining it. And when I think about my friends’ success in getting published, I realise that it’s not that which makes me envious. Yes, it’s lovely to see your work in print. But what I really envy is their ability to generate ideas. And that’s what I really need to work on, to get my envy to work for me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why write fantasy?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/why-write-fantasy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Judith Field]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 16:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Pen Across the Pond]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I was doing my English degree, one of my tutors didn’t like fantasy. In&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was doing my English degree, one of my tutors didn’t like fantasy. In her opinion, “the supernatural takes over the story”. But isn’t that the whole idea? I wrote a ghost story screenplay. She liked it, but classed it as “family entertainment” (children’s literature was a genre we weren’t meant to write in for that course, but she did me a favour and stretched the point). Perhaps she thought fantasy was childish, juvenile. That fantasy was all fairy stories. You know, living happily ever after, and all that. Unrealistic.</p>
<p>But what’s wrong with children reading that sort of thing? Einstein is quoted as saying “If you want your children to be intelligent, read them fairy tales. If you want them to be very intelligent, read them more fairy tales.”</p>
<figure id="attachment_6831" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-6831" style="width: 206px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/HCA-reading.jpg"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="wp-image-6831" title="left-image" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/HCA-reading-300x200.jpg" alt="HCA reading" width="206" height="137" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-6831" class="wp-caption-text">Andersen took children seriously</figcaption></figure>
<p>I recently did an online course about the fairy tales of Hans Christian Andersen. He had the courage to write stories with unhappy endings. He didn’t believe that you should try to be good because it pays, but be good because evil stems from intellectual and emotional stuntedness.</p>
<p>Far from being a matter of happy-happy-joy-joy, fairy stories can be frightening. Neil Gaiman has said that if you are protected from dark things then you have no protection of, knowledge of, or understanding of dark things when they show up.</p>
<p>Children like being frightened by fairy tales. They have an inborn need to experience powerful emotions. Andersen scared children. His tales are full of supernatural beings, talking animals and objects – just the sort of character I love to write about, too. Not everyone is harmless and well-disposed. In the Andersen stories, the character who turns up most often is death.</p>
<p>One story we looked at was &#8220;The Little Mermaid&#8221;. Even though it’s got a sea witch in it, I’m not sure if the original would scare kids. But, unlike the Disney version, it’s not a happy story. Or is it? In the end of the original version, the mermaid (who is unnamed) does not win the love of the Prince. She can’t.  She is an outsider and the sea witch has taken her voice, her greatest asset. The Prince has to marry someone of his own rank. The Little Mermaid does not have the ability to challenge this status quo because she cannot communicate with him.</p>
<p>However, she achieves immortality by gaining an immortal soul, which (according to Andersen) mermaids do not have. She creates it herself, by dying, turning to sea foam, joining the daughters of the air and doing good deeds for three hundred years. The very end carries a sting in the tale for the child reader, because the daughters of the air are able to get into houses unseen (which might be scary). The three hundred years that they must work is shortened by one year every time they find a child who gladdens its parents and earns their love. But if they see a naughty or wicked child they cry tears of sorrow, and each tear adds a further day to their time.</p>
<p>So it looks like the Little Mermaid has to carry out some sort of penance. Why? Because she dared to swim out of line? This ambiguous ending allows the reader to use their imagination to interpret events, to help bridge the gaps, and write their own ending to the story. So, perhaps I could say that I write fantasy to transport the reader to another world: the text world. As Stephen King says in <em>On Writing</em>, “Description begins in the writer’s imagination, but should finish in the reader’s.” Fantasy offers an alternative world against which we can judge the actual world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who&#8217;s afraid of literary miserylit?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/whos-afraid-of-literary-miserylit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Judith Field]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 16:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Pen Across the Pond]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am. Or at least, I used to be. Let me explain. I used to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am. Or at least, I used to be. Let me explain.</p>
<p>I used to spend a lot of time feeling DEPRESSED. I thought it was that cyclothymia again. But then I made the connection between the low part of the cycle and looking at writing websites. In particular, at competition winning entries. I&#8217;d read them and feel sad, discouraged, like I should give up because I could never write like that.</p>
<p>Then I rallied a bit and thought &#8220;they&#8217;re all up themselves, I don&#8217;t want to write like that&#8221;. Then I realised that the depression induced by said literary mis-lit wasn&#8217;t down to the fact that it made me feel I couldn&#8217;t write. I looked again and came to the conclusion that, if you want to win most of these things, especially the prestigious ones, you must write about someone dying/suffering with something progressive and incurable, disadvantaged/oppressed, sad and lonely or preferably all of them. Literary, because there&#8217;s no doubt it&#8217;s well written. But it makes BLOODY DEPRESSING READING.</p>
<p>My problem &#8211; I don&#8217;t want to write about that sort of thing, there&#8217;s enough of it surrounding us in real life.</p>
<p>I never had the chance to ask my mother about her writing, how it felt, what inspired her. How she dealt with the knock-backs. And it&#8217;s 42 years too late. Although my memories of her are a teenager&#8217;s, I don&#8217;t think she was precious about writing. And I think she might have said &#8220;If you can&#8217;t beat them join them&#8221;.</p>
<p>So I will delete the jolly little story I was writing, about a single mother who gets a job and meets lots of new friends, and start another one:</p>
<p>&#8220;Daisy looked out of the window, tracing the raindrops&#8217; trails with her finger. Soon there were too many to follow, except with the tracks of her tears&#8230;&#8221; I think the rain will make the roof fall in and then I can get in a bit about homelessness.</p>
<p>Hold on, though &#8211; that&#8217;s been done. What else could I use? Dementia seems to be very popular at the moment, too much competition in the competitions. Same goes for poverty, oppression, cancer (terminal for preference). And a friend has suggested the roof fall on Daisy but that she makes a miraculous recovery &#8211; only she&#8217;s really dead. Da capo.</p>
<p>There is one rich seam that, so far, seems to be untapped and from which there is an unlimited supply of material. Stories about women in their late fifties who have trouble staying awake? Any takers?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reading and re-reading revisited</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/reading-and-re-reading-revisited/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Judith Field]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 15:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Pen Across the Pond]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I posted a while ago about a book that I love here. I asked whether, using the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I posted a while ago about a book that I love <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/reading-and-re-reading/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>. I asked whether, using the novelistic convention of dramatising exchanges and giving direct speech to characters, to convince the reader that what they are reading is real, goes beyond the bounds of true biographical writing?</p>
<p>Here is another book that I read time and again, also memoir but amazingly detailed. It&#8217;s<em> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/37200.Anybody_Can_Do_Anything">Anybody can do Anything</a></em> by Betty Macdonald.</p>
<p><a class="right-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/ACDA.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-6301"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="alignright wp-image-6301 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/ACDA-183x300.jpg" width="183" height="300" /></a> I’d read her books<em><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23770.The_Egg_and_I\"> The Egg and I</a></em> (which, like the Curate’s egg, is good in parts) and <em><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/37199.The_Plague_and_I">The Plague and I</a></em> (which I love), so when I saw <em>Anybody</em> in a second hand bookshop in 1981 for only 25p (36 cents at today&#8217;s exchange rate), I grabbed it. I re-read this funny and uplifting boot, with its brilliant character descriptions when I need picking up. But I leave it long enough between reading that I can’t remember the text word for word. When I do read it, I feel a thrill of recognition, like meeting an old friend.</p>
<p>Published in 1945, it’s a memoir of life in Seattle during the Depression, in the early to mid nineteen thirties. Betty leaves an unhappy marriage and, with her two small daughters, goes back to live with her quirky, warm, and supportive family of four sisters and a brother headed by Mother, who “with one folding chair and a plumber’s candle, could make the North Pole homey.”  Betty says &#8216;“It’s a wonderful thing to know that you can come home any time from anywhere and just open the door and belong.”&#8217;  The title comes from the positive attitude of Betty&#8217;s sister, Mary, who spends her time finding jobs for her sisters (especially Betty), and Betty often winds up in uncomfortable, and sometimes dangerous, work situations.</p>
<p>The character descriptions are wonderful. The book is often contemplative, for example when the electricity is cut off because they can’t afford to pay the bill. However, it’s never miserable or preachy. The last chapter is titled &#8220;Anybody can write books&#8221;. Mary has met an old friend who is a talent scout for a publishing firm, looking for North-west authors.  Mary says &#8220;Of course I do, my sister Betty&#8230;&#8221; She hasn&#8217;t actually written anything, but Mary sets up a meeting with the talent scout and Betty ends up writing her first book.</p>
<p>The final sentence, of Mary’s, is wonderful. Betty has just had her first book accepted and tells Mary about her “strange, enchanted feeling”. Mary says &#8216;“You just feel successful, but imagine how I feel. All of a sudden my big lies have started coming true!”&#8217;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Surabaya Johnny &#8211; On Swimming, Aging and the Borshch Index</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/surabaya-johnny-on-swimming-ageing-and-the-borshch-index/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Judith Field]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 16:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Pen Across the Pond]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=6196</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I watched a silly programme on the TV last night, all about exorcism. I don’t&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I watched a silly programme on the TV last night, all about exorcism. I don’t need to worry about demons, I have enough trouble with humans. Earlier in the evening I had been diligently watching another programme about discount supermarkets, but I missed the end because a woman from the Hateful Satanic B*st*rd Corporation (HSBC, for those lucky enough not to have to deal with them) rang up to tell me I had exceeded my overdraft limit and when could I pay some money in? Was there a particular reason why that had happened? Yes, buying food and children’s shoes. In the end she suggested I cut back on my expenditure till I next got paid.<br />
Still, today is another day. In fact, Friday: bed linen washing day, and I manage to get all the beds changed (hateful job) before Jack’s school transport comes. That means I can put the washing machine on and then go swimming, but it is also something of a gamble as there is a good chance the outlet hose will come out of the pipe and I will come home to a swimming pool of my very own, in the kitchen.</p>
<p>At the pool, I decide to see if is really cheaper to hold the sort of membership deal I do, which allows you to swim whenever you want, but which I only use about twice a week at the moment. “It depends – are you over 65?” says the receptionist. Should I say yes, in the hope of getting cheaper swimming, or hit her? In the end I do neither, but slink off with a line from Kurt Weill’s song “<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-ebY8MB0qeY" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Surabaya Johnny</a>” playing in my head: “ich seh schon aus im Spiegel wie eine Vierzigjährige”. It actually translates along the lines of “I look in the mirror and I am like a 40-year old”. I am not sure if the protagonist, who tells us that she was 16 when she first met the dastardly Johnny (“take that pipe out of your gob, you dog!”), means that she is now 40 or that she just looks like she is. I’d be delighted if this happened to me either way, but just to make things worse, you usually find the line translated as “When I look at my face in the mirror, there&#8217;s an old woman staring back at me.”</p>
<p>I go straight from the pool to the cash machine (the scene of the great debit card robbery) to deliver the death blow to my savings account by drawing out the last £50. This ATM is outside the supermarket, where there is beetroot for sale. And if beetroot’s here, can borshch be far behind?</p>
<p>If chicken soup is Jewish penicillin, borshch is Ukrainian Valium. I’ve found that the amount of borshch I eat is inversely proportional to how good I feel. I don’t mean that eating lots of it makes me miserable – the mood comes first and the lower it is, the more borshch gets made.</p>
<p>I think of it as the Borshch index – the bluer I feel, the redder the meal.</p>
<p>Even the production process is relaxing because you can’t hurry it and the beetroot takes ages to cook. There are loads of recipes out there, the key ingredient is beetroot but it seems to be up to you after that. This is the one I find the most anxiolytic, in fact called “bortsch”, but let’s not go there:</p>
<p>500g beetroot<br />
1 large onion<br />
500g potatoes<br />
2 tbsp oil<br />
2 garlic cloves<br />
1.2 litres vegetable stock or beetroot cooking liquid<br />
2 tablesp lemon juice<br />
salt &amp; pepper</p>
<p>Wash the beetroot, place in a pan of salted water, bring to the boil and simmer till tender (this is the “can’t hurry” bit and I find it can take an hour or so). Cool slightly, peel and chop, reserving cooking liquid.</p>
<p>Wash and chop the potatoes, peel and chop the onion. Saute in hot oil for 10 minutes. Add crushed garlic and cook for a further 5 minutes. Add the stock/cooking liquid, cover and simmer for 15 minutes until tender.</p>
<p>Add the beetroot and lemon juice, season with salt and pepper and continue cooking for 5 minutes. Cool slightly and blend until smooth.</p>
<p>35 years ago my Russian teacher told me that the last letter of the word is called shcha and in those days (at any rate) it was pronounced “sh-ch”. So that’s why I am pretentiously not spelling it borsh, borsch, borscht, borsht or any of the other variants.</p>
<p>Once home, I find that God has smiled on me. Not only has the washing machine not flooded but the first lot is dry and all the shirts are non-iron ones. Into the drier with the second lot, which is all bed linen – that must mean I am catching up.</p>
<p>Better do some day job work. I have very stupidly agreed to translate a scientific paper into English, about the treatment of cyanide poisoning. Well, it’ll make a change from phone conferences. And nobody will know any better when, according to me, the abstract starts: “This paper describes the role of borshch in the treatment of a 52-year-old HSBC customer who preferred prussic acid to phone calls”.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jolly Writing Weather?</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/jolly-writing-weather/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Judith Field]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 17:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Pen Across the Pond]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=5947</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A rainy day in Mill Hill town Had me low had me down. I viewed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><a class="center-image" href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/rainy_day_free_wallpapers_9442466031.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-5979"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="aligncenter wp-image-5979 size-medium" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/rainy_day_free_wallpapers_9442466031-300x292.jpg" alt="rainy_day_free_wallpapers_9442466031" width="300" height="292" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">A rainy day in Mill Hill town<br />
Had me low had me down.<br />
I viewed the morning with alarm;<br />
Working at home had lost its charm.<br />
How long, I wondered, could this thing last?<br />
But the age of miracles hadn&#8217;t passed,<br />
For suddenly I saw you there<br />
And through rainy Mill Hill town<br />
The sun was shining ev&#8217;rywhere</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">(with apologies to George and Ira Gershwin)</p>
<p>The only person I can see here is Shadow the cat.</p>
<p>My computer has gone to sleep, I hope I can post this before it falls over. It’s doing that thing where things shut down very slowly. I sing<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kV5JbDJXwyM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> “The Keel Row”</a> while it does this because it’s the right speed and it echoes the herky-jerky motion of the picture on the screen as the application closes: DOWN-stop, DOWN-stop (try singing it and you&#8217;ll see what I mean). Trance, it isn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>And above the strident hiss of tinnitus (aka &#8220;that bloody racket&#8221;) I can hear the washing machine running downstairs. I have no choice but to run into the street, grab the first person I see, and tell them about the wonder that has befallen me.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">But as I pass the kitchen door, I notice that the washing machine isn&#8217;t on. I go back upstairs and do a bit more of that day job stuff they pay me for. A few minutes later, I pause, and I can hear the machine again. Another trip downstairs confirms that neither the cat, a poltergeist nor anyone else has switched it on. Who needs a step aerobic class?</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">This happens on and off all morning, interrupting my day job stream of consciousness. I have to assume this is some kind of auditory equivalent of a phantom limb pain, caused by the fact that today is unusual in that the laundry basket was not impacted with filthy duds by 5.30 am so <em>I didn&#8217;t need to put the machine on</em>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Working from home – I have managed to procrastinate quite a lot today. I have been writing instead of day jobbing. The latest story, now at draft 7. I doubt whether this is going to be a lucky number though.</p>
<p>Then when I’d done that, I tried to find a music file of the Israeli song “Sharm el Sheikh”, to send to a colleague who is planning to visit the place. Not that she asked me to, but that never stops me. All I could find was a midi with a rotten accompaniment to the melody, if she still wants to go after hearing that then she must be really keen. If some more annoying work comes in I will translate the words and send her that, too. Stalker? Well, only from 9-5.</p>
<p>I have just sent off my another writing competition entry. The last one got nowhere. I tell myself it was too quirky. The closing date for the last competition passed two weeks ago. Perhaps if I stop this, it’ll have the same benefits as stopping banging my head on the wall.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>All my stories have initial working titles, then they get real titles. That one was known to me as “Perky Scouse Girls”, and that’s all I’m saying for now. The next competition closes in the middle of March. Time to close &#8220;Perky Scouse Girls&#8221; v8 now, computer permitting: all together now:</p>
<p>As I came thro&#8217; Sandgate, thro&#8217; Sandgate, thro&#8217; Sandgate&#8230;</p>
<p><em>Come on…</em>Finally.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Now start another story: Racism v1.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
