<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Issue 051 &#8211; Luna Station Quarterly</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/category/issue-051/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/</link>
	<description>Stellar Short Fiction by Women-Identified Writers Since 2010</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 18:12:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Issue 051 Author Interview: Fiona Moore and &#8220;Misrule&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-fiona-moore-and-misrule/</link>
					<comments>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-fiona-moore-and-misrule/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 11:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 051]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In today&#8217;s Issue 051 author interview, Fiona Moore chats with us a bit about her&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>In today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a> author interview, Fiona Moore chats with us a bit about her holiday-meets-folk-horror tale &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/misrule/">Misrule</a>&#8220;!</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Within a small village or town, sometimes traditions can carry on unchecked. Mary found a creative solution to alter the holiday from within. What is the importance of diverting their revelry instead of stopping it, and how does Mary “win”?</strong></em></div>
<p><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28946 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/claire-rush-Xc-eD801bTI-unsplash-169x300.jpg" alt="" width="169" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/claire-rush-Xc-eD801bTI-unsplash-169x300.jpg 169w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/claire-rush-Xc-eD801bTI-unsplash-576x1024.jpg 576w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/claire-rush-Xc-eD801bTI-unsplash-768x1365.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/claire-rush-Xc-eD801bTI-unsplash-864x1536.jpg 864w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/claire-rush-Xc-eD801bTI-unsplash-1152x2048.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/claire-rush-Xc-eD801bTI-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px" />Fiona: I think the key realization for Mary was when she stopped thinking of Misrule as something that needed to be ended, and instead as something which had value to people, but that value had been subverted by Stebbins playing the system. Once she worked out a way of doing an end run around Stebbins, people came on board and supported her efforts, and Misrule could become something that helped the village rather than an excuse for bullying and revenge. So she &#8220;wins&#8221; by taking control of Misrule on behalf of the community, then giving it back to the community.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Everyone in the village agrees that Misrule is important, even an outsider like the vicar. Why would they feel it important even after the misery it causes?</strong></em></p>
<div dir="ltr">Fiona: Even though Misrule causes misery, it&#8217;s still, to some extent, serving its intended purpose of providing people with a cathartic outlet for their frustrations and a way for the poor and downtrodden to experience the privilege they don&#8217;t normally have. As Mary herself admits, she&#8217;d done harm herself under the guise of Misrule. In the end, Mary has to acknowledge that there&#8217;s good in Misrule, and that it&#8217;s best to change it so that it minimizes the harm and maximizes the good, rather than doing away with it altogether.</div>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Misrule seems to draw on folkloric traditions like the Wild Hunt and MidWinter celebrations. Are there some specific traditions that you drew from for this story?</strong></em></p>
<p>Fiona: Specifically, the Twelve Days of Christmas and the traditions of Misrule and Saturnalia. But I also took a lot of inspiration from the British folk-horror film genre. Misrule owes quite a bit to <em>The Blood on Satan&#8217;s Claw</em>, in which a demonic influence causes a group of young people in a 17th-century village to run amok (and I&#8217;ll freely admit that The Vicar is in part based on Anthony Ainley&#8217;s character in that movie). Folk-horror movies often explore ideas like identity, community and justice through British folk traditions, and I wanted to do some of that too.<img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28948 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/peter-kleinau-7uLjsxzQUzk-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/peter-kleinau-7uLjsxzQUzk-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/peter-kleinau-7uLjsxzQUzk-unsplash-1024x680.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/peter-kleinau-7uLjsxzQUzk-unsplash-768x510.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/peter-kleinau-7uLjsxzQUzk-unsplash-1536x1020.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/peter-kleinau-7uLjsxzQUzk-unsplash-2048x1360.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><br />
<span class="im"><br />
</span><em><strong>LSQ: I loved the ending, where you predicted Stebbins would turn into a joke. Also, that Mary found romance at the end. What are your favorite kinds of stories to write?</strong></em></p>
<div dir="ltr">Fiona: As you&#8217;ve noticed, ones with upbeat endings! &#8220;Misrule&#8221; is unusual for me, though, in that I usually write science fiction or horror. It was interesting for me to do a straight fantasy rather than a story about self-driving cars with anxiety issues.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-fiona-moore-and-misrule/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 051 Author Interview: Dixon March and &#8220;Redbean&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-dixon-march-and-redbean/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 11:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 051]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28918</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looking for the perfect New Weird horror story? You&#8217;ve come to the right place! Today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking for the perfect New Weird horror story? You&#8217;ve come to the right place! Today we&#8217;re highlighting <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a>&#8216;s &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/redbean/">Redbean</a>&#8221; and talking to author Dixon March, who shares the unsettling inspiration behind this story.</p>
<p><span class="im"><em><strong>LSQ: What a delectable horror story! I was especially impressed with the creative worldbuilding. How did you get tortured souls from beans?</strong></em><br />
</span></p>
<div><img decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28926 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/kaur-kristjan-KyC_xxID4Eo-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/kaur-kristjan-KyC_xxID4Eo-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/kaur-kristjan-KyC_xxID4Eo-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/kaur-kristjan-KyC_xxID4Eo-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/kaur-kristjan-KyC_xxID4Eo-unsplash-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/kaur-kristjan-KyC_xxID4Eo-unsplash-2048x1366.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Dixon: Wow, thank you! That compliment will keep the miserable screeching bean of my writerly confidence warm for a whole year.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The world in this story was not-so-subtly inspired by one of my neighbors’ utterly bizarre Halloween displays. The year I moved to the block, the guy two doors down from me sets up a plastic skeleton with a cowboy hat, sitting on a hay bale and holding a sign that read, “Pray for Harvest: Corn, Beans, Souls.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>It was among the most sinister things I’ve ever seen. It actively haunted me. I live in a large city in the middle of the US plains states, which is a very agricultural environment even within crowded urban spaces, so out here we&#8217;re susceptible to bad traffic <i>and </i>corn cults. A neighbor into <i>harvesting</i><i> souls </i>is not something to ignore.</div>
<div></div>
<div>As in most cases, I managed my terror by writing. At the time I was interested in stories about criminals and frequently built settings that had a mix of urban and rural environments (which both have their share of monsters). All these things tangled up in my nightmares until it came out in the form of a mutated Jack and the Beanstalk tale.</div>
<div></div>
<div>I don’t know where the decapitated heads came from. Decapitated heads tend to show up in my stories more than I care to admit.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: This story has just the hint of a dystopian or at least an extra dysfunctional society. Is this a genre you like to write in? What are your favorite types of stories to write?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Dixon: Oh, yes. To me, the best stories are those that reflect the dystopia and dysfunction we live in now. A sort of &#8220;death sight&#8221; if you will.</div>
<p>My genre of choice is New Weird, which I liken to speculative lit on the edge of fantasy and horror or a spooky, pessimistic magic realism. To me it’s a fiction rooted in anxiety, liminality, and estrangement. I’m also a fan of cosmic/sci fi horror, ghost stories, and anything gothic for similar reasons. My favorite stories speak to the disillusioned and disenfranchised.</p>
<div>While I write in this genre, I actively avoid the tropes handed down from weird fiction writers of old who used these genres as a soapbox to promote their own xenophobia and misogyny. It has to be said: they made some ridiculously wrong-minded stuff. Still the genre has a great potential to illustrate the monstrousness of <i>institutions</i>. This is why my favorite stories have characters who are outsiders, law-breakers and anarchists and contrary intellectuals and antifascists—you know, cool people.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Larron’s backstory puts her in a delicate position: on probation, hungry, and without friends. She is also still a thief. How does this affect her decisions about what happens to her in the story?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Dixon: The reason Larron is able to survive and thrive within the confines of her struggle is <i>because</i> she is a thief. Just like ol’ Jack.</div>
<div></div>
<div>A thief, on some level, has to be insane to so easily trespass where they’re not allowed to go. They make their living off of this transgression of space and class, and they see opportunity where other people see do-not-enter signs. That’s why Larron’s response to the strangeness of the Jackelsons’ farm is not to cower in its shadow but instead to exploit it.</div>
<div></div>
<div>While I don’t necessarily espouse breaking into strange cottages full of decapitated heads that appear behind our apartments, this willingness to transgress is something to be admired. So many rules are imposed on us by institutions (consume, breed, obey) to make us more easily controlled (and devoured in some cases). Maybe if we learned to break the rules more often, we’d be a little less hungry.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: I love the power of the last line. She has her crowbar, and she has some attitude. Why do I get the feeling that Larron is about to conquer the world?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28928 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/m-wrona-pCgxm-HDMNs-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/m-wrona-pCgxm-HDMNs-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/m-wrona-pCgxm-HDMNs-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/m-wrona-pCgxm-HDMNs-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/m-wrona-pCgxm-HDMNs-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/m-wrona-pCgxm-HDMNs-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div></div>
<div>Dixon: I’m glad you got that feeling, because she is. Larron can’t outright defeat the Jackelsons—they’re too large a monster—but in small ways she can defeat them to get what she needs; food and resources for herself and her unborn, in the same way Jack brought back those golden eggs for his mother. Larron is absolutely going to use that crowbar to crack open creepy cottage windows, sneak around the monsters to take what they’re hoarding, and profit off it. In that, she models a strategy I’d like to employ more often to confront my terrors of the dysfunctional world we live in (and potentially that soul-harvesting neighbor if he ever comes around to start something). Even if we can’t bring these institutions crashing down on our own, then maybe in small ways, we can still undermine them. We just need to think like a thief.</div>
<div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 051 Author Interview: Jordan Hirsch and &#8220;2122, Barrel-Aged and Biding&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-jordan-hirsch-and-2122-barrel-aged-and-biding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 11:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 051]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What happens when a space pirate&#8217;s past comes back to haunt her? Issue 051 story&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>What happens when a space pirate&#8217;s past comes back to haunt her? <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a> story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/2122-barrel-aged-and-biding/">2122, Barrel-Aged and Biding</a>,&#8221; that&#8217;s what! Today author Jordan Hirsch is here to talk about the writing process for this fantastic tale.</div>
<div dir="ltr">
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: You do an amazing job building the anticipation here! What is your advice for creating tension without totally giving away what&#8217;s about to happen?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jordan: For me, the smaller the detail, the slower the pace. If I can focus on a character&#8217;s hangnail, a barely audible chiming in the distance, or the rough feel of burlap, it makes the reader lean forward, drawing them deeper into the story. If I can slow them up just a bit by taking a microscopic view and then choose the right detail to hit on whatever emotion I&#8217;m hoping to evoke, the anticipation and tension should be there.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Shida&#8217;s past is hinted at but never fully explored. Why did you choose to give readers only a glimpse? Why not explore more of what was surely a rich and storied life?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jordan: This story was loosely inspired by a real-life female pirate, actually, so I felt like the backstory was already written! But generally, I&#8217;ve always been fascinated with epilogues, with what happens to the characters after the main tale. Where did they go after their battle/conflict/trauma? How did they keep living their life? What about all those loose ends&#8211;they&#8217;d need to get tied up eventually, for better or worse. I asked myself what it would be like for a space pirate in retirement, and the story went from there.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Where do you see Shida going from here? Do you think you&#8217;ll revisit her in the future?</strong></em></div>
<div></div>
<div>Jordan: I don&#8217;t know if I&#8217;ll revisit her. I typically don&#8217;t like happy endings, so I kind of want to avoid writing what could happen next. There are still members of her former crew out there, so she has to be on guard. Will she be able to fend off the rest of them? Will she even want to? I&#8217;d like to think that she&#8217;ll live out the rest of her life in peace as a barkeep in this little space station saloon, but I&#8217;m not so sure.</div>
<div></div>
<div><em><strong>LSQ: Who and what inspires your writing?</strong></em></div>
</div>
<p>Jordan: I often find myself inspired by other creative pieces: stories, poems, movies, songs. My brain tends to get fixated on one minute detail, such as a word, a tiny element of the setting, or one specific character trait, and then go hog wild fleshing out an entirely different story based on that one thing. If I&#8217;m lucky, this new story works independently of its initial inspiration. However, this can lead to funny reoccurrences in my work. I don&#8217;t know how many drafts of poems and short stories I have from the past year that feature the tartness of lemon (one will be out in March, in fact)!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 051 Author Interview: Kathryn Keane and &#8220;The Last Wake&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-kathryn-keane-and-the-last-wake/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janna Tinley Miller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 11:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 051]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the holidays quickly approaching, your family traditions may be on your mind. Today, Issue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the holidays quickly approaching, your family traditions may be on your mind. Today, <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a> author Kathryn Keane talks with us about traditions and how she used them as fuel for her story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-last-wake/">The Last Wake</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Old traditions and family are at the heart of this story. That these traditions die with the wake of the mother is poignant. Why did you choose to connect the two things in this way?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28905 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/roman-kraft-7sPg5OLfExc-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/roman-kraft-7sPg5OLfExc-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/roman-kraft-7sPg5OLfExc-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/roman-kraft-7sPg5OLfExc-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/roman-kraft-7sPg5OLfExc-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/roman-kraft-7sPg5OLfExc-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Kathryn: Traditions matter because of the people who practice them. Having traditions, customs, rituals matters. Without them, we become unmoored from ourselves and each other. At the same time, though, if traditions hurt and restrict us, or if traditions have no connection to our values, our loved ones or communities we care about, we shouldn’t be bound by them.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I had been thinking about a family bereavement at the time of writing this story. I’d observed and participated in a lot of funeral traditions after this family member’s death, and seen firsthand how the loss of someone with a long enough memory is essentially the loss of a culture. I connected the death of old traditions and the death of a person because they were connected in my personal life. I also connected them because traditions and people are one and the same. We are what we do repeatedly.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Even though Paul had long since moved away, the ghosts appeared only to him. Though he felt guilty about not visiting and was out of place, why was he the better choice over Margaret?</em></strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Kathryn: I wrote about the ghosts interacting with Paul because his relationship to home and family is more complex and interesting, and it’s more emblematic of what I wanted to write about. Margaret has a straightforward relationship with her hometown, her social class, and rural Irish culture because she’s never wanted to leave it. Although she’s more narrow-minded, she’s able to be more nuanced and mature about home because she’s developed an adult relationship with it. Paul still has an adolescent, black-and-white viewpoint of home as somewhere purely to escape from. Being confronted with the ghosts and the value of their stories is him being confronted with the limitations of that viewpoint.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Paul has also achieved social mobility, and to do that he’s had to leave – and he’s had to Westernize. The writer Edward Said, in his book <em>Culture and Imperialism</em>, discusses how colonized cultures like Ireland react to their colonization. He describes three distinct stages: stage one, where cultures wholly identify with their colonizer, stage two, where cultures aggressively promote an independent, nationalist movement, and stage three, where cultures settle on an understanding of themselves as a hybrid between what came before the colonizer and what the colonizer imposed.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">It struck me, reading these ideas, that they’re very like how an individual human being grows up. First you have total identification with the parent, then an aggressive denial and separation, then an understanding of the self as both what was given to you and what you’ve made of yourself. Paul starts the story in that adolescent mindset personally. But it’s also very present in terms of how he conceives of Ireland vs the wider world. He wants to be anything, anyone other than the person who came from the material and cultural limitations colonization forced on him and the world around him.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">At the time of writing this story, I was also thinking through how best to write about Irish culture in a speculative context. I love fantasy, science fiction and horror because of their ability to depict ambiguity, strangeness and possibility. For a long time, that literary project seemed to me to be the complete opposite of the Irish literary tradition, which focuses heavily on the restrictiveness and narrowness of traditional Irish culture. With this story, I wanted to find a way to integrate both these things – to create Said’s hybridity in my own style.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">In this story, Paul learns how to integrate his origins into his conception of himself, both individually, and culturally.  He’s the better choice for the ghosts because he’s the one who’d be most changed by them, and because he’s more representative of postcolonial hybridity.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The ghosts seemed like the nicest people at the wake and they told the best stories! Did you base these women on anyone you know?</strong></em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Kathryn: Every character I write has their basis in real people. But it’s never a one-to-one relationship – I find similarities between people that are relevant to the story I want to tell, and then blend multiple people together. The ghosts are people in my family. They’re also family friends, and acquaintances, and strangers I’ve met out in the world.</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Everything was going to be different, and yet still Paul connects the internet cable. Is there a parallel here to modernity and changing country life?</em></strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Kathryn: Writers can’t make definitive statements about what happens ‘after the end’ of a text, or beyond a text. That’s up to a reader’s interpretation. So I don’t want to definitively say yes, everything was going to be different, or no either. But if you’re asking about my intention while writing, Paul saying this, and it being refuted by the ghosts, was actually intended as a final denial of the reality of his mother’s death. Keeping the ghosts around, and keeping the house the same as it always was, was my way of representing his wish to put off the grieving, the acceptance and the corresponding maturation he needed to go through.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28906 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/umberto-FewHpO4VC9Y-unsplash-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/umberto-FewHpO4VC9Y-unsplash-199x300.jpg 199w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/umberto-FewHpO4VC9Y-unsplash-680x1024.jpg 680w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/umberto-FewHpO4VC9Y-unsplash-768x1156.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/umberto-FewHpO4VC9Y-unsplash-1020x1536.jpg 1020w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/umberto-FewHpO4VC9Y-unsplash-1360x2048.jpg 1360w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/umberto-FewHpO4VC9Y-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1700w" sizes="(max-width: 199px) 100vw, 199px" /></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The internet cable entering the rural household, though, is absolutely intended as a commentary on modernity. Ireland in 2022 is the wealthy European headquarters of many of the world’s largest technology companies. Ireland as recently as 1982 was a place of widespread poverty, with governmentally sanctioned censorship, an ethnically monolithic population and religiously motivated institutional murder. Our modernization process happened fast, and Ireland and its people are still haunted by its past. The cable to the outside world is well and truly connected now, but we’ve still got our ghosts to contend with.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 051 Author Interview: Rebecca Harrison and &#8220;Anwen&#8217;s Song, Efa&#8217;s Shoes, and the Halls in the Hills&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-rebecca-harrison-and-anwens-song-efas-shoes-and-the-halls-in-the-hills/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 11:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 051]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Happy Tuesday! Today we have Issue 051 author Rebecca Harrison with us to talk about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Tuesday! Today we have <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a> author Rebecca Harrison with us to talk about her original fairy tale &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/anwens-song-efas-shoes-and-the-halls-in-the-hills/">Anwen&#8217;s Song, Efa&#8217;s Shoes, and the Halls in the Hills</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: What a gorgeous porquoi tale! I love how the sisters’ plight and song remind us to sing at Midwinter. Tell us about the inspiration for this ending.</em>  </strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28799 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/bruno-van-der-kraan-v2HgNzRDfII-unsplash-300x199.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/bruno-van-der-kraan-v2HgNzRDfII-unsplash-300x199.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/bruno-van-der-kraan-v2HgNzRDfII-unsplash-1024x680.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/bruno-van-der-kraan-v2HgNzRDfII-unsplash-768x510.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/bruno-van-der-kraan-v2HgNzRDfII-unsplash-1536x1020.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/bruno-van-der-kraan-v2HgNzRDfII-unsplash-2048x1360.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Rebecca: Thank you! I wanted to write an origin story for carols, cos after food, they’re the best bit about Christmas. Or maybe they tie with presents, but they’re definitely in the top three. (I’m a tad obsessed with ranking everything – I spent way too much time the other day ranking owls, and I still couldn’t decide which bird got the number one spot.) *insert ‘what a sad little life’ meme here*</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">You can imagine how much time I spend every year deciding the top ten Christmas Carols. In The Bleak Midwinter has been number one for the past few years, but Good King Wenceslas was always my favorite as a child, and whenever I was trudging frozen paths, I used to imagine I was treading in his steps, in the hope it would warm me.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I tend to write a lot of stories involving music, despite my main passion being chocolate.  I have a novella coming out in January which is a gothic folk horror, sort of <em>Jane Eyre</em> meets <em>The Wicker Man</em>, and my heroine is a composer. It’s called <em>The White Horse</em> and is being published by Spooky House Press.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I also wanted the last line of &#8220;Anwen’s Song, Efa’s Shoes, and the Halls in the Hills&#8221; to be the same as its first line. Just cos that’s really cool. The Mortal Engines tetralogy, which I love, ends with its opening line.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ:</strong> </em><strong><em>I recognize the dancing-to-death shoes of Snow White’s witch (I so love that you included them!). In the same vein as the above question, how much is real folklore or fairy tale and how much is your own story?</em> </strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Rebecca: To be honest, I didn’t remember those shoes! I had to look them up! Though I’m certain, at some point, I must’ve read the proper Snow White. I do remember The Red Shoes, but the stone shoes in my story are kinda the opposite of frenzy and heat, they’re more about being worn down. It might’ve been inspired by my own experiences attempting to dance. I’m a total clodhopper. I’m so heavy-footed, friends nicknamed me Hannibal. After the fella who crossed the Alps with elephants, not Lecter. I don’t like wine.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Anwen’s Song&#8221; is my own story, but it was def inspired by <em>The Ice Palace</em> by Robert Swindles which is an origin story for Father Christmas. It’s an amazing book that doesn’t have the love it deserves. Before he was the cuddly fella scoffing mince pies and steering reindeer past the moon, Father Christmas was Starjik, a child snatcher whose sled was pulled by yellow-eyed wolves. The Ice Palace also has one of the best opening lines ever: <em>Turn your face into the East wind, and if you could see forever you would see Ivan’s land.</em></p>
<p><strong><em>LSQ: Tell us about your choice for letting the sisters lose their voices. Is it an acceptable price for them?</em>  </strong></p>
<p>Rebecca: I didn’t want Anwen to get her sister back by magic, I wanted her to work out how to do it without any supernatural help, and that meant losing her voice. I was a bit inspired by <em>The Three Ravens</em>, or rather Jim Henson’s <em>The Storyteller</em> version which ends with one of the brothers failing to transform completely and being left with one wing &#8211; the narrator concludes ‘<em>but he didn’t mind, and nor do I and nor, my dear, should you.</em>’</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">By the way, if you haven’t seen it, you must watch Jim Henson’s <em>The Storyteller</em>. Hello, Jim<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28800 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jakob-braun-izpGQ-T1ghA-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jakob-braun-izpGQ-T1ghA-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jakob-braun-izpGQ-T1ghA-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jakob-braun-izpGQ-T1ghA-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jakob-braun-izpGQ-T1ghA-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/jakob-braun-izpGQ-T1ghA-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> Henson, fairy tales, and John Hurt and his talking dog &#8211; what could be better? In case you need any more persuasion, every episode starts with these words ‘<em>When people told themselves their past with stories, explained their present with stories, foretold the future with stories, the best place by the fire was kept for the storyteller</em>.’ I always read my folk tales in his voice in my head.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: When the family was singing together and the Barrow men were creeping up behind them, it was terrifying! What are your tips for writing tension?</strong></em><strong> </strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Rebecca: Thank you loads! I’m not sure writing tension has ever been one of my strong points. My strong points are eating cake, and having the bedtime of a nonagenarian. A medieval nonagenarian at that, the sun’s gone to bed so I’m going to bed. And on that note, it’s getting dark here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 051 Author Interview: Madeehah Reza and &#8220;85 Days in Flight&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-madeehah-reza-and-85-days-in-flight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 051]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28735</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What happens when the science in science fiction takes a backseat to the human relationships&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What happens when the science in science fiction takes a backseat to the human relationships in the story? It looks a little something like our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a> story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/85-days-in-flight/">85 Days in Flight</a>&#8220;! Author Madeehah Reza is here with us today to share how this story came together.</p>
<div><strong><i>LSQ: I’m in awe of how many relationships you managed to pack into this fantastic epistolary adventure. How did you get the idea for this story, and was it always going to be told in letters?</i></strong></div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28738 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/andrew-dunstan-qdUDnCjo7e0-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/andrew-dunstan-qdUDnCjo7e0-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/andrew-dunstan-qdUDnCjo7e0-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/andrew-dunstan-qdUDnCjo7e0-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/andrew-dunstan-qdUDnCjo7e0-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/andrew-dunstan-qdUDnCjo7e0-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Madeehah: I&#8217;ve always been intimidated to write speculative fiction, whether it was the amount of research needed for even the smallest of technical details or the fear of not being &#8216;accurate&#8217; enough. It wasn&#8217;t until I read Becky Chambers&#8217; body of work that I realized: I adore the human side of speculative fiction. The science-y side of it is just the backdrop; it can inform and entertain the reader but it isn&#8217;t the focus. It&#8217;s the humans (or sentient beings) in the story that pulls me into the world; in the case of &#8220;85 Days in Flight,&#8221; it&#8217;s the bond that Amira has with her grandfather. The other relationships blossomed from that core bond.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The choice to tell the story through letters was completely spontaneous, as a lot of writing can be. Amira is stuck on a &#8216;tin can&#8217; ship with no way of communicating with her family on Earth. That&#8217;s tough to imagine, especially in our hyperconnected world. Looking back, I think it was influenced in part by journaling, something I practiced during tough parts of my life. Those journal entries seemed like writing letters, letters to parts of myself that seemed unreachable, but that I wanted to reconnect with.</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: </strong><span class="im"><strong><i>I feel so much for Amira, but I also feel for her mother, and for Priya. What a terrible decision to have to make. How did you decide who should go on this journey and who should stay behind?</i></strong></span></em></p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be honest, it was quite random! Looking back on the story as a whole, it was always a choice for the characters themselves as to whether they would want to stay or go. Amira, being a minor, would have to go where her mother went. But Amira&#8217;s grandfather and father made their own choice to stay at home, on Earth—this could be because they didn&#8217;t believe what was happening or because they didn&#8217;t want to live in uncertainty in an artificial environment.</p>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div><span class="im"><strong><i>LSQ: Let’s look to the future for a moment, and please don’t break my heart: are they going to reach wherever it is they’re hoping for? Will it be better? Is Amira going to get to start the first ever inter-planetary mailing system?</i></strong><br />
</span></div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28739 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/nasa-Q1p7bh3SHj8-unsplash-2048x1363.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>
<div>
<div>Madeehah: This short story is actually set in the same universe as a novelette I&#8217;m working on. I&#8217;m not keen on breaking any hearts but, unfortunately, Amira doesn&#8217;t quite get to fulfill her dream of mailing her letters to her grandfather. That&#8217;s as much as I can say at the moment!</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 051 Author Interview: Ashley Libey and &#8220;The Witch and the Water&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-ashley-libey-and-the-witch-and-the-water/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 10:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 051]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28712</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lovers of sea creatures big and small will appreciate today&#8217;s Issue 051 author interview. We&#8217;re&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lovers of sea creatures big and small will appreciate today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a> author interview. We&#8217;re chatting with Ashley Libey about the inspiration behind &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-witch-and-the-water/">The Witch and the Water</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: </strong></em><em><strong>This gave me some very </strong></em><strong>Little Mermaid</strong><em><strong> vibes while also feeling like its own</strong></em> <em><strong>lovely, unique thing. I love the transformation that Bee experiences, both mental and physical. Where did you get the idea for this story?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28716 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/frank-mckenna-OD9EOzfSOh0-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/frank-mckenna-OD9EOzfSOh0-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/frank-mckenna-OD9EOzfSOh0-unsplash-1024x682.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/frank-mckenna-OD9EOzfSOh0-unsplash-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/frank-mckenna-OD9EOzfSOh0-unsplash-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/frank-mckenna-OD9EOzfSOh0-unsplash-2048x1363.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Ashley: For me the idea for the story started with the sea witch and then grew from there. I went out to the coast early one morning to read and watch the water, and while I was engrossed in my book, an older woman seemed to suddenly appear in front of me. I was surprised I hadn&#8217;t heard her approach given how rocky the beach was and the idea for the sea witch popped into my head. From there, I started thinking about who might seek out a sea witch and what they might be after.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: I think there’s a part of all of us that would rather pick the water. Bee doesn’t seem to be escaping from any massive trauma or downturn, she just needs something other than what she has. How did you decide her motivation?</strong></em></p>
<p>Ashley: Bee&#8217;s life represents something I think a lot of people go through&#8211;it&#8217;s that time of life where nothing is particularly bad, but nothing is particularly good either. For most people, this will change, but for Bee it&#8217;s going to last forever. She knows on a subconscious level that she&#8217;ll never truly be happy. I wanted to explore a story where a woman didn&#8217;t put her head down and just take what she&#8217;d ended up with.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Okay, so Bee becomes my favorite sea creature at the end of this story. Why did you pick that, and what’s <i>your</i> favorite sea creature?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28717 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cristian-palmer-XexawgzYOBc-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cristian-palmer-XexawgzYOBc-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cristian-palmer-XexawgzYOBc-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cristian-palmer-XexawgzYOBc-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cristian-palmer-XexawgzYOBc-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/cristian-palmer-XexawgzYOBc-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>Ashley: I love octopi and I&#8217;m curious about their association with the monstrous (like Disney&#8217;s Ursula and the myth of the Kraken). While writing this story I wanted to play with the idea that by finally figuring out what will make her happy and unapologetically taking it, Bee might be considered monstrous by others in her (and our) society. Personally I really love jellyfish, all the way from the little guys to the behemoths. They&#8217;re fascinating to watch and seem like they&#8217;re from another world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 051 Author Interview: Sherry Yuan and &#8220;External Processors&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-sherry-yuan-and-external-processors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 051]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you could plug in to someone else&#8217;s consciousness and use it for a quick&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you could plug in to someone else&#8217;s consciousness and use it for a quick knowledge boost, would you? That is one of the moral dilemmas in Sherry Yuan&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a> story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/external-processors/">External Processors</a>.&#8221; Today she sat down with us and talked about the ideas behind this eerily possible tale.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: </strong></em><em><strong>The concept of External Processors both intrigues and horrifies me. How did you create this device and the world in which they belong?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28696 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ruben-rodriguez-IXTvnOOSTyU-unsplash-169x300.jpg" alt="" width="169" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ruben-rodriguez-IXTvnOOSTyU-unsplash-169x300.jpg 169w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ruben-rodriguez-IXTvnOOSTyU-unsplash-576x1024.jpg 576w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ruben-rodriguez-IXTvnOOSTyU-unsplash-768x1365.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ruben-rodriguez-IXTvnOOSTyU-unsplash-864x1536.jpg 864w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ruben-rodriguez-IXTvnOOSTyU-unsplash-1152x2048.jpg 1152w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ruben-rodriguez-IXTvnOOSTyU-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 169px) 100vw, 169px" />Sherry: The idea came to me in 2021 while reflecting on the experience of the pandemic lockdowns, and in particular how much it differed for people on opposite sides of gig economy apps. I live in San Francisco, which had one of the strictest lockdowns in the US. Residents who could afford it could completely avoid the risks of public areas like restaurants, buses, and grocery stores by paying other residents, through various apps, to face them instead.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I first moved to the Bay Area in 2018 for a tech internship, when Uber and Lyft were among the hottest startups. Their messaging at the time focused on bringing communities closer through ridesharing, which felt very utopian. I took one Uber ride from my office where the driver happened to be a tenured coworker. He told me he occasionally drove after work and enjoyed talking to his passengers.</p>
<p dir="ltr">By 2020, the people who’d dabbled in the gig apps as a hobby had already lost interest. With the threat of COVID-19 and the debate around whether ridesharing or Instacart was essential work, the apps felt almost dystopian. The External Processor device suddenly felt like a realistic next step.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: If not everyone has ExPs, and assignments are harder without them, why are they allowed in schools? Is the knowledge acquired by using ExPs truly earned, and does it stay with the clients, or is it fleeting?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Sherry: The school system I imagined bans ExPs for tests, but doesn’t regulate them aside from that. Of course, some students have ways to turn them on undetected and cheat on tests.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It felt reasonable that ExP would be allowed for homework and studying. It’s not too different from how some students have private tutors, who may do parts of their assignments for them.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The question about gaining knowledge is interesting; when writing this story, I thought of ExP’s main advantage as being productive rather than acquiring knowledge. But I imagine either advantage would stay with the clients. One could argue it’s as earned as any other service you can buy, like a haircut or a restaurant meal. What would be a crueler twist, which I didn’t add in this story since Mandy was able to disable her ExP without losing knowledge, is if clients had to keep paying a subscription fee to keep the knowledge gained from past ExP sessions even if they’re no longer actively using it.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: I was very surprised by Eva&#8217;s decision to become an ExP client in the end. After being a server for so many years and experiencing firsthand the toll it takes, do you think she might reconsider like Mandy did?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Sherry: I think Eva understands both the toll it takes, and that it’s the best option for a livelihood for many of the servers. My hope for Eva’s future is that she’ll find a way to change the ExP system, so that not only she can stop using it, but people will no longer have to work as servers. Unfortunately, that didn’t fit into a short story. While she’s still a student learning how the system works, she can’t afford to handicap herself. She’s worked so hard for the scholarship and I don’t imagine her risking losing it by refusing to use the ExP subscription that came with it. It’s a very “If you can’t beat them, join them” scenario.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: Who and what inspires your writing?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28697 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/jj-ying-8bghKxNU1j0-unsplash-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/jj-ying-8bghKxNU1j0-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/jj-ying-8bghKxNU1j0-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/jj-ying-8bghKxNU1j0-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/jj-ying-8bghKxNU1j0-unsplash-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/jj-ying-8bghKxNU1j0-unsplash-2048x1536.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">Sherry: What I read has the most direct impact on my writing. My favorite authors include Stephen King, Ted Chiang, Margaret Atwood, and Kazuo Ishiguro. I also listen to a lot of short story podcasts, such as Podcastle, LeVar Burton Reads, and Clarkesworld.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I studied computer science and psychology at the University of British Columbia, and a lot of my story concepts are inspired by both innovations in the tech industry and recent psychology studies.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I joined an informal writing group in 2021, where I get together with a few friends to read each other’s stories and give feedback, and it’s been an amazing experience. It helped me polish my stories more than I can on my own and get over my fear of letting other people read my work. My fiance Russell is also a writer, and every story I’ve published has gone through multiple rounds of his editing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 051 Author Interview: T. K. Rex and &#8220;The Hall of Being&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-t-k-rex-and-the-hall-of-being/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[catlauria]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 051]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28662</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Another week, another spectacular deep dive into one of our Issue 051 stories! Today we&#8217;re&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another week, another spectacular deep dive into one of our <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a> stories! Today we&#8217;re talking with T. K. Rex, who discusses the rich real-life inspiration behind &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/the-hall-of-being/">The Hall of Being</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: This story felt absolutely joyous to me, and was a joy to read. What a beautiful exploration of a potential future, as well as a great way of looking at the past. What inspired you to write this story, and what feeling are you </strong></em><strong>hoping</strong><em><strong> people get from it?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28665 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sunguk-kim-tIfrzHxhPYQ-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sunguk-kim-tIfrzHxhPYQ-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sunguk-kim-tIfrzHxhPYQ-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sunguk-kim-tIfrzHxhPYQ-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sunguk-kim-tIfrzHxhPYQ-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sunguk-kim-tIfrzHxhPYQ-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/sunguk-kim-tIfrzHxhPYQ-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />T. K.: I’m so glad that was your takeaway. A big motivator for me in my writing these days is to envision paths forward into futures that we can still look forward to, even if most of the worst predictions for climate and collapse come true.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This story happens in a place I’m deeply familiar with &#8211; the East Bay hills in the San Francisco Bay Area. There’s a very strong Humanist, Pagan, and Arts &amp; Crafts presence there, especially in Berkeley where my mom lives, and that culture was a big influence on the Hall of Being itself, on the design of the buildings, furnishings, music (which btw I noticed my sandolin got spellchecked to oblivion, but that was supposed to be a science fictional instrument). A big theme in my writing is ecology and place, and I like to show how native plants and hyperlocal economies can be a bigger part of our lives, and an answer to many of the challenges brought by globalized industrial manufacturing and agriculture — with agriculture being especially important here in California as non-native crops that didn’t evolve for this climate use 80% of all the water that we have less and less of every year.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Another very Bay Area thing about me is that I work in tech, and at the time I wrote this, I was training to become a manager and thinking a lot about leadership and facilitation and inclusion, and feeling a lot of imposter syndrome, so that was definitely a big influence on where Currant is in her own journey in this story.</p>
<p dir="ltr">A whole lot of threads came together writing this, but I think the kick that got me going in a really dark time — I started the first draft around January 2021 — was just wanting to craft this vision of a way of life that integrated technology and science and spirituality and art in this really inclusive and human and kinda weird way. You gotta have weird. It’s what the ancestors want <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: The tradition of going away and then coming back changed is so strong, both in the real world and in the literary one, plus the mystical journey that Currant went on. Did you pull any of your details from real-life experiences?</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">T. K.: Oh definitely. I moved around a lot as a kid, and there were years when going away was all I ever did. Sometimes I came back, sometimes I didn’t. I think I went to twelve different schools across four states. The most formative coming-back experience was halfway through high school, when my dad and step-mom in New Mexico split up and I had to leave the one place I’d ever managed to spend four whole years, and move back to Oakland to live with my mom. I’d lived with her near there when I was a little kid and visited her many times since, but I was so homesick for the desert and I missed my friends in that really intense way that only a sixteen year old can. I had genuine culture shock going from Gallup, a little desert down on the edge of the Navajo Nation, to this huge metropolis, even though it was so familiar and had, once, been home.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As hard as that was at the time, I see a lot of value now in how (willingly) spending time in other places and with other cultures broadens your perspective, especially at that age where you’re itching for adventure and if you don’t find it in a safe way that’s built into your community’s way of life, you might very well find it in much more dangerous way.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I knew kids in Gallup who died of drug overdoses before they could even start thinking about college. I remember hearing once that our county had the highest rate of teen deaths by alcohol related car accidents in the whole US. There was this feeling almost every kid I knew there had, that there was just nothing else. That this economically depressed place in the middle of nowhere (that I happened to love) was all of the world they would ever have access to. There was a real hopeless feeling to that place when I lived there. I think that’s changed a bit since I left but the wounds of colonization take generations to heal and the parents and grandparents of kids I went to school with were still victims of the boarding schools that the rest of the world is finally only now hearing about. A generation before me, Native kids were still physically abused even in public school for speaking their own language. When I was there in the late 90s, Navajo was offered as a language credit and the Code Talkers were celebrated in the media, but there was still a<em> lot</em> of bias in that system. Even though most of my classmates were Diné, almost all the teachers and school administrators were white. I have no idea if that’s changed at all.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I’ve never really felt like I belonged anywhere, and my immediate ancestors are all from Europe where I’ve spent a grand total of like three weeks tops, but imagine being forced to feel like you don’t belong <em>in your own land that you and all of your family have always lived in</em>. And simultaneously knowing you’ll have zero opportunities to ever leave. And having that connection to the land that your people always depended on intentionally severed on the physical, spiritual, and psychological levels by generations of occupation and oppression. That’s colonialism and it’s alive and well in 2022 all over the world. It sucks. It sucks for all of us even if we don’t think we’re in a colonized group (btw Europe colonized itself first) because it prevents nearly <em>everyone</em> from forming the kind of close, long-term relationships with our local ecosystems that would make us all stand up and fight if we truly saw what’s been done to them in the name of ever-increasing shareholder profits.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I can’t say that this story even attempts to undo colonialism, but the world it takes place in is one that is starting to heal from it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The mysticism and spirituality in &#8220;The Hall of Being&#8221; is an amalgamation of all my favorite things about the different religions I’ve spent time around, without being an actual religion. I was raised Wiccan/Pagan but when I lived in Gallup, I attended church sometimes with Catholic friends, dances with Mormon friends, and pow-wows with my journalist dad, who came from a secular Jewish family. His beat was the Navajo Nation, and he was invited to a peyote ceremony at least once, which he described to me when I was about thirteen or fourteen. I think you can find the influences of all of those traditions in The Hall of Being if you go looking for them, although I tried very hard to avoid appropriation. I really wanted to create something that felt like its own thing.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As an adult, I found that I didn’t need any religion to feel a spiritual connection to the universe — it was all around me, and studying ecology and evolution and deep time gave me this perspective of being intimately connected to the earth and all life on it, in a much more detailed and real and nuanced way than even the earth religion I was raised in could. My earliest memory of truly dizzying awe was on a kid’s fossil hunting trip in Oregon, when I found a fossil clam and realized that I held in my hand something that had been alive there millions of years ago, long before my ancestors looked human. For me, nothing religious has ever surpassed that feeling.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I’ve also come to understand that the real value of religion for so many people is not just spiritual, but communal. And that form factor, of communities coming together every week or every new moon to connect and make space for each other’s personal challenges, and maybe even dabble in transcendence — that has a lot of value, and can be extremely hard to find if you’re not religious, or don’t feel welcomed by the religions around you. So the Hall of Being is my way of bridging that gap to envision a spiritual, communal activity that connects people to our shared, four-billion year ancestry as part of this incredible, unique biosphere, and celebrates diversity because it’s <em>fundamental</em> to life and evolution, to the health of our communities, ecosystems, bodies and minds. We all know the value of diversity on a personal level no matter what our politics are — we get bored eating the same thing every day, frustrated when stuck in the same place for too long. We need diversity in our diets, activities, and day to day experiences to stay physically and mentally healthy. It’s not optional. And it’s as true on the biggest scales as the smallest.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As far as psychedelics go, I’ve only used them a handful of times, and while I’ve never met<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28666 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/kyle-glenn-xY4r7y-Cllo-unsplash-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/kyle-glenn-xY4r7y-Cllo-unsplash-300x200.jpg 300w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/kyle-glenn-xY4r7y-Cllo-unsplash-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/kyle-glenn-xY4r7y-Cllo-unsplash-768x512.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/kyle-glenn-xY4r7y-Cllo-unsplash-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/kyle-glenn-xY4r7y-Cllo-unsplash-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /> anything claiming to be a god, each trip has absolutely broadened my perspective and had a lasting positive impact. The substance described in the story is carefully engineered and completely unlike any modern-day psychedelic. I wasn&#8217;t trying to reproduce an acid trip, but I was trying to say loud and clear that mind-altering chemicals can be extremely useful tools. If you&#8217;ve never tried them, it’s so important to do your research beforehand, know what dose to take, and have that experience with people you trust, in a place that’s safe. The cultural use of psychedelics goes all the way back, it’s probably older than <em>Homo sapiens</em>, and I think it’s really harmful that current policies cut us off from that part of <em>all</em> of our shared heritage. I’m glad to see attitudes starting to change and decriminalization making a lot of headway the past couple years. Psilocybin was just decriminalized in San Francisco this year and I’ve had more than a couple coworkers rave about the therapeutic benefits and recommend microdosing for anxiety, which, I mean, wow. What exactly do lawmakers think all the people who are still in prison for possession were using it for? All “recreation” in a system this broken is therapy.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>LSQ: So, which of the ancestors is your favorite? I’m a fan of the </strong></em><strong>Tiktaalik</strong><em><strong>, myself.</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">T. K.: <em>Tiktaalik</em> is wonderful and since you mentioned it I have to tell a story. A few years ago I was in a lecture hall listening to Ted Daeschler, one of the paleontologists who described the species, talk about <em>Tiktaalik</em> and its place in the early evolution of tetrapods (us). He mentioned this term &#8220;transitional species&#8221; which often gets translated in popular media to &#8220;missing link.&#8221; I asked something along the line of, &#8220;How do you know if something is a transitional species?&#8221; His answer completely blew my mind: &#8220;They&#8217;re all transitional species.&#8221;</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>Deinonychus</em> was my first favorite prehistoric animal, and <em>Parasaurolophus</em> was my second, but ever since I learned about <em>Arthropleura</em> I’ve been entranced. Imagine a millipede two feet wide and nine feet long, crawling along the forest floor of the Carboniferous era, munching on fallen fern tree fronds, watching giant dragonflies fly around, and just being a super chill giant bug. I want that life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Issue 051 Author Interview: CL Glanzing and &#8220;Fishbone&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue-051-author-interview-cl-glanzing-and-fishbone/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jen Gheller]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Issue 051]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lunastationquarterly.com/?p=28576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In today&#8217;s Issue 051 author interview, we&#8217;re chatting with CL Glanzing about the inspiration behind&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In today&#8217;s <a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/issue/issue-051/">Issue 051</a> author interview, we&#8217;re chatting with CL Glanzing about the inspiration behind the haunting story &#8220;<a href="https://lunastationquarterly.com/story/fishbone/">Fishbone</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: The level of detail in post apocalyptic stories is always impressive, and this story is no different. What kind of research did you have to do?</strong></em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28653 alignleft" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/mrjn-photography-YpZ2cj4s0oo-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/mrjn-photography-YpZ2cj4s0oo-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/mrjn-photography-YpZ2cj4s0oo-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/mrjn-photography-YpZ2cj4s0oo-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/mrjn-photography-YpZ2cj4s0oo-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/mrjn-photography-YpZ2cj4s0oo-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/mrjn-photography-YpZ2cj4s0oo-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />CL: Thank you! I think I may have been unconsciously influenced by a really horrifying 1984 BBC film called <em>Threads</em>, which was about a nuclear winter in northern England and it imagined that language would essentially disintegrate over the next generation. I used to live in Scotland, and I always imagined the solitude of the Highlands as becoming a refuge against climate change, rising sea levels, natural disasters, or man-made disasters targeting larger cities. So I tried to invent my own dialect, imagining the last surviving diaspora from Scotland and northern England, set a hundred years from now. The story may have also grown from some pandemic-pessimism when I was living near Heathrow airport. I had read that air traffic decreased by 70%, which was great for the neighborhood but also made an eerie quiet. Watching a plane take off actually became a rare occurrence, and I wondered about a time in the future when the last airplane will depart the UK. I thought it would be a rather significant event. I thought about the people watching, and why they would be left behind. I am not a native Brit, and sometimes the idea of being stranded on a tiny island terrifies me.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Hannah does her best to survive in such an unforgiving environment, but it often feels hopeless. What is it about her that kept her going in face of everything crumbling around her?</strong></em></p>
<p>CL: My favorite books growing up always seemed to revolve around kids having to survive in some kind of wilderness, like <em>Hatchet</em> or <em>Z for Zachariah</em>. I admired their resilience and perseverance. I think all the kids in &#8220;Fishbone&#8221; have created rich, inner lives for themselves in order to survive. Hannah still cherishes her relationship with her mother to an obsessive degree. Jeremy works on his pointless boat. Simon imagines himself as a savior. But what I think makes Hannah different is that she realizes that she cannot live in her fantasy forever, and things must change if she and Jeremy are going to survive. She’s fiercely protective, and in a way she assumes a kind of maternal role over Jeremy and her environment.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Simon&#8217;s cult intrigued me, especially Hannah&#8217;s observation of how young and scared many of them looked, and their inattention when Simon wasn&#8217;t speaking. How do you see them getting along without Simon?</strong></em></p>
<p>CL: After most of the adults of the community are gone, the children essentially have to fend for themselves, and Simon has filled the power vacuum. But I don’t see his followers as a mindless congregation. They’re just frightened children looking for guidance, although probably in the wrong place. And I think that they will fare much better without Simon. It probably won’t be a utopian democracy, but I want to believe that there is always hope for humans to learn from their mistakes and do better.</p>
<p><em><strong>LSQ: Are there any other projects you&#8217;re working on? If so, could you tell us a bit about them?</strong></em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-28655 alignright" src="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/abhishek-koli-DsxD_bTq8x0-unsplash-200x300.jpg" alt="" width="200" height="300" srcset="https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/abhishek-koli-DsxD_bTq8x0-unsplash-200x300.jpg 200w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/abhishek-koli-DsxD_bTq8x0-unsplash-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/abhishek-koli-DsxD_bTq8x0-unsplash-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/abhishek-koli-DsxD_bTq8x0-unsplash-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/abhishek-koli-DsxD_bTq8x0-unsplash-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://lunastationquarterly.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/abhishek-koli-DsxD_bTq8x0-unsplash-scaled.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />CL: I really enjoy writing speculative/sci-fi/weird fiction. I’ve written several short stories in that vein, and it would be wonderful if I had the opportunity to publish them. I’m also trying to edit and polish a bit of an ambitious novel that I’ve been working on for a while. It’s set in three separate centuries of European history &#8211; post-bubonic plague, the Napoleonic era, and an imagined future of the 2100s. Its gothic historical fiction with a heavy dose of magical realism and science fiction. But finding time to write while working a full-time job is tough!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
